American accent Guido van Rossum yeah
you know one of the things that I love
about we know is that he is always
willing to share his pinion
and so I was thinking about what
it will I was thinking that the first
question that I
that the time I ask you just sort of
Kiko vertically as whether even have
Python 2.8
ob and sell
we know is truly
he is the his a not only been in it
never did care for life
but he is part he is the guiding force
that helps keep us all in line least
it least programming language wise so
without further ado
Guido van Rossum the
thank you fan well van too hard act to
follow so I'm not even going to try
I I have a question for the organization
is it possible to have microphones out
there so some people can
ask questions or am I too late with that
request
there are microphones okay on an island
go to my father slide
so to be honest
I always stress out for a keynote
and is here and was worse
and I had total complete mental block
because the thing i really wanna do if
give you another super technical excited
talk about to let
a sin que el cap 250 3156 buck
there were like three or four talks in
the regular program already dead
explained it better than I could
I did that talked last year I did it
again
at the San Francisco buy from me
defended by did it again at the Bay Area
pie from the interest group
I really don't want to certif repeat
myself in that way
so I was really thinking
oh my god what can I do maybe maybe I
should just read from fan mail
because I get a lot of fan mail
and if if you're if you've got a
certified certain type of brain
its all very funny but
actually then I thought about it and I
thought moment probably some of the
people who wrote me that fan mail
are India's audience and I don't want to
embarrass you
I don't want to embarrass myself and
maybe it's not actually that funny
so I collected I asked on Twitter what
should I talk about
I said have racked my brain every time I
had sorta
a brainwave all I should talk about that
I just added to a list and then finally
a lacked last night I collected all
lists I had
women text file I thought oh I'm going
to become randomly
so the first thing I'm going to do is
actually write the code that will
randomly pick
something from the less now they'll give
me some time to grieve
also at I would love to take questions
and as you can see
I today I'm making a choice to only take
questions from women in the audience
because throughout the conference I've
been
attacked by people with questions and
they were almost all man so I think the
women have Sardar there a lil behind and
they can catch up here
Island see how can I find my
you I bingo
okay let's see will win either random
number generator I think
so year
near display how do that that is very
sad
%uh PowerPoint too clever one sec
now handling it
you see that yeah so
a see what what was the rest of the plan
and let's define a function
analysts big question
now
like see for 11 global variable okay we
have a list of questions
but is not yet initialized
actually I can K you know I wanna I
wanted
uninitialized initially and
you can you get you cancer to get a peek
in
into my brain by hearing me talk about
what im
what im doing well programming so we
have a list of questions and we do
something like
if list of questions is
Mt we're gonna have to initialize it
so what show we initialize it to
questions is open and some file
so what was that
II
classy I'm so glad we at least we have
static type analysis here
live static type analysis we should we
should
all have that in in our software and
opinionated
to Co programmer who
tells you when you're screwing up
the
K E and we're going to use return around
choice
left chill chill just tried this
let's try to slow slow see if I can
remember how to run it
source must be saved sure
yeah
I know several have you already saw this
coming so
I'm
on this issue really weird
clearly in Heidelberg I can't I can't
get my cock cursor care where I want
I so this is this is certif
this is a taste of what students trying
to learn Python
are going through in real life sometimes
and somehow I managed to solve my
problem
yes and
CA and run geekdom
it I think they're worth
airline that just said geekdom in my
list the question so let me see what I
can
add live about geekdom I
I'm a terrible geek myself I mean
cool earth would you write such a stupid
program in front of 2,000 people
and think they can get away with it then
stabbed is like as sign up absolute
total
lack of social skills last last night I
discovered one ive one ive mining
Eagles charms is I do not know how to
extract myself from a conversation
many of you have profited from that many
others accuse have wondered when
I was ever done Kayla different let's
let's pick a different question
and again probably just type it here
oppose the idea of exception
expression that sounds like a half-assed
question but I think what it comes from
and it's probably one of those things I
copied and pasted from Twitter
there's being a very elaborate pap
that propose that we
at a new type of expression to Python
against its gonna have to be added to by
if we're going to do it and it would
like
let them actually hey I have I can't I P
I can
can show what it was supposed to look
like something like axe
is the the of by
days for X there the
slit settlers a.m. accepted the key
error
and if it was a key error will say
its none out his lead is not currently
valid syntax 0
but that's what it would look like
and their hall that the
the PAP goes on at Lang in all the
incredibly
good use cases where currently you have
to write a four-line try except flock to
do some very simple
seeing and we have a whole bunch of
methods in the standard library on
various functions objects
that are only dare
according to the author of this pap
offers to
to certify deal with the fact that you
you can't
caption exception certificates Eisley
and I'm still I'm still
against this idea I think its on
ugly syntactic wards to at this and the
call on in the syntax drives me nuts but
any
other sin tax proposal that has has been
sir def
considered for the PAP looks even not
clear to me
and I really don't think that there is a
big problem
to beast that that's being solved here
the problem is
that sometimes people 12 food everything
in one line
and I think that's just that certain
burge you should try to resist and just
be
take a pause take a breath its
okee to to spend a few extra words were
not were not pearl
I
enough on that topic let's pick another
question DVD
who here even knows what KVS oh that's
awesome
who has ever used TV
well soak EV is more popular than I
thought
I don't know if any of the key people
developers are here
TV is Inc the Redis
great tool that you can use to write hi
phone code
on your mobile devices and
it has back and is actually it has
certif implementations are back and what
you can
wanna call them that run on my OS or on
iPad
on iPhone but also on Android then you
can also run your program
and in the browser on the desktop
and I'm I may be mentioning some
use cases that aren't actually yet
implemented the TV certif
lets you write beautiful
user interface applications that will
run on a variety of platforms including
mobile devices
unfortunately when I talk to the people
at home at work at Dropbox who are
developing
aP's former for mobile devices Dropbox
just launched a few new apt for mobile
devices this week
day said well we would love to be able
to use that but it's not fast enough
and I think the key people
deserve incredible kudos for
starting it but they need help they need
a need more technical expertise
for all those different phone platforms
and for Python to help to make it faster
to help
maybe build a community around TV that
is
is larger so that keep you can actually
be successful because pipe from
doesn't have a story for mobile devices
and if TV is the only story for mobile
devices we have we need to
worked a lot on that story so if you
have
into rest in hacking on something
incredibly cool
that will benefit everybody who is go
who was eventually going to
be using mobile devices and mobile
devices
will get better and lots of things will
will sort of
open up once you support mobile devices
we gotta get Python in the phones and
waiting for
boon to mobile or Mozilla mobile OS
I don't think that that's it that's been
the sort of the successful strategy for
actually getting pie from on the phones
enough about that question
worse the next one how awesome despite
3.4 yet have you checked it out yet it
is awesome
it is the best pipe from ever
and its incredibly accessible it is
also easier than effort to port code
from by 2022 Piper flee or to write
coded works both in by phone to and pie
from the
3.4 is
the biggest step I would say
towards making everyone happy
and police go used by complete at fort
even if your main project is still
written in Python to
start getting yourself used to biking
3 download fifa leader for installers as
the
ultimate Python interpreter arm every
system you have
play around with it the number I folks
are very close to switching to buy
completely already
of your web developer using flask for
Django
well there are some theoretical
Portsmouth
it's still hard but give it a try and if
you find something that doesn't work
with by completely wrapped
help someone make it work
as as fam said we are this community and
we can
we can make it happen yes we can we can
all work on being a community and its us
an arson
community community but there's lot of
software that needs to be
improved and fixed and and and sometimes
thrown away
and that's that's what this community is
for so
please help us anyone have a question
yet
you're not a woman
p.m. can you get your girlfriend to ask
that question
all sorts of yes
other side I'm curious what you think
the worst part
contributing see python is today you
mean the
though the worst part of the experience
of of trying to contribute
whatever is the biggest headache 30
perform well for me personally there
aren't very many headaches
what's the Serta but what I worry about
most
is that it is so incredibly difficult
to get started and it
it used to be that that So Def when I
first wrote
see pipe bomb I mean it was the most
complex code I had ever written but I
try to write it as sort of a
straightforward and simple and clear as
possible
and four years people said wow you got
it you gotta read the C code for Python
because it's so clear you can actually
understand how language works
but then generations of people have
added contributions and we added unique
code in
various slow things were improve so they
were faster and there's a
custom memory allocator and the code is
actually not straightforward at
all anymore and so it's very easy to
certif think oh here's
fearsome here's a little bug in Python I
bet I can fix that
let's look it up in the source code and
be completely overwhelmed
and sir if you find well I also talked
to a lot of people who say well
and piping program I don't knowingly see
so it sort of
which which is shocking for me because
when I wrote
when I started hi farm I mean every
everybody was a C programmer and then
maybe they would also learn some other
languages like Perl Python
so what certif I do know exactly what we
can do to get people
into contributing more but I agree there
is
dairies a difficulty in getting started
and
and here I'm just talking about the
technical difficulty understanding the
code in finding out how it's organized
and
finding where did being that
jury view you see something wrong
happening
figuring out where in the C code that
that wrong decision is being made is far
from from simple
you may have to run a debugger you may
have to
grab all the source for magic strings on
if often certif in
indirect phenomena Rotterdam there's
just the line of code it does the wrong
thing
so unfortunately that puts the bar for
successful contributions very high and
this is even before we get to the point
of well
if you have fixed something can
successfully
now you have to come convince accord
report developer
to give your patch the light of day
look at your bug report looked at your
patch
give you feedback help you sort of make
it also work on all the other platforms
we care about
so I would I would love if we could
certain if this move now that process
and
it used to be that I was the one who did
all that and intuitive I would sometimes
take shortcuts now they're
there are too many contributions and too
many open bugs and too many
lingering patches for me to be very
successful in
taken care of all that even though I I
want to
bud everyone else who is assertive
really knowledgeable and I'll
basically all the people who can review
your patch
are already very busy and so the
question is how do we can grow
that several people how do we get more
people
into the core certif and it's a high bar
to pass you have to
sorta first win the trust of the
existing core developers because
week we also don't want a bunch of
newbies
certified changing pipe bomb and add new
features that
don't actually work or will will
distract
a other users more break on certain
platform so there is
there is a real certify reason for for
having
thorough technical review for all
contributions but at the same time
duck that review process and the process
of getting new people involved has
become very
heavyweight and cumbersome to that that
is
as is something done does worry me and
thanks for for asking
thank you
so discussions about up high country for
when I had teach a class arm we often
have this conversation and what version
up I found two years
and we often a
do not use and 34 without 27
re I go through the process of
explaining at the hard thing for new
people to understand why we would be
using
why you would want to use 27 over 34
when in every other aspect of our lives
are always wanna be on the newest and
greatest and best
so my question for you is am
with small incremental changes that are
happening in the community as people
upgrade libraries
arm when you see the tipping point
happening
where there's a large majority side have
Mitt taking a lot of action to move over
234 cuz I i mean
maybe I'm wrong but I personally feel
like it hasn't gained as much momentum
as as I would help
that's a very valid concern
a I am personally
very optimistic that this will sort
itself
out now how exactly will it will it sort
itself out
my mice are def what
what I see I talk to people in different
sup communities
I talk to educators I talk to scientists
I talked to web developers I talk to
says Matt administrators
and everybody
actually assertive has a different view
there are people who say well when I
teach a class
I don't use any third party libraries
and I just use the turtle module that in
the standard library
and I'm so happy with Python 3 because
like
these can things that used to always
dread my students over in class when I
was using buy from two to teach have
all gone away you can thank you for
listening to our complains about cloud
bite into
and changing the input function and this
and that
and so Darius a group of people who are
really have the game there other people
who
right large certif new code
and dayy d like to do everything
themselves
and they also say oh wow let I can use
the a sync i/o library in Python 3.3 or
3.4
I'm so excited I'm going to write my
whole new framework based on Python 3
using a single i/o I'm super excited
about this
then there are two people who have
sixteen million lines of code
written by 3,000 certif mediocre skilled
programmers
and ended its all Python 2.7 button
have a bit is probably actually was
written in the days of item 2.3
only just by the grace of God skill is
compatible with 2.7
or every once in a while there the
someone fixes it when it
when it breaks but not before the break
and those people have no
did Eric they're just completely
overwhelmed by how
on earth are we going to get this much
code in
it written in a dynamic language where
there are no type declarations the
compiler is
okay with almost anything you type how
are we going to get this code ported
over to pipe from
3 and and certif still be assured that
the output
is correct because thats really what we
care about
and and so I think they're there is
any credible spectrum
it turns out from talking to various
people in the numerical or scientific by
from world
but does guys are actually had over the
web developers
the number by a world has more
successfully not only ported
the software but is in the process of
porting the community to Python 3
they asked for a matrix multiply
operator in Python 3
they're getting it in 3.5 which is still
a year and a half down the road
but they're already excited about it and
and that by itself is giving them a lot
of motivation to serve be ready when
that matrix multiply operator
arrives in the language at
my colleagues at Dropbox are not so
excited about porting to buy for free
because they've got
a huge live code base and and there are
like
dozens of developers who add more to it
every day
many of those developers have sort of
tunnel vision their focus on one
particular feature
or one particular abstraction and
there's no one who has a good overview
over serb what what would happen if we
try to run this
in the pipe roughly and even with
smaller code base is that we have a drop
box that are somewhat separate from that
a we've we found out
if you if you certify use every hack in
the book
dead and then many of those hacks are
going to do not work
with the next version of pipe Anna
what are we going to do about it
patience
let certif don't
don't worry you don't bang your head
against the wall because you're behind
curve
there are plenty of people who are
skilled happily running Windows XP on
their computers to
maybe mate maybe not so happily after
Microsoft the
stop the support but never lasts
lead they're still running XP
but it will be many many years before
buy from 27 is sort of
abandoned by the pie from poor
developers
I admit that when we first planned title
and the transition we thought that five
years was a really long time because for
me personally i
I'm bad at predicting in the future and
I'm really bad at looking
say five years or more when people ask
me what
gonna happen in 10 years I just throw my
hands up in the air
so we lead Sep what we thought was a
conservative
trajectory for how long we would support
by from 27
there is a PAP that declares the end of
life or buy from 27 something like May
2015 which is actually
in a little over a year we just had a
long discussion about that topic
at the language said summit earlier this
week
and we're going to update that perhaps
and we're going to make it clear that
well was still want everyone to think
about moving and we're going to
certif helped people port and I hope
many of you
went to for example Tracy vers talk
about porting to buy perfectly and a
specific strategy of
writing single source code that can
execute correctly both on the vital to
and buy from 384 for high enough
versions of iPhone to
the and we're going to pour more
resources
in helping people make certain if that
porting process successful
but the help is not going to come in the
form of compromise versions of Python
to help is going to come in the form of
tools
less specific port help importing
stragglers in the that certain if the
dependency ecosystem like if there's a
particular module it still hasn't been
4 to Dubai from three and it is holding
people back
and the PSF or other organizations that
have have some
interested in this will be able to help
and so what
what you can do yourself is a don't
panic
Bebo opportunistic certif
you probably have a whole bunch of
different pipe from projects
see if there's one review projects where
you can use by completely answered have
become comfortable with print as a
function and learn to use all the cool
new
as a unico support and that bites for
his is taxed
and so five years from now I'll be
standing here again and I'll I'll be
looking back and I think we'll be in a
much
much better situation and fifteen years
from now we'll all
sort of look back and laugh about when
we were also worried about
the by from two to three transition and
I never wanna do another transition
in the same way fortunately software
changes so fast and
need to have better tools become
available that what Everton next
step is that we're going to have to take
beyond 3
and will be able to plan taking that
step in a very different way and we
won't
have have to have discussions like that
biz you
paid what's up we don't I am a byproduct
graduate student and I love iPhone
especially a scientific Python stack
however I do not love installing it and
I was wondering and it kinda makes it
very easy UN actually meant just
mentioned that there's plans to
introduce meters implication
in the future are there any other plans
to integrate I done with other blaster
and kill libraries in the future to make
to integrate the scientific libraries
with arm for Python I'm not really the
right person to
to answered after and
my understanding is that there are
several companies
in the scientific numeric by from the
world who are competing in the
tournament
building the best magar superjumbo
sumo installers the include as much
third-party numerical software
as as they can manage their are
installers both from and fart and from
Anna continuum
that that claim to solve your problem I
don't and and I'm not and scientist in
that sense myself
I have never had the opportunity to try
it but I hear from a lot of other people
dad their actually doing very well
with nose installers and maybe some of
it
is well at the latest version of the
installer will be even better
but I think you have great
deal of reason for optimism there thank
you
you're welcome on
I went to Julie pagano's excellent talk
yesterday on imposter syndrome and one
of the things she spoke about was taking
your heroes
ahh pedestals and making them seem like
a
regular human beings again so the
question that I wanted to ask you
is are there times in either Python or
other software projects are other things
you work on that you feel intimidated or
like you don't have the skills that you
need or any of the other things that
especially people just getting started
feel when they try to contribute back to
the community
I have a lot of that
all the time I can be incredibly
insecure
one news item that that Sir def
touts the virtues of Perl 6 can
can game make me sleep mad
someone asked me this morning while I
was walking to the hotel
about they have like Edward
they have one obnoxious Java programmer
and the Java programmers always showing
of the superior tools in the Java world
like he can attach
a debugger to a running process and
extracted stack traces in n/a me gently
start
certif hyperventilating and thinking oh
my gosh
why don't we have that and then I
realized old well yeah
lived wing where and pie chart room and
then
komodo probably all do that too because
is just a matter of a little bit of
technology we don't have an interest in
our library but really
we hardly have a debugger in the
standard library I'm probably the only
person
who who is still the bugs using just BB
as it is in the standard library so
if you want me off up my panda style
I'll happily come off
thank you you outcome
and that's all the time we have thank
you so much
you're welcome