I can key on a morning fernando's the
creator and currently developer by
Python
a founding member numb focus and
professor UC berkeley wrong way on
on hot good morning everyone thanks for
stall to the
the organizing committee this is only my
second time in Canada my previous one
was further 2012 Pike on Canada
which was a great event and today I want
to talk about something that served 0
tells into a Jessica was saying she was
fine mod reaching
to the next generation are of of
programmers and members of society were
kids and i'm talking about.
the reaching to the scientific community
which is a community that I
but I belong to and how the the Python
world has actually and that the open
source community had actually had a huge
impact
in what science are is and what signs
does
arm the ideal have signs that aren't
many have you made
sort of have a a rough sketch what
science is in your head is that we r
searching for truths about the world
that are verifiable better
on objective that we validate by
reproducing
on by building upon the work of others
and which is a collective enterprise of
humanity about understanding nature
are and I and improving the world and
%uh the reality of Sciences is actually
unfortunately a little bit different
it's really the the pursued a very
highly cited papers and procedures
journals to pad your CV
arm validation is basically kind the
referees actually
get my paper through into the Journal
and that they did not receive my coder
my day and they didn't really do
anything
with her with for replicate in my work
arm and it's basically you don't really
have to
don't have to outrun the bear remember
so as long as you get funded
on it doesn't matter what your
colleagues didn't arm
an open source software is actually a
different community and we've
I sorta lead a double life from an
academic scientists in a research
scientist at UC berkeley
arm and %uh but I also sort of softer
suffer developer by night unfortunately
these days by date to
but Tom but I've learned a lot from this
Community from all the view
on and I think all other I know there's
many I saw remembers from our scientific
by the committee in the room and
however I think we've all learned a lot
from you guys arm the
this is a a world that is or open
clobbered by definition you
with this community builds its software
out in the open arm
on the Internet its continuous in public
process there is no big
hold everything in secret until you get
the big splash press release
and the big paper published arm the
credit
is naturally distributed its and commit
logs it in the mailing lists and
activities
but happen in public are your ideas get
reviewed in public whether it's a PAP
are whether it's a purple request on get
hard arm
it's a process which is reproducible by
necessity
you cannot really software and hope to
debug what up what a problem that
someone is having halfway around the
world
unless you have some machinery in place
to make sure that when they install it
you have some understanding what's
happening to them so this is a community
has built
both technical tools and practices but
make
things reproducible by nature arm you
expose
your bugs in public that the problems
are tract publicly
and are discussed publicly arm and
testing is part of the system its
it's a mindset of saying we know we make
mistakes we know stopper has bogged
so we build testing into the process and
one of my colleagues Matthew Brett
at berkeley told me a couple days ago he
said you know what one other thing that
really
starting to work with open sores people
talking as how often
I made mistakes in my code the code I
didn't used to test before
in but I published paper was with was
pretty much always wrong
unless I tested it so now I it has
changed the way I think about my told
into buy time for us in the open source
world
have really had a huge impact both in
this broader sense of sort of changing
how
we approach the work I've signed but
also more specifically in in in a
tactical San scientific computing is it
is
is something that started in in the
world the floating-point
number crunching for 10 in the fifties
but has evolved in different directions
on the one hand
we do increasingly abstract and complex
things mathematically
arm but we also now it is the business
of scientists today
to actually talk to hardware to talk to
databases this morning was having
breakfast
with somebody who works in Hawai and
writes control soft for the telescopes
in Hawaii
arm that acquire de da in a choir
astronomical images for analysis I work
with college in astronomy
at UC berkeley arm who right exactly
recon mission re very famous astronomers
on and and Nobel laureates work right
exactly like a softer in Python has been
a fantastic tool for the scientific
community because precisely letters
bridge
this huge growth were for train isn't
enough anymore but let us Bridget
by reusing and rebuilding upon all of
that very high quality fortran CNC plus
plus code
that we still do have to use a very very
brief history the slides were given to
me
on West matter to the morning by her by
her by Travis but it's a very very quick
history of how
the numerical core on the pipe in world
came to be tracing back to june fourth
and
and im here going in the nineties who
started what became the numeric library
that live we went for round renovations
on called mama Ray
arm be a Peregrine kills leadership on
the Hubble Space Telescope team
and eventually in 2005 try to Solomon
houman many have you know
cannery marriage to an American number
ray efforts into what is today to numb
pie
library and um around 2001 trial disarm
Eric Jones was the founder and fart arm
I hope you're here
Eric I haven't had a chance to see yet
and power Peterson got together and
created
thus I pipe which is both the site by
library but also the site by conference
and community that has served as an
aggregator and fart
has played a leading role in basically
shepherding the community over the last
decade
arm and I became kinda our space I
became sort of our world
arm but i wanna bring that story back to
the last couple of months were something
exciting happen and it's proof
but we can have a very meaningful
dialogue with your community
and with the pipe on core team arm this
are in February Nathaniel Smith proposed
who's won the lead numbed by developers
proposed on a act be as a valid
operation in the Python syntax which
would mean introducing
the at character as a new binary
operator to represent matrix
multiplication
armed he wrote a very for a PAP you went
out to all over the scientific mailing
lists for many projects and gather
feedback
and on April eighth we dose and are very
short one-line email to
pipe on dad saying I'm not checking the
PAP so you guys can stop joking around
there was on a joking thread going on
I guess end and he said okay that set
with weakness is going and
and sold thank you
thank you agreed on a fan on everyone
put work into that and I am very
amazingly
for the day to readers email was April
8th by April 10
the issue on the track was closed
Benjamin Peterson in two days basically
actually implemented
that the paper which was which is
fantastic arm
soap really thank you guys
so for aus assigned to spite on gives us
a lot we get
very importantly separation of concerns
we can dump a lot of work
on pipe on dad meaning the work on the
language thinking about the compiler
thinking about
kinda that the syntax of the language we
can have a dialogue about it but that is
mostly
their responsibility in that look frees
us to do other things on
and your community to build XML libros
and web libraries in all kinds of things
that we use
arm it gives us a huge amount of
leverage with all those tools
it gives us access and a dialogue with
industry there's a lot of
partners from industry who are many of
those people in those walls
who now there's kind of a natural way
above talking to them for a for a
scientist's
and there's also in and I want to
emphasize the so called her and a
community
right the BD FL model arm the PSF the
models are these conferences a lot of
these things are in many ways different
then signs and I would say that they
actually represent those ideals of signs
that I was talking about earlier
are better represented arm by our by a
lot of the things that you guys have
done I certainly have learned a ton
from from this Community in from working
on pipe on dad from and seeing how these
communities operate
arm but I hope that I can show you that
in the other direction that it really is
a dialogue that goes two ways that
we also contribute arm we build tool
that have broad impact I did a quick
check with the Debian popcorn command
in and numbed by is reported as being
installed Rafi in fifty percent of
Debian installations
that's a lot it means that the
scientists have built a tool that
really is an important pipe onto land
and that benefits many many
packages it ships now in OS 10 out of
the box Mavericks
ships with numbed by and matplotlib onto
can plot
de da are the box in in a in or stand
and it's not just numbed by we have a
big ecosystem these are sort of the poor
packages have the scientific ecosystem
numbed by side by Matt bartlett's Empire
kinda the base layer
arm other scientific ecosystem but we
also have to likes I could learn
and pandas that there have been
tutorials about here for machine
learning in statistics network axe
for graph theory analysis that Matthew
Russell uses in his in his beautiful
book
psych its image for image processing
sites on which also the
the core language team is now I know
they've had discussions about
so we have a rich ecosystem a federated
ecosystem of tools
but I think our our valuable as well we
bring a different community
which means we bring different usage
patterns have had really great
conversations with Nik Cochran about
how the usage patterns and the kinds in
ways that we use the language is
different and that actually is
valuable because it brings a diverse in
your ideas to that to the community
and going back to what Jessica was
saying well many other scientists
are in academia we teach work
universities which means that
we can expand pipelines reach arm maybe
not exactly in the direction that she
was talking about but there is
overlapping but between those
communities
are for example UC Berkeley and MIT have
recently in the last couple years
changed
our core CS courses from arm
from from scheme to aren't too tight on
and Brooklyn after this we did a really
quick rewrite of the SACP book
that is about as pie pan oriented and
obviously that bad has drawn that has
Paul
arm we we have efforts to reach out to
into the scientific community to suffer
carpentry project
that is hosting a greg is speaking later
today Titus brown is here in the room
was one another one another
our town of dark and leaders in that
effort arm that sets up a carpenter
reaches
out to practicing scientists and teaches
them how to do be better computational
our people arm in in as part of their
day-to-day scientific work
I really encourage you guys to engage
that
and there's also something that I think
should be discounted which is that in
the last couple years something is
happening there was this big data signs
buzzword
and yes it is a terrible buzzword but
it's there arm
in what's interesting about this is a
plot that I didn't make this is copied
from
from a blog post that came out looking
and unfortunately the funds are too
small for project for projecting but I'm
I was just too damn just using the image
the lines the lines that go but the red
line that is kinda
trending down is are the blue line
that's going
up is I pipe on the Green Line is pipe
on
these are abstracts at the Strada Riley
conference which is the big business big
industry
data science and big data conference and
it means python is really playing a role
there and this is because
the school that many of us build for
scientific research all asunder
exploding in industry
and people in cutting companies in an
industry are realizing that the pipe on
stack
for science is actually a great stack
for building those kinds
for working on those kinds of problems
arm and so I think it gives pipe and
reach
and exposure into our own aside industry
that have added that is potentially
going to be a very important problem
business-wise
arm there is also interesting changes in
science itself in the funding so last
year
UC-berkeley together with you duh but
NYU we won a competition as a
collaboration
arm for a roughly $38 million dollar
grant from the more foundation and a
strong foundation to build
data science environments whatever that
means over the next five years and
interestingly
in our proposal in the Berkeley proposal
Python an open-source were
add the heart of the proposal and in the
emo use
between the three institutions there's
explicit language about open source
software
Connie out of this initiative this was
announced at the white house last
november
arm and at berkeley what we did is we
actually got the university to fund
to create a new institute is called
abruptly sacked Institute for data signs
bids
right now we're remodeling the main
campus library at berkeley to house at
on Tim O'Reilly in pure nordicware our
keynote speakers when we
when we launched the announcement their
arm this is the on the lower left you
had a picture of Katie Hoff
was one of the women who lead the
scientific Python communities wanna
chairs on the organizing
committee for a conference arm with Tim
O'Reilly during our little poster
session
and in the upper right the person on the
lower at the bottom it's all pro martyr
whose
the noble laureate in physics from two
years ago home
miss cover the acceleration and
expansion of the universe and he's our
lead PI
arm and I've been helping him I have
somebody so my tweet about how to teach
a girl a young girl arm pipe on a up to
a few months ago that's because Hall
was asking me how to get his hair his
kid into pipe on and soap eitan really
is basically playing a role at the heart
are one of the most ambitious
initiatives that we have right now in
transforming
arm science arm in education we're
seeing
this is harvard's CS 109 course in data
science
all over its all it's all pipe on all of
the
homework sets are these absolutely
gorgeous I don't have time to show them
to you in detail
but there it is absolutely gorgeous
extraordinarily elaborate
arm data science problems with fury with
references with de da
are if you want to learn are sort of
really hands-on
arm data science goal go through those
lectures and do those problem sets are
absolutely wonderful
arm we've also learned from the PSF and
dog
several of us if you're if you're in the
room arm hat what book got together a
couple years ago in created a foundation
with the help in conversation from folks
at the BSF
called them focus which in many ways
plays a role similar to that of the PSF
but in the scientific world
arm I encourage you guys to go see Lee s
Highland was one of our
off of that %uh the key people in them
focus and she's here at the continued
if you want to talk about what we're
doing in in problems akin to those at
the PSF has been reaching out
to the scientific and academic
communities with open source code and
bridging between academic research and
industry
arm
so this is I I wanna switch gears a
little bit now from from the big picture
open source in science into the one
specific project that I've been involved
with
that Alex mentioned which was our I pipe
on on it began
as me trying to procrastinate a little
bit on on on finishing my dissertation
and wanting a but many by the way most
of the project when I showed him that
slide
but had I can where somebody's the says
postdoc
or 10 your procrastination project are
in the scientific community
so a scientist we have a long and proud
tradition of doing that
and i buy them is no exception and began
at me trying to get a better shall
for pipe in part by then had an
attractive shell but it's for limited
on and I wanted something a little
better at the beginning it was a a .259
line scrapped
but basically just hacked into changing
the input and output prompts
and added output caching to the prompt
unloaded numerical imparting libraries
et cetera
arm thirteen years later I thought it
was going to be just after noon happy
that's what I call my advisor
arm been 13 years and now we have about
a hundred fifty thousand lines of code
of 15 power 15,000 commits three hundred
over 30 contributors
arm six languages now there's a la jolla
script and their
arm and its obviously not my work I
really wanna stop for a second
and emphasize that everything that I'm
going to show is really the the print
the output
are very talented team our brand Rangers
Mike OPI his ethics professor at Cal
Poly in San Luis Obispo
mean um is our lead engineer arm at a
time he got his PhD in plasma physics at
UC Berkeley and he now works there
full-time
the people who are both faced in that
slider simply boldface because they are
full-time developers we now have enough
funding
to have six of us working full time and
Mattias be sunny and was at the top
right is actually here in the room who
the only core developer
who is on was here arm but it bare all
really the ones we do all the hard work
I i don't i'm taking credit for someone
else's work at this point
we have funding that we are very
grateful for on the upper P sloan
Foundation
arm funds to the bulk of the salaries
but Microsoft Research has made
important donations the project and
we're grateful for
on and Rackspace I know you guys are
here thanks a lot because you you got
support
both in services and Kyle Kelly who are
who has become a core developer
are supported by Rackspace arm and so
how did we go from 250 lines of code
250,000 all we do is basically
exact exec your source in use are decked
arm
what we do his basically which create a
lot of staff
around language independent tools for
what happens at the shell but an
abstracted fashion I'm gonna show you
examples about
the simplest way that I can describe it
quickly is that we have basically
created a protocol
for interactive systems to talk to
programming languages
so you can think I'm it's sort of like
an HTTP style protocol
but for interactive computing not have a
format for storing
those interactions sort of like HTML but
it's how it's exactly a Jason data
structure
arm at the protocol level we provide
when you install a pipe and we provide
one kernel one of these interactive
colonels it's the I pipe and colonel
what what used to happen just that the
shower now happens over the network
we provide three clients the same
terminal client if you've ever used by
Python
but also a graphical cutie console
client and a web known book
this is being presented in the web
notebook army
there's a format a format there's an API
for converting
those notebooks into other other forms
about what and that's going to be
important as we'll see in a minute
on we have a notebook sharing service
call NB viewer
are which is hosted by Rackspace is a
mentioned on and we also have a library
for high-level parallel computing
but takes a lot of the ideas from
multiprocessing and concurrent futures
but
on but presents them in a way that is a
little bit more amicable for the kind of
thing that we want to do in science
arm so it does execute code and what
does it do well if you
if you simply import some and and you
load a dataset
and you hit enter you can get plots on
this is actual code
where we're planning with matplotlib
and awe and this is you it's plotting
with matplotlib but it's actually using
the 32 to the rendering so two lines of
code will let you load a data file
and Dom and and visualize it quickly
we don't have to arm NV and we always
are for being able to do that
but in addition to executing Python code
we can mix and match with other
languages
arm so this is and I apologize if it's a
little small for you guys to see the
code on the back cover and the very back
of the room
but suffice it to say that what we're
doing here is executing inside the pipe
and process
loading a Julia interpret julie is in a
language other than 90 for numerical
computing
and the end the next block is now Julia
code which is making call backs the
Python code in producing
a plot by mixing and matching Julius in
touch with Python syntax to
generate a figure using matplotlib from
an internal reloaded
Julie interpreter and job but the the
integration between the languages goes
pretty deep and Julia we created this
figure
and we pull it out and display it as a
pipe on variable and we can keep
modifying it afterwards
as a bite on data structure arm you can
even mix and match at the level
of having thus the call stack be
completely intermingled so this is an
example a writing the classic fibonacci
are little example from the python
tutorial but as a two-step recurrence
that a one-step recursion
where now one version a few notches
written julia and the other one is
written in Python and when you call
the outer entry point that switching
back and forth between the two
and you can see how the two step records
in stock unfolds
arm in there so this did these are the
kinds of things that we can sort of do
cleanly
without with the iPad from colonel
we can arm as I said we can load data
and look at it let's imagine that I have
an image
with in this case some random values in
imparting and I'd like to know
well where r Wareham what where are the
higher values economically start
start thresholding this image and Dom
and looking out and playing playing with
a threshold to see were
were important values in this case said
it's random noise but normally do these
kinds of things with real data
arm but this is the kind of thing where
it's very useful to be able to have
interactive controls and so we've added
we've added the ability to simply grab
save applying showed applauding call but
chose the image
threshold how to value and simply say I
want that but I wanted interactively
with a slider that goes between 2n 2n by
simply writing that by simply saying I
want to interact with that
I automatically get a slider which
allows me to change the image threshold
and whenever a move
that slider its it simply calling back
into the kernel from the JavaScript side
calling back into the kernel we
executing the code and letting me so I
don't know how to write Grieco denied
open already old enough and I without
reading the Evergreen code
but I but it is useful to have
interactive controls for primary
exploration of 10
and being able to write just one line of
code and saying I want iraq with a fresh
whole argument
is extremely extremely useful and
certainly for us in scientific work
where we often have to play with
parameters
be able to bid do this kind of thing
easily is very nice
arm and now that we have this connection
between what happens in the web browsing
what happens in the back and
we can build things like spreadsheets
but where r than a nice aspect but I
like about spreadsheets
is being able to many people ate the
data entry aspect I don't like the fact
that the blend in
data input and output arm so this is an
interview with a toy example again but
to show the kinds of things that become
possible
cue and and loading a data frame are
planned as a defendant in this case has
random numbers and if that's what it
looks like when I printed
and if I simply Colleen arm
the added function this is a little
JavaScript table where I can now go in
and at
when I look at it again be edited values
have changed so basically
I can have an added double data
structure right in right in my notebook
right can make the data transformation
but I'm still doing
the visualization with normal code so I
can mix and match the things that a
better natural to do
with with hand in activity such as in in
a spreadsheet data manipulations but
leaving
the computational part 2 explicit code
which means I can unit test
that I can run against a validation
sweet I can we use it with other forms
of input if I if I want to
me we've actually gone
the this interaction between this
ability to to Iraq between between the
web browsing Dallas script and the back
and
is Argos fairly deep arm so this is
this is an example love riding a little
bit of code that uses the three
to simply fact arise a number and as its
factoring the number it sending data to
the d3
23 draft directive layout are and I can
I can say well if I want to spread
illustrated
I know 72 has a lot of factors so if I
want to illustrate how do
how to factors Asian work I can I can II
can run this it's sending data to the 2d
three ND 3z event handlers
are responding in real time to the
number to the pipe and colonel which is
sending a day da
are ended their updating we I don't have
call back in ten hammers wired in here
but the three could also send call backs
back and and made may be based on the
node you click
Omniture job done stop fact rise in that
particular branch or something
aren't so these are obviously toy
example but there there there there to
illustrate
that would really built an
infrastructure that lets us get
arm really why your back potentially
very sophisticated computational
services into into the
that the environment on the web browser
this happens to be running locally in my
laptop
but that code could be running on an
arbitrarily large are back and
that is attached to a huge data center
to a supercomputer and we've done that
on but that is still rendering in your
arm in your notebook
although this is based on a fairly
simple architecture the kernel
executes codes sends messages over 0 MQ
and clients listen to those messages
and as I said we ship a terminal a cutie
and a web console but people can write
other clients
and as we'll see a minute to they have
on but people have also written other
kernels
arm they've written kernels in many
languages now
arm in particular were excited about the
fact that we now have a colonel
in our arm and it's really great because
the Arcana lets you do things like this
so when we have in our kernel
this is now using pure are syntax this
is our sin taxes is not bite on cent tax
and its loading some let slowing the
library for mapping that is apparently
very popular in the art world
arm and so if you want to if you happen
to need to use pure are we have in our
kernel we have a pure Julia colonel
as a short in a previous life we aren't
we're now up to something like
up to something like eleven are well ten
functional ones
and yesterday somebody tweeted that arm
that they were working on an Erlang 1
arm this architecture this architecture
is based
arm candy expose not only not only as a
notebook
I'm you can create your own web services
so this is an example
on this is an example of a non notebook
looking in for in interface where I
although I still have a van handlers
but there's no ko to type all I have is
my own web service
that called back to a pipe and colonel
and reuse is 100 percent or code
bought presents a different web
interface so if you don't need a
notebook document style thing
but what you want is a web service that
attached to the back
you can just reuse the Dallas reply
reason you can reuse all the
communication protocol
machinery but you don't have to expose
it in our
in necessarily the same way if that
doesn't make sense in your application
and so around this arm with with this
infrastructure what we're seeing is an
ecosystem of tool growing
for us as I said obviously we are
scientists that's what pays the bills
so we're trying to use this to do better
research and to do research that is
reproducible this is an example of a
paper
we published last year this is one other
nature journals in in this case in
microbial ecology
and this was a collaboration with
biologists I'm not a biologist where we
did
some and we ran some code on Amazon
cluster arm paralyzing using iPad and
perilous economic analysis and in the
end one in one day
we were able to go from a serial script
that would've taken about a month to run
to our result that that's an afternoon
we called it the editor
other Center journal and asked if we
could submit a rapid communication paper
for for that because we had a we had a
publishable result by
by the end of the afternoon arm but what
we did was in addition to publishing a
paper which is as i said what pads
what pat's the CV's arm we actually try
to do something a little better which
was
to publish the virtual machine images
that we used
to do this work in this was following on
the on the steps of Titus brown I
notices in the room
who had already done this with one of
his papers which is due make available
the entirety of our computation
in the form on Amazon machine image so
all you have to do if you want to
replicate
our our work is to cart to copy that
config file that dictate that tells you
which Amazon machine image to
instantiate and then you can effectively
replicate exactly our competition and
then begin
exploring maybe the Bronner space ask if
we made an incorrect statistical
assumption at Satara
obviously you have to be your Amazon
bill but the machine images there with
all the code
are with all the current data to do it
and so we're trying to show that it
really is possible to do
to do computation that is battering and
communication about computing
that is more reproducible people are
using this for technical blogging
so this is an example J rendre plus War
II is also here he was teaching
yesterday
whose blog wow this is his blog
but his block which is a beautiful
Python blog every blog post he makes is
a pipe and notebook so if you want to
have a conversation
about something he's saying you don't
have to argue in a vacuum whether he did
something right or not even as good
basically download the blog post and run
it yourself and
having go down to the commenting section
and have a more have a more informed
discussion
arm and he's written a pelican plugin
make it very easy
on on my blog is also the same way we're
also seeing paper books not just papers
but entire books being published in this
way
so a colleague of ours was I don't think
a wrote a book on piping for signal
processing where the whole book
was created as notebooks and he
publishes not only the hard cover
expensive glossy paper Springer book
but also a gift Repole on get Hobbes
where you can download and execute the
entire
the entire book arm a Riley has a book
called mining the social web and I know
the author Matthew Russell was teaching
workshop here
the book was in written as notebooks but
it has a collection of notebooks for all
the examples in the book
so again you don't have to wonder
whether the other copy paste that the
right thing or whether they
change the script at the last minute and
that they did not think the book because
although the results are actually
execute a ble
arm in a lot of this is based on
isn't it takes advantage of a tool that
my PSP sonya was here in the room
wrote in 2012 cover notebook viewer in
which allows you to paste
if you want to give a notebook to
somebody and you want them to be able to
read it without installing anything
all you have to do is paste in here the
URL or the guest idea but notebook and
we will render it for you
so this is an example of a Julia
notebook if I click on that
what you see is this this is a web page
this is just my web browser I can't
execute anything here this is not
called this is just an HTML page but I
can go ahead and download if I click on
this
I will my browser will download that
notebook so we make sharing work as easy
as
put it somewhere online and send you
call it the URL they can view it as a
web page
and I believe they can read the analysis
it later they won executed that's fine
they can do that
but at least we make it very very easy
for them to see
what you're doing and we see traffic on
Twitter constantly where people are
sharing
their work in this way and I want to
take I
a case study that we saw happen last
week arm
up precisely based on this so 530 a dot
com which is Nate Solar's
new data-driven journalism gig published
arm published an article
about analysis arm humour gender in
movies gender and funding statistical
analysis of
on gender and funding in the Hollywood
industry and I'm going to discussing the
details of the article it's a
it's a darn what I wanna show is this
was what 538 published
on a couple weeks ago on so this is
actually the web but the 538 website
in an iframe in da Brian Keegan who is a
postdoc
at arm was a postdoc at Northwestern
here social scientist who does network
analysis said
when I wonder about those conclusions so
he went ahead and said
I'm going to replicate to that but I'm
gonna do it in the open
so he wrote this
and posted on get hard and posted a link
on and leave your to end a twenty year
which is
this incredibly detailed when we close
this down here
it's this incredibly detailed notebook
analyzing in replicating in critiquing
the results do repinned loading the data
scraping web sites
Chris creeping IMDB running all the code
doing statistical analysis it goes on
and on and on and on
and then you you have plots you have all
the kinks to its this extraordinarily
in-depth and detailed critique of 5 30
eights
analysis they hadn't published a code
right so he went in posted this notebook
and to their credit two days later 538
replied and i'm only quoting a short
excerpt of their reply day said
Keegan made a point 538 and similar
sites
should make their data available we
couldn't agree more and they put up
their code and data in their case it was
in our
on a repository and get hard so we're
seeing in this case a social scientist
basically saying
we can do this battle we can take the
mentality of the open source community
and public and make this stuff up openly
available and actually changing within
two days the behavior
on a side like 538 arm others are
building
many others are building a top I pipe on
both open source and commercial projects
and thought was a sad
has been a supporter love our since the
very beginning on they were the ones who
funded the work that let Brian tonight
to be able to create all this protocol
architecture
early on for their cannot project which
embeds I pipe on
on in a console here continue analytics
I which is also also here arm are so
hosts
a version of the notebook online so that
you can are without a without installing
anything you can go and use an online
it's called walkre it's basically an
embedded notebook
microsoftr the team into the team at
pipe and tools for Visual Studio from
Microsoft
arm just put out this is a screenshot
from a blog may post the two days ago
on with they had already a version that
integrated i buy them but they continue
to improve the integration between a
pipe on
and and the pipe and tools for Visual
Studio plugin and one interesting thing
about this is that
when we first met with them we only
showed them where the Qt console called
was in our report we never actually have
seen their code
all they saw was okay this is the man
this is the page that describes the
messaging protocol
and this is where the Qt Co does it okay
will take not Andino and
you know it's rock when home and on and
R&R year later they came back in there
was a above plugin for Visual Studio not
implemented
the particle may continue working on
that on the we've also worked with them
on making it very easy to deploy
on the is our cloud service man just on
Amazon arm if you are an Amazon there's
an open source project RMIT called star
cluster this is what we use for the
biology paper
that lets you spin up in a pipe in
parallel cluster with a notebook front
and
by just copying back and one one config
file basically are for star cluster two
beautiful open source but you don't have
to put
is there an ID because obviously have to
pay for the service are we saw last year
at SI pyaar great talk from the IBM
Watson team
now the people who did the job buddy
contest but the team that acquiesced
tasked with
turning water into a product and this
scheme
are replaced an existing Hadoop Java
JavaScript d3 clunky infrastructure
that how to slow turnaround time because
it was all back she had duped and was
very complex the deploy
with an iPad and close running in
parallel and a notebook interface for
the engineers to login
and they went from about a thousand
lines a job I just emailed the three in
a complicated
deployment system to an interactive 070
deployment login
log in through the web browser right
writer code are
turnaround interactive time went from
two minutes 22 seconds because it's all
done in memory with the African pearl
stuff
and then when you're done you save and
use and you send a businessperson
just just the link to the notebook and
they can just you your report you're
done on this was again something that
the IBM Watson team did
without our involvement at all arm they
were just thought they were just
are they found they found are they found
the project in the use that arm and this
was in July a blaster and I was very
happy when I saw
in a in November that they turn it into
a that what is now like a 1.8 billion
dollar business unit
at Microsoft so it's obviously something
that has been used for
for serious products arm a start up from
the mayor of writing go from Boston
Ubuntu bus services created an
environment for
riding collaboratively academic
publications on Google Docs style
but for really for academic writing
called of the Riyadh and that you can
write using my paper notebooks right
in right in the environment so you can
collaborate on lock textile academic
writing
using I pipe on on in the cloud thanks
to
arm thanks to the machine with these
guys have built another
up scientifically are oriented start-up
also
also there now in in Boston cop lightly
that lets you load their libros and plot
but it's actually
hosting the plots on their servers are
so that the code and out our available
there and you have %uh
you have a unique URL on for their for
their plots but this is all interactive
I think they're using
arm well actually I don't I don't
remember if they're using the three or
not but
when you run that code you get a plot
embedded into your but we know that how
to start a queue ID
referring to the current data that you
can share with others but it fully
integrates with a pipe on
and I and we've been would be no working
with them on
on this we also have a project for that
came out of our
University of Toronto and our don't want
to lead on the lease on this project
this year Tara charms from called nd def
he's been given to provide but again by
some for carpentry Greg Wilson
that lets you defend marriage notebooks
it regarded
these files are Jason data structures so
they're kind of a pain in the neck if
you defend
just withdraw text if they're horrible
so these guys are building a web service
to give you
kind of civilized structured dipping
emerging
I for these documents and saw this just
told me that I'm out of time
on but that's good because I I am
wrapping up
so I E II one can have
go back to to the 32 the two kinda main
directions one is that
pythons and so is very it was
interesting to see Brett can on the
first morning said that he came for the
language but he stayed for the community
because I look back
at my last slide up icon Canada in 2012
and I had that exact same quote two
years ago because that is it that is
also true for me I
I got sucked in when I was a grad
student looking for something to
procrastinate on
because the languages was awesome I I
had written on a pro coach for managing
my data
in a when I realized that 24 hours after
having read
just the python tutorial be at the
standard official one in in the docs
I could do in Python things that I
wasn't it's not a
didn't know how to do them in Pearl I
didn't know that were possible in Pearl
and and I had written it on a pro card
so I but when I said okay
this is what I'm doing armed but it's
easy to say that when you're at in
looking for something to do other than
finishing your dissertation it's harder
to keep dot as a career and what has
kept me in is the fantastic community
boat in our
Saipa a world which is an amazing crowd
and as larger
are open source piping to me that I've
come to but I've come to meet
arm on the iPod iPhone side I hope that
that have shown you that we've built
something that by having
open protocols and open formats is a
useful tool for computing in a very
broad sense
and it's not a scientifically oriented
only tool guess we build it because we
needed
but we hope it's a tool that can be
relevant to many have you and there's a
lot to contribute tonight by then
there's
many projects have been helping
obviously you should work on what really
interests you but if you want to work on
a paper there's plenty of room arm
and finally I wanna close by thanking
first of all we know for creating this
fantastic
a tool and for being open to
conversation like for spec for 65 which
is only the last one has been other
similar ones in the past and the entire
by 10 Def team arm and also to
Diana and a baller had nine o'clock and
a baller who have done an amazing job as
well as the
the local pipe on organ pipe on
organizing team thank you very very much
and I don't know
if fibers from I think we're out of time
and habitat questions
one or two now or out in the hall I'll
Bobby here for the rest the conference