good morning everyone and to make sure
the slider
area perfect okay so this is not about
Python
the next teaching the next generation a
Python programmers and
on this to talk that uses a lot of data
from the United States because that's
where I live in where I went to school
or I have the best and personal
experience but I think a lot have are
the lessons and opportunities to
collaborate based on
I we talk about and transcend national
boundaries
I'm are you really does start I am
particular state in the United States
though
%uh this is Tennessee tennessee is
famous for a lot of things are most
notably
country music and Jack Daniels I
but it is also the place where I went to
high school and where my family now
lives
their 285,000 high school students in
Tennessee
I and how many than you think are taking
Advanced Placement computer science
which is on the most common
our computer science class a high school
students in the US can take
I'm international law exam now to 35,000
students
how are we doing so
reaction have an exact number the number
is 251
so Western .1 percent have a high school
students are taking
the most common our computer science
exam so with that framework and my name
is Jessica I'm a director for the
Pythons after foundation
I'm I spend a lot of time I and energy
and money thinking about this problem in
particular
how the Python community can be apart
addressing this
lack of engagement so bad as well we'll
talk about
today of your statistics for you
first are in the United States there's a
lot of enthusiasm for students learning
how to code
a lot I really important and famous and
rich people
even the President of the United States
believe very strongly that I'm all
students should have
at least the opportunity to learn how to
program in school
unfortunately reality is lagging
significantly behind the enthusiasm
and so this is a graph I have and
participation in all over the Advanced
Placement
exams all these national I am exams on
friday is subject to the top we have
English Language and Composition
arm and source skimming down the west we
see that I'm narrowly beating out
2d studio art is computer science
I about an order of magnitude behind the
most popular classes
and this black and Asian actually hit
home for me very person likes I actually
have a sister
in bolivia who is in high school right
now and she is a perfect candidate for
this type of Clash she loves electronics
this is a picture her soldering
a radio kit I she loves math but in her
high school she goes to a public high
school in Nashville Tennessee
on the closest class that she can take
to a computer in class
I is a casa teachers how to use
Microsoft Word I'm
and her experience is actually the
typical one now because of the way that
education works in the US
its decentralized throughout the state
we don't actually have good data
on engagement in non AP Computer Science
classes were using AP as the benchmark
in there is one that is most common
I we know many schools teach apcs and we
know how many public high schools there
are
so we can %ah per pound you know how
likely you are to be able to take a
computer science class in school
the answer is that most students simply
don't have any opportunity
so this is a
are kinda bomber are but actually gets a
lot more troubling than that
okay sir in Tennessee last year
251 students took the exam the CS exam
and 165 past offer pass rate of
sixty-six percent which is actually
at pretty normal for TP exam at the pass
rate for african-american students was
less than half
that and actually their entire states
in the United States were no
african-american students take the exam
at all
their state's 10 Hispanic students have
taken the exam
and despite being fifty percent of the
population there
even states were no girls took the exam
and you ever gonna look at these matters
should be honest about the statistics
I'm it may or may not be statistically
significant in so many states
on you're out there may just not be that
many african-american high school
students in montana
you know that that may be true but I
think this is no
real comfort to the students who
represent these demographics
if I were a girl in mississippi and I
were thinking about taking a computing
class
are and I knew that if I took apcs
I might be the only girl in the state to
do it
that does not make me feel like this is
something that people like me deal
but they were supposed to do. and I damn
well better pass the exam otherwise I'm
gonna be a statistic that people talk
about
I we have gender data for all %uh VP
classes I
and a really interesting way I'm looking
at this data is to plot a log
the ratio I'm so here is that plot I'm
so
I for for all the classes and issues
right that means there are more girls
and boys taking the exam
its use laughing these are more boys
than girls
and this crap is is really interesting
for for a lot of reasons I mean actually
if you look at this and there are more
AP classes in which girls outnumber boys
right we see at the top
but as soon as we start looking at math
and science classes it starts going the
other way
and in fact computer science is the most
gender skewed
class
and this matters to us this matters to
us because we spend an inordinate amount
of time
and energy and money and blood and sweat
and actual tears I'm doing some modus
any quality representation that starts
in high school
and an earlier so this absolutely
matters to us
does blow leaky pipeline matters to us
but it actually matters to me for a lot
more reasons I suspect it matters to you
from a reasons as well
no one reason I want students to at
least have the opportunity to learn how
to program to engage in computational
thinking skills
is because I understand how impact our
ring programming is
like learning how to program changes the
way that you think about and interact
with the world
I want more people have that experience
I want our politicians worm
making decisions about the way that my
country is run
actor to have that experience
and also as Python he says %uh this is
important to us for the long term
success the language
it's important to us that people are
learning how to program preferably in
paper I'm
okay well this has been sort of a
depressing in traction and it seems like
it
impossibly huge intractable problem
so what can you and I am actually doing
a space
well we can actually take art in so many
statistics okay so
AP Computer Science Camino state is the
most gender skewed
Advanced Placement exam by its
in Tennessee my home state
almost a third of the test takers are
actually girls
I and this is the highest percentage of
any state United States last year
can guess why this is the guest
it
the reason is one person as one teacher
her name is Joe
and she teaches computer science an all
girls Preparatory School
school in chattanooga tennessee sheet
almost half
RB apcs test takers who are girls last
year
and what this really means is that one
motivated teacher can set a national
record
and this is one person and i'm looking
out across the room and thinking about
the people who watch this video
and I ask an honest an earnest question
which is what
what can a 200,000 per cent community
like ours that spans the globe do if
we're serious about this
we want to do something about this well
I asked I'm about you people I I asked
my job
CS education researchers I how to answer
this question I
arms with a giant pile on community out
what are some things that we can do to
make a difference
I was going to be the fire hose
responses
I'm I'm gonna give you everything and
not all these ideas have to resonate
with you but I hope that at least one
guy's
let you leave here with something that
you believe that you could be a
are going to talk in for a big area some
policy
student engagement supporting teachers
and curriculum
developments and for such as policy
gears map in the states that counts a
computer science for something
to graduate high school and even if you
don't live in the US
I if you're probably in in a similar
situation
on there is a problem that computer
scientist typically only an elective
and this is a problem because it does
not
align incentives for the people involved
if you're an enterprise a high school
student you are already way too busy
trying to graduate and can I resume
you can hopefully get a scholarship to
afford college
I'm and you're not gonna waste time on
some elective on some topic that you
don't know anything about
and assume so I take it schools don't
offer and teachers definitely don't want
it
invest their career and training in some
class that will have dubious
attendance so here's a very concrete
thing that each of us in this room could
do
begun a fun call our local legislatures
we call our school board's and ask for
computer science to count as a math or
science credit
in our state said your stay is not green
where you live outside the US and this
fact is true for you too
pick up the phone on Monday and helped
change the sadistic
here's another problem
on there's actually not a way for people
to consist to
are you nationally find data on what the
graduation requirements are
or how teachers get credential to teach
computer science
so if I'm a policymaker I'm a school
board member I actually don't have a way
to know
and I am way behind my neighbors and I
should be embarrassed
and this is a problem for the
policymakers because they don't know how
to fix this problem
like they don't know how to get the
state an aggregate it put it somewhere
that would be useful
but this is for sure something that you
and i could honestly probably fix in a
weekend
like at this friends on Monday we could
rights in Python that automates the
process and I getting this data from the
various
state and local science on and produce
I'm
away for policy makers to actually make
good choices
around his head X so this is something
that we can actually do
tomorrow Chur
should I take of no aka
is this
is this podium enough is a good kick it
here's the problem
a computer scientist of hot in Java
and I'm not hitting on Jonah like not
because it's cool
john is a great language in a lot of
contacts the job is a problem for CS
education because it is a bad language
to teach in
and I'm not saying this teachers say
this me think about it here in a Java
program think about which goes into
hello world in Java
is very hard to differ talking about
classes headed to differ talking I did
oriented programming it's a total
nightmare
if you've never written a for loop
before and actually just be a quick
picture hands here taking out a walk
down memory lane
arm to who didn't UTPA BCS exam
in Pascal after yeah now
yeah feedback on steep of class so it's
impossible to class
k Java goal okay so so job
is have actually been around for a long
time and is getting pretty long in the
tooth
and rubs a problem because it's not a
great way and exciting scenes about
programming
I we have data on this because ends on
people have been gathering data on what
languages
colleges use and also what languages
teachers wish they were you saying and
what languages teachers
think they will be using ten years from
now in a compendium called Brians list
which has been going on for for decades
and replaced is really interesting to us
says Python
users here we see that every summer 2012
reads list
pied you're still in third place Java is
has a lock on first still
but if you ask teachers what they wish
they were using
they all say Python
here's another fact about Reid's list it
was actually last updated in 2012
and the reason is because the way to
read list is gathered
is that a human being calls up a bunch
of other human beings and ask them about
this information
and this sucks for us because if we had
the data for 2012 for 2013 and 2014
we would see Python skyrocketing of that
list
and this matters to us because the way
you back College Board be announced
during organization behind AP the way to
decide what language you use
is based on were industry is trending
towards and what teachers once
cell imagine a world in which
AP Computer Science for tot in Python
imagine a world in which
high school students in their learning
how to program a lot how to program a
python
like that would be an amazing world for
us for a long-term
you for the longevity of the language
will also be a more fine computing
experience and high school
and this is not a pipe dream if we got
the data to college word
this change I think would happen in four
to six years
so you're excited about that possibility
let's get them the date is Vic can make
good choices
good to hear a couple of our policy
opportunities
next up
student engagement there's a really
basic problem here which is
students don't know what computer
sciences so that i won a ticket
high schools almost too late for the
reason we talked about earlier you are
busy training graduate and get the hell
outta there
so we need to engage people before that
we need to provide a earlier
opportunities for exposure
and you what I can do this we do not
have term we do not have to invent
how to do this we can hook into a lot of
existing infrastructure
4 engaging students about computing
here's one great example
are the pilots are foundation sponsored
18 tech camp in raleigh-durham
was run by people in this room for
summer camp for kids learn how to
program in Python
on raspberry PIs there are groups like
The Girl Scout and Boy Scouts to
are have a ton and experience on
teaching skills to kids
right they have the kids and they have
the infrastructure
they just don't have a program that's
the only piece to the puzzle that they
need
there are times after school programs
where
were kids on especially go through
modules they're learning about
are in their learning about music and
they would love to be learning about
programming as well but they were really
don't have the teachers like the old
they have the computing labs may have
the students
and how the parents excitement but they
don't have the people who know how to
actually do this
service idea engaging students directly
is exciting to you
it's actually very tractable problem
just take advantage of existing
infrastructure
you can make a real difference in your
local community airtight have a local
opportunities here
a couple soon engagement options
number three supporting teachers
here they sad fact of life
for CS teachers if your computer science
teacher in high school
you're probably the only one your high
school to imagine if you went to work
today and you're the only person who did
what you did
and if you had a problem for you had a
terrible day at work you didn't really
have anyone to talk to you
if your stock on something if you
working on cricket Obama you don't know
what to do
you don't have anybody to talk to you
this sucks
but we have a huge community let's bring
man
into it there are a lot of really easy
ways to support teachers
once upon a service call a person an
email your a local teacher teacher at
your local high schools okay
i think is really cool you're teaching
computer science
and if you have any questions about
curriculum stuff for your sake I boger
environment so that you can buy it
I would love to help argue BT A in the
class
or offer to visit the class and and tell
the kids would really like to be
a programmer your brain to local user
could agree with a camera kirkum
problems
be on all of us at our local Python
project night sela to really easy ways
to support teachers just by bringing man
into the community
number for curriculum development this
is this is really interesting is a
really interesting time for Python
in this area so what exciting things did
you know but there's a new advanced
placement computer science
class as being piloted right now
in the United States is called CS
Principles and this is really exciting
to me
because look at what it focuses on
if some programming but also a lot of
really interesting ideas that will
appeal to a much broader range students
pairing programming with creativity and
data and the internet how to make it
impact with the skills
this seems like a really exciting way to
increasing engagement where
the apcs a hasn't
on but unfortunately there's actually no
did a CS curriculum 4
AP computing principles
in any language and I C span i guess i
say hey this is like a huge market
opportunity for Python
like money if the most awesome way to
teach kids
this AP curriculum was in Python
everyone would use it
right teachers have a limited amount of
time a Thursday bangin
I'm curriculum make use of a shelf
they're going to use it most
teachers on have the time to invent
their own curriculum on a fly
and the stuff seems so cool here's an
example the lesson plans from the
website
crypto graffiti like Alex Gaynor where
are you let's write this car parking lot
in together
data as arts inventing and sorting
algorithms this is fine mist of and we
just need
I is enhanced tackling this problem
and this is also sonya transcends your
national boundaries
on there just aren't that many curricula
that that meet their curriculum
guidelines for schools
but you can use to teach programming in
high school
get here's a good example is actually
surfing Python my favorite introductory
tax
written by alan dow name is probably in
this room on
it's great at the college level but on
there are some problems with tactically
deploying this and high schools
which is includes that you're off in a
really locked down computing environment
are not so what one person I talk to you
measuring about how
no in his computer lab and in addition
every me firewall of
on even the teachers don't have the
ability to install software on machines
Anish for good measure they would glue
gun shot
the USB ports system like a duck
as their only option in if this is your
computing environments to do stuff
in the browser right and people love
Python so much
that there is some people are have
created a project it's all open sources
online on github
that ports thing Python to an
interactive web
curriculum
and perhaps the most famous or the the
most-used example has right now is
sculpt which is a javascript and
traditional Python that is used by
course era
the teach hundreds of thousands of kids
a program but here's the thing:
this is online on get hard and there are
things that teachers what's called
to do that it can't deal there are Open
tickets on get hub
for things they wish they could do.
I'm good at fixing bugs bye week whether
we want this to be the case or not it is
possible that the future of teaching
programming in teaching Python in
schools is
in the browser so we should pay
attention to that
shouldn't be a sideline issue
so you're into n their attire really
interesting Creek you landed on
opportunity is for us specifically in
the context of teaching
programming to kids
better for big areas that is my fires
for you
and what kind of interesting about
there's a first time for such terrible
absolute numbers in such terrible
percentages but it really doesn't mean
bad
if UN I do one thing it has the
potential to make a significant
impact on these numbers to make a
significant impact on the bottom line
and also fortunately we are part of the
community has incredible network of
support to how
I S make these changes in the world we
have the Python Software Foundation
and we will give you money and we will
connect you with people and we will give
you resources
if you are willing to take that time to
reach in Turkey your community
and make one of these changes so here
are a couple ways we can help
running sprints
hey if you're excited about your sexy
nurse call to buy eggs
we will feed you pizza why you do it
enough your friendly
in that unit with your group local user
group we have in our region Education
Committee
specifically devoted to doing this kind
of outreach
on you now if you wanna run a tech camp
I'm doing is designed curriculum like
we can help find that this happening and
then we also have a general grants
program sour
now let your imagination go wild really
anything is possible and and where we
would be excited to hear from you
okay
who challenged here here gonna be back
here in this room
a year from now am I ask is do one thing
just one thing whatever resonated with
you all you have time for us to call
someone
do that if you wanna run a sprint to do
that
you wanna help it the summer camp do
that but do one thing
much report back next year and see how
those numbers see how that bottom line
has changed here a couple resources for
you some classic
tax on why things are the way they are
as well as
I'm saw all the data that i've been
reporting at all are publicly available
see you wanna check it and you're now
sees you are Apsley able to add
this is my pitch to you thank you all so
much
for listening if you want to talk more
about this
half thank you
so I would love to talk with you all at
yeah I'm headed home for the summer
basically and Leslie so I will first
I'll be at the rally with the expo hall
and directly after the the break are at
the break on and I would love to hear
the study gotta get free stuff like free
books
at at the booth I'm but I'm also you
know happy to talk for hours and hours
over dinner
so thank you so much and I look forward
to seeing what we do in the upcoming
year
the horror stories war stories
good stories I homeless addition
are as much as you can in royal
university students was a
they can help bettered each young kids
by Tim
compared to teachers may be good they
can relate to in also
force you was in her new to programming
the best way to learn is to teach and is
better side but
gets but if in both university students
I did take them to you a city or
get one appears to high school up the
kids can relate more to us
then the teachers thank you and is
teaching teachers problem in particular
is really interesting
I'm in the US but also a lot of other
places
empty going to you at the UK right now
be people are starting to realize this
is important our passing policies that
say hey we're going out is hinting at a
program
but we actually haven't figured out how
to teach teachers how to teach
programming at scale
so that's a whole interest in Canada
forums as is worth thinking about
thank you you 100 percent II a
can have had something related to the
use in this AM
as mark a question a on speaking with
the teachers especially the science
teachers because
size becoming so much more
interdisciplinary and
unit the University levy see everyone
needing programmers to do things for
biologist mathematicians do and did you
see any the teachers at the high school
level
wanting to learn how to program and what
was there feeling about that
soon hit I think that the state in power
in house was actually pretty depressing
and porcelain particularly his
schools don't have a bucket computer
science often in the business
silo and not in their science silo in it
there was music like the people
available
to teach maybe don't super match that
that the skill set that is required
on I think lots of teachers are excited
about the idea to do his program and
they're frustrated by the fact that
there's no credentialing
and aren't like clear classes are they
can take
to on to learn the skills they need to
actually do it
I'm sad I think I think excited but
they're fresher IT infrastructure
problems
make Jessica
caroling I do outreach and San Diego
and for the Fab Lab and I haven't
seventeen year old and a 19-year-old
I'm worked with teachers and wanna
the really I'm relatively new to Python
in last couple years and one other
super cool things even be on language
which i think is so fun the program in
is the breath I'll
libraries on the things you can do
in astronomy music a biology
those are things that really resonate
with kids
and kids are sort of sucking up the
Instructables and that kinda stuff from
like
late elementary school on and it seems
like we've got a great community of
people with a variety of interests
it would be really nice if like the
Python Software Foundation could somehow
even just I Python no perks on cool
subjects
and have sir the clearinghouse for them
even beyond just the formal curriculum
because I think if you touch the kid and
engage the kid
they will suck it up they're like
sponges
cell I totally agree and in particular
yeah
if a bunch of us are going go out in the
schools and we want give our best pitch
for why I programming is empowering
interesting
you're having a clearing house in and
suggestions just
pre pre-written press it would be really
useful out first just a reminder sending
what is the base of logarithm in your
ratio chart
I am at a2
now I think so and okie thank you and
the actual question is
I'm are there in you are efforts to
lets a cold sores them I curriculum
creating the effort because to me it
sounds like a problem that
technology console 50 your treasure map
crowdsourcing I mean I wouldn't call it
that is certainly there are distributed
efforts on line that are happening for
sure
Eminem I find it incredibly encouraging
that the thing that has evolved as
people
developing some unease to tools yeah in
the open
under permissive license on Getty up but
actually a a pretty good said in the
world so any get collaborating on the
staff
get a crowdsourcing a sub is absolutely
possible way to see the people
do it and people who are who are talking
to teachers while they're doing it like
doing it in a vacuum
probably wouldn't be successful but you
engage in the people who will be using
the common
I'm I I come from a country called Oman
in the Middle East
and I'm over there I'm quite privileged
in terms of economic status and so on I
live here in Montreal now
but computer science is not a respected
I'm
discipline in the middle east by the
people who are in the upper middle class
and upwards the decisionmaking
policymaking people
I was wondering if you know any groups
who
or projects at work towards raising
awareness because I'm pretty sure I can
count on one hand or two the number of
people I know
were intact for my country on
and that's a real shame and
you know there's such as an opportunity
there to get people involved but
you know everything here is about
getting it to work
in a place where it already respected
but it is not even respected how do we
go about that
yeah it's really a question on there
certainly resources that are somewhat US
Pacific that I can say like Co .org has
allotted
data and glossy material to present
in your own way to treat digestive or
the people and something that may
translate
across national boundaries then we can
talk to find out more international
efforts into space
agreement hi I have two questions
a the the first one is our what is the
role
or how do you see the role of our Khan
Academy
in or similar online
kinda like universities or schools
from and the second one is I'm
is there any the centralized 'em
curriculum or centralize project that
house definitive
time time line or people dedicated to it
because
um Brett like we the first step of
solving a problem is identifying India I
think he did a very good job
explaining what the problem is arm and
things we could do
arm but I think I getting
a rallying people is a good step but we
also need
arm a good project with
people they can raise hands and say I
can do this specific thing
and it might not be only decentralize to
this room so
what's water than your next steps on on
this rallying call:
and here those are by two questions got
I think I can ease grade and it's great
because
it is on it clearly is delivering value
to a lot of students in a lot of
teachers and because
it is and yeah it is one of many actors
in this space irv
on massive online learning and that the
more competition there is there that the
more we learn about what is a fact and
the better it will be
on don't tell you the second question
I I think that what people folks
finalists are doing this is is
that I'm a lot in these initiatives are
necessarily super local
so so how you there are mailing lists
for people interested in a7 our mailing
lists for
for teachers interested in programming
on but fundamentally it's
your every every school and every school
district is
difference and you end up on meeting
with the people locally who who
on know how to make it work in in that
particular context
so so or so while there are worse on
your mailing list in
national/international at on
ways to connect with people I think that
fundamentally these are problems are
solved
piece by piece locally are you going to
track it
I'm I i cant I die I don't have a
solution to this whole problem
appear on the stage but I'm sure that if
there's interest in that type of project
I we could think it's thanks
you mom third mentioned the the teaching
teachers problem
arm in one actions you didn't mention
was actually
programmers becoming teachers arm
is that something you you know
in US teaching certificate or as the
difficult career
challenging I'm we would do you think
about that
love a programmer's actually become
teachers yet at the really question
on so B&B teachers really hard and
teachers go through a ton of training
on to become really good at what they do
and I have a lot of experience and make
some good at what they do.
I'm and and hour if he if you
were trained as a programmer you
definitely can be a good teacher but
there's a lot of context around teaching
pedagogy that you you would have to
catch up on to be as effective as you
can be
so that's about one aspect I think TPA
teaching
add p.m. developing the infrastructure
so that people who were trained as
teachers can become computer science
teachers
on is probably a good idea even if we
can tap into some external resources to
get teachers and
your promise and there's an insider's
problem you have to really love teaching
kids
to dump your of free food and
$250k job to go make 40k
innis yet in an environment that is
really really tough
and yeah solidarity that some
I'm I'm so I met a couple teachers and
for our live by a school the other day
and on when the ladies is really gone
her she teaches web design
and she's awesome and she wants to teach
my time but it
Sun is just not encouraged so what
they're doing is on the person is
teaching programming at the high school
on is usually like one in the US
teachers on the land is lowest in a
temple
and they do not want to teach it so an
S&D has and knows nothing about that
computer science says nothing about
program and could really care less
on and so right now there's a one in
teaching and on
her comment the other day well as that
on
she really didn't care about it and that
and there were a lot of girls in the
class and she said
financially programmers anyway on so I'm
just very frustrated
you know charleston south carolina
minutes you know a little backwards
but on I I is it's very frustrating to
hear that and
on you know as there's some people
they're sending us back in its actually
some other women are anchor setting the
women that and I don't get it
I don't know what to do I don't know
what to do with that year the change is
gonna be slow if you'd be incremental
but it will definitely happen
yeah if we put our collective efforts
together %uh
will converge on a thing you wanna see
here I definitely believe that
pay I just wanted to shut out one more
organization one that I don't think I
heard you mention
black girls poet is enough you big
cities across the country
arm I volunteered with them when you
show up your
only to commit to a single day usually a
Saturday eight hours
and the experience it you have with
those middle school girls
does it all reflect within the
presentation they're excited they're
engaged they learn quickly
and it is that the wonderful thing to do
so if you've got a free Saturday
and they're in your area or you wanna
bring to your area
strongly encourage you to make it happen
Ass'n cock
a game at early engagement is is so
critical
Center really have a question I'm gonna
hijacked the might cure for minutes make
an announcement
um I had the privilege of seeing an
alpha version is talk down at Pi
Tennessee
and as a result in conversation that I
had with some people there after that
I was back down in nashville two weeks
later for workshop called click
arm the idea behind click was to put 50
working software developers
in 50 teachers in a room together let
them get lightning talks tell stories
talk about problems and solutions
and then spend the afternoon coding a
project together in scraps
just as away as sorry develop those
teachers support relationship suggests
it was talking about so um I'm actually
I want the organism cope i
and in Columbus the local paper on user
group along with a number of other
sigues
in central Ohio we are going to do click
Columbus
in first quarter of 2015 arm if anybody
is in the room from Ohio and you want to
get involved were in the very early
stages of planning this
on the guy one around the conference
wearing a pile higher t-shirt
find me thank you acid in it sound like
a model that could definitely be
replicated in other cities and at that
screen
the last question now your are several
years ago maybe five or seven I
actually contacted my old high school
program teacher
and I'll given open-ended have what can
I do to help
with the bring up how love love the game
here I'm
I'm very involved in local geek
community
and would love to help and have gave me
a
well get back to you and never did
and have
that was it so do you have any count
pointers for
alright well i really wanna help my
local community how do I
how do i crack that not how do I get in
there in and
get to the people who may be willing
to engage with the local
community are to bring in that help to
make it happen to have any thoughts on
that
yet you know it teachers are a tough
spot made they are
teaching everything her in the trenches
every day and I had a very much time
to to plan outside and when you're
actually teaching and I think that
to the senate you can give specific
actions that you can take
on that and it harder for them to
consider the options in and get back to
you if you say hey
I noticed there all over your students
are dunes I would like to help fix that
by
recruiting from these other spaces that
they may be really receptive to that
country ID our saying hey
I'm available on these days next two
weeks to come talk about programming
with your kids would that be interesting
and so I think your specific actions are
the other
are the best way to appeal to teachers
who are super hurt all the time
on and then even dirtier there's also
you know
the schools in a school boards are a lot
of pieces within the local community
that can be engaged with our answer
specific actions
any and all I got that phone call to
your local legislator your local school
board saying hey please make this
Candice matter science credit is another
example very specific
concrete action thanks begin
are yeah I read
okay thank you thank you all so much
come find me any extra