right well let's go ahead in
get started so I name is Cedric is
has been awhile bomb too too long time
did you do the Python community
I she created the pike and poster
session she created the
pie cut education summit and she is
tired
people had a program in Python in and
write your contacts
and she speaks in large both up icon and
her experiences where gender transition
in the tech community
and she is going to be talking with us
today about farewell and welcome home a
python in two genders
please welcome Mary cedar
so my card
okay I'll so I want to start with the
disclaimer
I am basically what I'm going to be
talking about is based on my experiences
in my observations there could be two
reasons for this:
one of them is maybe a little bit of a
weasel in that
you can't call BS on this this is my
life the
other thing is that I want to make it
clear that I cannot speak for
all all transgender people I cannot
speak for all trans women
I cannot speak for all white late middle
age trans women from the Chicago area
are I can really only speak for myself
this is an important point because
up marginalized groups people tend to
assume
that one of them represents all of them
and that's just not true
are so this
is in fact a very difficult talk for me
to give
in its very weird for me to be in this
situation
I have been teaching in speaking for
decades normally
I the back of an envelope in five
minutes I'm good to talk for
hours ask my former students
arms so this in fact that I've told my
story a few times now and it gets harder
I every time I think party that is that
in spite
above the disclaimer I just gave you I'm
afraid that people
think I am speaking for a lot of other
people I'm really scared screwing it up
I the other thing though is this quote
from Laverne Cox
lover in is a transgender actress who
stars
on orange is the new black the Netflix
series she's
also quickly becoming one of the leading
%uh spokespeople for the transgender
community this is both the reason why
I'm scared and this is the mantra that
I've been clinging to
in order to go through with this hit is
revolutionary
for any trans person to choose to be
seen
invisible in a world that tells us we
should not exist
so this is in fact my revolutionary act
and parted my story is in fact the story
of the world telling me
all of my life that I should not but I
cannot exist
so to start a long time ago and some of
my friends made fun of me starting back
this far
are I was born in a small town in
nebraska in the country doctor declared
with great confidence
it's a boy unfortunately he was wrong
in fact I was transgender and what this
means if you're not familiar with it
is that some time before I was born
something very essential
in the the way that my brain works was
set to female rather than being ill
I I try to stay up to date on the
literature and things like that up but
in fact
their is no clear explanation love this
at this point there are clearly genetic
factors
they're also clearly epigenetic factors
timing's a poor man's
various things but we don't know what
causes it there are probably more
trouble causes
and in a very important way it doesn't
matter
what military's is that I never chose
to be transgender I never chose to be
born
with email body and a female breen mind
whatever it is
are I always just was
now as you might imagine
I even now with this is a hard thing I
in those days in that time
this left me fairly confused I knew that
things were
rate I also learned very quickly through
fairly pervasive gender policing that
I could never be a girl or with the
girls are like the girls
not only that but I learned very very
quickly and
and I'm talking about back 45
I could never even talk about it never
never no one can know that's so
you can imagine I was really confused I
until
eventually I N O when puberty hit this
became a very
urgent issue in at about that time our
family got
I Look magazine this was in are january
of nineteen seventy which shows you how
freaking
all I am and here with Steve McQueen's
mucho face smeared across the cover
with an appeal to the president this
would be richard milhouse nixon
I to unite the country there was also an
article on this new
bizarre freaking weird phenomenon I
transsexuals male or female
I read that article and I saw myself in
its secured the hell hath me
I found that are all transsexuals were
deeply troubled people
who have to leave extraordinarily
complicated lives
if you read this article closely you
will find that they are deeply troubled
people because they are almost always
on able to get treatment
and they live extraordinarily
complicated lives
because if they do get treatment they
pretty much in
as a price getting treatment they have
to enter what I call the trans witness
protection program
that is in that day this was actually
part of the medical protocol
if you wanted to undergo any sort of
treatment for are being transgender
you needed to goes still as we say give
up
all connections to your former life no
one bust ever know
or something horrible will happen to you
this made quite an impression on me as a
as it I
a very young teenager I in fact it's
interesting when I ran across this
article online about nine months ago
after four decades I still had a whole
paragraph served is committed to memory
for beat 'em
%uh so faced with this information I did
I made the sordid rational adult
decision that any thirteen-year-old with
absolutely no one to talk to did
I decided is to just not me I would just
not let it happen
I wasn't this buried that's it no
problem
I am and so I'm
I went in now I eat struggle to fit in
as a boy
and what I mean by this in retrospect I
can see is that
I really wasn't comfortable trying to be
a member %uh a group of boys just was
never meet
I as a very mention there was no chance
that I was going to fit in with the
girls
that was right out so in fact the only
third way open to me
was with the handful of people who are
certain into science and doing things
like that
now that's not to say for geeky your
transgender cuz that's clearly not true
but in fact we did have boys and girls
there
there were a lot fewer even in that time
a lot fewer above the sordid
gender policing and episodes I
the what you would get normally so this
was a way to survive in a way
it was also very interesting I mean for
us in those days
I'm the technology that was accessible
to us was
astronomy and telescopes how we ordered
lenses made telescopes I'm
ground a mir's for reflect urs we did
all that stuff
it made us very very very strange kids
I in central Nebraska back in that day
but at least they understood what we
were we were geeks and nerds and that
was
well wasn't really great but OK I in
fact we're is so weird that we would end
up in the newspaper from time to time
are wanna my friends joked that must've
been a slow news day trust me
central Nebraska in those days pretty
much every day was a slow news day
so their am on the right with my good
friend Dave
we're still friends to this day %ah and
by the EC long noted the bottom sister
people
are always very interested in before is
an after his with transgender people
art what it used to look like what's
your you'll be more that really gets
going
iight and for transgender people in
general this is fairly uncomfortable
I just wanna admit I am no exception to
that these are not comfortable things
for me to show you
so I was geeky kid
I went on to be geeky teenager and to be
geeky young adult and then a geeky adult
I got a PhD in Greek and Latin
literature
then huh along the way in a story that's
really too complicated for happy hour
talk
I ended up switching from being are a
Latin teacher
to a school Technology Director
software developer I teacher
I chief d/b/a are pretty much everything
so I ended up doing a live programming
starting in the ER
late eighties I programmed in artsy in
Pascal
I in Visual Basic I am ashamed to say
it's my only option for something don't
judge me
II did various things like that along
the way actually
open source came around and I thought
this was just great stuff
arm I i switched to Linux I switch the
school's servers the Linux
that's the great thing about being the
technology director nobody can stop you
ice started a lug I am
I actually at a Linux world and Nathan
our kind trying to decide it was 2000 or
I learn Python so in fact
at least a few love you may have met
this guy here
he doesn't work here anymore so
I became involved in the Python
community fairly early on
the matter-of-fact I think it was with
the in
three or four weeks %uh learning Python
that we were teaching it
are two ninth graders at the school I
was at
that's because the alternative would
have been teaching them something like
Java and that just made me cry
I and it worked really well I ended up
teaching this to other teachers at state
national things
I'm I taught this to people at Lenox
mass
I it's a story that other people have to
tell to once we got started we really
wouldn't shut up
arm I E started speaking fairly early on
again on Ethan you're going to give a
talk at the first
up icon that really was a pike on back
in 2003 we were just talking about that
I I talked it some arm state and
national
our computer educators things I just
felt tonight used to do kind of a road
show to the National
educational computer coordinators
convention um
I did things like that I ended up doing
some writing
up my writing career was a little bit
peculiar I went from being the humor
columnist for a dog training magazine
I to working on I'm not making that up
II was on the cover once
arm cell %uh to arm
actually working on a couple attack but
projects are most recently I did the
second edition adequate python book
are which sells well enough thank God I
actually get a little money for it so I
invite you to help that
arm I E at
made the mistake I've saying to Steve
Holden when he was such a rough the PSF
you know him there's anything I can ever
do
and before I really even got that
finished
I he said you like really like a poster
session up icon
okay I'd honestly never even seen a
poster session but the man had spoken so
we figured out how to do that
are and through some twisted events that
I haven't quite found them
I ended up in the Python Software
Foundation so
basically I was getting a lot from the
Python community this was something that
I liked a lot
I think are you know Brett summed it up
for a lot of us out when he said he came
for the language in stayed for the
community
iight this was really a good thing for
me
the problem was I was still
transgendered
and it's hard to describe but this is
like the whole phrase
born in the wrong body you're trapped in
the wrong body is something made up
by a journalist doesn't describe my
experience certainly
instead the best analogy that I've been
able to come up with so far
is if you know you really tired and you
know you've got a really long day the
next day
and you can't sleep and you lie in bed
and you think about
how you need sleep than you think about
how you're wasting the time
you should be sleeping thinking about
how you need sleep when you think about
how you got to think about needing sleep
use to sleep
and then you're back to thinking about
how much needed sleep and you sir go
through that for what
it's like that every our every day when
you
for me at least it was when you
transgender I think that gender
I think about how much time wasting
thinking about gender thing about I'm
not gonna
you back it just continually grinds away
at you
so I started telling myself if I could
just hold on until I died
it would be okay the problem is I wasn't
dying fast enough
I and in fact people think this is maybe
me being a drama queen or something
forty-one percent of transgender people
attempt to kill themselves
this is just a fact because almost every
trans person I've talked to
has come to this point with the only way
this can and is when I die
that's not a generalization about
transgender people particularly by the
way that's a generalization about how
you're treated
so this led me to
too stupid to think have some weird
things and I started thinking that the
only thing that I could do
was embrace my truth and you notice they
say my truth because the truth that
society had been telling me
or the world had been telling me was
that I couldn't exist
and I decided that to do that
would probably mean giving up everything
remember back at thirteen I had absorbed
this into my brain
that the only way you're going to get
out if this was to basically leave
everything
and this was a very painful thing to
think about but like a lot of trans
people had come to the point where
even if I lost everything that was fine
so
I E started to think about other
alternatives here
arm I had toyed with the idea of doing
the education summit
as a farewell thing to the community I
would do it and then disappear
going to the prions witness protection
program the only problem was
actually started accelerating the peace
my transition because well
it was just such a freak relief to start
moving in that direction
iight that that wouldn't work so I
actually thought about
what was for me harking back to learn
Cox a very revolutionary
night idea what if I just did it and was
open about it
up first thing I looked at codes of
conduct
I look for specifics what happens to me
if there is
a problem if I am harassed this was
important to me
other thing I did was they started
telling a few people I Jesse Noller
a V alaska some people I would work with
them high con- and they were all pretty
cool with the idea
and the more I talked about it the more
I decided that I would go ahead and take
that chance
so I did I started by teaching at some
Python workshops for women I i spoke to
conferences
went icon it was good the education
summit was fine
okay some other people I work with an
organizing it were a little bit confused
when the names on the emails change
typology I
up but in general it went pretty well
arm
in fact the more open I was the easier
it was on it was for me
because I didn't have to worry about
being outed it was easier for other
people because
they certainly know what to expect at
the other interesting sidelight
is that when I told people they
sometimes felt an obligation to share
some deep dark secret about themselves
like i cud
prompt the man they had it to answer
back I'm
cell my takeaway here is that
we talk a lot about diversity and that's
real
soul but we should be ending on this
point except that
I'm I'm a contrary in in my old age
%uh so it is not quite all rainbows and
unicorns
or as you might put it this is kinda
common in social justice state circles
right now
we don't get a cookie we the Python
community quite yet
um I want to tell you a little bit about
the realities that remain
I am almost always the only openly trans
person in
in the room and we talked a little bit
last night the transmit up about how
weird it is to actually
be in the company of many other trans
people all in the same place school
that's weird arm and
by openly trans UK government suggests
that
are rather the UK government's official
figure which is the only official figure
I've heard
is that one percent of the population is
transgender in some way
and yet people tell me all the time that
I'm the only or the first trans person
they've met
somebody's not telling the truth I and
they have a very good reasons they can
they they don't dare be
out I'm not real I was never I never
thought less of a real man
now many people don't consider me a real
woman I am not real
are I have become a thing a curiosity
something so weird it's perfectly
acceptable to ask me
are who I love how and when up which
bathroom I use how and when
are all sorts of things like that that
you would ask other people
there is sometimes a flinch factor
in being seen as beauty friends
acquaintances whatever I think somehow
the rice
she's trans people to realize she's
transfer you can think about me
this happens I have lost friends
virtually all the couple my family no
longer speak to me
arm a career I spent over 20
well over 25 years teaching it's very
frustrating for me to hear people
talking about the need for
educators who also know how to program
because in fact the odds me ever
appearing in front of high school and
middle school students again are
virtually nil
and if you think I'm overstating that
you just think about how you would pitch
that to your local neighborhood
okay I am more joy
I when your trans you're always the
punchline have an easy joke
if I never hear the punchline and she
used to be a dude
again in my life I will still have more
than a lifetime supply
are their issues with rates there is
a very heightened risk violence
and as a a white person up
I've what's a privilege still I have a
job I have money all of that
I am far less likely to suffer this then
a trans woman of color
but even so relatively speaking
everybody's percentage goes up
if you're a trans woman this is all the
price that I have to pay to be who I am
but honestly I wouldn't change this if I
could it took me a long time to get here
but I'm at the place where now if you
offered me the chance to go back
are long long time ago to central
Nebraska and fix things
I don't even know what that would mean I
wouldn't take it
and that's partly because I think that
as trans people we have something that
is very rare
in very valuable we've actually seen
some of these things from both sides
high-impact what was surprising to me
transitioning to to to be perceived as a
woman
were all things that I thought I had
figured out that I thought I knew
I and in fact
it's different when they really apply to
you as opposed to just thinking about
so I met some people who I thought we
just amazingly bring it
that seem to have no recognition
whatsoever
that didn't feel like they were welcome
that didn't even always feel safe in
other words
I was in a different world
arm and you know someone these things
and stephen was alluded to when we were
people were talking at the pie ladies
lunch I now in technical
no contacts here think I've been many
others certainly at work
I'm the only woman in the room I have
now become invisible this one was a real
surprise to me
I was all worried about being harassed
me came to Python the first time
as a woman no I was invisible basically
almost every woman died
even maybe interacted with on Twitter
recognize me or interacted with me
and almost every guy including people I
had known for 10 years or more
looked right through me I honestly and
and and again it's sorry but this is
true I honestly had to step in front of
some of these people
and yell at them to get them to see me I
N and it's
it's not as though they didn't know I
had transitioned or anything like that
%uh so and and eventually done some
looking around this is actually fairly
common thing
are Men arcade have trained not to pay
attention to women in professional
settings
so this is it's just I I found it to be
true
I am now always judged by my appearance
as anywhere else female in the room
will be able to talk about a great lakes
I cannot assume personal security
anymore
this is something that i think is a guy
you don't even think about you go where
you want when you want
I can't do that anymore double standards
are now the norm
as a guy a used to be arm just a nice
guy
not just a nice guy as as a woman
shortly after a transition I got
feedback both that I was too nice
and I was an approachable at the same
him
I don't know how to do that so these are
all things that kind of
that have to do with being marginalized
and
so if you're not a if you're not
marginalized
you don't understand that you know the
things that you want for a conference
for space for anything
tend to be viewed by the group as extra
in your not always sure
if you're welcome arm if you object to
something
and these are all sorted from my
experience interacting particularly on
I with with people in the pipeline
community even I
if you object to something you're angry
and probably your bad attitude is
hurting your cause
I am and and being angry can be like
just sort of know I just said dishonor I
am
you can if you call somebody out these
are two words that I really hate
you can be bullying people with
political correctness are starting which
%uh
I've never seen anybody start a real
witch hunt
these ball strike me as people who are
privileged to don't want things to
change this is what I see when I see
those words
and no matter what kind blowback you get
you started
and we've seen this in the pike on world
many times we've seen on tech world
we get a big blow up this way probably
every six to nine months in the tech
world
this just happens so
those are all the things are going on in
them
business world I know this cuz I had to
go through when I i transition we talked
about this a great link
there's a business case for diversity
businesses now no
in the business that I work with I'm the
only out transgender person in
are North America a 16,000 employees
okay it's a very all 85-year-old
conservative company
Daisy have a party line that diverse
group called to solve problems better
and that we need every single talented
employees we can get we don't wanna lose
the people we have already we want the
biggest possible employees pool
all those things are the standard
business case
for diversity
so this should also then be true the
should be even more true
in the open source impact on communities
I and yeah I honestly I'd
I was not able to catch adidas keynote
but I gather that's exactly what he said
I want to listen to that part definitely
um if we're talking about being
open which we do all the time that
necessarily implies
I at you know the notion inclusion and
diversity
so here again i at the end and the Wii
is in question marks because these I am
not speaking for every March wise person
in the world
I am just trying to give you an idea of
some things that occurred to me what do
we want how can you shot us
up how can you keep us from being so
irritating arm
okay here your some things first wall
understand that everyone is different I
don't mean this in the sense of
diversity
we're going to get a certain
predetermined ratio of genders in colors
and things like that mean
everyone is different in a murine a
different weights
alright we have a whole like enormous
bank of different little settings all
that can be different
aren't you could have sexuality said
here you can generate issue here
reset here religion here all of these
things
and they are not connected the fact that
two people happen to have their
sexuality setting
in the or less the same place whatever
that might be says nothing about the
rest a bit
I think the more that we embrace this
fact the more than a lot of the other
issues go away
lipsky um listen to its
spots a social justice movements now
have kind of a little motto nothing
about us without us
but codes of conduct
up codes of conduct that actually say
something real
are very important codes of conduct it's
a trust us we're all nice guys
don't in fact those make me angry
because that missing the entire point
a code of conduct I outreach matters
I I need to thank I would never have
given the stalk
anywhere if somebody had asked me to do
it I certainly wouldn't be giving it
here
if Jessica and asked me to give a talk I
don't think this was the one she was
barking on but she's been very gracious
about it
arm outreach matters allies matter
this is important I have never witnessed
in decades being undercover as a sis
gender person
and being undercover as a male person I
have never witnessed
when when when it's just that group I
have never witnessed somebody standing
up
to say not that you really shouldn't do
that that's transphobic
or no you really shouldn't do that
that's sexist I'm not saying it's never
happened I'm saying
for decades I've never seen it we need
allies that will actually do that
safe spaces spaces where you can go one
way or another whether it's
all trans R all women or whatever or if
it's some other strategy
ways to make yourself comfortable so
that you'll take part
are very very important so to conclude
if we're gonna throw around words like
open fair inclusion
inclusive things like that I would argue
those have to be true for everyone
and that's all I've got thank you
look
now I am freaked out thank you so much
hmm
we have time for what one or two
questions but wanted to you
yeah sure thank you so much for sharing
that experience as
arm one thing that I have noticed in the
community and
not everyone does their but on
people who are in a marginalized group
often feel very threatened to the point
where
if they genuinely are being a jerk to
someone and you say
hey stop that your being a jerk to them
just the way that you would say that to
any non marginalize person
they go your assaulting my identity
rather than going you're criticizing my
behavior
do you have any suggestions on how one
can give them that feedback
to maintain and non-hostile community
when that hostility
is coming from and marginalized group
have I don't I guess the thing that I
would like it
if I were doing that in that case and if
it really was
sorted that threatening a at the
situation is somebody that release
really clearly that I am
you know felt that way is that maybe
this
would be done sir Dave in a very low key
kinda privately first
I i hesitate to say oh well you know we
deserve special treatment or something
like that we've got somebody who's
scared already
then maybe keeping things very low-level
might be
a way to start but I I don't know it
depends you
thank you very much 11 high and you were
talking about the experiences
being invisible are feeling invisible
when you came to the conference
and I wonder am I if that
in some way for some people whom I did
been looking right through you
if it was at a flip side reaction to
not wantin to staring not knowing how to
relate to you like to do you think that
there is
that kind of misunderstanding going on
or
how how would you know I I considered
that but the vast majority of them
the really they looked certain right at
me and then read on
through me and any update it really was
almost surprising it wasn't one of these
third
it was just sort if and and that their
reactions have completely
surprise when I actually would say
something tended to confirm that
right thank mmm get big again the next
talk in this room is married
are talking about the Vino married her
temperament get outta here