hello
hi are so we have a show in your county
from India
today and she's gonna speak to us about
won't hurt others had me on disconnect
thank you please welcome us
hi everyone I
thanks for coming to the stock %uh mean
and disconnect is actually
a song by Porcupine Tree I did not make
up the good name myself
a this dog is about a
a happy eyeballs a guarded them that
implemented interested
edited boring guy the hostname important
I
today in this dog I'm gonna talk about
all the
Catholic a think programming mistakes
that I made
to do it and no how to do things right
though you can do them right from the
get-go and a
hopefully you'll also get a themself
the amazingly awesome community that
blistered hands an Abergavenny
I'm studying computer science and money
by India
and I'll lately I've been working on a
%eh be BM God hippie that that
implementation and by well
happy I bought I implemented this
because it sounded good
no I'm lying I implemented those because
everyone kept telling me that
it's a crazy complicated and buying
and
and on up if you're not be you bite out
to be 100
vie est belle garden exist and
how it is useful but the BIRT
I really didn't are getting all have
died
and after implemented still
endpoint interested there API is that to
breed the implementation
up servers and clients from what they're
supposed to do
so up that a client and buying basically
article updates so has the connect
method that big so
fact he and other day loans are deferred
fighting with the connected to depart
most important in particular are big to
host name
resolved addendum I double host
addresses and %ah
you don't the connection to the rules
that is established first
so the name is illusion by peter is done
by
sockets energy I meant good and
the V this works is that when you pass a
horse named
this method it does also into might've
been posted this is redundant mister
those connected the hosts
end a no dead
these addresses can be ipv4 ipv6
what this means for us is bad I am
then you want to connect whatsoever you
need to identify it but then address so
a ipv4 is the therefore division of
Internet Protocol and uses it could be
due bird addressing scheme
this gives this arm just over $2.4
billion
addresses but they aren't allowed though
there as expanding so fast that this
is not enough you started running
charter practices know that's why I B
six comes in
and saves the day basically it uses 128
bit
addressing scheme and a gives us many
many more
addison's and a the long-term goal is to
transition to work completely
eventually bike it up
I mean might be fought applications do
prefer ipv6 because after all it's the
internet up the future
bike don't start that although some most
of the applications have this
ipv6 addresses be balloon art book
properly in the servers
so if %uh servers a ipv4 by Tim Berg on
a looking but ipv6 connectivity is
impaired
though body is ipv6 capable applications
like
their browsers email clients on the
those word
arm let's see they would
in got a few seconds I believe not to
Genzyme
don't know how long it big but yeah
April a incurs some delay
before falling bach to ipv4 and
back harms though application
performance then
users a experience with ipv6
and it slows down a doctor bins and
dots a problem so happy eyeball to guard
them
solves this problem for us it say is
that
once we have the list of resolved whose
dad this is
we should a connect who work in the
order in which they are
don't endo you're done the connection
that established first this means that
we are trying to connect to multiple
hosts
who showed us is that was returned to us
but the thing is that
okay initially when I heard the song by
them I thought that okay maybe
what be you going to do here
disconnected the first address and
a regard how long back ok then the next
Addison the less regard how long dark BX
then compare the two dimes and then
probably
a the one-dot eggs less a bank and it
back one
but I was very wrong are what happens
here
though high-level objective of the
SunGard them is
do I returned a connection ass quickly
as possible
and up the VI the example that I just
explain used pecan expand that would be
a lot of time
so what do you do is be the the
initiated several connections
in badelain and then the one that
connects posters were done by the others
are dropped
bike another objective abyss
a guide them and Latino and bind because
you're starting to talk about then point
is do a is to basically you
seve network resources and
if the first host addresses connection
is establish quick enough there could be
a beast of follow-up
resources to connect to other areas as
well
so we introduce a $300 million secondly
that means third we don't actually
initiate all the connections together
the subsequent connections are
initiated up here a little bit be so now
moving
on up a missus and mister ten-point and
be wanting to balance things in it how
do we do that
listed as any synchronous Iran given
night looking for a book
and I just want balance things
so well the good news is that the state
is good i doing
badly things especially deleted network
operations
the reactor that busted reactor
is good doing might build things at once
by doing multiple things I mean that
Bates formidable think that once
and that its job essentially
so what happened here is that connect
PCB
returns immediately it doesn't babe for
the connection to actually be
established
it just Rick dunce initiates the process
of starting a TCP connection
and then returns adeptly and a
the reactor caused this method F
bend the connection is finally done an
established
so that back to me the been you to
specify a call back back would be God
led the do so let me know that the
connection is done
now the second part of that are the
members about
should willingly both the early October
the method by
gone leader does this for us and
in this your basically should you link
the
a applied to the function F after 5
seconds
so that's what bag does and now that I
knew that
what I needed to do and that was to
growers capable of letting me do this
I love being too hard to write unit
tests for this
because the spec is kind of complicated
and the only way to know if viv done it
right
is do bill would the as
driven development be so the first thing
that
I needed to know was should I use the
word he acted in the best
are not so what happens here is bad um
but I did this the early October
actually
tries to better delivered the operating
system event in real-time
doctor that stone avoid by the but
beauty testing UN unit testing
especially
V should limit are going docked with
external word
as much as possible and the actor
doesn't do that for us said
just it is the means to talk to the
outside world
and me to avoid that so
don't be gone do this that's wrong but
not long but
thats not advisable I T so
there's a SW guide Clark interested
died on what does the same thing bag
a we were going to test for dinner got
up it how the gonadal mattered bag a
third
should you've delayed called and it has
I'll
a method got a good month so what's
happening here is my belly
clock initiative you're telling it that
okay this is the function that I want to
gone after five seconds and then second
you're saying that okay here I want to
know what would happen if packwood bonds
by fights against
what about event will take place on
basically triggers
the third it's like I aim is frozen and
yeah I bonds in the clock
I'm as as in how we like so
now moving on to the and implementation
I didn't have a name for this it doesn't
always go Idaho standpoint
so we had a discussion about that the
first edition
was hostname endpoint because it big
whose name
an the next word or whatever purple
colours
appropriate the next addition misty CBN
white
mostly because we hadn't used the name
yet but
a also because it the
dog connection was established by RTT
but the thing is a host names are not
parts
BC they are not even part if I P
they are about to be in it and on
ninety-nine percent though
this endpoints mentality was the NS so
BNs and buying but then again
a BNs can be used to resolve names
for other things as well and this
endpoint won't let us do that
its its just to establish connections to
servers and clients using BCP
so this name wasn't right either so
the important thing to remember here is
docked a
ECP NBN as the girl implementation
implementation details that important
implementation details
but nevertheless the I dot so
what we need to remember about this and
buying is that it be true was named
and the next do it gives us the
connection sold them and point it was
now moving on to the implementation a
I had no idea how to go about that it
was even if
I did understand the spec after a lot of
I dunno speculation it it makes sense
but I had no idea where to start so a
john paul was my mentor during mice deal
with some other food project
would I was doing around the same time
suggested a few simple steps to get
started
the first one is this listing its
feeders
on a piece of paper are a txt file
something something next we're starting
them
now a idea behind starting it from the
simplest dude
the most complex is that I'd
the complicating things are only
complicated than you tried on
do them honored once so if you first
finish
implementing are dealing with the simple
pings are simple parts of then buying
then
the complicated but don't seem to want
to get enough to draw
so bob was the second step well with her
grandmother died in your dust
for the first thing in that list that's
made sense because
I already talked about is driven
development
so coming together lighting best part
okay before that on then a
now I'm going to this doubt all the
different mistake that I made to out
this endpoints development
the first one was that then I was trying
to implemented
I was trying to catch the failure
that was supposed to it bill in an
exception
in it in an acceptable Aug and I had a
unit test for this
and it was feeling and I was
kind of confused about what was
happening and turns out
its its the movie that de foods book
what do you do with like a lot the first
line with the word it forward
I'll give me a connection and
the death would be good fire but the got
back on it
I dinner back the important thing here
is that B is rebuilding
and the bay by two functions work is
back a
you can either get done are you can
raise but you can I bought
and since it was returning something
there was
the sting was wrong the right thing to
do here would have been this
we could have us top 10 i Barack where
back over girl
overdid effort and I would do the air
handling finance
this first the first mistake I meet and
alone
something out of it second one than you
think is driven development
this is the back like is opposed to get
a first you write the best that fields
then implement the feeder
and the best spots you like another
guess that feels
you implement another feature and things
bus
but the back in that I was getting was
this
and it was beard
by a on my best to had one thing in
common
bacteria residing at a time arguing the
run it was the last night the mistake
that was doing here
is bad I was rebuilding a good effort
from the deaths
i've a store they're doing best what's
been the bill but mister B actor
and we don't want to do that
for reasons that I had mentioned before
that reactor is a means to connect with
outside Boyd
man Espino mister Diack up nobody out
there what it does is add rice to
again panicked about a boy and
third-best
week for some message to come back from
there
and they'd forever basically but dryer
the twisted best
to a defines forever to be about by
120 seconds I think so it
boers dining out the best for dining out
so the lesson to be learned here is that
we don't want to go and efforts from
tests
we don't want to do that that goes a
then be our dining unit a sec if you to
death
we want to limit how to much be docked
dew
external being its you might keep need
to be
doing this if you're see if your guests
are talking to
the next on a database I think they got
but in even in case you need to do that
you need to remember
a simple basic rule that probably a unit
that shouldn't be talking to
things outside of your application
still other something else that I needed
to remember never it never ever getting
efforts from unit tests unless you
really have to
and if you have to just bring you think
the design of your abit
okay moving on bill so this is the right
thing to do I just moved back by nine
and on the year thus were busing until
everyone is happy
now I mentioned something God a
dog dog advance in the years lights
I E worse to more for big dick dying
because time is presented as double a
very act dumb
the pink is a good so far I was not
dealing with the should be regarded by
to the end point because
remember simple things first complicated
things needed a
still the simple things were working and
everything was going
now I just introduced a single I know
believe God's and my best
very dining out again they were feeling
are sometimes timing out
but not in a way that would tell me what
was going on
so I blame all you do for those because
then I didn't interviews died and my
court up
everything was working II the back and
everything stopped working
and up initially 300 milliseconds was
the
bang that I was using I change that busy
goes against
so that I would know what was going
wrong and years again the immediately
that's like
right now grade I would need to advance
dying for this
by a don't sell out I was wrong
I didn't get how all of this was looking
so lift who was a the person who died
right to be your game and then ended up
writing twisted instead
a he was helping me a
on he was answering my questions and
helping me fix things and then buying
and he said that he courted marty is
from the matrix and
he said that I was thinking too hard
about it he said that
it he said it's just a number and no
devere clark's call you to my pic books
is bad it's art it connects although a
called third
I B over me then sorts them by number
read this number is the time of they
should you got
and then cause them one by one and
that Sarda made sense and our
Bang Bus frozen but still the US against
had be like to hike to bed the clogged
ears again top bud and it is supposed to
move forward now
that ok as doubles work and
there that's how things were bare I
bid Sardo falling boo
more I a I did talk to fall into
more Gabbana end up the main
even behind all of this with that others
trying to what things together
too high I was trying to understand the
bigger picture and how things fit
together
even before implemented the smaller
parts a baby I
so again this was glyphs idea that
I levy need to stop thinking so hard
about those and Eventbrite turns out you
can you would like without knowing by
you can most of these are just things
guarding a
other things and end there is no reason
behind it sometimes even
its just sunless to think that you need
to
do and the out their needs in order and
the
person was implementing it too was a
particular order and
that's about it so this help and
not it it was riding behind a nice abie
it seem to follow the spate properly
but then by the perfect a the only way
to know this was due
get it for a good review the be twisted
scored review process books
is that a you were going to get you
submit it would review
be booed review it and then they assign
it back to you
you improve it but the comment and he
summitted back in the review
any Sunday sometime men it looks good
you get to merge it so
this Holme the connect method for this
endpoint look
it was working but it's like more than
hafer though method are nested
and on Dhanbad suggested that
connect could possibly be implemented as
an independent object
instead of having so many nested
functions inside even suggested that
in bringing this to finite state machine
would be a great idea
if we have a state machine framework for
missed it because it's
sold by the way if you're staying for
the Sprint you should diner suggested
we can work on this together if that
something
so fine a state machines I what's coming
up next
hopefully double it proved to be the
cord look
the previous night and at last I wanna
see that
there will be a day another come up on
the stage in talk about how I
implemented
some software that save the word and
I dunno defeated the aliens gave his
glorious victory but that is not the
date
a bit embarrassed are good ass targeted
art there was
helpers always there sometime at in the
form of a good review
sometime as a Bay program in session
sometimes as
a simple reminder that I needed more
sleep
so a what I'm going to see is that
I wouldn't have been able to die I do
this alone
the dog the patient why is and amazing
mentorship by
John Boyle be there if and in fact on
the twisted community
so what i'm saying is that I'm really
happy to have
all these all the friends here out there
and open
the community so thank you and no
this is the link to the beget in case
you're interested in
taking a look at the development
yourself and thats
me on Twitter you couldn't read it you
can barely audible to stop winter
if you like something about it you
didn't like something
that would be great so thank you
better question okay but he has a
Shin so any questions
anyone I guess
no one yes I would
okay so I was asked by the by the mascot
happy eyeballs
it is a good question because it's a
funny name a out there though
let's a every debate about the gay
shouldn't wants the user's
do be there but that and so
baby the bed uses
the word happy I boats to differ do it
audience the people you are viewing this
happy eyeball to guard the basic needs
that
the user's of the web applications
and %ah they're happy because the sting
is working fine day so anyone else
then thank you Ashley for talk
thank you