good afternoon everyone my pleasure to
welcome Michael Bair
long time speaker icon and the creator
see crockery
is going to be talking to us today but
building apps Websense o'clock
what's good my big on recross
hi on
I want to thank last-minute something at
the comment and I Jason Meyers
for doing great talks on sick of me and
Hellenic right for me so we can
trade for them it set me up to do that
the either I'll talk to oversee
cockamamie
on so is called fun it's being there
that's right back writing the app I
what is this talk about
now this is about writing out larger out
longer lives applications
out with relational databases and see
clock me and I
house he bought me deals with that kinda
by issue
I'm the foundation is what we call but
the code that we write when we first
plug in our foundation are frameworks
and libraries so when you first start to
rate your app
before you begin writing you use cases
you have this thing that I call the
foundation
like your your data types that are
special and other I
things to deal with constraints and
orrin patterns I
I think that having a healthy amount not
too much up-front code is a good thing
rather than a failure %uh libraries and
frameworks to do everything
possible I'm sick of me as designs with
being able to write these foundations in
mind so how do we define
but a foundation is and is not the
foundation
it was the technology reusing like we're
using plaster pyramid I
you know what libraries frameworks how
we structure our directories name our
files
what kinds of architectural patterns
were going to be using
I how we build without ever using
integrated
I testing configuration on
so the decisions we make will be the
foundation will determine
I'll when a new developer comes in the
project what is that copper going to
need to understand in order to add new
features to your project
I and it will kinda determine exactly
what it's like when you start with hey
the customer wants this new feature
where we start where we
to the middle in wedowee and so here the
attack the italics around is
are the foundation years it's the source
file database server application
its the the basis for patterns indians
that we're gonna repeat
throughout the app it might be reusable
in other applications I'm and it
represents have the way that we've
adapted the frameworks and libraries
refusing to the the task at hand Asus
is sick specific so what we're doing so
the foundation is not
I replacement for premature libraries
if not the start of our company's new
app platform Celica writing our own
amazing system that we're gonna
published its really meant to be
specific to what you get
what you're getting done it's about
practicality purses trying to
make some bigger thing I not a
reinvention at the wheel
on last the wheels you have a terrible
pretty obvious right so it's the
foundation and actually the slide is the
plug for
the pyramid web framework I
you because we don't have any parent
talk this year
and then we have three sick of me talk
which is great but at
just I feel guilty that we have some
talking term has not so act like you're
in it and the sample app we have here is
a pair map
I like about here that I really love on
the view are under my love this to you
make out your view function has a little
decorator
that says this view well talk to this
template this kinda template you back to
have several
render decorators I think it's really
cool um
I think it's keeping it in the right
places I like
it simpson testability at st.
to detail and of course when I work a
pyramid nothing ever works
nothing ever breaks nothing ever does we
don't expect his parents components are
like
super duper industrial rock solid and I
always trust them
100 percent so it's really great and
karen is a Quester marginally
like me and then of course you don't
have to use
pyramid you know if you can write a
foundation and framework meaning you can
of these
last I'm alright
sup this is the link that I met just
made public on bitbucket hopefully
that work so if you want to go so
basically this talk if you want to go to
this application
everything I'm talking about is going to
be in it app and you can't download the
app and you can run and play with it and
I'm gonna have it up on the Secaucus
site is kind of like the beginning
actually having
sample ap psych the pyramid tutorial had
a sample app
and this will be another one I'm
so many girls next slide if he's going
to make that bucket
see you got out busy name right
so an overview of what I'm going to try
to cover
I the meta holder I asked conventions
and recipes
session scoping which is the part that
makes me nervous to talk about
a constraint naming I a little bit of
migrations not too much
and then some some thought to have been
testing
the medical there is something that I
got from first working with pylons
one-pound bill that a project that have
this file called medigap by:
and i actually break it out into several
files and I just from that from the
minute I write the app I know there's
gonna be a metaphor there
which will have the foundation will have
fun
various files that are going to deal
with the kinds of things I know that my
happiest
worry about so the name the app is ATM
craft and hobby like model folder
and then inside a mock mile the first
half but there's nada which were gonna
deal with
database stuff in the abstract
in there we have in it P Y which
provides names to import from the
outside
are based by: is fundamental units like
your session you're too tired
base I object-relational mapping helpers
I schema generation a definition helpers
and then things to do with II special
data types
so the first part conventions slash
recipes
I can't quite figure out the difference
between a commissioner recipes that are
kinda interchangeable
the call the convention slash recipe is
to reduce
as much repetition as possible and
day-to-day code without taking it too
far
things we use her recipes are up i cant
auctions make sense
sick of me events compiles recipes
custom types
sick of me is really or if it was just
kinda programming in Casa trying to
make the system work better more
predictably it wasn't there in person
water too but as we've got to version 7
it anymore more mature in protective all
but some recipes conventions become sick
of me features la 72
on why aren't these conventions recipes
part of the clock to start with
well one place that we often draw the
line is with naming things
seek walking really doesn't ever
watching name
anything it doesn't want to name a table
here columns here constraints
something to do with naming are to be
not outta the box to come up with some
way to
come up with names some conventions do
become Peter shirley's partially
I'm the project rise to I know we like
features
but we like to start with making
something as a composable set of
components that you can kind of build
mix and match different things out of
them rather than just a flag
like do this but rather you come up the
recipe for like do this thing or maybe
this or something else could adapted
do that we think it's more flexible an
open-ended and
force subplots be here is if you are you
know
the famous proverb give someone a
fish and feed him for a day are or
give someone an event wasn't for fish
available ok
and then you can fish for all the
applications you
walk or something like that
or just to come
is a really really simple convention
that I actually years
its it there are more complicated burns
it at that are more flexible
but this is a simple one you want all
your classes to have a primary key
that's an integer surrogate ID I sick of
me
with declared it lets you make a mix in
class
I that has ID so every if you any class
that you apply surrogate PK to hear will
have an ID column
and then any class that wants to refer
to another circuit PK can have a
function
I you'll see in a sec how the use this
call reference call that will make
another column
with a foreign key that points to your
ID column and this is very
obviously kinda hard coded there's more
flexible persons
that are actually in the app I'm if you
do this circuit pic. a reference call
thing
it looks like this so you might have a
class
to use net called account balance I that
subclasses
acquired base answer he PK and it has a
table name
and then you have a reference call to
another table called balance type
and then I as a lot of you might know
she caught me has
the relationships by default separate
from the foreign keys
so we have balanced type is related to
the balance at class
so this is a little bit better and
having
explicit I D E calls column integer
primary key
was true balanced i buy tables column
are in key
balance a little less verbose a little
more repeatable and unless things to
type in
and more poorly last things to change if
you want to change how you do things
arm this is a really really simple quick
quick and dirty pattern the example app
has this pattern
what's implementation is a little bit
more complicated so you wanna press lied
but this is the you know elusive
many 21 relationship so what many no one
does a function that I
does does basically what you see here
which does basically what you see here
so and I wrote a blog post about these
years ago that's the clock me a call
that magic
a new RM and it really was in your
honor's just
using recipes on topic walk in a2 make
it less verbose and
and khaama press keys that work for your
use case at hand um and actually the 911
too many have come up with a recipe now
that so-called I probably will lead a
sick of me but
you get the point is that you can if you
can see talking about for about you
should try to come up with patterns to
kinda
are reduced how much typing based on the
app at hand
on another example conventions are when
your database you're talking more than
one database
or charges one day this and they have
some kind of single function that you
want is have a python
I object that represents it like I often
want to do our
the current time on a database up in UTC
and I if i'm talking post-crescent
single server they have completely
different functions that do this
and progress has as far as I know this
yeah this whole current timestamp a time
zone
UTC stop so if you have things like this
with your database
you can make your own little quick ad
hoc functions
and use the sick of a compiler extension
which is documented on the site
to come up with a lot of functional
things like this so that
when you use the UTC now function it
well our resolve to
the current timestamp a time zone on
post-crescent it will resolve to get
UTC date on da single server and then if
other databases are available
up by default the Rays and then you have
to implement how that would be done
brother david is a step on UTC now is
another function that maybe we should at
the Sikh Aug it's pretty common but
the concept years ago some other weird
funky you're using
you can you can use that as well
are using that recipe began I execute a
SELECT statement select
UTC now are working as UTC now is the
default
in a column so created that means that
every time a row is inserted
into orders you get a default timestamp
in created at
I and them another our way to
conventions with events
I when you build up sick of me meta-data
I you get at the table and columns and
meta-data things together
as those things are connected together
sick of me admits events
that you can intercept and do things
when they happen
the most useful friend in that regard
after parent attach
it happens when you connect a column to
a table or tables when the data
and constraints to table things like
that this recipe will
at columns to all the tables that will
store the
right be created at time for a row and
the update at that time
for a row and this is a way that is that
having all your tables X
at happys columns explicitly venues &
event and to stick them on at each table
gets created
so that's a recipe on
custom types I everyone well have a lot
of people use cutting types are very
handy for when you have some kind of
special Python behavior
to take effect for a value that's going
to the database and of no use this one
to be crypt
password tight I as data goes
out to the database it is run through be
crypt first
as data comes back from the database it
is wrapped with a
proper class called password that will
do comparisons using be crypt
so this is you can try this out on the
app as well in a 2-1 see with this thing
looks like
it means you can kinda add rose to the
database
without giving the crypt at all you just
put your secret I'm a secret
any insert Azadi cryptid value and then
when you query
for a client record that has yet to fire
that we want snowflake in this case
we can just compare the secret field
which is actually the cryptid
persian you can't read it it's not plain
text all the point X is gone
to you a plaintext password equality
comparison here will actually run the
I'm a secret
token through the crib before doing a
comparison so
using a sick of it because the typing a
little ingenuity
you can you can have this site
transparent a
encryption a password smiling caption
on so that the entire recipes and
conventions
that is more in the sample app to be
looked at
I and then apart which is more
concerns me a session scoping cuz I'm
just
I was trying to people understand
sessions coping this is really hard to
do cell
sick of me up sequential knapper defines
access
the essential object known as the
session
and when we write a web applications to
thinking it to really worry about with
the session
out where we get when we handle the
request
and when the request is over where is it
where does it go and also had to be
initialize in the first place
so the pad is a lot of ways to do this
I'm gonna show three patterns for had a
how to get the session during
our request on the method that most
people are very familiar with and
everyone uses
is called the scope session the scope
session is basically a wrapper around a
python
read local which means that when you
talk to scope session and you say hey
mister scope session can I have a set in
place
it will are consult a python preval
variable
and return for US session object that is
specific to the current threat
issue in a different thread you get a
different session and that's really all
it does
ominous assumes that the web framework
using is going to guess we have one
request
per threat at a time meaning it won't
work if using like tornado
where you have not or question 13 I'm
that are mixed up
um so if you're web system my eye
keys I request to threats you can use
the scope session
and just have a session is local to the
thread and that worked fine in this is
very common and I
is this an everyone uses this is very
common
another parents on that is you can also
use Cup session
not using a treble
have is not directly you can send a
Skype session
a function called the scope funk which
as a function that will give
this session the scope setting registry
some kind of token they can use
toukie to you get the current session so
with pyramid
you can use a function that they provide
called get current request
which forever so you get from local but
not within sick of me using it when
pyramid
which by the way they hate rather close
but this will work I
you can say from character the whole in
forget her request I
please give me the request for the
current a thread and then please give me
the session at Scott
that quest so you can do this to and
have carried you the trouble stopping
said it yet
and if you had a web framework that
didn't have thread local
request model this would also work like
you had a
a tornado Auction Co get her request you
can you Skype session with tornado in
this
would probably work or have tried
and then the third method is don't use
code: session at all
don't do any kind a global stuff like
that you know when you work pyramid
there's always a request object
let's just put he on session
directly onto the pyramid request as an
attribute
because everything we do in our apt is
already has the request must get the
cousin from there and then there's no
more tropical anything
and then you are on the good side of
Chris McDonough Stamper
on cell yes so you can say
impairment they have an event called you
request it gets fired becomes a new
request
so hey paramedic times the request I
let's create a new
see caucus session and stick it on to
your request and that's it
that's how it works so you can do that
too I like that from local thing cuz
I I don't feel like having being
required to have a request
everywhere all the time but to yourself
so after those three methods a acquiring
the session how to get rid of the
session at the end
on everywhere prima has some kind of ok
at the end of a request to clean things
up
as a sick of me docs I think everyone
knows it
when you request is over do a finished
call back
that will call session da clothes or
Skype session that remove
everyone should you know be aware this
is in the DOCSIS I kinda
where primer 101 and at the end of the
terrible
sessions coping section possesses
i think is really simple and and it just
while people are such problems with that
um constraint naming some new features
in sick Bokoni
on database constraints like monkeys
indexes I
UNIX acceptor a have names
so that you can target them in your
migration scripts when you want to
create new ones are drop
existing ones and change what they have
I am
controlling these names like having all
your concerns me and especially as a
good idea but very tedious to do
I manually and sick of me as you know
doesn't provide any names cuz he caught
me as I wanted you named it doesn't want
to tell your d/b/a is your grumpy
DNA dvs what to name their stop so to go
and what to do it but it doesn't want to
have a hard time it'll give you easy way
to do it
we can make names on a Mac leasing
scheme events %uh specifically that
after DL attached thing I after para
task and I showed you earlier
on however sick of me is now made is a
very comic convention to use events to
create names here
constraints and and other things we've
added a new feature called naming
convention
which allows you to set up a naming
convention up front with your meta data
and that will do the best thing for you
so now in sick of me as your 92
dash 09 for meaning we fix the bugs with
it
as a 094 most about I you can make up
the salat
dictionary with your meta data that has
about a string template
that will apply names to are a lot of a
common
constrain topics like primary key
foreign key UNIX checks and indexes
so when you use a convention like this
one here and you can read the doctor how
it works
you create a buzz will look like this
where you get all this handy
you can see all the constraints are
named explicitly and so when you write
your lender migrations
I everything that you want to target has
a name joint drop a primary key and
recreate it you know the name
the name isn't the weird auto-generated
name that your back-end database my two
I you know if you're switching between
different back ends
different databases have different
naming conventions built in so this is
the way to override them
that make sense get
I've using Alembic I am
this really squeaky states can hear that
squeaky on Jerry limit migration I
we just had a great talk analytic
migrants I'm sure you all know Olympic
following now I am pre-olympic mean
at what we're doing here is if you can
best be have a lending look at your
database as exists right now and look at
your
class meta data as it existed it will
compare them
and it will generate a new migration
script based on the diff of those things
on this is a pretty it works well
but not perfectly we want you to modify
this we want to check the scripts not
perfect by any means
but this now if you get away islamic and
to talk is your on foreign integrates
with
the naming convention Peter very nicely
so that you get a migration script with
those naming conventions explicitly are
right now
in your migration
so the only point is that Olympic up now
integrates with the name a commission
feature in a in a better way than it did
before
upcoming features for Olympic and Selena
talk about this a little bit
I multiple virtual directories automatic
branch resolution kinda like a merge
it's actually pretty easy to do I
versions
up Olympic right now are a linear West
so it's like version a version B version
seen as a straight
went west and now it's going to be is
Paul on the feature
you know the morbid directed graph where
any person file can have a number of
parents
I and Atlantic okay
and wanted the lightning round which is
testing
and I've come up with some interesting
things about testing that I want to show
you
um cell protesting database enables
miles there's two approaches now there's
one person with them for a long time
which is
the transactional approach that since he
caught me docks
and recently on the job I had a client
who want to
do a lot of tests that are against their
model classes but they want to be able
to run without there being
database available so I worked up a new
system
I which is called the mock approach and
I think the mock approach really need
it's a little more
TDs but it kinda call and maybe next
year I'll
think Mark is awesome I think right now
it's it's interesting
so transaction so basically the the
caller testing here who want to be able
to test
Armada classes and mr. class is really
need to be able to query against the
database
to do things how to me test those
classes
Sony transactional model this is an art
our documentation what we do is
we I basically have the test run
in a database transaction and when the
test is complete and tears down
the transaction is rolled back anything
that happened within the task
it to the test can freebie reading right
from the database
but everything it does is then rolled
back so that test ultimately had no
effect on the database
so them the simplified structure for
that is that in your set-up
you want to make a connection to your
database you want to begin a transaction
and then you want to bind the session
that you're using for your task to that
connection that is now open in
transaction
the way see clock me does transactions
that session
more say hey I'm a I'm a session I have
any cash I'm gonna do some work to
and begin transaction and commit my
transaction when session goes to commit
the transaction it won't actually commit
because it's part of a broader context
that is scoped outside a the life span
about session
and this was written this way very
intentionally to support this kind a
pattern where you can nest
a transactional containers so in this
test
in the picture we want to basically this
added to the database freely
is ever ever you wanna test against and
then your task you can query the
database really
and and just your test and then if
you're session must commit date it's
fine
if your session wants to do a roll-back
on
that can be done as well I actually
worked out with someone on Twitter
this example will not do that but there
is a way to add more than some more
complexity such that if you're
unit test was to also roll things back
on a session
without the X X a including trans-acting
back at that can be done as well
with a little more work and then when
the track the test is over
we close the session the rollback the
transaction and because the connection
returning it to the tech support
first this is kinda team failure at
least art
everyone here only one person to say
yeah and I'm like a right
in practice it looks kinda like this I
you have a picture that's going to
create model objects
and then in your test your be basically
calling upon a picture to get
the data set up that you need and then
your in this case for testing a
a pyramid view kevin has awesome article
that down the request but love it you
make it any request to put everything
into it
and then here we're sorting that this
request race a
a have 403 Erica
based on the token that has a that's
been timed outside cabin game
to working that way
sojourner than the measured advantages a
transactional testing
its easy I think it's easy I'm I think
it will suit was integration test
integration testing your testing have a
broader scupper functionality all the
way from your view all the way back to
the database and back up again is coming
a whole stack
is happening it's really not as much as
a unit test
and disadvantages are that it's could be
slow you doing a lot of database
a set-up and tear-down the test might be
to generalize you what you might want to
test a much more
up you might not want to have all the
database stuff happening with your test
as well
and unit database so that's
transactional testing so the others mop
cuttings mock testing
and if you're in the bucket repo this of
I'll mock session P Y
I shows a basically what looks like a
sick of me says in that really
this I module uses almost no sick of me
at all uses the Python mock
library I was talking to Michael of your
Don
out where he is the author of the paper
mache library I love
I really love the Python mock library
give it two thumbs up
and I this thing basically is 9 never
sent out of the box
mock with a couple little twist to make
it
I such that you can but setup stake
seek walking Aquarius that are
parameterized meaning the different
parameters you give it
you can assign different return values
to the not how many people here are
familiar with using MOX for testing in
general
just the idea that you have this mock
which kinda acts like something but it's
not really that something is just
actually a is an imposter it's like I am
i pretending to be the thing you think I
am
so this thing is not a single guy says
at all it's it's trippy just a mock
I but as you might be able see here we
can have different queries and plug them
in return values that are different
and you can even plug on a side effect
no result found and then later when you
go to query
but the the calling code is assumed you
have to basically build up these queries
to be exactly what the calling code
will be calling upon which is one up
reasons cop
and it'll get back data that was just
like it was hitting database as you as
you tell
so the simplified structure marketing
super duper crazy easy
there's no transactions ok act is
nothing just get a
mock session and the set up and that's
it and you maybe plug your mic session
interior interscope 72 think it depends
on what session
scoping pattern using the picture is
just
I setup the mock session with some pre
cans
take results and then the task is
call upon the picture and then call a
query as you need and and you get the
the object back so it's very easy but in
practice is actually
I i've have found it is more difficult
because you have to basically going to
the code that you're testing and look at
all the cords doing
and you have to replicate every query it
needs perfectly
so that you you can anticipate what
query is the functions gonna call
how they're gonna look and what kinda
returned I so here this
hoskins just the fixture part was
performances but one row
one-line insert a record and scan it and
you're done here we have to conduct a
spate what what the query is look like
right as I make sense why we need to do
that so you can see in this
and and the pictures that are in the
sample app you know go look at them
you know you can see the cattle you know
it was just more tedious to write these
pictures
um but the end result is you can still
write the test my utilities act the same
I and even nice are you can sometimes
you can looking to the mock
and make sure certain things recalled as
you expect on so the test themselves
look exactly the same
or or better um so that's the mock
system and I found to be
very interesting once I got that mock
session to work I was really like wow
this is kind of a mind blower
I but I'm still not sure I advantage to
mark kasinga that there's no database
needed
a test can be focused a smaller units
because you you know less over
immigration
in a person courage is your cutting a
modular because and now we've got a
right these mock that are matching all
the sequel foxes you really have to be
on top of higher cuz organized
such that if you know feasible to be
mopped
and its past the snow did
there's no set up a tear down really
disadvantages to mocking is that the
pictures are really tedious to create
army won't actually catch problems with
your are amateur
like if you're sick of me or am isn't
configured correctly or you're sick or
queries are right it what they want it
will not actually cast at all
to testing class and then address the
problem knocking in general I can people
than talks about this much better than
me
I'm if you do too much mocking your
kinda you can have been a writing a
mirror out
gotta up the code to your testing in the
first place I'm so sometimes
your marked out tasks can end up just
being test that the code
does what you told to do even though it
still be in correcting the mock won't
actually know that so that kinda marking
issue um and then
for the final rounds we can look a
little less so I mean
the example ap is I gave me the link and
and we have purposed the
acting send the PDF first so you can get
them online sup
um what I will do is the source of the
source code you can go up to that fuckin
look at the source code please download
it
I what we'll do here's will run the
pyramid ap am run the quote-unquote
client
here comes the part where this will be
great if it works
which showed so I have the pyramid ap
running in this window
Sosa serving I
on a its Xeon it's actually a on a web
service that
acts like a miniature ATM machine for a
bank see you can send
deposits and %uh money into it and it'll
basically store your account information
on how much money you put and
and then you can make a withdrawal %um
you can withdraw money from different
quote-unquote accounts
I and it now has a maybe five or six
cables
I'm it's a cute little app
and over here is a job app that is
actually going to be the client
on this java app I your see in a minute
what it does it sir it's actually
at just just shot app is actually a
client for the
pyramid ap but is also a server for the
client
that I'm going to run and I don't know
how much you can see
so this should be hosts home
works
so this client is a program for
Minecraft
this is also known as the CAG at the end
of the talk
like the talk was terrible what we
should do that silly gag at the end
now that's cool so
own it it's nighttime okay so you can
see the extreme right
fortunately our our ATM machines open 24
hours
yep and that is busy as a chicken in my
bank
K so the idea here and you what you want
to do is kinda watch
the blue at the can you guys see that
the terminal on the side there yet
in Minecraft ATM machines ready informa
casts
something at the chest I it actually
made a web service call
back to the pair met up and on
what it did was it had it basically has
an auto connect a
for my session so basically this this
test being open is like a sec is a Sat
is it
open session to the server and out the
first thing that the
ATM craft I ap want to say is oh you
have six diamonds and 6 I'll lapis
blocks
so is from there's a Minecraft I'm block
codes
so there's my inventory and I can t take
three diamonds out in a withdrawal
went down to happen here you can see
something else happens
and basically said on I withdrew three
diamonds
and you can see over here there's a with
dropped call to the web service
I you now and I can collapsed last night
sticks and stones
but the stone in the bank's IMing
deposit the stone
and I if you look at the the channel its
so basically
have that's what does a damaging
so if anyone has questions for Mike
in come on up I'm going to use my powers
for evil and ask the first question
I'm you're talking about sessions coping
the thing you'd didn't want to talk but
I apologize for going back to it but
a one thing that ever 100 a few times
in proms I'm trying to solve the idea of
a long conversation where over multiple
requests
UN meeting the same ocean open session
if your medical in a complex subject the
12 and under or something
are there any conventions that you would
recommend you since you brought me for
letters and more dollar on
is it well on transaction or the
question was was a good question
yeah so it along transaction that you're
running yeah like let's say you have
somebody who's making a play doctor
craske is already in a complex
object in a brother who just want to
roll back plug it in the browser
down the ACP across the state was so you
wouldn't have a transaction open between
requests
so I mean there's different ways to do
it I would you the difference at Brees
request
and just kinda resuscitate the stated
you need each time
I wouldn't try to get to basket at
bus thank you yeah eyes a possible to
get their transactional rollbacks
working
signal light tapped out for a while and
then to
the trend that you mean like DDL
rollbacks alright nested transactions
and rolling back with Siegel light
for okay so nasty mean safe points
yeah I guess they should work in sick
like aka
take points II believer working aka
yeah I had a question everything the
talk %uh stop mocking start testing
from I believe I'll after two years ago
at the Canton
up over your opinion on that especially
with now this new mocking 7 Recovery
Disk
intruder thought what what what I didn't
you stop mines are set by I knew the
idea is kinda
some things I was getting at right that
yeah I mean thoughts
does my thought is that mocking I think
it really call I'm I've kinda been
bitten by the Mockingbird
but I am have yet to you get bit by that
bud
you know painfully so yeah I know those
caveats up by having the market also I'm
kinda
swinging from one side to the other yeah
hi
and wonder if you thought about making a
pyramid scaffold
out of ATM craft I
okay if I knew it here at Scapa
what I could do that much as they like
the template thing rehab I think press
like I already know you have
yeah you know what I venture yeah so I
its yet so I A
is like it pp Pakistan play yeah I think
I'll be a good idea on
I yep we should have people look at what
idea to make sure I get I mean
it should use them more the way to 18
pratt was written was very very
simplistically it doesn't use that that
those ok
transactions that would you probably
should years I'm said property to a
little more
stopping it but yeah I think yet that
would be great
your I've got one more
sorry home what are the initial things
that attracted me to see brought me
coming from hibernate was the ability to
just use table mappings that I could
have my model objects be just plain ol
Python objects
without having inherit from some magical
base cost and then incident
martino sessions I be able to abstract
might get access to repository or
something
how you feel but I've I've not seen not
much Mike Turzai registers right you
what's economy is so strong I started
out very
in in spire by hibernate and for the
first
three or four berths been hacked Clarita
we had um
just map like your class where poachers
people pose
are I and then you have a table then you
know the mapper and I just found
actually went to try to use that system
it was really tedious I some people do
work that way
on but it just seems like
from a pragmatic point of view it just
works at more easily to hack your
classes in Table somewhat
are sometimes use a certain style which
is in the dock switched where you have
your class
laid out but instead having that the
table columns
in line lbs a in air attributes
underscore table point to a a complete a
by itself so
oftentimes do more of a hybrid approach
on
but the separate I mean my work hiring
have a section of house was really just
too much tarts are ya I don't I don't
have a
a golden rule there which is why sick of
me
is always so nice about everything
because I really want to be kind of
open-ended
thank you if there aren't any other
questions you can sync up with Mike
after the talk but
thank you very much Mike
in