hope you enjoyed your first full day of
talks last talks love this room
I had like to present a gram double din
who generously offered to fill the slot
on very short notice
he is the author of some stuff for you
may want to use called mother WSUI
and he is currently a senior engineer at
your elec and he's going to beat
speaking to us night about the best
methods for creating the creators
let's give a warm welcome okay
before I get started this it this is a
talk I have done before which is what
managed to just drop into the spot
pretty quick I've presented New Zealand
park on
last year on I had put in is a proposal
for this conference bit can get accepted
and if you followed my blog he would
have known i
to the huge blog post series beginning
to you about this topic
and such I'll see something quite
passionate about
and it's an interesting topic reaction
on you get from it and because I select
gay way beyond a
normal way that people usually brought
decorators I I sorta
all gonna lose people in in what I'm
describing because it's %uh much more
complicated what they're expecting
I get a read on the reactions of why do
I care about all this detail why do I
need to know
the way I had do it now were I don't
quite think it does
which is Parliament explaining an so
thing to take away from any guesses if
the don't quite understand it
an why i think is really good about what
I'm doing
in this and what i doing in the block is
set I'm not doing what a lot of people
do when they
they talk about a topic like decorators
you get a lot of blood processing
Hey look I've went in understood
decorators on the weekend this is what
they are
and I'll explain in a few paragraphs and
I think that elect to it and
I like to go beyond that and I'll I like
tea
create a story about how I got to that
solution
are what something how it works
so if this final a few devotee blog
posting yourself
are really really think I should do that
don't just say I worked this out this a
solution
describe the journey you went on to get
there
exit really interesting to read that
when people come along too ida
and if take anything away from that you
don't understand what I'm talking about
please at least
do that and I hope you enjoy my story on
this one so
I should mention of the cult in my eyes
to talk to morning
under courageous so he's covered a lot
of really basic stuff here
I'm nice what he's talking about sorta
that's my
this three or four slots and I get into
the hottest up
so this is just a quick recap cotton was
talking about to aviation never written
your and decorator
ninety if any Houston you would know
that x-rays from
from at symbol used to prefix usage
the at symbol here though is little more
than see
tactic sugar one can do the same thing
invoking the decorator function
explicitly parking
passing in the function to be decorated
and replacing the original with the
result
in fact this is what you had to do
before the decorated syntex was
introduced in Python 2.4
to decorate a syntax is there for just a
shorthand way
being able to apply rapper around in
existing function
or otherwise modifying the existing
function in place
while the definition of to function is
being set up tomorrow illustrative way
of showing how rapid works
to implement using a class object the
classic
instance is initialized we've and
remembers the original function object
when that now wrapped function is cold
it is actually the underscore call
method up the wrapper object which is in
fact
this in 10 with 10 call the regional rep
function
a pass for rapid isn't particularly
useful
say normally you would actually want to
do some work either before or after the
wreck
functions call or you may want to modify
the input arguments
all the result it's a posture the rapper
using a class to implement the wrapper
for a decorated is an action that
popular
instead a function closure is more often
use
in this case in nested function is used
to the rapper
and is that which is returned by the
decorator when an hour wrap
function is called the nested function
is actually being called
this in turn would gain call then call
the regional rep
function in this situation the nested
function doesn't actually get past the
regional rep
function explicitly but he will still
have access to it by the arguments given
to the at a function call
just us away with the need to create a
class to hold what
resurrect function and that's why is can
convenient and generally more popular
now when we talk about functions we
expect this tend to specify properties
which describe him
as well as document what they do these
included underscore name
and underscored doc attributes when Lee
is a rapid a
this no longer works as we expect as in
the case of using a function closure
the details of the next to function
returned
if we use a class to implement the
rapper as poss instances do not normally
have it done disc on a match
be attempting to access the name is the
function will actually result in
actually care
exception the solution here when using a
function closure
is to copy the XP to Pinterest from the
rap faction to the next to wrapper
function
this will then result in the function
name and documentation strings be
incorrect
needing to manually copy the attribute
is laborious
and would need to be updated any for the
special attributes added which need to
be copied
for example we should also copy did
underscore much electrocute
an imposter free did underscore call
name
and underscore underscore annotations
attributes war
added to aiding getting this right the
Python standard lobby provides the fun
tools top bracket decorator was dust is
tough for you
if using a class to implement the rapper
instead of two fun
tolls top bracket decorator we would use
to fund
Torstar update wrapper function instead
so we've managed to fix up thing so that
the function name
any documentation string is correct but
what if we want to query the occupants
best cation
this also files and instead of returning
the occupants best cation for the
wrapped
function every test that the rapper in
the case if using a function closure
this is the nested function the
decorator is therefore
not what we call signature preserving
a worse situation again acres with the
class wrapper
this Tommy getting exception complaining
that the rap
function isn't actually a function as a
result
it isn't possible to the right and i
cant specification at all
a Van Nuys iraq function is actually
still callable
now as well as normal functions
decorators can also be applied to the
method to classes
often even includes a couple have
special decorators cock
class method and static method
converting normal instance methods
into the special method types methods
have classes do provide a number of
potential problem sir
the first is that even if using thanked
All Star Trek pics of fact all tied up
tight rapper
in your decorator when a decorator is
applied around
hospital static method it will fail an
exception
this is because the rapid credit by
these did not have some in the
attributes
big cock it by Battlestar trappist and
rapper
as it happens this is actually a pot to
pop and it's fixed in part for free
by ignoring missing attributes
if my run and opossum free we still have
trouble a
this article is by Fragma types Shin at
the Rec functions directly callable
this not actually be the case a rapt
function can actually be what is called
scripta meaning that in order to get
back callable
descriptor have to beat down correctly
to the instant
first so all I decorate is using
function closures all
ha strap it may appear to solve tough
tactics failing varies corner cases
and also I don't do a very good job
preserving the ability
to introspection the latter is a problem
for documentation tool
ID's and also some performance
monitoring of profiling tools
so let's go back now look at these
descriptors it's a turn at
be a key mechanism in all it is a
descriptor is an object attribute
with binding behavior one has attribute
access has been overridden by methods in
the
descriptor protocol this method
underscore get
and the school said done totally if any
of those methods
act on for object it is said to be a
descriptor
what this means is that if actually be
the classes any is a special message
define
when the corresponding operation is
performed on that
actually have class denies message will
be called instead of the
default action this allows an actual bit
over right how those operations are
going to work
you may well be thinking that it never
used make the subdirectories
but fact is that function object are
actually descriptors
acid where functions region had a talk
last definition
is a normal function when you access
that function using a DoS attack chippy
pop your invoking the underscore get
method
to find a function to the class instance
turning it into a
found method of that object
so when calling a method of a class that
is not the Thunder skolko method
divisional function object it is cold
but the underscore home if it after
temporary object
that is crated as a result accessing the
function
the problem with class method was that
is dependent on the descriptor protocol
being applied astute underscore call
method annexes some the result
returned by done disco que when it's
cold
the way to solve this is for rappers to
also be descriptors
to wrap it is applied to a normal
function the
Dundas Coco method of the rapper's use
if the record is applied to mess it up
clocks
the Danisco K if it is called which
returns in Newtown rapper
and the Dundas Coco message if that is
in fact instead
to sell asap rapid to be used around
descriptors as a proper case the
descriptor protocol
sent using a function closure will
ultimately fail if used to read a
decorator
which is implemented as a descriptor the
situation we therefore have
he said if we want everything to work
decoration always uses patent
the question now is had a waitress the
other issues we had
we solve painting using functional stop
practice in fact What's Up tech
wrap it before but what do they do or
reckless chess users update
wrap up so we just need to look at it
are shy ones imposter freed up free
although that actually has Anna Paquin
as well which is fixed deposit free to
fall
casing to try remember is we try and
look at the body of the update wrapper
function is what it is
in these default bearable circuit past
as assigned an updated
days in a sign what we were originally
manually assigning
pasta mixtures that underscored d
an update is something newsday's we need
to see what's happening with it
looking at the body is a function free
thing to being done
Fist of a reference to the wrapped
function saved it underscore apt
this at the park is how it should be
done lost the second is to copy days
attributes such as to underscore named
underscore doc
finally the third thing is to copy the
contents have done this court date
from the rap function into the rapper
which could actually result in quite a
lot object need to be copping
if we using a function closure or
straight class wrapper
this copying they would be done at the
point that the decorator is applied
with the wrapping a descriptive though
it technically now also needs to be done
in the fam rapper as the down rapper is
Craig
every time rapper is Cole for function
down talk of
this is going to be too slow we need a
more performant way of handling this
the solution is what's called object
proxy this is a special
wrapper class which looks and behaves
like what
racked is a complicated based in its I'm
rot
some actually can adjust gloss over love
details at this
shot though it copies limited attributes
from the wrapped object to itself
and otherwise is a special method
properties and underscore
get at her to fetch action beach from
the wrapped object anne when required
what we know how to do is to arrive at
our wrap a class from the right object
proxy
doing so attributes like to underscore
named and underscored of when create
from the rapper
return fais for the rap function stay
calls like inspect don't get ek acts pic
and inspector
gets off will also work in return what
we expect
hat now for implementing a decorated
appears to work correctly
but needing to do all that each time is
more work than we really want
well we can't do therefore is Craig
decorator to help the scrape decorators
this would reduce the code we need to
write for each decorated to a single
function shank
what what this decorate a factor need to
look like that
as a tent at declared factories quite
simple and it isn't really much
different to using a partial
combining out new wrapper function I'm
from when the decorators to find with
the wrapped
function when the decorator is used and
passing them into a function wrapper
object
to Tampa skolko message about function
rapper for when the rapper is used
around in all of action
now to score to decorate a wrapper
function with the wrapped
function and i cant leaving the calling
of the wrapped function up to the
decorate a wrapper function
totally losing at this point I guess
in the case where pining a function the
rapper's also passed the bound rapper
I lied I just
the bath rappers more or less the same
with the Dundas Coco method delegating
to the decorate a wrapper function
so we can make rating decorated easier
using a factory
let's see what we had have excelled at
other problems we I'll see what I see
what other problems we confine
the first such issuing crating
decorators come work
on both normal functions an instance
method
class this from have saw changing at
decorate a print at
argument pass for a normal function the
oxygen get a top love to arguments
did the same for instance method and the
result is the fact
the problem here is what have to
decorate want to know what the actual
instance of the class was we have lost
that information when the function was
bound to the CAF
and is now associated with the wrapped
function passed in
rather than the argument list and she
used normal function claes
into on a on a method have class you
know what you
usually happens you get the self
argument passed an explicitly
so we don't have that in this case
to solve this problem week may remember
what the instance walls
that was passed to the Dunder school get
message
when it was called fun function this can
then be passed through to the down
rapper when its credit
in about iraq to the instance point it
can then be passed through to the
decorator wrapper function
as an extra document you may have missed
it but
on the previous I just begin to fall for
the case for normal function
in that top level rapper we passed non
for this new instance
argument so then the bottom iran-iraq
this then allows us to be out to
distinguish between normal function call
and instance method call within the one
decorate a wrapper function
the reference to the instances even
Pasig partly so we don't have to juggle
with the argument
to me that at all the way for instance
method
unfortunately I got done now is when
calling instance method by the class of
the passing in the instance has an
argument the instant pasta decorate a
function is not
instead the reference to the instance
gets passed through the first argument
to delete this variation we can check
for instance being non
before calling decorate a wrapper
function and popped the influence of the
start of the I can at least
with any is a partial to bind the
instance to the REC function ourselves
and call the decorator wrapper function
we then get the same result no matter
whether the instance method called by
the class
or not this fatal does so upset things
the way we have a class method
also causing the same issue for static
method in both of those cases
instances also pasta not
the result is that the first the real
first Acme ends up
s instance which is of the games because
rock
we can handle that in a top-level wrap
up by looking at the type that the
wrapped
function prior to doing binding if it is
a class method
or static method then we know anything
else is likely to be instance method for
a class of static method
we use the original bad function wrap up
before the fetal was added
and miss the fiddle into a vision and
the rapper specifically for instance
method
we're still not quite there the IKE
ministers right again
at the instance is still not for static
method this is a problem
public or traceable sent it isn't really
much different to normal function
for a class method been nice for the
instant actually be
ha exceed is a class type corresponding
to the initial
class argument for the class method
big question is whether is another way
getting this
tent that there is a way are still
getting the class
getting the class but the getting mixed
up your mind and
ninety get this one right tent out there
is a way of still getting the class
class method is beyond this is by
accessing
a special actually and and and discourse
self abound faction
we therefore eaten all the instance the
Danisco get message was passed
and used it underscores self attribute
state
success finally we now have the
innocence argument
for instance method being the instanceof
the class
for a class method it is the class
itself after normal function instances
not
have one more situation consider that is
where the 12
decorate costs what happens then in this
case the instances still not
so from that we cannot distinguish it
from a normal function
if we also look at the rat function no
will say that it is a class
type whereas it would be a a function in
the case
have a normal function being called so
we
likely may have a way to distinguish so
this works at okay
because take a look at the type of what
is being wrapped in this case
this means we can now have the ability
to create a universal
decorator that is a decorator can't
Taman
what it is wrapping this does away with
the need to create separate decorators
for functions instance methods which
would otherwise do the same thing
as a decorator so far did not allow
arguments to be
spot when being applied to function if
documents to the decorator
require the decorated definition comming
nested within a function to create a
function closure
when the app to decorate a factory
function is used
it pretends to in a decorator faction
positional okay with documents could be
used t
I have a preference for using came up
que les documents
as possibly a better conventional
explain blind man
so if I couldn't have default values the
how to decorate a factory with take the
rap
function as first I commit with not as a
default
decorator arguments holler decorator I
can't would now be passed it
keyword documents on the first call
wrapped will be non
and a partial issues to return to
decorate a factory again
on the second call wrapped his past and
this time is ripe to decorate a faction
because we have to fall I could say we
don't actually need to pass the IOC
in which case to decorate a factory is
applied direct to the function being
decorated because wrapped is not not
when passed in decorator is wrapped
around the function immediately
skipping a return to factory second time
now why said a convention having keyway
documents public good idea
is that possible Friel ash to enforce it
using the new keyword
I only arguments in text this way you
avoid the problems have someone passing
a decorator argument as the positional
argument for wrapped by mistake
for consistency k what I N E arguments
can also be in force for required ACK
even though isn't strictly necessary
the final result is we now have a manger
crating decorators that prepares to
function name
documentation strings arguments best
cation
and even retrieving a sauce kit one
decorated can be used on
classes functions instance methods and
class methods
it's also easy to spot decorator
occupant a final act to be optional if
desired
so one magic decorator
so this has been a whirlwind tower at
this topic as I
as much as I covered it still doesn't
actually cover everything I could
and and since this is actually slide
site did last year
I some other details of how I do it
changed a bit
so to blog post series liked it back at
the beginning in the year
if you wanna know more about it go back
and rate those because
they have the final solution I ended up
with for this to cover some more
little caveat to call in a case which
stuff and I am NOT happening here
and so you get a block sector you
actually make if you go to Blogger
of pesticide its blog blogger is a pain
have used
I save knife I actually easy indicators
like it up repay for wrapped
and under the you'll find a.m. a subject
to call blocking is an index in there
evolved to blog posts and the recorder
on hand to capture the math
blogger now I'm up to blog post 10 I
think in that Syrians
I'm not done and
I actually wanna iced living things
talking about
decorated spot i wanna talk next about
Tom how to decorate a module
does it I'm which it tries to use to
magic to try and solve this problem too
but doesn't solve all the problems
I'm beyond that I wanna talk about
object proxies I wanted and talk bout
did
the case at Monkey monkey patching and
and
function wrappers and had generally
isn't is decorated in some respects is
a subset up monkey patching
monkey patching applying function
rappers decorated just
a a.m. sanitized version you can use
your bank code manually
someone talk about a lead as well i
wanna talk about some other topics do is
stop post import ok so
II I could go another 10 posts yet so if
you're interested
now so I should
the said he did go to to Colton Myers
talked this morning
cake decorators are easy they're easy as
you can see by what explain
well they're actually bit more
complicated than that now
rather than go on trial did Kate
everything I've done which
could blame on a bit I I do have I have
done a listen to package it called
wrapped
at up on key topics up on popeye I am
and I say it
its as use of caught my eyes example
this morning if you select
actually don't have a good example here
it's impossible process
I am if you gain to what they say
if you gonna write decorated for
yourself yehiya fall in the night
sent where at that using a function
close it the public
I happily satisfied everything you need
to do but he need to make it
work if you gonna provide decorator
lottery which
has to be used by other people then
Chinese wrapped
because united in it should work and not
have always funny caveat
on cases say try say hi
now live into questions is sick I will
I'm a plug
I so I worked in the relic I the reason
I know about all this stuff is because
we do horrible stuff with monkey
patching
I'm we take your code which run in
production
you trust as amazingly because I go in
there and do
lots and lots of nasty stuff to it and
this is why I worry about this stuff
and make sure it works because if I do
something wrong
news function closer there are lots lots
the cases were all break your code and
you'll come screaming at
so that's why I'm just know it's tough
yet we've got test the pie party on to
not
I'm so if you are already scooting off
to some the other
I'm restaurant more formal nothing's
please come along an I guess they'll be
the congregation at people at some point
we'll head down
so a come on and enjoy that and I can
talk to you later reading this stuff
but otherwise right now she got any
questions
so if you have questions you can just
grab your hand we have time for maybe
one or two
reynolds run over to you and give you
the mic so please raise your hand if you
have a question for gramm
I S to two quick things that that's
likely related am
you still have in the current version of
pack about wrapped
the am you do is is is instance
have class matter static method so
somebody were to implement that
that word of actively remove some the
arguments but didn't
subclass class method then it would
still break am
to this event now you're asking if it I
would implement
class method myself as opposed to using
version that's
part of standard Python word I'm
wrapped and electrically
now I
it does look at the type is it too much
to a
I'm did the
stopped working I don't hear the huge
echoes coming back like I was before so
oxy mustn't be working
tech I Sep
by Michael a decade after back at the
quick the question was I understand it
and their I some the magic but I
explained a
it was at it worked by looking at
way that you're using class method or
static method our decorators already
and some in the magic was dependent upon
that
Anna what that means is it that you were
to the
go and implement class method or static
method decorators yourself
great dislike us in will wrap still wet
the answer is for those things not the
trip day
cuz up tested this is if you really
needed to do that
for some reason to extend class with
unsteady it didn't change it slightly
for some reason
you can actually derived from them and
once you do that the isn't
and check for ecstatic with a classmate
to works
and wrap still works it up
attack that the question is whether I
see this
as something that could going to stand
library and
it some think that has been suggested
and at the minimum
cuz your apt is great Raptors great to
play with and I've got lots of ideas is
it's not just the function wrappers and
decorated
tech treats explain now Augusta thing if
the function you
post import Hawks Tom and monkey
patching functions and things like that
sarcasm
long way beyond that the one of the key
things in the red flag raised his magic
object proxy which I
totally didn't talk about on there
there is a I'm the week rift proxy
object
which saw this a optic proxy bit its
not because it's a special one related
to we Chris so there's no
just object proxy implementation the
standard library
so one of the things that may lease come
at this is that perhaps if
ones people very fun what I've done is
right not just insane
is that at least the object proxy could
go into the standard lobbying
because I know it's something technique
conkland had the idea of pushing
that we should have something like that
in those 10 loving numb he is back in
and nothing ever happens so have ended
the discussion on that
for everything else on you're getting
the actual decorate a factory near would
be really nice
that I feel like one side do that I've
lost to be controlled play with it
say having K I think that's all we have
time first let's give them a big round
of applause
me
head