good afternoon everyone
thank you for the second top and are
open source
session um very excited to
make a few announcements I need to
remind auction winners
that they need to go to the reception
desk right away to pick up the prize
otherwise we will auction them off
again I and the second thing is that we
are having sprints
so the conference doesn't and today I'm
all
through the this week we're gonna have
sprints it is
probably an amazing time to meet
developers love fantastic projects
like pie pie and mercurial and
pyramid amongst others there's a chance
for you to submit your
own projects so if you want to do that
if my leaders spring prepare
a 20-second talk that you're going to be
able to present
right after lightning talks today to get
people to come to your Sprint
and stick around after the for the all
these closing messages
I'll where you gonna be a fine exciting
wonderful products to work with
with that summer the best Python
programmers that arm
on the planet in this in this in the
city
so it is my pleasure to introduce
Elena Williams we'll be talking to us
about the Hitchhikers Guide to free and
open source
participation thank you very much yet
thank you
on up well welcome to my talking I'm
thank you for coming and I just wanna
say on it
a real risk running overtime and also my
slider an experiment I'm reacting
against that I am
helping nothing on a slight upward
everything on the slide it might be very
distracting
but I wanted the slides be a interesting
for people to rate them lighter and
there's a lotta contact I have too much
content
is a crop down from an hour-long talks a
um
this is me I have no time and I'm
standing in front of you
because of this guy and his name is
Andrew tree jokes he also love the async
shell tool and also I love this and the
server which is one of the most
ubiquitous Lee used
open source project in the world I mean
it's probably got be in the
cancellations and it's more than 20
years old
and he has seen it all every controversy
every legal battle
Santa has done it and I'm I knew this
guy at my university but
I thought he was like a really scary
like net and down
tell you and 10 doubt he's wonderfully
charismatic and generous and he die
night
one week if his life I at to do an
autumn session to give a postgraduate
level course to arm teach
student at a party but not this was the
only one of its kind in the world
all the lectures online at on the
university website and also check much
each even case
they dispute me anytime I'm so please if
you have a deep on
interest in open source checked his
watch that because I've all the examples
site stalk always has to start would be
a and as
what he's open source and what we're
talking about is free software but of
free in terms of exchange for money
internet free in the times all freedom
of space like free to do what you want
to do
and why the time I can source got
involved was in 1998
a netscape navigator the best very
serious project to
release its cloud publicly and down
because I love being eaten alive by
Internet Explorer
but it was the beginning of the tech
bubble and nobody liked the idea of
using the word
free so they repurposed is 10 open
source
from for only three letter acronym
organization to use that tend to
describe
a proper open source like out like a
publicly available
newspaper fine book or something like
that on I do and Richard you does
so a lot of people are really precious
about these tens
that he is uses them to change the I
will also be using them interchangeably
but when I say I can source
when I main is free software on my site
state otherwise explicitly
so free software exists because of
copyright
height we all have an idea as to what
copyright he is
on in that movie industry association
sense
unlike to basically sums copyrighted
what you're allowed to do
you can look at it spree much country
anything else to it but the one that
really matters to us
is you cannot change it and
that the shooter powder medically it
your eligible for copyright
if you're product is fixed created as an
amazing talk about is a park on last
year I strongly suggest you check it out
on but this makes for some really
interesting copyright exception said you
know i
fashion dance architectural features
recipes automobiles & perfumes
all exemption copyright I have
trademarks
but no copyright sigh I wake up like our
sport is very
very mu and he didn't even make sense
before the soda sixties
two separate hardware and software isn't
enough for unity 0
you could put on multiple be too hard
with software was a thing at a time
right but
because it's very young hungry at sorry
covered by copyright
and now I'm did you also can't talk
about free software that took met this
guy
and this guy Richard Stallman gets a lot
a very hard time for being a bit have
not job in Ossining talk twice and he is
a little bit crazy but
I do what anyone to underestimate he is
a James even the people who don't like
him
a willing to say he's able to produce
very large quantities extremely high
quality kiting on a full scholarship to
Harvard
today the hot that tough and graduated
magna cum laude he's a very very smart
and retrieval had nothing but the
highest price for you and say to
continues
but he came up with this idea this hack
on top of copyright
we could issue another license that
would give away your copyrights
and I'm the first GPO was a bit sketchy
but they've been a proliferation of
licenses Inc then
their sixties thankfully the Open Source
Initiative in their 63
recognized licenses and being legally
tested
and will stand up in a court of law to
protect yourself you're right you're
softer way
but night that also least 28 rejected
licenses it look a lot like open source
but actually hunt side you understand
the difference now that
on open source is publicly available
source for free softer is
what let me illustrate these so did you
know I
that the Microsoft cannell a Windows
cannot is publicly available to
academics
and I'm pretty much always has been so
you can get the the Windows kernel code
and
basically look at it so I N analyze it
if you want but
goodness gracious don't you dare try and
change that code
and if you try to sell those changes on
your lawyers would
dropped from helicopters or something
like that I'm
so and have another really deep in open
source issue and this is a bit dense but
if you have an interest
deep interest check out that lecture
because the
being too tired and what he's interested
his level is at what point
how much that we die source code you
need to change get a really sry
issue a license for itself and the
answer is probably
there's no and now to change you can
make I'm
whereas transcript yeah absolutely he
lost to fit it in
hello hello well to get could you
license at to gray area
it's really messy and you have an
interest to get that lecture
arm so what this means him is that
if you look project doesn't have a
license
the author can't simply turn to see if
they wanna their white
but crude I'm nothing is done
always use a um and if one of those
official licensed dozen other things
people just because you're giving way of
suffer for free doesn't mean
that I can turn its soo ewe I am and
and re also this is the first time right
unless it is the first loss in table
right any guys blow for blow it all the
problems
without license and they're a big love
and justice he started teaching this
course
um he had been contacted by a lawyer
eighteen years after the fact you can't
willing to resource coach
and he had to go to open up Cody Grimm
Chinese French change it because a
lawyer asked him to observe a bad
license decision he had made very early
on in the pace
arm site and he want to become a
technical lawyer please do
the record needs more than all the the
CB your lawyers come from the Technical
Community First
%ah if you have legal problems at the
Law Center
if you have a project you want legal
coverage for it to be considered
have all this legal open source a a
not-for-profit stuff covered
protect the friends African 70 and give
these people money because these people
he writes
on side why would you want to contribute
to open source
and this is the answer as to why you
wanna can choose I from those but really
what we want as human beings is we want
autonomy mastery and purpose I this is
why people learn how to play musical
instruments
on but more than that to complete allies
what we want is to
feel a sense of connection everything we
do is for these
and down even psychopath one if you
listen to connection but it's just
misguided and all everything about us is
healthier
when we're connected to our fellow man
um
and also we have this incredible prima
donna I can't think of another
discipline
in which from there comfort love your
own comfort you can
I directly 19 it through an intermediary
directly
interact with the very best in your
discipline me nuts extraordinary
and and had become the best when you
interact with those people in you
comes could aspire are also it this is
it kinda
saying that if you have an open source
profile
and employees will bo2 know your
capability in your business
Michigan at Vantage 20 love your peers
on and is also these aspect
love missed compulsion to want to save
the world and I think
you either have these are you dying to
know this is a very big deal Andrew and
that's something I feel very strongly
about
but a source to be aware that with an
open source not everybody is motivated
by this they will be people who
you know don't have the strongest person
to have their own motivations like I'm
corporation to up essentially and the
other thing is is that we'd
probably write code anyway on I mean I
it's just fun
it's fine if we could write code and
then collaborate with other people who
make things that changed the world a min
that's that's extraordinary hi an
so when I first cabey's talk this was my
take-home message is that all projects a
different so when you're approaching
United new open source project
recognize its differences so is it big
is silly is it serious
II is at the limits Cano is it a little
script
help old is it is at dead is it branch I
knew it at that
bubbly things are really taking off pot
I have the people involved with rose to
the people involved
and what organizational structure like
um bahash we are piped in a week I don't
know if he knew this
um but I before I started researching
this I don't know how much the open
source world I thought pike and was back
on
i keeping it was more than expected the
weekend my style via
open source world and this is 2013 early
2014 to
is is Python a some is say
so I reckon for pike in there are
actually two types project
and forge ahead is reinforced me by amp
but he's got my case alleging and what
the scratchy shows
is the 265 something project I analyzed
on get help
Ste the vast vast majority in the have
one contributor you know the four
thousand most active projects on k-tel
so many of them only have one
contributor that the median number is
chill 1 Nov
contributors for the what has a
most-active I'm so
what this means is you but you really
famous projects that you Django raising
MMK Shinya pythons
arm but the vast majority the project in
the world
out at me all help in the world and in a
small number
they're really really highly refined on
site
if your insight have a dish and idea for
the project Frieda mean you'll have
completely different experience
depending on the project
some projects of funny the limits come
I'm looking at you very frank very
high-quality developers leave some
projects going to print
ha style am and so where should you find
project
and this is a quote from Scott by it's
not where you are use what you've got to
do what you can
because this is the question I always
get ass next and down
this is the true and correct answer to
this question and
I'm sorry pal how does Jess can refinish
H
the eyepatch project it's amazing on but
we thank you be sent to the people have
like it would be the funny in the reason
is
is because everyone's abilities
a different so just because you've got a
PhD in computer science doesn't mean
that you baby
you know anything about software
engineering are developed to hear any of
those guys it doesn't mean you know you
know anything about
user interface on so I when you try to
find an open source project
its you can see reading you it's what
your interests are and what problems you
wanna solve
and down then at the next at defining
project is learning
to not having a good sense when you're
using
free software which I trust everyone he
does
down and then look been learned to look
at going beyond being a passive user
are look for a date house when you find
a bug don't regard to bug
isolated ami takes the time to write a
dating back report
think about what you're doing and I'm
mideast
dist it takes time and effort and I
think this is it the
might second-biggest message from users
when you want to contribute you first
open source project Scott
small on a case on the first
contribution I ever made was that when I
was doing the subject actually
I must poking around in a really large
on project and I'll
notice that the copyright tight hadn't
we still have the phone
and was my ever sent me a and I am and
other anybody important had to do that
they've definitely would have done it by
now so I did I i
when i search not found the source code
I downloaded I kept the change in my the
charge
I pushed back whole process took about
eight or nine minutes
arm and that shit that is the open
source contribution prices
you find the change that you want to
make you find the source code
you make the change and in use send it
back but that it's like a
123 process find it
change it retain your contributions open
source is a simple as that
safety first contribution also bear in
mind that
on you're learning how to contribute
when items was project you're not
learning the skill
that you're trying to do there is no
cash I doing something that's at the
edge if your ability in of SQ mi. it
at because they're a very serious
dedicated professional people
you can already do pretty amazing stuff
in the project to give
hundreds and hundreds hours have time to
these projects
and counties bolt up and baby accorded
fell apart like he just
can't there's an ecosystem you work up
the ranks you can
make plugins in integrating between
understand the culture
being a culture of it is a really big
deal like there are people who give a
lot of cutting back to you
on projects you aren't Corp contributors
because in not a good cultural fit
interestingly usually friends like a
week
are site we fun project %uh conference
prints like I
but sin is a sin in a few hours lease
and fine
things in with your domain knowledge
were controls that you want to use
and fine people do you think we're good
things that people you know are working
on
so if things you can do is a program on
his a stuffed you do during the day
um but also interesting thing to the
different is helping out on i SAT and to
get tree
ticket triage ng anchored to you but
there are some significant differences
in the
software methodologies Ivins was
purchased a close as project and I
believe that this is the biggest one
is it just because you submit a patch
doesn't mean that it's gonna get
accepted
I we have this incredible privilege an
open-source
make aspiring to this perfection
unlike work money resources and time
our no object in open source project
site we can I aim for perfection its
extraordinary
side there's a lot of criticism is in
the
the next version of tanker that's coming
out as a big ray factor fam
the way at selected by my count this is
the fifth
Maggie jet to get major attempt at least
years ago was hammered chiropractic the
core developer working on it
that did this very fix this very problem
a year ago and that was rejected
and it was done and the one that's
getting merged
now was based on not a lot about work
but
you are you it has been allotted
rejection let's fuck
another really big deal in arkansas
culture and Andrew felt very
emphatically strongly about this is to
be completely and self-deprecating Lee
truthful
to you you know an extreme so your ego
is
just not welcome United source and a
and is this factor which is I'm sure the
people can't go through the whole entire
careers
and never actually have to engage with
anybody around them
resist you know you I here by choice
and at the long the more interaction we
have the more the longer
your participation is likely to Bay on
another thing you can do is to
ask your employer to give back to me a
project to put an open source license
on it and somebody's person cross
successful
you Django on some things you can do
as at Nankai to now this is something I
would
footage say-so softer development is
very new field amber essentially
open source is not for profit the
not-for-profit version
in other older not-for-profit
organizations like metal some point yet
I recognize
that 50 percent of the paper who were
involved that organization
on not doctors 98 minister to people on
logisticians and technical people
and I think you know I think that is
something in that us
sigh I am as unknown Qaeda
if you are learning to program I would
strongly suggest I encourage you
look at open key projects don't have to
tell anybody
rate route retrieved tickets as I come
in and you
find that my cinema pretty down like
communism
pic tighten that kinda thing maybe
eventually you get your head around the
project if you're a tin of patches
but also there's all that other stuff
his translations and
content one of the most in demand
open source contributors in Australia is
a technical rusher
okay so I am Nick site I'm not talking
to program is in the range all the
program is
block your ears and i can say this
because this is my second korea
am and I think there's a and
misconception that if somebody knows
something a lot about a certain topic
that people in shame
that that applies to all demanding a
legion that's kinda not
trees are on regularly surprised by
things that I can to the second nature
that seems really really smart people
who act just
dying night and I am and
the tricky isn't trying retreat and out
there is
so if you're a capitalist then I'm
night you will be OK say the guy he's
been programming since he's I hate
is not scary he's probably gonna be
embarrassed about that so he you're okay
with that
he'll be okay with that and you have
every right to be here site
eat day I carry that on my other advice
you're not program is learn to use get
help
I wish I could teach you how to do this
now I've got a whole other deck but and
jerry cans change my time bomb
learned years ago we and again has a
reputation for being recalled
they say you have to be a genius to end
user markets rubbish I think we have to
do
is concentrate so when you make a mess
in your browser
just take a step back have a Breda and
focus on it step-by-step
methodically its it's not as Inc bad as
people make it out to be site really
quickly had a project on a
don't ask make college talking after me
say to stay in your say can you tell you
but
for use a point of view I'm not at a
project I know it pass an order could
help for anything like that
these guys have also given have given
talked about this Daniel injuring can't
right
have you got fabulous talked recent pike
and about this but as a user I will tell
you
please please let me install your
project this is the first step in
country
I have create and open source project I
just
change in Brighton United make my time
at it and work on the project and I
couldn't use it um was so you in my big
graphic
how most open source project have only
got one contributor
on if you -ism another misconception
that if you
make your kite public then paper will
just
want to contribute to it but that's just
not true like you want
he would actually contribute to your
party first has to be pretty good
project but
also you need to be be really clear with
the kind help that you want
sigh I'm also of English are of a
recognition
and for people who are involved
have and this is a really kinda personal
thing
but there is a lot of rejection I but I
said I
automatically reject things because
humans more than anything else in the
world
we hate rejection and no matter how in
bed somebody's in a project for how long
they've been around a confident by %ah
a rejection by Kelly to believe you dies
in SciTech you gonna reject me make it
okay for that might decide
most the time you've got a good race and
drop them in I tell you I would not get
back to someone else's work anything
it's a subsidy
that just do that don't let people just
went out to an automated system
deciding am you never know are you might
have
leanest stoneman 19 min in your
community and
you might say something that a in
essence honey singh just always
you know they nice and my tree
communities nice today
on and but people will change by virtue
of being in
open source I these people are pretty
self motivated and smart and creative in
they gonna move on and that's daddy
screw like people should move on
and project leader should move on to a a
burnout and
Chan its its a thing and it's cool it's
fine
site I'm right near the end like I'm
totally in the highest-rated my talk I
am
what I'm I'm gonna do n/a Ravenscroft
did and I'm gonna hijacked my questions
which is
I would love as my first question for
somebody who
isn't currently indictments was
participate he hasn't had my
contribution want to come up to the mike
like now on and first Telus if you
want a but something that you can do
like something that you're really good
at
and the kind of project you'd like
interest in going on although I am
the kind of things you feel have been
your Baria
to you being involved a plea hidden
and say kids have really I really want
to hear from people who
who I'd you know not sure %ah
sadist some my first things I please
communicate this is a massive deal in
open source I it might my personal
theory that ninety-five percent of human
problems are caused
by Paul communication and they will also
be solved by
good communication
and if anybody can think a problem
problems that aren't gonna be really
interested him
explain your problem very clearly in
bold letters on the front middle don't
rapid in all this fluff
be tests and short and get to the point
on do what you say you're gonna do I
this is a real
temptation when you start getting
involved something like this you wanna
on oh yeah I'll do that I'll do that but
only say that resist that temptation an
issue
evil you already there I
also a if you do decide to do something
you having a bit hard time
don't agonize I come everybody has gone
through developmental process to have
been at the state today you're at site
now probably 90 bit on don't feel bad
about
askin so I have this incredible
privilege a few years there wasn't a
problem
couple of projects with this guy and I'm
whose
by any measure like smart rat on
and he was so quick to say I don't like
it was amazing I am
he would use I got you're a ready person
I was with had like how does that work
and what you doing here
that sucks interest me annis if you
really good
you leverage or Billy did say I don't
know I and down
pie Danny was giving this to a
confession to Joe developer a few years
ago
please check it out I his rule of thumb
in the world from the head at nasa
his stepfather an hour disco ask some
money
am and turn up 10 up to subside
thank you for attending up you guys are
awesome you're already here
finished I do have some some little
trees and I will say so
if somebody takes a job inside Redmond
ore Palo Alto that you're like not
totally not cool. with
um don't backstab them I'll probably be
back
it's a really small community yank don't
you know and make things on their future
shift also I don't criticize somebody's
technical solutions are working if
somebody's running the open source
project
through a system of complicated Excel
spreadsheet they don't want to be doing
that either
but it's currently working and don't
make it harder than it should be by
giving them a hard time about that
unless you're willing to fix it and I
got this from a tweet
about a year and a half ago money from
someone in this rain actually that
doing criticized other projects
site for the proprietary well have you
got a problem tonight it was pretty
don't blog or tweet about it
contact the project my kitty cat or just
don't say anything at all
when it's kinda tough Italy's top white
stuff but somebody made him mad like I
UK you could do something like that and
very lastly I'm if everything
does go horribly awry in you end up
feeling
light brownish come back yeah I take
some time away
take a few days off thirty something
different the comeback you always
welcome
say said nobody cares about how many
times you mess up
just he is always so long as you come
back and
also the very last thing you can do to
contribute
open source if everything else is too
much simply say thank you find at the
project I know
the project that you love hiya Pike on
what's in them
email these things always save people's
lives like in the Dark Knight when
you're lonely and sad then
you can wait look at that needle save
your life and that comes from people who
don't participate
so I'm if I do have a minute thing I do
I'm are personally have to say thank you
the Pythian divest grant I'm absolutely
would not be standing here
if it went to disarm because obviously
he hum
I'm have this conspicuous physical
difference and I never
came to conferences never ever I was
completely invisible in the shadows for
you like the best part ten years and
down
I was desperate to be involved community
but I would never ever turn up to attend
a conference
the for my first Pythian conference the
diet last a
registration had my finger hovered over
the button and I don't have any friends
going and I was like
not I'm not gonna go I just dying want
that feeling like
walking in and no way and then a couple
weeks later I got the email for the
diversity granite changed my world
site I just wanted to mention that and
say thank you
and thank you to you to the state
and animated you
cya placed I get Alice
hi a it's not that I have been made
contributions to open source but I
I think to ticket and get help aren't
too much too many
I am a 10 my problems a
with a contributing to open source is
that
back like four years ago I i try to make
a contribution
and they were total jerks that made me
back of
I'm since trying to come back little by
little but one of the problems that I
have is that
I don't know exactly what I like or what
I do well
wow that's a really interesting
point I mean in the open source
community like
for my day job I obviously helps things
that I do very well
but in I don't know how to translate
that too be useful to yeah I would I
think is that it
this in it the third part of that which
is papal site on
if you do have friends here or new
friends here all the conference %uh the
spring to coming out
often people iight mice the project I've
ever been involved with have come at a a
conference
rates and you just kind of an hair and
at the table and on
you know talks might full advert things
that you feel confident that you can do
and obviously by virtue of being in that
environment i
want you today say I'm
I don't know that's a strategy I'd
suggest an down you know have fun in
communities where people
I'm attend I cannot talk
meant went back in as much yes I did
have another comment haircut picky
I'm pretty terrified
the solvent thing and just getting into
it but yeah
care my worst i cant cuz I'm a little
bit
but it did I feel like I think it's easy
for me to make my table fixes and
spelling corrections but it's hard for
me to make that leap to
actually some code so like what do you
think
could help hang around just hair and
kicking ties and fix is in
become familiar first start talking to
people
am I sooner or later you'll find that
you wanna bite off more
it'll happen the other way around like I
you naturally you look
understanding up the projector working
on increase
and you just it will happen T an issue
just keeping you and you end up talking
a paper you
stott understand it better just by
having conversations right now to avoid
it I imagine say
hang in there and thank you yeah and
on kids stay in the community he'd hey
thanks for the tacos haha sand and ash
thank you for attending dome not attend
next time
I am cell get have projects are really
easy to contribute tokars
get-ups nice n meetings call cell what
about projects that are not get have
like have you had experience
contributing to them
and hell did you get overly I mean if
it's mercurial our SVN or something its
have a headache but other than learning
the toll-like is there any easier way
tear start learning the to live with to
find some
no ahead about how I mean I have to
mention the genetic you contribute to
the
clinics can this is absolutely
spectacular II pieces
for my other coaches on that Smith all
the patches by
email yeah exactly sell that stake thank
you like 30,000 miles a month its
spectacular
among cyanide fishing trawlers hot
stop it's a difficult problem thank you
already
thank for thanks for the tag group
greater absolutely you should get an
accurate on all the conferences ago
but the it's not a question its
a something I wanted to say that it
throughly cool to hang around
open source product at another the we
have this
supper channel for from simply log onto
and often people come to
honor to ask a specific question with
for their specific problem
but the days stay around a little bit
longer
and they see other people answering
questions
and later on when no no none of the
experts
I around some other comes and asks one
of the popular questions again
and they remember to ask her so they day
help those people yeah even though they
didn't really know five minutes before
yeah yeah
so that really works yes yes and that
there is a is a
one of the beauties ive I'm so thank you
for that comment that's excellent
say thanks sweetheart a-line not
reporting cycle
thanks to you talk Elena your passion is
absolutely incredible
as well as really appreciating the I am
to fly to get as much information to us
as possible that's awesome
thank you had obvious I as a quick
question about
I
you know because the open source
projects like observed pretty much
seem to be well hind engines they're
running you just say everyone kinda in
think
it's like a factory up a guy critical I
think misconception
lol me for pro-life observing us okay
gorgeous would reject had observed urban
a novelist narcotic seems like a
where do I insert my sock is everyone
seems to be conover you are running and
going to like nothing I said at the
beginning that's why I want there's one
other point on it might really strongly
really early
that there is a small number of projects
that happen like really tight and I'm
like exactly what you described love
serious professional dedicated committed
people
but most projects on-site you have two
strategies eighty you can handle is
really big project and he feel like
you're involved enough to contribute or
be involved with one another
other ones that pic some really obscure
thing that somebody just
smashed out one night and I probably
need everything for like now
they'll be desperate for your website or
documentation or
like feature feeling ano something like
that so I yet it depends on which
strategy prefer to imply that this
tons all the work that needs to be done
thank you
project
I can I may be on the whole to chat to
people more like I'd love to
talk to people in here tables
experiences thank you very much for
coming