the storm in welcome
Kate Helston she's going to talk about
how it is to be a full stack developer
I
hi everybody welcome I am so my name is
Kate huddleston
I'm a software engineer hell from San
Francisco California
that is a picture me and then also my
self portrait
I A do it because my mom decided
recently that she wanted to embroider
jean jacket for me with an image of a
computer girl
cell I was three jean jacket without on
the back if you want to find me later in
the conference
I so why am I getting the stock
I summit this presentation because I
I'm in applications developer and when I
started doing contract work
I had to manage the whole stack myself
and
am it turns up I than is usually part of
a much larger system
and when you come outside at the
application layer be it can be very
confusing
you can get lost there are a lot of
pieces and that's pretty much roughly
how I play Tetris as well as how I
program
I am so it can there's a lot of stuff
going on
and it's important to understand how the
system works as a whole
okay so what we're gonna talk about
today
I'm gonna walk you through a semi
typical web application
and I say semi typical because missus
computers in are always a lot of
different ways to do things
I'm gonna walk you through kinda the
system of systems which is
development staging and production
environments as well as deployed
and along the way I'm going to talk to
you about some helpful Python libraries
what we are not going to talk about
today
we are not going to talk about massively
scalable applications
so if you're looking to build something
like Google or Facebook or
understand those were not going to talk
about that today we're not gonna talk
about
every single insulation on the machine
there are things missing from this
presentation because I cannot cover
everything in 25 minutes and we're not
going to go into the nitty-gritty
details up anything
okay so
ASME typical web application how many of
you have heard
the term lamp a LAMP stack nice
I've actually never programmed a lamp
staff stacked specifically
but what it refers to is Linux Apache
mighty Quinn PHP in his/her kinda the
four core parts
love a and small for SAC web application
its key operating system which in this
case is 1x
the web server which is Apache the
database which is my sequel
and the application language which is
PHP however most of us here probably
don't program that sac WI
I program something like and Lynn limp
Ellen pp amor Linex
and an axe post crests paper so you can
change out the parts of this stack
um the next part of his presentation
I can either speaker or I can do in song
because I kind of came up with the theme
song one day was getting ready
so soon have a strong preference either
way
song okay I was kinda hoping and writing
that you would say that alright
its to the tune of the Brady Bunch theme
song
in alright its
the store even Evelyn xserver and that
was hosting a patchy in some Epsom
although them around in Python because
it's awesome
the smallest one with flask and is the
story
opposed to server that was busy with
some data
up its own it was clear these two should
come together
that's the way we build our first ball
sack web app both back where
about it boesak whereabouts at that's
the way we built our first full stack
lab after dun dun dun
hey mean the
yes you are free to laugh at me now
nothing
an but this actually had the right
content amazingly enough
being pretty as corny as it is it some
with all the parts %uh
a small full stack web application that
has operating system the web server
the application and the database and so
I'm if you take a look at these parts
the web server is what receives requests
and gives back responses
and annexin G unicorn or a patch in mud
whiskey are
typical tools that people use for their
web servers the application layer which
is where at
the a book up a lot of Engineers spend
most of their time
this is where frameworks like genuine
flask live Python libraries
severe front-end code maybe a static
files although those can technically be
served from anywhere
because they are static and then finally
our database
and a lot of people use relational
databases like post-crescent quell my
sequel sequel server
you can also use alternate dated
alternative data stores
like you value stores I'm such as red as
a Mongo DB
you can use those in conjunction with or
in love
a relational database people kinda do
either these days
so you start adding stuff to a small
web application now you've got things up
and running you have a website
it you know served by pages you might
have user authentication and
and things like that and so now you want
some logging you wanna know what's going
on you wanna know who's accessing about
application
and these can just live as log files on
the machine for now
because you have one server and it's
pretty small see just have maybe it's
unicorn access log
some Python logs whatever you also
probably have something for version
control
he probably don't just have cut hope
code hosted on this server
and so for version control people use
get an SPN
and they use get her orbit bucket to
host code repositories
but
so next now that everything's working
and running you have a web application
people come again
it you know does whatever it is that you
want your application to do you like I
wanna start sending and receiving emails
maybe I would like to send by users
newsletters or I would like to verify
the e-mail address when they
sign up for my site now you have to set
up an SMTP server
you can host this yourself or you can
use some other great services out there
for it
like postmark ap Sen grid Amazon s yes
and they have really great freemium
tears Mike 15,000 free
emails i still havent is the mall happen
so now you have your website sending
emails
doing other stuff but you realize as the
User is registering
can't put in there username password
email they had register
from these tasks are taking a long time
in the kinda blocking the UI
which is a bad experience for your user
you like I would like some %uh these
tasks to run in the background
like to kick them to an a synchronous
task service and you also might wanna do
some web crawling
so if you wanna go out and get data
across the web you might do that in the
background might wanna schedule tasks to
do that so there's a lot of things that
year
it thinking you might want to have run
in the background if your application
so setting up in a synchronous tasks to
some make sense now
it's important to note that a
synchronous tasks usually have some sort
of data store
that there on time so I could read s or
rabbit MQ
to store the tasks that you're running
so
things that people typically use Python
are accused a Python library for a
synchronous tasks and you can use a
readiness to store the tasks
am celery in route and he was also a
really really comment sack for this
I mention a synchronous frameworks
because there are a lot of talk Sep icon
about them
so twisted and tornado am and you guys
can go to the stocks if you wanna
learn more about that section okay
so you've got everything set up you can
run tasks in the background do but
calling you had a pretty Bell bust
what application now and you're starting
to have
some airs the people are emailing you
and you don't really know what's going
on sale like I should probably set up
some exception handling
am and right now exception handling can
just be emails
you have your SMTP server setup so every
time Python urging go throws an
exception
you can email yourself and know that
there's a problem see you can go in and
fix
is
writes this is where we're at this is a
a pretty small single server
web application I'm you have the other
services like version control in SMTP
server
but now we're gonna start pulling things
out in two separate services because
your web application is getting larger
it does not fit on one server doctor
database
has a lot of data in it now and it's
growing faster then
your web application and so you pulled
out into a separate server
so now you've got two servers here at
your front end server your database
server
and you have to make network calls to
database
see also do some math any realized that
there's someday to the people in the lot
that doesn't change very often and so
you can add any cash so that you don't
have to make this number calls and so
you can serve up the state a really fast
some typical things that people use for
caches are men cashed
reddest or varnish you'll notice read as
can be used for a lot of different
things
an monitoring
see you have logging an exception
handling but now you need more
monitoring you wanna know what's going
on you wanna know what the performance
looks like he one of your site goes down
so there it was like New Relic they do
great performance monitoring
am NOT geo stirs IT infrastructure
monitoring Pingdom will tell you if your
site is up or down
seeking a really delightful text message
at four in the morning that your website
is down and you have to fix it
because that's what I love doing it for
the morning
okay your synchronous tasks these are
growing
a lot is taking up a ton of the
processing power under single front end
web server
so you have to pull these out into a
separate server cancer right
the database you still kick past two at
the same way but you can scale that
independently now as well
exception handling is also growing as
you get more users
and %um our code you generally get more
exceptions although
hopefully not but probably so emails are
insufficient
you can use tools like sentry will give
a shout out to Senshi cuz I think David
came as here somewhere
that conference a and it will aggregate
your exceptions
and give you a lot of really great
information about the types of
exceptions that people are hitting
finally win a pole logging out into its
own service you can
either hosts your own log server or you
can use tools like locklear Splunk
when you have multiple servers running
you need to aggregate those logs across
the service otherwise you're gonna have
to log into each server
check the logs on the machine and thats
inefficient as you grow
so you an aggregate all the logs and you
wanna do some
public data mining on them to get useful
information on dove
user patterns another sub so ugly in
spunk will do that for you or you can
build it yourself
okay so be sure to point that out in two
separate services but
your web traffic is growing even more so
one front end web server
is not sufficient miss restart to have
two or more
servers the load balancer in front the
load balancer
world will kick your traffic and across
the web servers they can also talk to
the same database the same a synchronous
task servers
and to the user books like the same
website but you can now skillet
as your traffic grows you still have all
these other services by the way
that you need to manage and remember and
login target Ashburton take a look at
and then the final step for our web
server is
database replication so you don't want
any single point of failure
you might actually have done this
earlier but you can set up a master
database
never replicate to a slave database if
you master goes down or something bad
happens you then have a backup that you
can fail over to
you can also do cool stuff like right
data into the master and read of %uh
read slates
at this point you might also have
multiple servers here a synchronous
tasks cuz if you're doing a lot of web
calling getting a lot of data
you're gonna need multiple service for
that and so you can scale them
independently
so this is a pretty robust small to
medium-size web application
at this point you probably can't manage
it all alone
to be totally honest especially if you
have the web but traffic that justifies
multiple servers
and all that okay next up
the system of systems so the storyline
happens at the same time as the
storyline that I was just talking about
at some point in building your
production web server
you realize that you can't edit the code
on production
well people are hitting at so production
represent everything that we just talked
about all the stuff down into one tiny
box
so you build out a development
environment where you can write code
tested and other stuff before you do a
very simple deployed tear production
machine
thing about that is that you want to be
as close as possible to production
if not the exact same and there are some
tools to help you do that
if you have a Mac or usable until Fri
operating system
you can use the end in the end rapper
locally to set up a
environments that have all the paper
cancellations if you use Windows
or you want really really exact replica
of production
you can use a vagrant and VirtualBox to
create VM's
that have the exact operating system and
installations
up production so those are really great
tools for that
deploy this point might be really simple
it might just be a get push
gonna get pole tier one server and
restart services
this will not scale down but this is a
place to start when you have one server
alright so now you've written tests like
a developer
but you want that to be automated you
want to have automated testing running
so that you know your tests are passing
before you ever pushed to production
so you had an attesting where in you can
use Jenkins circle CI Travis CI
these are tools that will help you run
your tests on a medically either
periodically
or every time you push to your get help
repel
finally you are you've reached the state
to the size we have more than just you
working on your code base which is
awesome so now you have buddies which
means you have multiple development
environments one for each of the O
this means that you probably need a
staging environment
you don't want each developer pushing
straight to production you kinda wanna
put all the co 2 one place
make sure it's all working make sure all
the automated tests are running
and then deploy to production so
staging is gated by testing still would
be but you have multiple Devin moments
at this point it's important to note
that you have see you have basically
three sets environments production
staging in development
you want these all to be identical you
don't want any surprises
in higher code runs see you hitting the
point where you probably
need automatic server configuration you
don't wanna log into every server
install everything
you wanna be able to create new machines
that are exact replicas of the old ones
immediately so if your front end web
server goes down and he decided to kill
it you can just spin up a new one start
all the processes
and it up and running and deploy is also
probably getting more robust at this
point if you have multiple machines in
production
you can't log into each machine and
update your code to see you need some
tool
to help you deploy across multiple slurp
server simultaneously
so there are a bunch of tools for server
configuration there are talks
on puppet in Sabal salt and docker
at this conference and chef is another
tool
these tools can also be used for deploy
often lot of them have
features for helping you deploy across
many different machines
no akin to its also has a really awesome
talk later today
specifically on the ploy estimate there
%uh
so if you're interested in this topic
you should definitely got his talk
up finally at this point if you have
multiple development environments
you might need some automation around
creating development environments your
some scripts
or if you use vagrant in VirtualBox to
create p.m.
you can use a lot of the server
configuration tools like chef and puppet
to configure those local VMs which is
really useful because then you know that
it's an exact replication up production
and also you can automate the the
scripts for that
the final level up systems of systems is
when you start pulling things and
production out into multiple services
so let's say that your code base for the
front end web application is different
from the code base
free a synchronous tasks those are
separate services
separate code bases you're gonna have
multiple development and staging
environments
they're all gonna work the same they're
gonna you know
aggregate things on stage into automated
testing and deploy but you don't have to
deploy two separate code bases
this is actually a good thing because
its code bases
smaller and more manageable and makes it
easier for you to play
Co changes because there's no such thing
as a small change to a large system
my haircut write some notes on hosting
I don't talk about this earlier but if
you decide to manage all the things that
I talked about
now yourself you're gonna need to host
your server somewhere
you can either buy a giant server and
put it in your basement
I love the 90's or you can host it are
someplace like a.w.s
Rackspace aurélie note
if you decide that you would like to man
to love the stuff yourself
i'm for talk last year I set up a
starter chef repository for configuring
a single server with
and an ex post grass rad/s and a couple
other things in this is up to date
see you can go Brian that and you can
have a web server up and running really
quickly
if you decide you do not wanna host I
love this yourself which
I do not blame you for there are a
couple tools out there some platform as
a service providers
that will do everything for you olive
the server configuration
all the installations security scaling
and her local do this for you they're
great Elastic Beanstalk
is Amazon version of this in a slow
behind her a good doesn't have quite as
many features but
I know they're working on it so these
tools are fantastic
I also made it as some party favors an
so all the things we talked about I put
into maps
and I put them in get home so if you
wanna take a look at any of these
resources that we talked about today in
one place
I don't expect it to be able to read
these by the way 'em
you can see there's the web server
and you know some other typical tools
that people use these are by no means
all the tools just a starting point am
for the application layers a bunch of
Python libraries
a buncha Python dev tools am DB libras
kinda fun stuff you may want to use
there's also that local dev tools
testing server configuration and deploy
see nafta member other stuff
there's whole buncha maps via I also I
did something really fun
I'm a damn a map evolve the talks the
pike on and where they live in the stack
so if you wanna do a deep dive in any
part love this
them stacked that I talked about here's
where I love the talks live
once again I don't expect you to be able
to read this but you can see there are a
couple of talks
on web servers and there's a bunch talks
on databases database library is
optimizing post grass
and there's a bunch of talks in a
synchronous tasks but mostly a
synchronous framework so
them tornado twisted
am monitoring there are a couple talks
on
monitoring application the book at the
talks at this conference are
in the application layer because python
is commonly used as
an application where code are
language and there's the Python core
talks kinda like how does Python work at
its core
there some talks on the front end
frameworks in Orem layers and database
libraries machine learning data
has a bunch a good stuff in here and
then finally
there a couple of talks on security a
bunch of talks on testing
and a bunch of talks on server
configuration and deployed
finally they're a bunch of talks that
while technical do not fit
in that the stack that I made a South at
that tournament they're just so that you
know that there are other
talks I didn't want them to feel left
out
threaten so the three major takeaways
from the stock
hopefully you know what are the basic
pieces a full stack
if nothing else I hope that you remember
the song and using it to yourself
I apologize but not really if the brady
bunch song stuck in your head for the
rest of the day
and second what are these pieces look
like in different environments so
devastating production
deployed and I'm some resources for
learning more
and and going forward so the maps
have the different parts the stack and
some other resources that people use
so that you can do research and get up
and running when you wanna do one other
things that I talked about
already so time for questions and if
anyone's terrified of getting up at the
microphone asking questions which
by the way i think is way more
terrifying than presenting you can find
me afterwards
or you can find me and for the rest the
conference
job thank you
hi I want to mention Charlie about how
to test
they have a sis arm so yeah how the how
do you um
replicated that because it's so
difficult into replicated database like
Indian
staging and the test oh yeah
test data test data that's a big area
com that is a really good question that
a lot of people are trying very hard to
solve
I some other common things people do as
they create scripts for test data
I know that there are services out there
I don't know the names of the top of my
head that will help you create
kind of development data because
oftentimes you can't
test on production data it either
sensitive arts too large
and thinking about those after to take a
look at them afterwards but now that's
that is a good question in a really hard
thing to the left
and you talked briefly about web servers
but maybe elaborate a little bit on the
differences between weapon whiskey
servers and how the interplay
um yeah a little bit so
the the sack but I mentioned is like and
an axe and Unicorn is a really common
stock
so engine x's a reverse proxy you can
actually serve up
pretty much anything from and annex even
serve up static files from a different
location
but it will also listen on port secure
servers and so you can use
G unicorn which is are always capitation
that will serve a pure Python code
specifically to engine action so they're
listening to each other
and so with Apache you need mod whiskey
or something similar to it
and they have to work in tandem but you
can actually switch them out you can use
engine X with
you there's you whiskey and a couple of
other tools
so that's that's vaguely how it works
thank you
new dimension fabric as a way for it
deploying into in eyes it
is it because you don't use it to the
recommend it or in
I didn't %uh there's a lot of things
they did not mention the stock by the
way
there are a lot of other tools out there
I didn't go really deep into the play
cuz I do think that now has a fantastic
talk on that
and he talks about fabric he talks about
you know selling tar files over to
different servers
com so he does really add up there are a
lot of ways to deploy
deploy is also a really challenging
problem to solve and so that's something
that you can you can do very simply
and very manually which is what I
illustrated by like get pushing in get
polling and it's not necessarily a
production recommendation
but it's possible to do that manually
and that simply but
as you grow and you have many many
servers it becomes very challenging to
deploy across all those servers
at the same time and so I'm I would
recommend going to Noah's talk because
he will tell you all about it
hi arm I attending her love like like
that legacy Python code
and the law and i've seen on love
previous developers where they said
run the in bill Python web server Anna
production date is run on Pacha engine X
nominee what what would you recommend
when you fall look for local productions
look feel local dive so do you like you
run it on the local populace
rely on local local llama I web server
yeah that's entirely up to you it and I
think and how much you want to be
testing in your development environment
so if you have a staging environment
that is an exact replica production
there's some things that you can be
maybe a little more lax about with your
development environment just use kinda
like a local Python
observer so that's what I do and I
double check that everything works in
staging before I ever deployed to
production
if you just have to have an production
you have a really small system
am anyone everything to be the exact
same you can
if neither saw all those things locally
or mention vagrant
bigger as a really awesome tool for
setting up the items that are exact
replications a production on your local
machine
see other local the am running and you
can have patchy and all that different
stuff installed
thanks
hey I'm
I was wondering if you could sing
another song 3 how
sadly I do have more spontaneous the
I I was curious you mention a few
synchronous frameworks that if you use
like twisted in tornado
I'm wondering light water use cases
within your full stack
um environment would you use that poor
arm
that is an excellent question I don't
use wesun tornado much
their com their fairly complicated in my
opinion
and really advanced is the chat servers
and things like that you know people use
twisted for I don't personally have a
use case my building up my bells and
whistles web applications for them
but that I imagine there are a bunch of
talks
at this conference on twisted and
tornado people who are experts will tell
you more about it
I am definitely not an expert on either
one of us thanks
Kate thank you again
thank everyone