it who will be doing and intro to doctor
talk on police give me a hand
and let's get started
thank you
I am hello everyone welcome to the and
FactoryTalk
on doctor as Carlos mention my name is
on jet
I go by I'm just are on Twitter but on
so I work for a company called New Relic
and p
we use doctor in Maine town project I
mean explain a very specific example
where we use it and how we
sawdust particularly hairy problem but
more on that
latter I I want to set the stage for
why do we want to learn about doctor why
is it important why is it worth your
time
so but skip started explaining a typical
web stack it
you know you have a Dr front-end server
Apache in Jackson
backend server like unicorn you is key
are model is she I
and then your engine go on top of that
its
not it doesn't stop right there i mean
you have a database which could be
possible as much equal and then you're
catching layer and your
background task manager and you know if
you're in you're a customer than you
have your elective monitor all these
different pieces an
if you have if you happen to be a full
stack developer
you could be modifying any of these
layers and
come deployment I'm you check everything
you run your unit ass everything works
great you run it on your local machine
to make sure that you know you haven't
broken anything and everything looks
great looking confident and then you
start rolling out a deployed
half an hour later you find out that
none of your customers are able to pay
so you her really roll everything back
and then you know try to start debugging
and that can be anywhere from looking at
La Paz to trying to reproduce a
production environment by Ian on
exactly matching the minor version of
your engine access to Jane Doe and
and trying to recreate the problem and
you know but half a day later you find
out that there is an environment
variable that you forgot to set in a
production environment
on does that sound familiar to anyone at
all up good
I'm not the only one and so doctor is
supposed to solve this problem in a very
unique way
and the way it handles this as your
double up man environment will be
exactly the same as a production in my
mind the reason for that is because
whatever you double up n
will be the one that actually gets
deployed in production and I'm gonna
show you how that
how you could do that and in and we'll
look at
a lot of different features a doctor up
before we actually get started
I'm bar before we jump into that I want
to start by answering a very simple
question what is doctor
I since this is a technology conference
I presume no one's here thinking it's
about Dockers the trousers company rain
by lot at this point to face as well
Irish you put them one leg at a time
and unless you're Superman please wear
the underwear inside
on any yeah I understand skidding
I doctor is an internal project that was
started by Doc cloud
and in 2013 so it's ups at a fairly
young project but
it has a very active community around
they died in fact the project was so
wildly successful the company actually
perverted and change their name to
doctor and
and and it's a project that's written in
go arm
and as a mention it it has a very active
community which is very welcoming and
helpful
I this is a definition taken straight
outta Dockers website that says doctors
and open source engine the bottom its
deployment of any application
as a lightweight portable self
sufficient container
that will run virtually anywhere when
they say virtually anywhere they mean
in Linux machines and and
had to make it even come get a in modern
Linux machines with the recent kernel
now but apart from that the definition
is actually
pretty good actually it's a it's a
fairly accurate description of what
doctor does
on if your family or with see a true
Derby St jailed
and or solarz owns the doctor is a
similar technology which provides an
boxing for a process as you are
it allows you to run your process in a
little sandbox on
that doesn't you know interact with
outside of its container and
and other things p so
doctor for this particular sandboxing
and uses latex containers
annex containers have been in the Linux
mainline kernel for about five years I
think
and so it's a very stable technology
that they're using
and doctor is in is a interface on top
of that that makes easy for you to
interact with the Xanax containers
and in addition to just you know being a
and be sitting on top flex containers
also provides some additional features
that makes it easy to use which is
a union filesystem on which we'll see
what it means in a little bit
on and you know nice version
system kind of like get but not quite as
powerful I am
and a REST API that allows you to
interact with the doctor
I am to contrast this with a with a
virtual machine
you have to bare metal on which a runner
host operating system and you know you
run VMware or VirtualBox
switches are high priced earlier and
then you install a full guest operating
system inside of that which is you know
been to our centaurs anything
and you know but multiple libraries in
in Django and
and then you run your happens out of
that now if you want to create another
one of these instances in a different
box then you have to go through the same
process
even in the same box you have to go
through the same process of actually
installing the guest operating system
are
you know launching a whole nother
snapshot of existing VM
which can be quite expensive and kinda
resource-hungry
comparing that to a doctor container he
had a bare-metal
and you hope Coast Guard operating
system which is Linux in this case
and if you install doctor then doctor
sets as a demon that runs on your
machine
and any time you launch a container gets
launched from
image well we'll get into that
terminology definition of what I images
and in just a minute but
it launches the image and multiple
containers can share the same library
because it it has a read-only lehrer as
soon as one is container start modifying
that
library then it creates cake a a
separate snapshot of that
and only the dips other doctors are
stored so that's that
advantage of having the Union file
system which allows you to
do these copy on write I am tight type
operation
so containers are very light weight
because they share the kernel with the
underlying operating system
it provides you the isolated instance
that you'll get from
running actual virtual machine am
because from inside a container it looks
as if you're inside a VM
but outside of a container it looks as
if you're just another processor just
you know its really that simple and a VM
even the stripped-down bare minimum
Linux machine takes
at least five seconds if you're a lucky
but container can start up in under a
second
on sometimes and just milliseconds
so I so that's the advantage of of arm
doctor now I'm not going to go into the
to the steps on how to get
doctor installed on your machine and it
started because they do a very good job
on that documentation and Dockers
website
but i just want to briefly touch however
run doctor on OSX because they keep
talking about it
you do use Linux containers if you are
in the net on a Linux machine then
you when you install doctor you get two
components the Dockers
a demon component in a doctor's plan
component and it runs on your host
operating system
and your client talks to the doctor a
demon and you write you get to you know
large containers and create images and
so on
if you are on OSX like mine then there
is a product called due to doctor
which is a very minimal Linux machine
like 25 megabytes
I that allows you to run doctor just had
just the bare essentials to get back up
and running
and %uh there is always explain so what
I do is
bouta doctor automatically launches a
tough one on VirtualBox in which it runs
its Linux and then a doctor demon runs
in Sarawak so
all the our stuff but I'm about to show
you will be happening in that particular
setup
I so I mentioned sewed and entries
couple after marge is here and then
we'll
will introduce from large ass we keep
going a doc sold I mentioned doctor has
two components:
the server component a client component
and
did the server component to the demon
has to run on a Linux machine
and it talks to plans into is one is
using a Unix socket
if the client happens to be in the same
machine or at through a TCP socket if
the client is on a different machine
on from different machines you can talk
to it through the TCP socket there are
plans available for Linux boxes or and
less action
you can use them to to talk to Anna
demand that's running in a
in a separate Linux machine let
time for a quick demo
let's look at what to what I have here
installed
so I have a client version installed
Anna how the doctor sir version
installed
and I want to just get started by
using a particular image and I can start
playing around with it now
if I'm pulling so what I'm doing here is
a sampling an image
from the registry an I am throwing out
some terminology such
I'm going to get back muscle and explain
what those are
and image is a read-only snapshot of
your on it's a read-only snapshot and a
container
is a instantiation of this image what
this means as
say you you're reading a master's thesis
and you spent two years you put together
an awesome pieces you sit there and you
type one letter at a time
and create a master copy and you're
about to give it your professor
you're not going to sit there and type
out the entire thesis again just to give
it a professor just gonna make a
photocopy and send it to him
and you can't make as many photocopies
as you want and a professor can happen
and turn make modifications in on strike
out certain things in
I do margin notes and highlights and
things like that but that's not going to
factor master copy
and it's not going to affect other
professors copies either
it's completely localized to that
professors copy
I am so this is the idea behind images
and container so and image
is something that you put together which
is kinda like the master copy reinstall
it alive a reason you create your in my
sector in my memory Abel's either
project files and do
all other stuff and when you're ready to
run that image
you instantiate a container sky like
instantiating and object from a class
and i'd get started it starts running
your container might start adding lock
files or something but that
those like funds will be contained
inside the container it's not going to
go back to the image in its on appleyard
other containers that are running
so this is completely contained I am in
the container
any they are been that or staff I
so a registry is kind of like the Python
package index
where you have a collection of Ubuntu
different projects that people have
pushed
and I'm going to pull a specific image
arabs registry and start playing around
with it
now repositories are just products in
this registry so
if registries can I get have been a
repository is your project repo
am and so it's just a collection of
images Europe our story
gay sampling and image I called base
you now if I do doctor images this
lists all the images that I have been my
local repository
even though I pulled a single image
there's four entries here at
sorry about the the though the point
being too great but
on it showing for images but if you
notice there are they all had the same
image id: so they're all the sex act the
same images but just different actually
happen to be
named latest Ubuntu went to quantal in
will do with her
quantal the typo a
help so that's that's how you list all
the images in your
and in your local registry dock appears
as a command that you use to look at the
containers that are currently running
and since we have been launched in
containers dock appears doesn't give us
anything it's potentially right now
so let's launch a container so what I
the way you do that
is you said doctor run and then give it
image name
and then given a program that you want
to run in the container that you're
about to launch
so in this case was echo hello even
though the below that printer in my
terminal
actually ran inside the container and
then it came back
doctor p- is still gives me nothing the
reason is because as soon as the process
is done
the containers jobs over and so it
stopped and dock appears we only give me
and containers are act actively
currently running
so let's run something a little bit
longer so I am going to do
a infinite loop sorry about that
and okay
but did not work well
okay
so Iran an infinite loop that was
pending hello multiple times
and this tied up my terminal
because I'm running it in the foreground
you can also run in the background which
is
the demon mode where you
do the same exact command with the dash
d option
what that means is it runs the command
in a in a container and put it in the
background
when you run this it just gives your
shot I D so let's see what doctor PS
doses
doctor PSA's that there is a container
that is currently running
with the command that is why the true
and it's pretty long
and that's the shower idea man a copy
that one and run doctor logs on it
doctor logs lets me see what is the STD
out that is currently in the container
so this is how you can inspector
currently running container to see what
is actually doing
okay that's a brief description of
images and containers and how you can
run them there's another way that you
can run which is the interactive mode so
the only command here that only changer
as I do a dash
I and the Dashti so I say is I'm running
10 tracked in morning batch D is
I'm not at my current TTY to this
particular happen and I'm about to run
in here when I run L as actually get
group permissions had a container so
inside a container as I mention it looks
exactly like a new fresh BM
so I have all the whole file system
available in and
on a ring for mean but when I run PS
there is nothing running inside that
because that and it will only thing
that's running is bash with what I
started this particular container
so that's the advantage of having a
container which can
on which can have its minimal processes
running in fact okay
I am let's mess around a little bit so
I am so this particular container and
modifying a bunch of things inside
by installing a couple of
am programs an because you know who
doesn't like
fortune-telling cow so let's try
try that so I just installed fortune
and cow say in my machine and Mike out
ultimately pork
that's nice am okay
so we saw that I modified certain things
and how to the container
no copies container shots gonna come in
handy little bit later
but again the dock appears doesn't show
me that the content is running because
when I exit onto the container container
has stopped
but it is not destroyed it's still just
summer sleeping
I am I still have the infinite love
running I'm gonna stop that
am so the way you do that is using
doctor stop
and and back is gone so that's how you
stop a runny container for for
for container goes arm yeah keeps get
running then you can just stop it like
that
okay let's get back to something
else so as I mentioned the container
that I messed with
does not translate back to the image the
original image because as a master copy
to prove
let's start another in track to command
and launch it from base
now if I try a fortune the command is
not found
so that was actually localized to only
that containers or whatever I modified
and ap and install that was in not going
to know that I
on I I stopped so
as I mentioned that shoddy comes in
handy because after you've created a
container and you've changed a bunch of
things inside a bit if you want to
create an image out of it because you
know
you brought it to just how you wanted
then all you have to do is take the shot
I D
use the comic command and given a new
name and now a fire and doctor images
I see the fortunate cow p
with the new image ID because files a
change in sight
so now if I run fortunate Cal
and check whether I have my fortune
and I do feel like it's mocking me but
but I hate
I have fortune so that's how that's how
you can create
a image out of an existing container I
am
mentor news1 other command call tag
what this does is it it creates
a tag it gives a different name for an
existing image to prove that it is
existing image
you notice they have exact same image
id: I just give it a new name
and called it and it slashed pace
towards the reason I put 100 there's big
at there's a reason for that because
this is how
you push to the registry if you want
your image to be available for
everyone else to download and use
then you can do that so this is your
registry
is how the registry looking into a
container surgeons and others and
other things I am but I think my push
has probably done yeah it was probably
done and if I go in here
and look at it there's the new 1i just
pushed
so that's how you can share things with
with people that too mom but want to
share images okay
so let's get back to the presentation
and get going
to introduce registries repositories
weeks I want to basic commands
how to pole less images run years logs
he has no other stuff
I but those are created by with by
Hannah you have to type in one at a time
and if someone else wants to recreate as
I mean you have to either give them the
image or tell them how you created the
image in the first place
I whereas doctor file allows you to do
automate all the stuff
here's an example for doctor far so the
says from the base image so you're using
an
base image as your starting point you
can use the in me to set an environment
variable
use add to the add local files from your
machine into the
images and run a bunch commands while
you're creating this image as
a step-by-step process so the apt-get
update an apt-get install
will happen automatically and CMD
command is actually interesting so every
time I do the doctor run
you'll notice that I had a program at
the end if you don't if you ignore the
program if you completely amid the
program's
then and this is the default program
that will get launched
I'm its nixon
here's the doc file
and the way you build that is say doctor
bill Dashti
Dashti is basically saying I want to
give it a new name
and doctor file is located in the
current folder I run that
it it actually installed everything and
now if I Brun there we go
so without a command I am it
automatically launches the commander
defined in my doctor for
okay
so so far we've just been looking at him
playing out playing with Linux stores
and things like that but
if you want to run a django application
you can you can create a doctor file
that sets up jingle for your insider
that had your project files into all-out
some sort of thing
on and export support and and you know
it'll
exposing a port basically means opening
a port in your container I
do all that and let's say you larger
container dodd
as I mentioned the containers completely
isolated if you open a port
eight house in and start listening on
that using django then that 8,000 is
actually not available
to your host machine it's only available
for that in that container
the way you can map your host machine
sport
to your containers port as using the
dash b.com
dash be option so you just a dash be
eight thousand colin White House and
then
adult automatically mapped the
containers 8,000 with the local machine
de pasion
that networking stuff there a couple of
other
and quick feet as I wanna go over which
is Walliams allows you to
mount a volume from their host machine
into your container there are
multiple different options that you can
do it Williams like
amount Williams between containers and
things like that but out for simplicity
sake I was gonna keep it
I'm simple where you can mount something
from the host machine into your
container
and anything you right into a container
will be available on the host machine
any changes you make in host will be
available on a container and you it
allows you to do read only mountain
I read write and all that stuff links is
a simple
service discovery so let's say you have
a compare that's running my sequel and a
container that's running
Django how's this Django going to know
what's the IP address and port number
that's available
for it to contact my sequel because
every time a new container gets created
a new IP address get assigned to read
I doctor automatically takes care of you
know which is now available IP address
and it assigns it for you
so the way you do that is use the
National Inc option
and that tells you that my sequels on
IP address and port number will be
injected into my doc I and my Django's
container as in man in variables so you
just designer Jane obligation to look at
these good credentials from an honorable
and you're good to go
and that briefly mention rest a beer you
can use it to pool images
good list containers I shipyard is
actually a project that
agenda project allows you to do all that
things are shown in command line from
your browser actually I'm exactly
prequel
the way we use it at New Relic on if you
guys don't know what we do
we you installer software read operation
performance monitor so you install are
softer on your server we collect
performance metrics and we send them to
our server
now we do this for I am all these
different libraries
I actually I think this is part of it
there's a lot more but
I had slight Stanford on anyway
trying to and do integration test would
mean like I need my sequenced in the
post-crescent stanza
a reticence densmore and memcached
different versions of Django
different versions a flask in all these
different things this was getting quite
hairy in our integration tests can only
run in Jenkins it cannot be runnin
locally the way we saw that was we put
everything in sight of a container
and on you can have different kinds of
versions for these different things my
so-called emergence will have it on
containers
I am and if I made some changes to the
Django instrumentation than I will start
a container with Django happens at a fan
which automatically has links so all
these different services will be
injected in
as a non rebelled and I just have to go
through integration
pasts locally and if I made some changes
to
cherry pie flask whatever it is all
these can be run locally and it is all
available
and ready to go I does actually made our
integration tests faster on Jenkins
because now we can run in parallel
since they're completely isolated from
each other on so we just rode some basic
simple
bash scripts to get get this thing
going. at actually works really well
I am so coming back to the original
problem so
power how would you solve your foot
October and things like
breaking being breaking changes happen
all time
the way you can solve this is put them
in containers
you're my sequel can be in its own
container your application stack in its
own different container
and each of your services can be in
separate containers
any time you make a change you're making
an your change in a specific container
and since containers are dirt cheap
you can actually run them on a dev
machine it's not like you are starting
up a whole the am in like
working inside of our a crippled I
machine or anything like that
and up if you want you can mount your
local machines
a a folder as your host I am as Williams
and it'll be completely available for
you so you can
do your government push to prod well
it's not quite as simple
and you probably want to push it to
registry and then from there you can
push to prod
but you know the registry doesn't have
to be the Public Register everyone can
see it i mean there are private
legislate commercial offerings are
available or
on you can actually host your own
private industry locally on your machine
there's like
Django Rob Dhaka registered to search
for and get open you can find that
real easily I am there is a really good
community
there's on IRC and 10 cochran actually
is doing a poster session
very friendly guy known just ask
questions to him
I am I think that pretty much concludes
my talk on I think I'm ready for
questions now
and can get if anyone has any questions
please go to the mic microphone over
there
so I'm kinda Shilpa I'll go and throw it
out there for your
I debugging how do you go about doing
that with doctor I
so so there are different level to be by
so
the the logs that I showed are a pretty
good example of what I something is
going
wrong inside of it now typically now
what we do is we tried to run SSH
demand also in that mean in a in a
container so if something is going on
and we want to go uninspected began as a
such into the container and
start to see what's what actually
changing the other thing that
we do is drop down one level I wanna
wear down where there's
alexi dash attached to mandatory level
so you can alexi data that if you don't
have SSH running in the container
because you want to keep your container
absolutely minimal I'm
but you could still do alexi data
pageant it puts you into interactive
mode
in the container and you can stay I'm
start messing around with their lock
files take a look at it and see you
home what what's actually going on so
those are some tips i have
if you need to have
different configuration for your
production environment like say you want
to turn off
debugging and have different you know
maybe you have replicated servers in
production
if you're using the same image on
development and production how do you
account for the differences between
those two environments
so that's a very good question so I
forgot to mention that there is a
staging environment
that is involved and in our actual
production deployment so
week not only as a friend ERATION
testing we actually use it in some parts
of our production
other doctor tells is not to use it to
100 hours you know
reached I but you know we like living on
the edge
anyway and the way we do that
is your steady environment should be I
have very very closely replicated with
your production my man and the way we do
this
and is after we we create our images
we push it to our Jenkins over an urgent
concern over actually changes all that
my memory will according to how the
production environment a bitch set up
and then add runs all its integration
tests on that exact image so whatever
the image
as will be the one that actually gets
deployed eventually so we run our
forecasts
I with how the the containers will be
and
with a ship from so animal fat helped
can
doctor be used to run untrusted code any
safe manner
as a sandbox I yeah I think that
was the intention for doctor so the way
it I mean it is a complete sand a
sandbox environment so you can run
something and
and there are a couple of features that
are kind of back which is you can rest
trip how much memory that the
container can consume and I a ton of
Cebu can restricted that something
you can look up on the documentation but
you can in fact be on
run your fork bomb inside and see if
it'll are if it'll
bring down host or not try high airway
rum
burned a python shop and we're using
doctor in production
I'm on the edges a yeah
but now we're still trying to figure out
the best way to
deploy a bike requirements files appear
they go in the doc file relieve
menopause human
relationship between you like irma
Curiel repository in
and virtual environments we don't really
need retrovirus a more were darker but
do you have any suggestions for best
practices on
moving from traditional virtual
environment and Pepe requirements
and checking out the latest for
development verses
tonight and doctor and we still use
virtual environment actually
because it's just easier to do well I
guess you don't need russian mom is an
art to pip
bash are requirements are txt but now we
just still have it in our
on environment but the so we actually do
it at the image creation step we don't
do it inside a book and i got to the
container has launched so that you know
the
deploy process is literally just take on
move the image into the production
system and they're like
you know launcher contain out of it so
that happens at the bold step
and on sorry I we still how r
how r on requirements as part of their
repository and then backed by the jury
as a whole gets added into the
image and then we run a bunch a
different cast
are steps to set up the image and
finally create a container for
I'm sorry we don't have time for one
more question
and not really a question docker does
support CPU shares
and highly recommend checking out take
it pittance all poor thing
for really get to work with them
environment
call thank you I would not have time
thank you very much
RV camper ended and