alright their last speaker in this
session
aged James Bennett he's gonna be talking
about the good parts for Django
hi
okay so I know you're all anxious to get
a lunch fortunately there aren't that
many good things in Django says won't
take very long
I'll but with quick introduction my name
is James Bennett
I am wanna be release managers for
Django used to work
at the Lawrence journal-world I which
the company Django originally came out
of
I've been involved with Django
for quite some hi not as long as Django
has existed though
are the initial public preview event
which I remember downloading and playing
weapon falling in love with I was in
July 2005
so we're looking at you know about nine
years
I love Django releases growing adding
code adding
features what is Django look like today
well we just did be 1.7 beta 160 01923
lines of Python
I was the count but I got outta that
Django is now you now
we will call it a full stack frame
workers we have
well a full stack all of these things
request and response and template hangin
or abdomen forms authentication and it
just keeps going and going and going to
have this huge
Lister features om Django can now be
literally described as the 800-pound
gorilla up the pipe on web framework
world
a title that I believe we've claim from
so
by growing enough bananas at them to
blow up the building Iran
cell this raises the question
aren't other frameworks smaller
or later or better or more flexible
in Django what is that the Django still
have
still dollars that makes it a good
choice so wanna talk about
three thanks mainly the
good parts of Django first 1i want to
talk about is gonna be
HTTP abstractions majengo provide
and the way Django handles the GDP and
your request response cycle
second is the conservative and yes I do
mean that word
conservative approach to adding features
third and finally our secret weapon
you know amongst our weapons are
surprises phiri fanatical devotion to
the pope
and the django application to something
we'll talk about it a few minutes
the first let's talk about HTTP HTTP
sucks when I love for that
okay AG DB has some problems
as in nineteen different request methods
god only knows how you keep track of all
of them and what options go
with them it is completely and
hilariously unaware that
unico it exists om persistence and often
streaming and security
and all these other things that we care
about here in 2014 work I know
either never added were attacked on
all maybe we should do that ten years
later
the chief be really kinda sucks is a
protocol to work with and traditionally
if you wanted to rate programs that
spoke HTTP
you wrote CGI CGI
is also not a lot of fun of here's
in phiri in phiri if you were to really
CGI tutorial this is what i would tell
you
would tell you that you're going to
write a script the web server is going
to set up all her quest information
environment variables
and then invoke your script your script
is also going to receive any submitted
data from the request over a standard
input your script will be in
read the environment figure out what's
going on read the standard input figure
out what's going on
do its processing and then on standard
output
send out your response headers and your
response body who here believes that
this is how CGI
actually works in the real world
notice not allow to happen that's a good
thing here's a CGI actually works
first of all you hope and pray that the
web server will actually invoke your
script it may or may not
at some point you're going to type a
command looks like this
you're not going to understand why
and if you don't get why you're doing
that ask someone who has a very very
large
beard to explain what that means
the environment you're going to be had
by your web server is full of a lives
and sadness and things that are going to
make you
upset at some point you're finally just
going to give
up on trying to figure out what you were
always requested because that
information could be in any have
multiple different environment variables
and you're just going to try to four mom
server after which she will finally
completely give up and start drinking
this is how
real programmers really do CGI I have
done this for a living
now fortunately in pipe on we don't have
to rate CGI
we write is key unfortunately whiskey is
basically CGI done
hi
I realize now some people may not like
you're in whiskey criticized
having a standard is important whiskey
is our standard gateway interface
but number one
it is the CGI style programming model
your hand in an environment
you are expected to parse and understand
what is in that environment
rather than behan handed any kind
normalize data
which means that your entire whiskey
stackhouse do parse that environment
okay now we pass it this component which
has to reporter said
with past data backup on Chester
reporter said and you listen up with
this massive parsing an environment
there
really was never that good have a
programming model pic
second whiskey doesn't really have any
way for different components to
communicate with each other in a
standardized way
you have to go and either invent your
own things that you stick in the
environment and hope something else
doesn't trample on them
or you have to go invent an out-of-band
signaling process
the way you return HEB responses from
whiskey sucks
as far as I know even people who really
love with you agree with me on this
and finally it inherits a cheap VPS
willful blindness to the fact that
character set other than Latin
one might exist somewhere arm
this is the real problem you'll run into
you the spec on whiskey actually
I don't remember exactly but it does on
pipe on three on pipe on
who you are required to return a byte
string
containing only com ISO 8859
dash 1 code points for a lot of things
and be
whiskey rat model actually checks you
passed exactly
the type stir not any subclass or
functionality
added to it cell
can we do better s yes we can
we can do much better so let's get
better let's start with HTTP request
let's have a class called HTTP request
let's have it already parson normalize
everything for you
let's have a have all the things you
wanted access now available as
attributes with dictionaries for things
like the queer history
for the post data but actually handle
character encoding any sane and
consistent way
so a programmer doesn't have to worry
about that when they're right your
application code
now we've got a request to a response
let's make each EP responses really easy
to construct and play with
let's not fool around with any of this
you know start response and send your
headers
and then do this and then do this let's
just happen each EP response let's have
subclasses
up the HTTP response were you know
common things like not being able to
find something
or needing issue a redirect then finally
let's tie it all together let's say okay
just try to call a ball that takes one
of these requests
ever turns respond to raises an
exception
let's do your all parsing the simplest
possible way let's just break some
regular expressions and say
this regular expression goes to this
call and you know if you ever need extra
arguments in there
okay with puts in capturing group in the
regular expression
and you know what that's it that HTTP in
Django
that all you have to do you have the
same normalize the PRI's abstractions
give this easy way has hopefully
everybody already knows regular
expressions right
you're all regular expression masters I
know you are
everybody does regular expressions easy
enough to wear
the Orioles and Billy Mays voices Justin
or in here
all but wait there's more
we also get Hepp and request/response
life cycle
we get a middleware system a credit all
middleware system sock
including jack goes including with
middleware including every middleware
system ever invented
they all suck be have to happen we have
we have signals
we have a way four components within
Django to signal each other and listened
to those signals
completely naturally completely back
into the frame or
we have the ability because everything
is just a callable to decorators
for composition you can stick
basically anything you can think of pre
or post processing
on any one of these callable just as a
decorator
because it is just call ables all the
way down turtles all the way down to
believe Simon Wilson liked
said from grow finally we do in fact
do whiskey yes we read Pepe 333 so you
didn't have to
because 20 views all these useful
abstractions you have a Django project
which is a whiskey application
and Django under the hood will do the
hard work of translating whiskey
to actually seen Hepp extractions for
you
personally borrowing a phrase from jean
is Wenski where he once said first of
job it doesn't have free
after that everything is gravy I'm
willing to take quite a hit in terms of
importing libraries to get seen
HTTP abstractions maybe this is because
they've been doing it
long enough bit I'd want to bang my head
against the keyboard sometimes
but to me that's worth a lot Django has
for my money and I've worked a lot of
remarks absolutely the best
each EP be abstraction and
request/response life cycle handling
on any of the current generation pipe
remarks it is
absolutely one of the best things about
Draco and
I probably still music even if I work
using any of the other components
second thing I wanna talk about is
conservatism
Django is a conservative framework
and I really do mean mass I really you
now
I'm not gonna call Django minimal I
don't think anybody would ever do that
Django is not a minimal framework Django
is a conservative
framework so take an example we have the
sculptor
that was new and 1.4 that
all it does is taking a string and
truncated at a certain number of
characters
hom you're familiar with jane goes
development process
you know that getting that and took four
years
I'm not even joke coming soon in Django
1.7
back and regardless just you're talking
about we have a migration API
built into the core framework
that only took about six years
Django is incredibly conservative
about adding you thanks things get into
Django
fairy fairy slowly
in fact now some things are getting out
I if you look at the last few releases
and you look at road maps and plans
we r either have removed or are in the
process of removing
quite a lot of things especially in trip
probably more of them are going to go
we used to have the comments framework
which is still in Django but I don't
think is anywhere officially documented
are used to be data burrell's
application which now is just gone
the local flavor application which has
now been split out into it
on completely separate package I'll the
markup application which no longer
exists
probably a lot more things are going to
come how to Django in the near future
what this means is the jan was reached a
point where things are difficult to
added
easy to remove and not just whole
library 3p eyes
you look at the deprecation warnings
that check issues
are from one released in the next thing
sir deprecated
we go 1 release to release then it's
gone
we are not shy about that you have a
compatibility policy we do deprecate
things slowly but we get them
out thank usually this is described as a
bad thing
a lot of people over the years have
talked about how frustrated day
are when they're trying to contribute to
check may have an idea for a great new
feature
and it just sorta seems like it stops it
seems like it takes forever
to get this there are poorer warrant on
with the truncate filter
literally did spend four years
championing
arm on every mailing list he could find
in every penny
at five and finally it did make it
but generally people treat this as a bad
thing
I don't think it's necessarily about
paying project
be as conservative as it is back I think
it can be a good
oMG conservatism as an approach to
framework Desai is a strong preference
for letting solutions bubble up out
community
and in fact Andrews talk about
migrations is a great example of that
we have had over jaggers history several
competing
migration remarks self is the one that
seems to have
one man captured hearts and minds object
users
we just pick something way back
beginning were all her own
we never would have gotten something is
good sup
I'll core framework these days
Obama for Jacob talk about this and I
think he's onto something
should be more about providing the
underlying API's
to like things rather providing fully be
features
obviously there are still some things
are gonna have to be will feature
there but mostly those providing API
support
an hours old this is you end up with
jiang is often criticizes make it hurts
what component you end up with things
that are more swappable than you
expected
arm at my day job at Mozilla
work on the muscle development at work
the
number of things in Django we don't use
or that we use
something else swapping and we don't use
the template system
ginger of swapping that it is really
easy and making Jack
use it result of this is often you get
slightly more swappable home you also
get more stability over
hi something that makes me at least feel
warm and fuzzy
is every once in a while see someone on
predator on a mailing list for hackers
or talking about how they try to check
way back today and they got busy doing
something else and now they've come back
to
they say wow I can see it's got all
these new features but it still feels
very much the same
premark I'll 45 years ago
Django is conceptually fairy Perrys
people op features go into Django
NOP when there's hype around them not
when there's lots of people saying
we need to have this now features going
when they're ready muster the time
we help om
competition often ends up giving us
better solutions
cell again as a wonderful example of
that we've also had another feature
re had competing proposals and we've had
things even sometimes that never made it
in
because we never could get a solid
competing proposal
I'll the very first year
that we did summer code officially I was
mentoring
Thomas now mentoring
are talking about packaging and making
Django more friendly to packaging
thanks to tools and he put in a to work
and it just never really played out
nothing satisfactory ever came out at
the community as far as making Jack
play nice setup tools ads we never
turned into
all and set up to this spring sometimes
that's the result of having this type of
competition is realizes
shopping way makes what makes the cut
so nothing goes into the framework just
kept
so Django overall
feel free to disagree I think Django's
conservatism
towards new features and conservatism
word at
toward making major radical changes he
is really one of its tracks
primarily for that reason of that person
who comes in
hackers read it or on the mailing list
with that person who learned Django
once upon a time had now they don't need
to
all over again draco is op a completely
new framework every year
we get features every year begin things
that we can do every year
but Django itself remained remarkably
stable and consistent conceptually
speaking of conceptually
the third and final good part this is my
personal favorite
I've given several talks on this is
encapsulation
applications or PB upon
in caps nation as Django secret weapon
I'll you look at other ways to do
applications
Django project as we mentioned is the
whiskey application
home what is a django application go
if you wanna talk about say cure risky
applications
for applications in a lot of other
frameworks are hung up
monoliths were black box a lot of cases
where you sort of feel a need to do
everything
him on application or everything in one
endpoint
and sort because of the nature whiskey
anybody who's
more thoroughbred exposing was key to
you all the way through
it's going to end up being a lot of
black box because it's harder for
whiskey
components communicate with each other
I'll
you don't have store up and down the
stack signaling
communication processes that you would
happen something else
see you end up signing either these
really huge things or these things that
order act like black boxes
or both %ah
whereas in django application could be
any of these things models use utility
co
middleware forms
but they're all the Django bits where
they're all the Django EPI
its how I mentioned for example you
don't have to use checkers template
system
but if you use jaggers API's floating
record template
it just works even if you're using
jaggers template system
a reason ginger if you're using
something else
Django give you a bunch of safe API's
rely upon being present a lot of safe
assumptions
you can make about things are going to
be present things you can use
and this makes integration lots of
different component
whole lot easier then integrating amala
for an agreed-upon black box
django application as a result are free
to be sorted
encapsulated pluggable functionality
first time ever talk about this was six
years ago
laptop a Chaka Khan California
at the time I thought this was the
selling point of Jack
I still think it is the ability to right
ankle application as
single reusable pluggable encapsulated
whatever you needed to do at the time I
example was generous tration jacket
profiles
some things that I put out there as
examples
I'll since then people have gone above
and beyond
in terms that are for philosophy
%uh Unix tools a django application
is just like textile one thing do it
well
cell now for example I have a personal
blog our personal blog has an installed
absolutist with 12 entries at
had my day job or work on ambien we have
an install the app's list with closer to
50 aP's
and about a dozen a those are ones that
either
rolled ourselves or specific Gambia the
rest of them
are either other mazzola tools were
things that were completely third-party
people there integrated you can do this
with Jacko
Django packages is a website that list
well packages you can get for Django
criminalist
2,206 available aP's
are as much as it's a cliche you can say
with Jack
there's an app for that I'll
aP's you we are at the secret weapon
in my opinion the fact that you can take
user registration or user profiles
for signing up with persona or
wiki or eighties
pick something else of India a studio
for showing Devils a web technology
you can wrap any of these things up
these were one-sentence ideas
into an application you can just pull
off the internet
plug in your website you a little bit
integration work you don't have to worry
about well as this app using some
completely different framework
is this app using some completely
different perhaps a complete
formal ivory completely different
controller setup
the lovely thing about Django music as
much as people complain
about their before stack are
feeling locked in what you get in return
for accepting some basic components and
you don't have to accept all
for you get in return for accepting some
basic component is the ability to do
this to compose
large complex sites with lots of moving
parts
without having to rate all of the code
yourself without having to do tons and
tons and tons
integration so much I love every
production Jack
site I C now a days is off-the-shelf
components
they're taking advantage back you can
just go
whole a bunch of Jack laps of pie pie
of Jack packages of everyone index from
and say okay we get that functionality
from
map that functional everything that is
up for your site your core business
logic you need right
you can probably outsource to something
else and Candace Rae water to collapse
that encapsulate
what your site needs to do I really
think
always have fought this is Jack a secret
weapon
I'll encapsulation usability possibility
applications and concept
of the Czech application is being
something so radically different
from what all the other type of remarks
were doing which was mostly
application is with application
I'll that's about all I've got. I hear
people clapping
in the room next door which means I time
this just about right
%ah so we have side 10-15 minutes for
questions
if anybody wants I believe we have
microphones
just one yeah I have
I have the two questions a
personalize their agenda booth in the
expo hall why
is there a jingle in the extra hole is
there one
others the Jenga with there's the
there's other with further rumors
there's a jingle
at all his mom's a reason behind that
why isn't there one
I don't now mom that would be a question
probably for the
yessir or someone knows more about that
than I do
okay and the other a question I have
them got in her
at recycle ok
I'm so you've mention using go
at your job and use gender
for the template partner Django and I'm
just wondering like was your typical
I Django by water use and jingle for now
and were parts are you replacing I A %uh
so work we we r the Mozilla Developer
Network of India
mostly we r Wikio
documentation web technologies which is
written in Django
mostly om back end is pipeline using
Django request/response tango or am %uh
ginger for templates with gym goers the
integration library
and a JS service providing scripting and
template like your
familiar with all Wikipedia you can be
like templates that dues for descriptive
things
are we have a service written in
JavaScript does that IOM
we also have a demo studio where people
can upload demonstrations a different
web technologies
that is entirely check things
we also we've sorted use jaggers
authentication system
are we replace it we use a Mozilla
persona zeal
occasions worse but the of remark is
designed Italy
that's what are using jingle for
at the framework to I'm sorry the Django
framework for like the admin
I have the jack Hannahan able to use a
little bit
but whenever possible treetop okay i
member now
okay I is really a plans operating the
orange juice milk is there was fifty
complains the RMB much slower than say
SQL
me up every couple years
somebody comes up with a proposal to
rate in API compatible wrap-around
sequel alchemy
project or am at every couple years the
person who comes up with that idea gives
up on
about six months later okay %ah if
somebody can actually
work I would certainly be interested %ah
but so far I don't think anybody's
really used convincing implementation
thank you I thanks very much to talk
I wonder if maybe this is an obvious or
you don't wanna get into it better
I wonder if I can get you to do the
obvious thing and I and maybe compare
Django to some the other frameworks
and say we things on the strengths and
weaknesses in each direction not just in
in your opinion
and thinking a fam a flask Ando
web to pie I'll I like flask a lot
I'll I have had a chance to use it for
anything
major I really like a lot of the eight
years carrying down
disorder the essentials doing web and to
say
anything that's not the web go find
something else to do
words going to do WebFOCUS meticulously
on that
I really do you like that sort do one
thing and do it well
I'll don't really have experience with
bison don't really have anything
say one way or another are you should
check it out it's magic coca
I'll
what do you feel or other worst parts
Django needs work
are everything I didn't mention is a
good part in this talk
that is that okay %ah now Django
the internals are really messy and
really hard to understand
they tend to scare off contributors
medic classes
wave wave wave wave wave wave way too
many better classes
in Django I'll the or am
is a minefield hits
their Kb I think half a dozen people
world qualified actually make serious
changes
the RM at this point I'll honestly I
thing dipping Jack eater it's the most
right now
busy good cleaning up the entire house
at
great is about to happen Apple three
factors my favorites that slamming 1.7
up
maybe next year lease week another
thanks else
up
john wants going twice
okay thank you all for coming out hope
you have a nice lunch
in
good