I know every like thank you so much for
coming I know it's a beautiful a
Montreal the outside and the snow is
melted but
thank you for coming into this room it's
my pleasure to introduce
I Jesse Davis and his talk on what is he
saying
how does it work and when should I use
it a round of applause place
hi everybody thanks
so this talk is going to be something
more like
arm what is a sink when should I use it
and how does it work or perhaps
and different arm ordering up that the
talk itself will be assertive
is synchronous so up
oh you guys liked that on some intense
Jesse Davis at work for Mongo dB in New
York City
and as you probably know in New York we
eat
three kinds of food we eat summer in
sandwiches
pizza by the slice and almocar say which
is
a Japanese word for something like you
go ahead and shoes
it's when you go to a sushi restaurant
and they just give you whatever is good
that day so
New York as a crowded place and %ah each
of these kinds of food has
a different arm bottleneck
as a trust to scale out to a very large
number I love
clients for example with
summary in sandwiches it starts off you
go to the counter
and a sandwich maker comes under the
sandwich maker pool
and you tell the sandwich maker what
kind of sandwich you want
on but kinda bread work Adam ingredients
and you have to this
one-on-one synchronous interaction
that lasts for the duration love your
request
so until the sandwich is complete
the sandwich maker doesn't take a break
doesn't talk to different clients
on that sandwich makers devoted to you
in till the sandwich is complete and you
walk away with it
on at that point the sandwich maker
returns to the sandwich maker pool
Intel another client pops of love the
eater cue
so the analogy that are making here is
for a
a CPU bound Weber service
on something that might
cryptographically sign your request
for something like that on in Dec hits
I you can scale out by either
making the sandwich maker faster by
say arranging the ingredients more
efficiently or you might add more
sandwich makers
until the space behind the counter is
fall so this is like
you can add faster CPUs or
you can add more prostheses Intel you
have this many prostheses
as you have cores but thats
it on you don't want concurrency here
it would make sense for the sandwich
maker to be switching between
different clients and try to make
multiple sandwiches at once so this is
like
a a CPU bound webservice
that doesn't request any external assets
in order to satisfy client request
there's no need for a saint here
each process should just handle a single
cloud requested the time
from start to finish without doing any
context switches
answer this is when not to use a sink
don't use a sink for sups a but
different kinds food have different
scaling properties so
what about Pizza it starts the same as
subs
you go n and the pizza cook
appears and you ask the cook for a
particular slice
a pizza the slices are already
made but their serve lukewarm so
the cook Texas less and puts it in the
oven and
for the two minutes it takes for the
slice to
keyed up you both standing around idly
in till the slices hot to cook gives you
a slice
and you walk away with it so
in this case I how do you scale-out
the pizza cook how do you deal with
multiple clients
showing up there once here
you wouldn't want the pizza cook to act
like a sandwich maker
you don't want to cook to address a
single client
and then stand around idly for two
minutes into the size has hired
then give it to that client and then ask
next client hate what kinda slow steal
one
if you had to devote a single pizza cook
to each client
you'd run out of space behind the
counter before you run out of space
behind other
so a the analogy that I'm trying to make
here
years I'm trying to say that the cook
ought to be a sink the cook should
respond to events as they occur
so its clients arrived the coke asks
each one what kind of slows to they want
and as slices become hot in the %uh been
the quick response to that event and it
gives the hot sliced to the client
on and in that way 10 or a couple
cooks should be able to serve a very
large number of concurrent clients
um now
the one that problem that the cook is
going to experience is that
are with lots of concurrent clients are
asking for slices and lots of slices in
the other end
the Cook is not going to need some kind
of
demonic for remembering how long each
slice has been and what client it
belongs to him
so this is sort of like a regular old
web service
that has a big slow back and
like a database or and of provider
arm here a sink is
a great idea for scaling because a
couple of processes can handle
hey large number of clients with many
concurrent I O operations but you're
going to need some way to stores stayed
well each operation is in flight the
same as the cooking it's to remember
which slice coast which client and how
long it's been in the oven
now this is even more true I love
a mukasey on or actually I just learned
that it's probably pronounced
our Marcus a but anyway on the way works
is
you and your friends you all go up to
the counter
and the waiter tells the kitchen
a bunch of people arrived and that's it
the kitchen starts making sushi whatever
is good that day
and as the sushi becomes complete
the waiter ferries each dish to the
clients at the counter
on once again you don't want a waiter
devoted to each client
because school run out of space behind
the counter
instead you should have one waiter or
small number of waiters
core event-driven who notice clients
arriving
and no to sushi becoming ready and are
able to multi-task
and upscale out that way up to the
limits of the kitchens ability to
produce sushi
and this is like a WebSocket newfangled
application
where clients connect over WebSockets
and awaits server-side events
so if you log into Gmail for example
your browser opens a WebSocket
connection to one of Google's servers
and then nothing happens the
connection remains idle Intel
a new email arrives for you on the
server
and then the server notifies you over
the WebSocket connection and your
browser updates itself
arm if Google's servers were to devote
a thread for every client connection
they would quickly be overwhelmed by the
number of threads
that they had to support because
WebSocket connections are very long
lipset has a very large number of them
concurrently
art for WebSocket applications in
particular
it's critical to minimize the resources
devoted to idle connections
so this is what a sank is for
it minimizes resources per idle
connection
while you're waiting for some event to
occur and
the main resource that you need to
conserve
is memory so we typically say
that a synchronous applications are not
CPU limited
but memory downed and that the challenge
is to our store per connection state as
efficiently as possible
the on influential paper on this topic
is called C 10k
its by a guy named Dan key goal
or cable and the papers better ten years
old
but it's still a really good read on it
starts off
a sissy 10k is the term that he Quoin 24
10,000 concurrent connections and
the paper starts off it's time for web
servers to handle 10,000 clients
simultaneously don't you think after all
the web is a big place now and
he goes on to say that perhaps in the
not too distant future
those who prefer using one thread per
client
will be able to use that paradigm even
for 10,000 clients
nevertheless at the current time if you
actually want to support
that many clients you're probably better
off using some other paradigms
so the orders have magnitude might have
changed
in maybe that a a hundred thousand
that yet maybe ten thousand threads is
supportable now
but I 100000 is not I but the principle
remains
that if you devote a thread per socket
you'll run out of resources for
representing those threads
first and artificially limit your
ability to hold sockets
open so if
arm if it sink is so great
and if the kind of web applications that
demand a sink
are increasingly common then
why is multi-threading still the
conventional approach wires and
everything already a sink
and um I think that the answer is that
it's hard it's hard to code
and the reason why it's hard is because
when you're waiting for some venture to
occur
on a connection you need to remember
what you're going to do when that event
happens
you need to store state so when a client
request comes in
and the server makes a related request
to the back and
in needs to stores stay are so that'd
remembers what it was going to do when
the back and response and
this is even more true I love newfangled
WebSocket applications
because in those applications
the wat he is indefinitely long
when you visit gmail you don't know how
long it's going to be before a new email
arrives
so it's even more critical to
efficiently represent that state while
waiting for something to happen
and the conventional way to store state
here's with a thread and with threats
you don't really have to think about
how do I store state with a thread
because
it's done for you threads store their
state with the program counter
with the stack and the local variables
in the current stack frame the operating
system and the programming language
handle it for you and your use to that
kind of programming model
is sick applications usually use call
backs
or some other a representation besides
threads for storing state while they're
waiting for an event
and call backs whether more efficient
and threads
we're not used to using them and they're
not
are designed to be easy for this kind
abuse case
so it's much harder to keep track I love
what you're doing
on because threats and call backs
represent is too extreme a
I love efficiency versus easy views
there are
a bunch of middle grounds that have been
staked out in between the two
so there are covert ans which are
incredibly important and L again and
beautiful and awesome and we don't have
time to talk about them today so
are BB the exercise for the reader
there also agree lets which is what she
event is based on which are
a little bit more like threads then
cover teens are
and on and on and on and the fact that
we keep
arm innovating in this area and making
up new terms for slight variations on
this theme
love I'm representing state in
a synchronous applications it suggests
to me that
no one love these techniques satisfies
everybody yet and so this is still kinda
for
alive hand developing area of research
so
are expect new are some things in this
area
but on
okay but so we've covered
to some extent when should I use it
and we'll come back to that at the end
again
but we can start to define what it is
now
and what a sink is is
on single-threaded sir can to concurrent
computation
but it can do I owe concurrency so is
single-threaded
a sink framework can have many i/o
operations in flight simultaneously it
can be waiting for many things at once
it uses non-blocking sockets and we'll
see what that means
in a few minutes and it uses some
platform-specific facility to
are register for event notifications on
those non-blocking sockets
on latex its the poll on Mac in BSD it's
called KQ
on and the final thing about a sink is
that it uses an event loop
to continuously process new event
notifications
and dispatch this offense to
arm event handlers
which are usually call backs but which
might also be covered hymns and so on
so when a random person says
a sink to you this may or may not be
what that person means but
this is my definition have a sank and
when somebody says that
node or tornado or twisted or tulip
is a sink they mean that
those frameworks conform to
this definition Service Inc so
thats a sink in general that's the
general programming methodology that we
call a sank
and now I'm going to switch to a
specific library called
a sync i/o which is wanna implementation
up this general idea
so know D is another implementation so
are
tornado and twisted on
that is a year and a half ago guidos
started working on it
a knew it a sink from work called tulip
at the time and that was the subject of
his keynote at last year's spike on
I'm since that time it's been renamed
a Cinco it's been merged into the
standard library
we'd overloaded with help from like a
dozen people
I including be I'm super excited and
proud of that
on the a
justification and specification
for iti a sync i/o standard library
Marshall
is in PEP 3156 which
is a surprisingly good read and it
defines
on both the standard event loop
interface
and it also talks about career teens but
again we don't have time to talk to Kurt
himself
on deal with that yours yourself up
art so we're going to build
an example application on top I love a
sync i/o
and up the first thing we need to do is
just kinda like
look at a little screencast that I
recorded
love this thing in action so we know
what it is we're building
and you can see
the its very standard there's nothing
special about this
its just the stereotypical
chat application these are two browser
windows
that connect to the same server over
WebSocket
and when one I love the
clients sends a message over the
WebSocket the server
rebroadcast said to all the other
connected clients
real straight for nothing special so
on all a Cinco applications are kind of
build
using the same set I love
layers there's the application itself at
the top
and the application uses a pair
I love arm abstractions to actually do
the work
and the pair is a protocol and a
transport
this is a on and abstraction that was
defined by a sync i/o
it was heavily inspired by twisted stirs
I'm
and the distinction is that 8 a protocol
is something like
HTTP or WebSockets
a protocol knows what bites to send
and it understands the meaning of the
bites that it receives
and beneath the protocol
is a transport so TCP as a transport
and the transport knows how to send and
receive
by its but it doesn't know what bites to
send it doesn't understand the meeting
at the Mets that every six
on is Cinco is relatively low-level
so it gives you transports like TCP
but it doesn't give you any protocol
implementations
like HTTP so if you want
a protocol you need to get it from
somewhere
I'm getting an implementation up the
WebSocket protocol
from a library called audubon
now beneath the transport is the event
loop
and that's where we're going to be
spending most of our time
the event loop finds out about events
and dispatches the events to event
handlers which are
call backs and the
bottom most layer beneath the event loop
is the selectors Marshall so
just like a san kayo the selectors model
is a new module
and the Python 3.4 standard library
and it abstracts away all of the
platform specific differences between
the pole and KQ and whatever the heck
people use on Windows on and it lets you
a just kinda generally ask for event
notifications without worrying about
what kinda operating system to running
on and
for this talk will consider selectors to
be magic
we'll see what it does but not how it
does it it's a layer beneath which we
don't go
so now we can finally start to look at
some code art
this is in Example dot hi
this is the chat application that we're
building
and the first thing it does is it
imports its
protocol implementation from autobahn
and Ines think I O you need both the
protocol
and a factory and the factory knows how
to
instantiate the protocol one instance
per connected client
so that these two will hook up in a way
that will see in a second
on the next part the example application
is the chat protocol
logic itself so
we have this global set of clients
that represent all the currently
connected browsers
and then we subclass
autobahns chat protocol
and we override three methods on Connect
runs
wearing a client connects to a semi at
ourselves to the global list
and then on message handles
incoming messages from clients and
rebroadcasts them
to all the other clients and then the
final thing
on clothes just removes us from the
global list whenever a client
disconnects from us
soap really simple and stereotypical
what we're interested in
is are how does on Connect
actually get executed in response to a
client trying to connect to us
on and my assertion is that
if we've understood how the arm
low-level Avent have a client trying to
connect
to our listening socket results in this
call back actually being executed
then we've understood how is sync works
so keep that in mind this is the goal we
wanna see how on Connect
gets executed and we're gonna get there
in kind of
to faces so the first phase is
we need to create a server and start
listening
on a socket so that happens down here
at the bottom I love the
example code so we
create their protocol factory we tell it
what kind of protocol to instantiate
it'll be the chat protocol that we
defined
and we tell it to bind to an interface
and listen on a port
and then the next thing we do is we get
the event
loop from a sync i/o and we tell it to
create
a server and we pass and the factory
and beneath that we're going to tell the
loop to start running
but we're not quite there yet the first
thing we're gonna do is we're going to
look at creates server
because that's where we start to
I'll listen for clients connecting so
hear this and the first part service are
pretty simple
we create a socket arm out so let me
first
orient you where you are your are now
a layer beneath the example application
we r in the standard library itself for
looking at the implementation up the
event loop
in the a sync i/o module and the
standard library
and we create a stockade we find it in
interface we listen on a port
the stuff is not specific to a sink so
it just kinda ellipse eased out the
details there
the interesting stuff starts when we
call
stock dot set blocking false
making a socket non-blocking
means that all operations we attempt
on the socket are either going to
succeed or fail
instantly but never block so whereas
on a normal socket you would call sucked
I receive
to ask for some by its and if there
aren't any bites
waiting to be received then you block
with the non-blocking socket under those
circumstances we would raise an
exception
so the next thing we do after that as we
get the sockets
file descriptor and we pass it into
the selector and the selector
is magic it's part if this
are magical selectors Marshall that
we're not going to talk about
we're not good as describe how it works
but we are going to see what it does
and what it's doing here is it
takes a file descriptor and
takes an event mask which is
the listed the kind to the dance they
were interested in
on and in this case were interested in
when the stock it becomes readable
because that means that a client is
trying to connect to us
we also pass and that third argument
which is on
any data at all the selectors Marshall
will accept
any data that we want to pass an and
then we'll get that data back out later
if the event they were interested in
occurs
so in this case were passing in a tubal
and the tubal
is the reader call back and the writer
called back
and the writer call back as non because
arm
a listening socket is never right people
but p
reader call back he is a new method
on the I'll loop called
accept connection so we've created a
listening socket
we registered a call back to be executed
when somebody is trying to connect on
the listening socket
and now we can look at what's in that
call back so we're going to look at
the implementation accept connection
so here it is this is the second
I love the methods on I'll do
that were looking at and a
first it calls except on the socket
it knows that there's a client waiting
to connect to us
so it knows that it's time to call
except underscore on the socket
and the return value of that includes a
new socket
called con and that represents the
new connection to the client and since
it's a new socket we have to call set
blocking false on that
to then we
instantiate the protocol by
executing the protocol factory and
protocols that
chat protocol that we saw implemented
in the example application
finally we wrap-up the event loop
and the client connection and the
protocol
and we still call it that into a
transport
so we're almost there
and we're gonna see held the transport
are finally
completes our goal love executing
on Connect so per soccer transports
in it function is here on
it takes the loop client connection in
the protocol
it calls its super constructor
and then look at it does at the bottom
there calls
self protocol connection made
and that was actually
our goal we wanted to see how
a client connecting to us caused
that method called on Connect to get
executed
and here you can see that we've called
connection made on the protocol
that makes another function caller to
and
it calls on Connect which
here's what we wanted to see so
does that mean that we understand how is
sync works
almost but not quite because
there was a detailed that is sort of
glossed over
arm and it's this we saw how
we past accept connection into the
selectors a call back
we didn't see exactly how the client
trying to connect to us
caused that call back to be executed
so in order to understand that last
piece
we need to rewind all the way back to
our example application here
we saw creates server and the chain of
events that it leads to
but we can look at the final line
looped out run forever so let's look at
that
on here it is and now we're back in a
sink a a we're back in the standard
library
this is the third van loop method that
we've seen
Wieser create server and accept
connection
and that this is the third and final
method we need to look at
run forever now
as you would expect from the name run
forever is an infinite loop
%uh while true yet
receives an event list from the selector
and as with everything else for the
selector this is magic
were not going to see how it works
but we can see what it does it returns a
list of
events that are currently ready on
non-blocking sockets
so we iterate through this event list
and each item in the event list is
a file descriptor a bit mask
I love a pending offense on that file
descriptor
and also the data that we are earlier
past an
so the data remembers the reader called
back at the rather call back so we
unpacked that from data
and then we check is the readable bit
set on the event mask and is the read
call back not
non if so then we don't actually
execute the read call back
we added to a list of pending call backs
and then we do the same forward the
right bit
we check if the right bit is set at the
event mask
and if the right call back is not nine
and if those two things are true
then we add it to the ready queue
once we've processed the whole list to
the events this way
we have a ready cue full love
pending runnable call backs so then this
the senate funny and
not very Python etc looking loop at the
bottom there
where we check the length up the ready
queue
and then we pop call backs off for the
ready queue and execute them
and the reasons why we do it
this weird way you might think like 10
jazz run all the call backs in the ready
queue
a call back can't do anything
and that includes adding new call backs
to the ready queue
as it's running so we don't wanna run
those secondary call backs now we only
want to run the call backs that we're
ready
when we reached the top up this loop
any call backs that the register and add
to the ready queue
will have to wait into we've reached the
next iteration over the whole
event loop arm and this guarantees
certain things about
on scheduling and starvation that a
Cinco de Mayo
wants to guarantee but up we don't
actually have to understand all that
his we do need to understand we up
earlier registered for event
notifications on a listening socket
and the reader call back was self-taught
accept connection
so here we are in the event loop when
that
listening socket becomes readable we get
the event
for that socket from the selector
the call back is except connection
and that's what we wanted to see we
wanted to see how that got pulled back
out if the selectors Marshall
and executed as a consequence have a
client trying to connect to us
so now we've seen the whole thing %uh
and for visual learners we can go
through it again with boxes and arrows
up so first we saw the application
startup
and a called start server on the event
loop
and then the event loop registered a
file descriptor
with the selectors Marshall and passed
in the accept connection call back
after that we return to the application
and we saw the application
call run forever on the loop and then
the loop
saw the event on the listening socket
and it pulled the call back out and
executed at
and that call back in turn called back
into our
chat protocol implementation and
executed on connect on that
said I we've seen the whole chain of
events and we've seen
had a very low and basic level how a
single
actually works are
so to review a sync i/o users
non-blocking sockets
and it registers prevent notifications
on the sockets
using the selectors Marshall which wraps
the eap polar KQ
facilities the event loop
knows about all of the non-blocking
sockets in the system
and when events occur on the sockets the
event loop
executes the Associated call backs so
that your application can
Ron its application logic in response to
those I O events
arm and now that we've kinda gone like
when should I use it what is it how does
it work
and then we've gone back to what is it
now we can
do a final review love when should I use
it
so like with medicine
there are indications and
contraindications
for a sec indications
in favor of a single are are
pizza so if you have
a web application with some kind of back
and
that you're spending most of your time
waiting for
rather than spending most of your time
doing computation
that's a good application for a sec arm
additionally if you have a sushi if
you're doing WebSockets
that means that you're doing very little
competition for each
open our website get connection
but you have to have a very large number
of them idle at a time
so a single as you to minimize the
memory that you spend
waiting for advance on this website gets
I'm and basically anytime that you have
a very large number of concurrent
connections
but you're not spinning very much CPU
on handle inclined requests on each
connection
that's a good application for a sink
arm contraindications are
when you want a submarine sandwich
when you're doing computationally
intensive
work in that case a sink doesn't win you
very much
on because you're not doing very much hi
ok concurrency
you're better off focusing on CPU
concurrency
said the additional complexity of a sink
doesn't win you anything so it's best
under these circumstances not to use it
arm another issued that a lot of people
get
wrong is the years and a sink framework
but they're talking to database with a
synchronous driver
so if you're using a blocking driver
with an
a synchronous framework you're blocking
your AVENT Bottle
whenever you talked the database and
your giving up all the advantages that
you chose a sink for
so are with my sequel for example people
often use it with tornado
but a long-running my sequel
query will have disastrous consequences
for your throughput under the
circumstances
see better off using multi-threading arm
in the case of Mongo DB
I spent a very long time writing a
non-blocking driver called motor
which allows you to connect properly
from 2002 Mongo DB
just to insured that you're able to use
in a sink driver within is saying
framework
the final issue that you have to deal
with
is up what if you don't know is sing
pretty well
and what if now is not the right time to
invest in learning at
I would say under the circumstances you
need to be
judicious in when you decide to invest
the time and learning at
its unfamiliar you can get it wrong
the code will look weird to you so
you need to decide that you're going to
learn how to use it
I'm and you need to decide when that
moment is
in it you know into period over which
you're creating your prototype for
whatever
on Duchess launch into it thinking it's
going to be easy
are 0 and the final thing about this is
on it doesn't have to be all or nothing
so it's very frequent that you have a
big complicated web application
with many kinds of tasks
and some of those like a chat
feature might best be served by a sync
service
and some other aspect of your stack
might be better served by a
conventional multi-threaded server and
that's fine you just mix and match those
in separate process season you connect
to you
the proper and point for the different
features
so thats all I have to say
%uh you've seen what a sink is how it
works
you gotten some are indications for when
to use it
and indications for when not the
next thing i'd say to do it here's
read Pepe 3156 are
a special look at the code routines
section of it
because it's really fun and cool and
are we didn't get to touch it at all
today
and on the next time you have a chat
application or something else that could
benefit from this kind of paradigm
give it a try and see how it works for
him so I think we have a few minutes
for questions five minutes for questions
great
on so other microphones
in the stands sir
great go ahead
are you planning to Court Motor for a
a sink II over if the plans that regard
yes
arm absolutely its kind of a problem
priorities right now both because we
don't have a lot
love manga TV customers on Python 3.4 in
production
and also because a sync i/o itself is so
novel
but I think that maybe in the next year
to indefinitely
arm looking for a way to make motor
kind of concurrency framework agnostic
so that our work
could work with not just when nato and a
Cinco but also probably I'm
twisted and a anything else that comes
out of the woodwork
make thanks min
hi thank you for this explorations very
clear and I'm
going to point a lot of people to it
one-fifth
record that great thanks and I just
wanted to ask if you have
and be quick advice for the backing this
kind of applications
because bagging an asynchronous
application this quite different from
the bank Inc
traditional application any advice for
making them
falls for the backing them over defining
that Louis
seeing what they actually i doing wrong
rate
it's incredibly hard as a matter fact
because the car back style
typically loses your traceback
arm you launch some peace a bio
and then your stack goes away and then
eventually the car back is executed in
something goes wrong but you don't know
why the call back is being run because
the
are the chain of events that led to it
being added to the runnable cue is
history on so
up catch at think really hard
arm I come routines are better than call
backs for this pic
okay because on for two reasons: career
teens
a keep all of your logic within the same
function or within the same
on stack up function calls and
a exception handling incur routines
is relatively normal where an exception
will
unwind the stack through a series of
colour teens in the same way that it
does through a series of ordinary
function calls
so on emphasize karu teens over call
backs when possible
and otherwise like good grief use
part-time use your debugger like prey
thank you sex a hut you talked about
having a central striker
for the database is needed when you'll
work I work in zyuganov's
haha out what about other kinds of I
feel that you need to do
that I understand the library like email
your local and Sun
all the that is blocking the current
exists rates so this is a huge problem
is that arm
there are protocols debtor implemented
in the standard library
like email and those are
mean the are formatting of messages and
the parsing every sponsors
is mixed in with the scheduling of Ohio
and would be nice if these things were
separate so that you could reuse
the parsing and formatting aspects
without relying on the i/o scheduling
but right now that's not really done so
this is G events big advantage is that
it monkey patch is the standard library
and replaces it I'll scheduling within a
synchronous lehrer
um without G events artwork
kinda in trouble arm
things get reimplemented over and over
and over again so there's a
a standard library email I'll model and
then there's a
a new one there was rewritten for
twisted
there's pie Mongo which is manga TB in a
blocking style and then there's motor
for 20 80
arm I think that a sync i/o
in the standard library is going to help
fix this
by giving us is standard a sink
interface to target but it's going to be
a few years yet before that really
happens
in the meantime there's just a time %uh
duplicated work
and that's really the answer can I take
one more question are
I'm so your the final question
us at a lot of pressure sorry
he said you implemented a a sync i/o
database driver for Mongo DB
yet but it seems really strange to me
that you did that as a new database
driver
wouldn't have been moored generally
useful to have
well you you can we separate the
database driver from
your a sink call backs using the work
you Im using
sedum workers sir so some
like if you had implemented that mean in
a higher layer in the or and more as a
layer above the Davis writer would not
have been another solution
so that may be the final place that we
end up
arm what I
said found when I started working on it
was that hi Mongo
mixed creating
requests with scheduling I O with
parsing the response
and those couldn't be easily untangled
without
starting from scratch so are
I did this hack where I schedule I O on
green let's
and I arm arrange for the screen lets to
be resumed
when the i/o that they're waiting for is
completed and
I have a long article about how I did
that arm
its kind of it works quite well
and it was a cheap way to get where you
needed to go
but because kinda technique that you're
suggesting as I think
is where we on the two had even if you
lose regular threats you could have kept
around the small number
threads for the database to handle those
calls
my thought was that green let's scale a
little better if you have a very large
number of pending operations
alright %ah thank you very much guys