now I well where we going to hear from
Salina de commande about how to
reach out to local teachers why should
and how to
this is a half-hour sessions will be 25
minutes than five minutes of questions
hopefully
so please welcome slain the fuck
okay so that Billy your are the slides
for this stock and I am linking to
hearing things if you wanna
grab those links as they go through your
welcome to have at that so
accuser is harping on this idea that we
need to connect with teachers and I see
teachers I mostly mean K through 12
teachers just to set
a little contacts for i'm talking about.
and I am
as I was thinking about you know how
I came to decide that I really wanted
more k to 12 teachers in my life I
wanted to get help from them
in the kind of teaching and I was doing
for pilot is which is mostly about
teaching adults I realize that this was
kind of how I thought about
this problem initially and basically
I thought as you know kids coming from
parents
which seems normal natural gas and
hidden and then the series it influences
you know you got the family the society
the piers the teachers
and then and then the school and then
out at the other end magically a Python
programmers pop out right
it this is kinda how how I really a
thought about things for a long time and
I am I mean it
like most the talk today is gonna be
about these a
leaky parts this pipeline is
assumptions and ideas the people
end up that end up becoming ingrained
at Lake math makes me anxious that one
that one so it's pretty early and other
one is that computer science is boring
and irrelevant and that has a pretty
significant impact on whether or not
people ever decide to try to learn how
to program
another one is that computer sciences
for white boys and there's
quite a bit research that's been done in
the last like tender
you know twenty years about this issue
and finally and there's a specific issue
that affects
Python which is that people believe that
there aren't any jobs and Foss
and that probably will come as a
surprise to her people who room cuz a
lot of us
are employed you know to write Python
for living
but there are a lot of people that
believe that that's just not possible so
I'm but this really only addresses that
point which at which you know people are
in school or they get outta school
and really there's a lot more to this
problem
not only can address all that but i just
want to point out that there sir this
bigger
donate out the hair a fish use involving
people I getting into an hour as the
computer science
and industry and
the thing but i wanna when you put the
head to head
good thing is that it's pretty leaky but
but the big
fundamentally believe about the leaky
down at is my head
I'm is that you know
it does leak n people the exit
our industry at quite an alarming great
but
an the work that I'm doing and if you
were here for the encoders are shut the
work that folks like barbara and
Katie you're doing so many people doing
wonderful work with kids and adults
right now
trying to get people back into the don't
and
and that's kinda what this stock is
really about you know Lake
people might encounter some movies you
know
these assumptions and thoughts and ideas
but there are things that we can all do
to combat it
so am say at Sony we don't
and and brings me to you sir the
meta issue that I encounter quite a bit
in teaching adults which is a
I've come to kinda think of this as the
possibilities problem
and there's this really a
affecting blog posts that
Julia for math wrote about a year ago
and it's about women in TAC
about her experience and she said this
thing that just really
kinda stopped me in my tracks when I
read it which
was you know I didn't grow up thinking I
could do anything I wanted to
and at every time I hear his head just
you I feel really overwhelmed because
it's so matches what I experience
win I go into workshops
in teach women to learn how to code for
the first time
I'm in this this is a picture we talkin
workshop teaching
adults about algorithms and they were
doing a pen and pencil exercise you know
trying to figure out how to get from the
airport to home
using about a different transportation
methods an
but as they were going to you that what
they said afterward was
that they finally felt confident that
they could explain what an algorithm was
the before the econ they'd never really
thought about what it what
an hour then was and also how that
related to programming in any way
and what it might mean to create their
own algorithms
and thats that's really powerful
transformation
for them so
here's now to go into all the reasons
why I think
case usual teachers in particular are
a a place where we can a fact
culture change at a pretty massive scale
an you know the Younkers worship I think
is a great example are doing this we're
we're just going out there and directly
interacting with kids and showing them
what's possible and if it's a wonderful
thing and I wish that we could do it
everywhere all the time and the great
thing about
public education United States and let
my comments really are gonna be about
a the United States there's lots of
interesting stuff for example going on
India right now
where live just introduce Python as a as
a
language that can be tight an at the
recital centre John a.m.
there's great so happy in other
countries that must make an essay will
be shipped to the United States
anyway if we could get more case Utah
teachers a
doing computer science doing competition
literacy I think it will change
a lot for us so when the fundamental
problems that we face
with kids is that they think math
just I mean nothing I think math just
makes them anxious
and there are a couple reasons am
there's some fundamental reasons
why this happens so early and one of
them
is timed math tests
and this starts as early as the first
grade there's research about
first-graders
and this particular study am was
there was an article that was published
at this month
2014 and this is a comment from a
second-grader
after taking a timed test this is what
they said I'm
I'm terrible at math and win
the when it starts that early it just
you know it kinda snowballs
a so whenever the things that would be
very helpful
for teachers at that level is to have
less pressure
to have these timed tests have these
performance
measurements have you know maps at such
an early age
because really what we want to be doing
at that point is exploring
and helping kids understand the beauty
and the art that is there
in math a much less than having to
perform
that they can add or multiply or
subtract whatever
in strictly time environment and let's
create
is that like a an initial Baylor
at you know she and many other people
are saying to publish now
peer-reviewed research that demonstrates
how
we can teach math in a way that doesn't
increase math anxiety
and I I have a link there if you're
interested in that
in reading that city in seeing what they
have to say about that
another attitude it out there am pretty
early
with kids you know probably love the
rich city is like
for six crater top-grade and the
computer science is boring
her irrelevant to their lives and
and a problem with that attitude is the
head ninety-eight percent of computer
science majors are exposed in some way
to computer science before
college so if kids think that it's
irrelevant
to them that early they probably are not
going to become computer science
majors because they just won't ever
bother to take any other classes
and then the other compounding
unfortunate thing is that
also most women who get computer science
degrees are exposed to it before college
into going to give you a sense of the
scale love
what we're up against here in 2012
about 25,000 students took the AP
Computer Science
class which is no respectable number and
it was actually
a almost a 15 percent increase over the
number that to get in 2011
but unfortunately when you can hear it
in
the number I love tests taken for AP
Calculus which he knows like
EF two usually take four years a mass in
the United States to get to the point
where you'd be ready for an AP Calculus
test
are you can see that we're working
against some pretty significant
and numbers there there's not a lot of
kids that are taking an AP
a computer science test so we're
starting way behind
am so is our lineup I lease and
you know I like I said I'm I mostly
teaching adults but I i think that
hi ladies is relevant because for a
number of reasons
and one of them is this attitude which
is also fairly prevalent
am and discuss quite a bit in unlocking
the clubhouse
and stuck in the shallow and and there's
a woman jay margolis who's done a great
deal of research into this person really
great
short readable books about her research
into this thinking can explain the
reasons why
kids think that computer science in the
United States is only for white boys
and and the impacted that which love you
probably heard
something like this and you probably
also heard that in free and open source
%uh for there's only maybe
you know 12 or 3 percent are women
a so but the the compounding factor here
the
bill leaky donut factor is that ten
years and only 58 percent of women
choose to stay in the industry well
eighty-five percent of men do
so I think the pie ladies is another
compounding
important and effort to try to keep
women in our industry if they managed to
to get there in the first place
so the last scan a a
school-related you know K to 12 related
issue that I wanna talk about
am 22 hopefully motivate you to go out
there and get in touch with teachers is
that
this idea that there are no jobs in free
and open source software
so you might get all the way through
decide the computer science is fun and
exciting in its for you
but then in the end you like our well
I'm never going to get a job anyway so I
probably shouldn't
finish my degree at so there's actually
some research
into these kinds about it is I'm a lot
of them are really specific to
it. you know so kinda the beer broader
IT industry
a as opposed to freedom cancer suffer
but they are
very related attitudes I think and this
this set every search was
an a survey about 6,000 students in five
different European countries
in a lot of instances what they found
was that the teachers and the parents
both
really poorly educated about what the
opportunities where they just really had
no idea what these jobs
we're like and one attitude that i think
is particularly relevant to free and
open source software is this idea
that the IT jobs are there to help
people
so who only fifty-five percent and own
up girls and only forty percent of
parents and teachers believed
that IT jobs were gonna help people
improve the world in any way
and that's really sad right leg is him
cuts what a lot of us is not not
everyone of course but a lot of us in
this room that's why
that's what motivated us to get involved
in free and open source %uh for in the
first place
because we thought we were gonna make an
impact on the world and change things
for the better an you know teachers and
parents like
a really have no idea that that's the
case which is
which is too bad so is my belief that
to you effectively change this you know
it is it's the culture problem
and it so much wider will hold the issue
I'm to do it I think that we have to
intervene at a lot of different ages
a lot of different for her stages at
also shown up socio-economic
levels an i think is possible to do that
with teachers because they span a lot of
those barriers in come in contact with
parents
and kids in a way that you know at least
for me for my part
you know I were from Oslo and coming
from a pit places extreme for religion
an awesome air-conditioned office that I
get to go to every day
and I don't come in contact with a lot
of the people that might believe that
there were no jobs
in free and open source software every
day but
teachers certainly do
so I've done a bunch of other computer
science and education topics in II link
to them here to welcome the CNA
going to a lot of detail about Common
Core
about an you know the state as computer
science
an education in the US there's lot agree
information out there from
the ACM from the computer sciences
Association stuff like that you can
check
all that stuff out there if you're
interested in
that and and now I'm just gonna go into
some very practical things that I think
that we all can do right away to get
involved
a with more teachers I think you're
really amazing model for advocacy
an comes from Dina perot a
the programs called ir been teen and
there's a link later to the website for
at
is me and basically with this program
does is it for it focuses on
african-american and Latino kids
bringing them in and exposing them to
programming for the first time
a.m. the the big innovation their
firm from her is she brings the parents
in the kids together
at the same time and then once they can
I come to this
day-long workshop on weekend she split
them up she takes the parents of in a
one-room
and they get to talk to a venture you
know it. exact super members or whatever
about
the curtain dusty to the industry the
fact that
a IT jobs are not in fact being halsell
outsourced
outside the United States or in Canada
right now that anyway
and this is that this is a very
prevalent
a idea a mess in the United States you
can't find an IT job
and it seems very strange to me because
man like we can hire fasten a friend
like we can train people pass in after
to hire them but you know there's still
a lot of people that believe that their
jobs are out there
so she suffers aside get them to talk
with industry leaders about the save it
and then takes the kids
in another room and a show some cool
stuff you know
does demos you know please robots you
know cool cool things that the
the kids be into and the
great thing about this program is that
75 percent the kids who have attended
these have seen involved in programming
in some way
the supreme dramatic impact in a in a
really important community
and another thing that I think we have a
big impact is teaching computational
thinking
to all ages and people
and if you've heard this before am to
net wing is kinda
seems like the mother above the current
computational thinking movement this is
a big long
thing and parishioners but the slain he
remembered I a summarized it
I'm which and how how I think it is as
its humans harnessing algorithms and
automation to solve problems make lives
easier
make the world better and you know it's
really focusing on algorithms and
on a mission peace and how humans
interact with machines as opposed to
just
them as opposed to just I'm thinking
about it in terms ove
map their programming there's a great
set of curriculum called
CS unplugged on org the helps that gives
lessons
for how to teach computational thinking
without using computers
on is also talk from the CS Educare
sorry from the
the Python education summit they just
happen as me a retard
on how to teach compositional think
using Python agree resources out there
and this is something that I think he'd
be really great if we all would teach
her family its
a hunch besides on a little earlier but
I I mean I don't know you but my family
doesn't really know what I'd do
naked I'm I'm actually for a living I
work on databases you know I came amid a
target act in a in a rate allotted
sequel and design data structures and
data stores like that
and a if I could teach my parents
just a little bit more about what it is
they do and my brother and sister for
that matter
and it and I we probably have a lot more
interesting Christmas conversations
hmm am
so at so those are kinda like the other
other two things work I like these men
ideas and went 1 direct action thing you
can do is find a local teacher
and fortunately & Co .org
has put together a wonderful resource in
the United States I think that there is
some information outside the US to in
in the US it's really great so if you
put in your city and state
at this your you'll get a list love
local
high schools and has middle schools and
his own entry schools that have
after school programs have are teaching
cs4 on CS classes
like in my community I found out that
and this one teacher Chris partner had
a four year computer science program in
this high school which is just amazing
spree and her death and in the US at
but anyway I i ended up meeting am a
different teachers
this way and a it's it's just a
fantastic resource and you can contact
his contact information
for the schools they renew and the way
that I did it and I
a air in previous oxo done on this
have like a template email your welcome
just a copy
and plug in your own information
and see if you can get a teacher to
respond to you and almost every
teacher that I contacted sent me an
email back and one meter
company with them which was just
wonderful
and then one thing that you can offer to
teachers
that's that they tend to want is for you
just to talk about your jobs the
classroom
its super relevant to the kids they
don't often get a lot of contacts and
must
you know they have apparent that's
already in the industry with people or
who are currently in the industry and
they love to hear about what is it you
do
of course he kinda gotta make your
presentation age-appropriate
that I am when I tend to use just are
not talking about a problem that I saw
them I work
and for me this is you know the most
basic level how I describe it is that
sometimes Firefox crashes
right and her almost everybody in the
room can relate to Pisa suffer crashing
on them
and you can I I tell the kids that I try
to help figure out
why that happens and then help other
people
make Firefox Firefox crashed less next
time
and here's how and then I can show them
either you know the variety of tools
that I use now I get to show them you
know a
Firefox phone crashing an
and others like hell also serve neat
stuff they can be there
Anna to help kids understand what it's
like to work in the industry
another great thing to do an is have a
look at the after school programs that
are out there
and the Computer Science Teachers
Association is a great resource for this
and there are local chapters I know that
I don't think barbour's
here bet she's she's got involved in her
local chapter in Austin Texas
and most most major cities have a local
chapter at this point
I'm your local tech Association might be
an option so an organ we have the Texas
Association workin in a very active in
Portland
opportunity with the teachers and
there's also just industry affiliates
so my my first job at a college was at
Intel and they were
an deeply involved in mentoring kids at
the local high schools
so often the larger companies will have
the structured mentoring programs and
it's actually usually not too hard to
get involved
in those even if you don't work for that
jane to a company
as a civilian organ here's three
programs that am I've
had some contact with her had friends
participate in
and you can you know officially they're
there there aren't a lot of Lake
big-name programs like in the UK there
are some by the United States there
aren't as many that I've come across
but Inori in we've got these three that
are really great and they are always
looking for volunteers
another thing people might be certain
interested in is lobbying am
and could argue again mike has some
great starter resources here
and you can check that out at at could
or promote and
the Computer Science Teachers
Association also has like a good
a vast array have resources related to
lobbying it's a little harder to come to
crack into you bet just starting with
their
research papers and i'm looking at their
suggested actions in this research
papers is a great way
to get involved in that
another thing people sir to forget about
his professional development for
teachers
a so I I had the privileges going in
actually key noting the Computer Science
Teachers Association last year
I was mean and like the gangster kirdar
code are which is
completely surreal experience but I I
guess talk about open source in
you know how I really wish that there
were more
a open source people in contact with
teachers can same through FEMA's
talking about today at but one thing
that teacher after teacher asked me as I
like so I wanna teach a class
that uses Python so what's the cool like
set of tools
that I should give to these kids you
know and so I gave
I gave a relationship just as a quality
you know get together flask late teaches
kids how to deploy something on her ok
you will be super stoked you know I know
how I can website and everything
but I am the teachers really would love
to have somebody coming give them
you know a tutorial on how to do that I
mean you can offer that and there are
professional development opportunities
mostly during the summertime
at you can after that's the school go in
for a day
and just like you know give give them
give them some ideas
for for teaching the kids or just you
know for their own
for their own edification
and finally am I really hit I really
wanna say teaching adults
I'm has completely changed my life like
I love it a
and be involved in pilot is is is by far
I
mean I I like fun it's great a bit be
involved in polly's is
is really when my favorite parts the
potentially
and I am and with adults you learn so
much some
so many things that you can share with
at your new teacher friends that you can
find
and I think it really helps improve this
first time entry
experience that people how the screen
open source software
and there's a lot of opportunities that
police forces all these workshops
a lot of times libraries will have
programs like the Monona County Library
where I'm at
has a thing called cyber seniors and you
can also do studio where shops
unjustified
invite if your friends so there's my
list
have stuff to do and her husband
I'm I'm happy I I've done actually done
most of these things to use i'm happy to
answer questions about like specific
things if you have any
and I just wanna close with am you know
I
I really think bill local connections
being in touch with your local community
are the way that we change
the larger culture and like I said you
can find
a this wonderful resources local
teachers just by going
to code are you in searching for your
city so I hope you'll do that
and thank you very much for listening
okay we do have five minutes for
questions so if you'd like to go to the
microphone please
it's just over hidden that's where back
here
in the back bunny I miss madame from
Seattle
and I'm kinda stuck on how the local I'm
middle school and high school in my area
are stuck on scratch and BYOB and other
kinda graphical
tools to teach that way when there'd
they're not making the leap into having
kids actually cut code I wonder
you have an opinion on whether that's
that's that can be as effective or for
really missing something by not teaching
his trucks
you know it that's a good question I
mean
it certainly is a barrier if they want
to rape eitan
rain X crashes in doesn't really
help you too much mean it the
the more important thing the most
important thing from
lake and long-term perspective is that
they get comfortable
with the idea of creating things that
they share use and and for themselves
like that
active creation is the most important
thing and i've seen
a lot of scratch programs that get kids
so point where they
are super excited about getting on a
computer
scream around that breaking things and
being okay with that and and
if it breaks down that anxiety I think
it's great
but yeah I mean as far as like promoting
the type of programming that's gonna get
you into
a computer science for anthony gets you
in the industry
yeah I don't know I don't know scratch
on its own
without the second kinda level
really really does that I don't I'm
seeing evidence it does anyway
hi I'm so I love what youve been
this Canon open in question a lot of
what you've been talking about has been
focus more on an urban context like I i
grew up in borderline berle
men of county North Carolina like I
think back when I was
I mean I only got into programming
because my dad used to run a BBS back in
the day
the giant like that the in like when I
was learning Python
I was pretty sure that I was the only
person in Randolph County who knew a
Python that lets
I white you probably hear yeah
so I guess the question is like how do
you
work how can you do this sort of thing
in
I kinda rural are borderline rural
environment like that where there's not
really much irv
attack industry or tech people to you I
guess help
now to question so I grew up in montana
and now no nowhere
and I was lucky enough to have
grandfather who is a TV repairman
and and ham operator aunt and uncle
that was really into hobbyists computer
assembly so I'm probably not the best
it so i'm not i'm not am
I'm trying every qualified to to talk
about
that sort of thing that what I what I
will say about the experience and
Montano was that the
the important thing was having a place
am
and it was just because the resources
were so scarce in the kids didn't have
computers in their homes
and this is kind of changing I think you
know I think it's much more likely than
a kid's gonna have
access to some kind of computer in the
home
but for you know the kids are in my high
school Muslim didn't
as so we had a computer lab and and we
had
teachers and parents %uh volunteered to
staff that lab after school
and out and that and now is how the
you know I was imparted that I was like
all that scary you know like I was an
intern at my high school
I really didn't get on the computer
anything and I was in college
but for the kids that were into it and
the teachers and the parents try to
place
I N that was what enabled them to
figure anything out you know so
yeah thats is as much expertise is I
have
in that area I think I think definitely
for kids under
in rural areas being able to access like
wider
resources really important and there are
some things like the Florida Virtual
School
is prolly to you big firms for virtual
school being one the other 1 I'm
like is slipping my mind at the moment
but you can a
take online classes there for credit an
that are recognized in a lot of states
not all states that a lot of states
recognize that for credit and kids can
get access to
am coursework early on that way thank
you
yet me my name's
Elliott intricate and I was wondering if
there's anything that you think is a
glaring
an a hole that we as a community can
build
curriculum are tools I am I've wet you
know
has no start to think about is like the
teaching stack like what you need
as a teacher you reach out to local
teacher what can you give them
as far as resources are tolsey is yeah I
it's really contest dependent am at Lake
at
I feel like in a little a little way
used service Lake gave me like the most
awesome like set up there for
that because I have I this idea that we
should have
a teaching section the Python dork
website
and an I don't wanna college education
think I wanna call it teaching
and I wanna find a way as getting case
you tell teachers and and and university
professors like that to that that
material in kinda put together
a set of resources a but anyway
like so that's one aspect of it and as
far as like the tooling is I think it
really depends on the resources that the
school tends to have
on so unfortunately much like
in a way that the pilot is workshops
really have to tailor
all their material to what the local
community
am is able to bring to the workshop I
think I think it's a minor you can have
to look at what the school has access to
get some schools they have like
ass unlikely next recisions others you
know they've got like windows
ninety-five pic
there's I mean it's it's pretty diverse
and difficult
environment out there so I would say
have a look at what they've got
and then you know see if cvp and create
and either VM's or you know a package
installer
and then and then blog about it so that
other people know that you made it
there are bottom efforts right now to
create
packages that work more universally this
is a huge problem for the workshop
goods the installers arm you know pip
install whatever
scanner sketchy a and you know the more
documentation that we build up about it
the better the installers will get I'm
I'm a for mile at I'm afraid we do have
ticked call time now
so could we please thanks Lena tearing a
thank you