here
good afternoon everyone it's my honor to
introduce Linda Coleman
she's a major contributor to PostgreSQL
and
she founded by ladies PDX open source
bridge
Postgres open do still keep chickens she
still keeps chickens
slut so derby warm-up and she's going to
talk about Olympic its iraq yeah there's
one that's even alive right now
skin back well dead chicken you were to
start up the stack okay so I'm
you %uh so the stock is about dearest
migrations and being seen about it
II uploaded the slimes are any sleep in
check him out there and and I wanted to
start out by
saying thank you and I'm sorry Sina Mike
Bair
to a who's there primary author Olympic
and
he Saturday the speaking after after me
so I don't think he's here right now
I and so for work
I work for Mozilla and I work on this
tool called soco role which is in
open source crash management and
a business intelligence system that we
run to
analyze primarily Firefox crashes you
can check out our source code
at that URL when you can also see our
production site that's running
and we use on back for all for
migrations and
while I have been app-icon actually my
coworkers have been running migrations
all on their own
is amazing and awesome ASO
as you might imagine from that
introduction
we use purse %uh so most
these things thank you am
a I I'm pretty sure that all the stuff I
wanna talk about today would work with
another database and I know that
Mike developed quite a bit for Oracle
but I'm just to let you know that all my
experience
has to do with using Olympic with as
Chris so I think the first thing to note
about databases is it delivery systems
and maybe they also the people that
maintain them
very much resists change and this
is my idea sir the evolution
have schema change process over time he
started out with
the yellow approach on the bottom there
and
people and another familiar with the
slash df command that that
allows you to actually at it strict
procedures and post press interactively
and the psql command line
so people do that products pretty
awesome that's gone on a
but pre camarena
evolutionary scale on and then over time
people figure out that maybe
you know they want a little more process
involved in their scanner management
they start doing things like
using revision control on their schemas
and then eventually
they do things like have a roll-back
plans and code review
and finally finally we sometimes
occasionally get
two tests that are run using generated a
ton of his honey
purity that contests on house
hey my people here K and then you might
move on to testing on prod like
data which is exciting and then finally
make it to testing
it completes each environment that has a
copy a production did and I will say
that I am
want it is very fortunate few that has a
complete copy of production
data in my staging environment and it
makes my life
a lot easier so here to say it can be
done
happens so what is seen
ski management well I think I to find
that as
executing a schema change in a
controlled and repeatable way
while you're working with developers and
also operations
I think that this is the only way that
you can get it to be controlled and
repeatable as if you have both the
developers and the operations folks can
i working together
notes the devil skewer but it it really
you really do need people
collaborating on this and the other
thing I have realized as i've
had to maintain the system for last
couple years
is a migration tools really are
configuration management tools for your
database
and one of a kind of quicksand had other
people that are working on these
problems
in some ways it can make the
conversations easier about really how
this is Manish why you need cover here
and why having downgrade scripts is
actually a really good idea
so has ever gonna talk about today
migrations there about communicating
change
communicating process and like I said X
hearing stuff
in a controlled and repeatable way with
both developers and operations
so when he came here for Olympic it's a
schema migration tool that integrates
with seek welcoming and I'm gonna get
into a lot of details about exactly how
to use it
I am i talked today might act
so my assumptions about people's
environments and why you might want to
use something like Olympic specifically
is that
human migrations are frequent automation
a schema migration as a whole
am we currently have an environment that
runs
a downgrade and an upgrade in Jenkins
before every build
afar a production code
am that your station varmint is enough
like production for testing
it doesn't have to be an exact duplicate
like ours but it needs to be enough
unease to have enough
bad data in it or whatever else it is
that you deal with him production so
that it can make it real
and also I assume that reading a small
amount of code is OK
and sometimes this can be a problem if
you're working environment where you
have to hand
things of wholesale to the DBAs I know
that
Mike wrote did Olympic with that
specific situation and mine in there are
tools built into it to help you with
that so you can just can rust sequel of
to a group of TBS if thats hired by me
runs
yeah so but no tools perfect I'm gonna
talk a little bit about some other
things that I think that
a limit kid learn and change and
things about it that that could change
in the future
I really think ultimately deviation
drive migration told twice cuz otherwise
are probably just not going to use it
and it really helps to have a toilet
DBAs and developers like
and I have to say a art darker skinned
areas both
really like go on the clock so here's
how the whole talkers are organized for
someone and share with you some day be a
problem
one specific one that I've had on her
talk a little bit about picking
the right migration to a long while a
nickel prolly work for you
and go through basic commands and talk
about lessons learned
and if I may some other things that I
think on that could learn from
my production environment
sign off that's very easy to read but
hand this is something that I had to do
to my database
not too long ago I'm and to just cut to
the punch line here it's kinda scary bit
have peel PG SQL have recently had to
drop and replace
about 200 partition constraints that had
the wrong
a constraint on them they were just
using timestamp instead of time stamped
with time zone
missus count one of those really
horrible messy d/b/a problems that comes
up that
is used as our reasoner it's an excuse
about why
people don't wanna use migration systems
this is one of those hard messy problems
that a that yeah
that you may not want to put in your
migration system
but I'm I actually used Olympic to run
mess
and that link their is the code the
actual revision file
that's in our our production release
that
has this code in it and it works really
well
and what what's act about this was this
wasn't the first time that we've had to
deal with this particular issue
I'll and it was a motivating factor for
getting Olympic into our environment
the change just sort of snack n
us sometime between January and April
into the production database
we at the time didn't have any useful
otter trail for how that happened
and some partitions were affected but
not others
and the original airdate it back to life
so it was time for us to examine the
process of how we're managing our scheme
and so I did that I broke it down
and this is what it look like
I'm so first of all we created Ross
equal
files for each change in reply test it
locally on some
some system is half an hour left up a
copy in at it some template files
recreate the old schema run and shell
script on it
update the migration on on on you know
commit things and then one other
worse most horrifying things that we had
to do was test it on stage
and then dumped the schema at a stage in
recommit that back
into our production refile I really want
to get away from this it was
it was really frustrating and often
times that staffer
committing the schema back wickets kept
because it was so
frustrating to do and this is our
process
pretty much now you know we create an
old schema
we actually use a clock made it to do
that with a model that pie
create an Olympic revision tests an
upgrade
commit their vision to the repo and
that's the last time that we touched the
production code at that point it's ready
to go
so just quickly yes so anyway
is great now to use on its management
changes
on experimentation on this particular
problem that I had revealed
you know which partitions could be
modified without deadlocking
I mean we just got to run it a a few
times over norian
to get the final change rolled out
everywhere and I was able to roll out
this partition
management change in regular business
hours
I didn't have to take a downtime to do
it which
for me was pretty amazing
so to without the visual
here's here's the steps I'm
to do this process with the limit to
make the changes to your mom about
higher maybe rustic well files you're an
Alembic revision dash a shadow generate
you editor vision file and the commit
the changes
and we also have another separate brand
re actually run manually the migration
on stage after the other to play ever
release
but another thing that we've just
started doing the last like month
is we have Jenkins run the downgrade an
upgrade as part of the test suite
and once were satisfied that that's
working well for everyone we're gonna
have migrations run automatically
on stage and may be on production are
nice little
still sketchy but I'm I'm hoping that we
get to that point
sorry I don't know if these are the same
kinds of problems are you guys run into
you back
we really wanted to have an easy way
including
and user-defined functions am in the
migrations
for dev and stage and we can embed bra
sequel in these migrations am
by default it includes downgrades which
you know if using South that's also
something
that happens there on it really enables
data is changed as a plan
this is how I get the developers to
review are changes
I send them a python file heard that
house in sick on that and they're much
more willing to review it
I'm so now we have a lot of code review
discipline in our process
I'm and the revisions themselves are
decoupled from release versions
and the branch min.order: rich I'll talk
a little bit more later
and I'll ask you promise of rest I was
able to remove a hundred thousand lines
of code
ok and that wasn't a former shell
scripts
I
and I was like the number one
contributor for that carter's so great
alteration I
I we had no more post deployment scheme
in check ans
are horrible and and now
were you know we're deploying tested you
noticed an odd
well and anyway this enabled attested an
automated stage
kleiman and we finally separated the
schema definition from
version specific configuration which is
incredibly
also important for stability so you
visit me
hi happy so happy now it's really great
I'm so if you're in the position of
needing to pick
data migration to a server choose your
own adventure a little bit
I and hear some other questions I think
it's important
can ask about a before you dive in to
any particular one
for small how often does your schema
change like if it's almost never
you may not need a tool hike Olympic
right I may just be
kinda wasted your time on do you need
the migrations well
it delivers what do you need my gracious
rerun without you and also can you
have them run without you individual
percent that knows a lot about the
schema
an are you able to test the migration
before you run and production
surprisingly this is not a question that
everyone asks
100 where they implement a system
I'm also can developers create a new
scheme I without your help
this is incredibly important for us for
new contributors because we have
outside countries contributing code to
this business intelligence system
three years for analyzing crashes and
it's kind of amazing and they really
need
too ill to do this without me a how hard
is it to get from the old schema to
anyone like we've got people that have
adopted so Coral Way way in the past
year ago and I sometimes need to
generate
her need I try to help them generate
migrations
from ancient versions up-to-date to get
them up today
I'm and also are changed rollbacks a
standard
use a patrol some people some people
don't ever go back to the donor of art
so
that's important to know whether he
better not
so for us we need to communicate change
when you apply changes in the right
order
we need apply changes only one
we need to use a lot arrest people were
needed because we have a lot of the
skill pts QR code
and we want to provide a single
interface
for those changes and finally I really
want us to be able to roll
bro back Chris Lee for stress makes that
pretty easy because if the
support for transactions which is really
nice sometimes
you know he many that another system as
well
saw I'm one thing that I struggled with
and was that the DBAs were not
super excited about what I'm gonna stand
this next
really hated the idea how to use the NRM
at all
on and and went on to say about that
is a before we implemented on Nick we
had three different ways of defining
scheme in our tests
and they were all you post
I different parts for the code and so
this is an opportunity
to show them how having a central source
or truth would be really helpful for
maintaining the schema
I'm sorry ass on USO is about having
that our Antioch
I don't have a whole lotta time to go
over all the details about this that
basically having a single source of
truth really helps a lot of stuff then
you end up with reusable components
and database version: independence from
the rest the code
on and also this ability to use rocks
equal
a some other stuff that we talked a lot
about was fitting into the existing
touring
enabling partnership with developers in
integrating in with the testing
framework
which is still something that I'm
struggling with now cuz I inherited this
huge
America that had no tests and now we at
least have a framework in
few task but you know that's kinda my
next large body of work is
implementing complete ass for our
database schema
yeah anyway this might help you if you
end up having to have that d/b/a talk
so I miss you actually using I'm back
so I wrote a blog post that walks you
through you
very practically narrative style like
how to do this
on hell that was interesting thank you
OpenOffice
am so ironic has a redox site
and the documentation there is really
great it's got a lot of best practices
built into it
some other vocabulary we're gonna have
to deal with right off the bat that may
be different
then other migrations news for small
revision
as a single migration a downer vision is
the previous migration
upgrade actually applying the change
downgrade
rolling back are downgrading and then
offline mode
which is emitting Ross equal for a
particular change
she had her on that in a minute
these are all the commands at uni to use
to set up a limit for the first time
it'll create a directory Psychonomic
slash
and then some stuff underneath their an
you know I I use for transfer all the
stuff so I put that in there too
and then when you're creating your
vision you can just a revision
and you give it a message half and put
our
a bug numbers in there as well sausage
fixes bug whatever
and their message and then you can use a
great hand and
it's got this nice position all sin
taxes while Rican downgrading its a -1
yr
minus Tanner whenever actor upgrade or
downgrade
so if you have a scheme to find an
armada higher
you don't have to do this but you can
you can just import that into your hands
up high and then
on Dec does the right thing through the
great
if you have helper functions and I have
quite a few of these for dealing with
like weird stuff that we have in our
scheme and also doing things like
applying permissions on particular
tables
for me without having to do a lot
actually work you can just import that
in your hand up I as well
make it available
I one thing that I've had to you also is
I'm just
showing you like a couple these things
show you how easy it is to come to
integrate to the typical TBA tasks in
here
but we need to ignore some scheme
elements that were not actively
a maintaining ash say in our production
database
with this particular Kobe 60 include
symbol
you can put things like ignoring a bunch
of partitions you can see there
got a regular expression to ignore
things that have eight digits
at the univer- much indicator a database
partition and I'm also ignoring the ski
Michael Dixie which were
for deprecating
another thing am that I've done is I am
managing a lot of Prosecco files
that have plp JSQ on them and I just put
a
create or replace function in there and
then I just shove the whole file in this
directory in this is how I love them
every time
a when you first set up a database
initially needed television
you're at in your Olympic return so
there's
command called stamp that's provided so
you can do that and so an example for
you might do that
is like we have a setup DB command and
then at the end of that we just stamp it
with
sir most recent revision in our system
and here's the of Lima am what you do is
you create
you're changing a leaky changer model in
some way
and then you say and then you create
your vision file which we already did
you know couple commands back and then
you tell it to upgrade a particular
vision here's where the
position all sent actually other
relatives in tax resale like -1 yr
plus one or something that doesn't work
need to use the actual
a you know actual revision id:
and then you'd just a dash dash sequel
and it will emit
rustic well a same for downgrade for you
have to do it
arrange that works great
so summer my lessons learned hand them
and dealing with implementing this
migration system
I was put the migrations in a separate
commit from
the rest of my schema changes so that if
I have to for some reason rollback or
production code I still
have the migration in the repo we deploy
our
approaching code under duress the same
would apply everywhere
so I'm this is really helped make its
way to Camelback
yeah so and then when you revert to
commit for
a general change you still have the
revision file itself
some people also separate their a
migration scripts out two completely
separate
as urs controlled retail and that might
might work better for you
I'm we and you know I try to store the
scheme objects in the smallest
reasonable
composable unit that mean different
things for you
we have a very large scheme as you may
have a
relies on a 20-yard removed her
thousands lined the code
but we use are in for the course Kiama
and then I put all the types
the user-defined functions and the views
and their own separate
sequel files I am yeah like I said
consider storing the schema and their
visions in a separate
source control repo if that's
appropriate for your environment
if you write tests run them every time
I am a we wrote a really simple tool
to generate a new schema from scratch
that we could run the tests on them
we're a simple tool to make fake data
for us
and then we also protests for those
tools from such of
and it has helped us kinda stay on us
with everything
I'm and when things failing immigration
process read another test
my more harping on testing testing
testing as have a couple more minutes 0
to quickly say here some other stuff
that I think
would be really helpful to be core
functionality in Olympic
one is just understanding database
partitions out of the box would be
really nice so they don't have to add
this thing to ignore them
a another thing would be to never to a
apply it to halt to a new column so in
progress little performance optimization
or if you don't
applied to fall I don't take out as many
locks doesn't take as long to add a
column
AB nice if the or are sorry its Olympic
understood that
I'm help us manage user defined
functions little better that's a tall
order but
her be so awesome if a there was service
in the Salish patterns
the pattern that we have having the
separate files works pretty well
but there are some drawbacks to it
having on it understand index
concurrently
when we're at it indexes would be really
nice on
having a little bit prettier syntax for
multi committee Francisca sometimes I
need to do things in a certain order and
I don't want my entire
a migration to run in a single
transaction
be nice if there's little prettier
syntax for that
and finally am this is something that
Mike Rd
his or and and wants work on can have
some
stuff out there for is supporting
multiple branches in history currently
your history with Olympic just needs to
be in a single order which I understand
is different than
am urging the immigration system and so
in the future
that's gonna be possible and I have some
ideas for maybe like a
sprint thing on Monday for hacking and
something but he's got some great ideas
for making this work
a more holistically in future
so just to close on I'll say
in looking out the different roles in
our particular school is perfect for all
situations
I think Olympic personally well for us
because we have a large
we have a large schema amber really our
team is really into on a mission we have
a really good relationship with our
operations
team so that works for for us
and I think that a big part of that was
choosing a tool that both the developers
and the DBAs could could like
at the same time so I'm awfully
hopefully this subcontractors you
something mister from sure some other
tools that I looked at
in my person my researching your
suggests definitely giving them a look
if
on it doesn't seem to fit for your use
case
and then hear some resources related to
lameque helper
faulty a thank you
so if anyone has questions for so you
know we have a five minutes for
so I think you missed a step in the 20
to 10 churches I'm
is the toolkit yours isn't still
maintained aa effect suggests
possibly techniques for migrating from
one migration system to another
migration system
not naming any names here but I need to
make a migration I
well so when I
when I did this I E want one thing the
Olympic enables is you don't have to
have on
like it completes you don't have to
start from zero
with it all so I just dove and and
started writing
migrations based on what the current
define skin was and I didn't even bother
migrating any the old stuff and i'd just
removed
so yeah
and it wasn't a requirement from our
Open Source users that we make those
migrations
work I'm I don't have a lot of great
suggestions
I was talking to someone a couple days
ago about what they were planning on
doing and basically they
the restaurant or to translate the old
migrations finance our
sorry it's a crappy situation I'm in my
my my best suggestion is set play
ignoring
and a smear foreign yeah got two quick
questions for you want as you mentioned
a tool to generate data
is that open source is that you have a
name for that project
oh yeah yeah now on
I know if I can cell
so my whole thing that we did its it's
very specific to us
and so I don't know if it will be very
helpful but it might be a good pattern
but the score repo itself which is just
mazzola CL put up this
action and so if you go to this a car
repair
an in there researcher fake data
dot pie Rob Homer wrote that and
it sir great you know first step we
we talked about trying to turn it into
like a more modular scalable not really
sure what other people needed so if you
talk listen to last like how we could
make that better weekend
spell it out cool thanks are many other
question you
base you touched on how South angry
scissors sequential how does
Olympic dress exert their sequential now
I'm back
there's some plans an architecture
designed to
make it so that you can have you know
multiple
children from one parent and thats you
note that some work that mike has
that's ongoing that you can use funding
for anybody's got
deep pockets that would be awesome
that's that's the plan
referred to be there my idea for like a
quick hack
is just to create a file that generates
conflicts when you try to merge
and and so I'm I'm prolly gonna hack
something like that and for us
that's that's kinda biggest stumbling
block for developers is still
commit to a migrations at the same time
that are unrelated
and then Olympic is like don't do not
her
and Jenkins was a but I'm that's really
the only
the major the only major operation think
we need to fix it this time
so you also said
that you run migrations during the
testing step on your
continuous integration server yes
database migration gonna take a long
time how do you do that
in a reasonable amount of time yeah
I well their
II the short answer is on I use
every possible trick in the book that I
can to make
migrations take out as few lakhs as
possible and to apply the changes as
quickly as possible in all situations
regardless of how much data is involved
an
so that's that's my quick answer there's
a longer answer
which is very long but yeah I just use
lotsa tricks
and I teach the developers like how to
do that stuff so I have and
a presentation I gave that are last team
work week you know that
was basically less tricks to make the
migrations run fast unfortunately it's
all we have time for let's give Selina
the ground repost