in
alright sorry about the delay
at the next up is by andrew goodman he's
one of the core Python developers and
he's gonna be talking about designing
jan was migrations
begin hand
hello one home for now am hello everyone
I'm Andrew as you've just been
introduced and the speaker stopped
working
area and and so as crews mentioned I'm a
jacket or developer
but I'm also the author of South the
popular jiang et migrations library
I'm thank you I've been doing this
for one now feels like an age is
actually a seven years
them and south is seven years old I
think in September this year
and so throughout all those many years
I am I've always thought migrations
they're pretty good
they've proven themselves useful South
has been very very popular
more popular I would ever imagined to
start out with ants
it's fantastic I've had people count me
saying them
they know they're writing and he is in
PHP but they still use jangan South
migrations yeah I just after the
solutions
that's kinda reassuring for me but
underlying this whole thing for last 7
is amazing South
he s it was good it was good for its
time it hats
a couple of bad design decisions
initially done
I'm and never to seven years ago I was
much more novice programmer back then
understandable as the years gone by at
got feedback between teeth my users
I realized that actually there are some
call on the line problems in South
and not only is it so they've call the
slight idiosyncrasies
is designed but also is lives next
Django is a third party library
it's not incurred while into cause I
should be there the model south of hacks
that is there purely
to be that integration the Django its
cool hack for reason is very obvious
light no sign that this is the bat by
the house with for love horrible changes
since to lapse the settings
runtime: filled with the RM in the app
cache in that's not good
and so about two or three years ago
me in some other call developers site
for making an initial plan for this
the idea was that we take south and we
take the
to abstraction back and got a bit better
take your database and turns into a nice
easy liar you can use and take that and
put into Jack itself as a
schema abstraction back and kind of
thing at the same time we put in there
some RM hopes that we get to the hacks
much on South
things like be able to change your
models at runtime be able to serve
load and unload for versions models and
CRM without how individual
settings this'll seemed fine am as a
a site that the same time the families
that we would have south to
and South he would be this other reverse
South a different format
by the user interface but using
underlying tanker library
now that was a should have good start
the idea
but when you look at the overall south
as well as libraries the
is one of the very few things in Django
everyone seems to use is almost the
unanimous thing that everyone present
migrations
and wanna john has big problems
historically is that for a new user
especially
you can be very hard to the side what
likely to use robot like you know if
you're going for
wreck I'm API's used rest ring want to
use piston develop many other month
and so on every other kind of thing and
so there is some value to having
a blessed optional were preferred option
the stuff
I family went on further the revised
plan was that but we would have
is migrations bills into Django itself
know it's such a fundamental part of the
way you are allocations
and for new users you to bring and
introduced into it
early on and so is felt that actually it
makes little sense
kohut Django it's a very underlying
crucial part of the label the
publications
and so possible incurred but the same
time
these are still logically separate items
I'm I've kept that separation between
the scheme abstraction back and and
migration sort of
front end user interface built into
Django itself
so even when 1.7 has released a new
start using this
you'll be using to obstructions talking
to each other and that means that if you
want to write your
own version of the migrations library if
you want to change the database at
runtime for
some kind of mad crazy reason we have
other reasons to sort of change not the
schema
that back and especially your idea to a
good API its well-defined and you can
step down and use a straight away
not have about those in second but I
first went to cover the key thing here
the I am NOT moving south and the Django
I am adding migrations in Django
I am this is a complete rewrite the
South code they are somewhat similar
incident ideas logic
but a lot of the code has been rewritten
on those migration fall home at three
different
to use interface income although very
different and so it is not the south
you know directly prepares a lot
assertive external similarities to
especially the way organizes and runs
migrations
the kind of asking writer and face the
scheme reduces is this
part of the database backends that
obstructs the scheme or operations over
databases in the same way the RM
abstract things like select Update and
Delete
ever databases the scheme editor blast
right things like CREATE TABLE drop
table Craig index dropped index and
things like that
as you'll see later at the end to the
talk this is very important for some
particular tree databases
is also written to work in touch and it
feels and models so
I'm South for those few of many with it
it works and turned the tables and
columns which is a great for the
starting point for doing
tables rationing my kinda stuff but it's
sorta falls down with more complex
column types in Django
and so what this does instead is it to
give
takes the malls and feel themselves and
then example a foreign key
have a certain name is naturally but the
column name is on the school ID
and with this other slightly higher
level interface
and the new migration stuff has a much
better idea love
what is changing what is staying the
same and it can too much more
intelligent things to have to feel
house models it can know the possum
future versions a field
taken to task strictly I'll minor things
you couldn't do properly
when yes South had just he should have a
name
has your field type and go legislative a
sequel artistically important
the mcdyess a dove other part this is
why I article
Django .tv migrations were just
migrations this is
kinda it's not separate if i Jankovic it
is
somewhat self-contained this is where
you have things like
the user interface other commands for
running I am
migrations the commands for Scott
migrations into one can also making
migrations
and you'll have to call framework with
migration from a kid's things that read
and write migrations files
think the result dependencies into
serialized so straight through plans
and things like the old detector which
I'll come to again the second
but when it does it takes your migration
state picture current models file
and it works for the difference between
them and that's how it can make
migrations for you
but underlying all this is a brand new
migration for
now for those who are familiar I'll show
him the slide
this is the old south migration for my
now it's very very small
I had five until my screen here but I've
highlighted their the top
so the I say faithful sick for that is
the actual coach on migration
this is making a simple table with three
columns the
the rest about file is what's called a
frozen Iran
saw South does is it takes the entire
history of your application
and freeze it into this big subjective
serialized fields in arguments
so I can reconstruct malls around time
that obviously not a great idea
I'm as you can see it's very verbose and
this is quite a small file
if any %uh view from these production
you will have seen files that are
much much love is my second half haha
second
56 and so the ID he was called the more
concise format
and not only that but a format that was
introspect on the carotid
this what you see here all is is it's a
class with two methods
fourth method and a pack which method
when you wanna migration
South just call the fourth method
positing an object that can make schema
changes
and then just let it run this is great
for sympathy in for the nice API
but it means you can't help immigration
will do but actually running it
and if you don't want to market the
databases that have stop alcohol fake
scheme object of my day in
fun through them the method itself hope
they're not call any month in the
process and record with the changes
so the change your status is clarity
format
and this is one where often having a
method you have issues operations
which themselves by simply I will
forward them back its methods
but the nice thing here is that I can
look at this migration in code as well
as
with just text editor I can see this is
crazy model
and you also noted that this is the
whole operation there's no second half
it this is
I all me a seven or eight significant
lines of code here
and the reason for that is that we have
was now called in memory running
so the thing that made these long so
they've pieces a
frozen are in before that announced that
dynamically generated from these
operations
what we do is we load of the migrations
in the full history of the project into
memory
and those operations was having a player
bring the database for words
have a special method that's called
State forward
more but does it as a representation of
the models and at the fields
in an in memory subject like object will
project state and that mutations that
goes
and so incredibly fast dissolving trying
Dixon sativus changes
we can run through every migration in
history buildup on a project States and
then you can
so they've friend about Project state
into an RN itself into a set of models
and that means that we can discard all
back strings information and just
take migration from remember in memory
takes your 10 milliseconds
and then you have a copy of miles way to
go and the money that you saw running
migrations
is also good for the order detector for
the altar detector
takes top run-through version as a hub
for taken on disk version
an indigenous goes through and test them
like what model are here
onto the old version what models have
called disappeared what has changed
assorted compares intelligently and try
to find remains a matching promises
things like that
and said it's a very useful way of doing
all the stuff but
but kinda the knife logical side
migrations little clean code is lovely
if that's possible like dutiful computer
science the world live
ship your obstruction I'm database
themselves are unfortunately
much much worse am there are
peculiarities
unique to each database but after work
through unfortunately South him the
plant experience in most of these
amber outside a run through them for you
here one by one
upon his post-race it's great let's move
on a
the second one
that's kinda PR stride sure his postrace
by the way
the second one is my sequel now my
sequel is a reasonable database
thats tempering my at reactions slightly
a bit as a few key problems
so number one DDL a state official
language that seems like tray table
drop table at index and it's not
transactional
so even they michael has transaction
some other time in in a TV mode
those transactions just finally stop
themselves commit when you try and run
things like at table at column and so
this means that
if migration fails part way through we
can roll back
and on post grades we just go okay
migration filed under: will think he
didn't allow
unfortunately my seat we can't do that
and so migration files and bicycle
you're kinda left up to run devices you
know it's the thing like well
we don't think o'clock and then you to
go in the diving then be yourself
I'm fortunate often not too bad a
situation is all
my just like I did one column in The
another one but it's a really annoying
thing for use at have like kevin is one
whole world have
jus running a command both myself but
I've into database in
typing come on to remove columns
manually so
that's amazing at my school also didn't
have check constraint which is
%um Gemini fine after the easy thing had
to deal with
we just happen says if this tatouages
feature
and that Jan graphical features like
this is like the sad face
supposed to be off transactions this
database has things like check
constraints
it is not there we just sort of know
about how that anything to deal with
and finally SS pumping work and freight
the idea of unique constraint indexes in
my signal F on the sign in the same
namespace
essentially so this means that whenever
you should have Creighton
remove a unique constraint you also into
effect in the end as well
we get round the having sorta almost do
because have different names for them
but its
annoying side effect is not really as
good as it should be
over cialis more fun in a certain sense
what fun
and or cialis generally fine its for so
very old mature database
but at a different simple syntax but if
things like things like counters and
triggers and stuff
the the language is different my second
high-stress
and is very picky about names he counts
I think stop name to the number imposed
in
Oracle them from a shorter length
friction on things like that
and it has some unique all sort of
behaviour committing to a from
a text field Django's have put the aloe
b.com title
inge orkut you just can't do that and so
in the back and we have to
at new column up dayton was later
crossed leave your common rename a new
column
which is a patent for Miley to sickle
light
I am the sequel lights
the idea of having skin migrations is
kinda like having pics fly
it's technically possible if you have
like enough equipment
it's probably not advisable I'm sequel
lighthouse
just to DDL statements bed the other
thing adding more but
has he has Craig table at column there's
no to the table with
there is a drop table sorry but there's
no to the column as I alter column
the snow sitive Brunton and this is and
to top it all off
there is no way to see Polanski was a
wrong time a park in a CREATE TABLE
statement
you do you till he gets like that but I
lovee seaports while former
it looks really nice in the terminal be
at a manly posits equal
or you can do other things things but to
get it back to its it much harder to
book with
and be flexible light it's not designed
for this see collided hun tastic
embedded database
really good about it is not designed to
run production that's light on please
don't do it
I am if you want is a for development
that's fine be prepared to witness
especially remember the sequel like
doesn't enforce constraints nearly as
much as the other two databases
so you can put the wrong tights and
columns and things and say when you put
the data across you may find doesn't fit
and used to be the sequel light was
because House press hard to install on a
Mac
back and fix now has a has pressed of
exists please go and use it
but that's kinda you know part of the of
the course we're developing migration
like
Django Hafiz historical thing if
supporting
you know for official back and the many
more unofficial back ends and
1 I'd love to develop house cuz any
solution i'm too much realists and
pragmatists and let us pass a realistic
solution
not gonna tell them the as compatibility
Django's
traditionally been quite good about
possibility we very rarely break stuff
in a
in a1 release pomp I'm sometime today
with a very good reason for it
and general even get all the way from .9
sick for 21.6
I know I've done this took a long time a
whole evening
without breaking much hope so cute do
the companies jumped 33 states make few
changes to the next jump in Seoul
that's about twice to this new be right
as well the money to Django
south is it South exists and South also
the pope said that these migrations
something as compatible with police me
too big nor properly
and so I've mall for a long time over
this the first version of the code for
this
the Alpha didn't have many ways of doing
this and in the end
a cantor very reasonable solution so
what happens is when immigration
is detected as the first migration
application haven't been applied
so basically you got a brand new app
that while some 1.6 got no time I
seventy at first migration
what China day because introspect was
gonna read more than their
it says OK will read all the trait model
statements work have a multi-table be
called
I'll see the tables cyst if those tables
exist it just
marks is applied didn't just as markets
down already marked by
and was on with his life and that means
that you can upgrade to 1.6 1.7
just by having an issue migration and or
to apply everywhere you want it to you
and it happens abductions happen
development happened every machine
it's a very painless process the poor
thing I is about three four lines like
this
saying move after migrations from this
come on
done to move south harder
and South have the same naming
convention is the migrations for its
files which is a
ap slash migration slash number
something for popeye
am what this kid code does is its will
try and put those that matter
naming convention and it catches the
enquirer's case the South file
and has a big nose it for you so any
move to South leading migrations
we have to do is make sure everything
right the newest version which is
I think the South I'm want on all the
new version you can
what you like rations way and a by
noonish migration on this new version
which is kinda what you do to sitive up
a South abandon migration set anyway
but in all of this will the lessons
we've learned like I've
been working through this project for
about you in a bit now
and has been for love French singing
think discovered long way
the first is this I for the summer
before I'm
this in Perth explicit but an implicit
amp a lot of migration stuff
in South was kinda implicit like the
structure the way it works
the code is all conventional mostly you
call code
and the new format is much more
explosive force it has less for
operations
if force in order to force atomic nurse
and that's pretty nice
and Alton on a topical that a all the
important out but
file with a much better way of resolving
those and so you can't I've integration
and the even more human-readable scandal
now may have a world which is
actually fantastic striking a base is
hard
this is Johnny a problem with any
instruction if you
told him on one thing you go downtown
denominator
Knauss migrations is not the lowest
common denominator
it is set about that we can like no if
you trying to certain operations on my
single week ago
no same basic light so there's there's
some advanced
stuff there but purely by supporting the
databases
we have to kowtow somewhat the housing
I can support things like post presence
am building that in the background
easily because that doesn't really fit
into the general flow
Django and so pricing this from scratch
for a new project
what I support more Beebe's possibly not
it depends on the Jersey like I think
poses for a two-base
I think it's very popular used but in
the jungle world materialists
and you know we have tripled as
backgrounds
compatibility is really good now the
health stuff for the Sabres code YouTube
operations
not only does that mean we can't respect
them well I can do with my Scotch
migrations which is when you basically
take
you know a hundred migrations history
and moving down to palm
I'm in South you can't do that was
markedly absent money writing you wanna
make an initial one for the route
channeling am in the new one what you do
is you
take under migrations extracted
operations for them on big list
they will compose or they're all Tomic
and then take less than an optimizer
under the licence hate that word the
treatment Lee they can optimize away
patent abner rename you can pronounce
the at optimize the list down down down
down down to fund a small that can
at this wine only optimizing I'm the
correct history like you got from like a
custom
command in their custom sequestration ok
awesome I'll they've
they stay in there but not in my eyes
way or the other be done stuff like you
can push
at columns and create tables taken
counsel at home
the columns like kinda stuff and it
makes all that and also the internal
code so much better
and finally feedback is vital I'm seven
years a feedback
i think is what has helped me out with
this math like I E
I develop web sites but beasley large
ones these days I am
for I can see everything and there are
people out there who are far more crazy
than I am and it's a good thing
they do horrible things migrations and
tables and they are the people who send
me feedback and bug reports
and they are how I've managed to fix the
horrible horrible part migration for
some nasty edge case you go on a signal
that committed now have the season and
they find it
all they find it and about I is very
important in in getting this to be a
nice table much of a make sure that it's
much more reliable and thing else is
and the last thing the next slide my
last flight
the last slide I miss you very lazy but
thanks on their I might
name to handle like against on great
thing from Sep
far on their and then and that way am
this is a bit different
migrations was made possible thanks to
kicks off campaign Iran
which raise over 17,000 pounds sterling
just just under thirty thousand US
dollars
am and it was all thanks to concoct
community contributions paying for my
time to write this
call the huge creature in a tangle and
so rather thanking me
late also thank everyone contributed
thank you very much
attack
have time for a few questions sir is to
have
yes a.m. I'm curious when I can have
this
so the scheduled release 1.7
is May 15 for them on the Aussie I think
it's sunny mid might end of May
and Django as a start getting never
actually made early states
I have
a I'm in charge this time JSF
I'm in charge the southerly so it will
hopefully be on time not very close to
it so and
my is my rock s I was wearing fur
migrations that require data changes are
like actual I like running commands a
change data in the tables how panels are
so there are operations the you can
write in Manali called fun seek one run
python
principal takes up toughen single string
and a strong that from Hixson
you could be possible function and you
get a scheme editor objecting to that
you like so
laxative ops if you drop a customer you
can optimize past those capacitive
opaque box
but they also left you want them think
again
for the talk I I'm wondering how do you
deal with
I am now that people use get everywhere
with branching
and I know that the Alembic kinda try to
deal with that and try to deal with
conflicts and people work in different
branches and you have to like
merge conflicts and I'm just wonder how
yeah what a question and so southeast a
strike
I'm sort of their history the Croft
migration number seed have
01 02 03 ani: product to our polls
and that's not good I'm the new stuff it
tracks explicitly
explicit and implicit the parent
repackage migration so
it knows as a forgiving that's for
people to stop
tell you you pretty much conflict and it
will offer you
if it detects the two sides are
compatible of your customers option
which will make a second migration
parent both ago this is fine remains the
bubbly I'm so there is
now protection there some like fixing
unlike code
merging is a lot harder like if it fits
any into possible compatibility
ill just block stop thanks is there any
plan for migrating myself migrations
to you'd agenda item migrations should I
just declare
migration bankruptcy start the hash
homeland fortunately I'm
the plaza yet to throw your own history
I'm yet sup migrations a
just been open for top so
one common problem with sites that are I
am that see a lot of traffic
is dealing with migrations that can
cause some
inconsistency or some down time in there
have been some various techniques trying
to do you serve
zero downtime migrations have you
thought about what about something that
could be systematized and brought into
Django I that as a future definitely say
important to like 1.7 I am for my rough
plan for this was to have
the operations can say her back and if
they are blocking and non-blocking
someone post-race adding and & Noble
column is non-blocking happened Tanksley
I said then you have a motorway say this
migration
with block I'm thinking go people lockup
a table
arrival have everything and sounds like
some kind of pain and then your
the people of people can go okay this on
site begins run it
this one is now blocking it Africa so
some something light up
will come eventually sweetie
K mama question please more
was there any overlap work order use
between
Django migrations MC block me a landmark
seems a more projects this do for the
submissions
sucks questions or is there are
overlapping or code reuse between
Django migrations and Siebel welcome
your lender can if you want them
I mean that they could be having so I
haven't been fired by
out Alembic another other frameworks in
packs of antifreeze in RM thing was a
spy by I'm a frame up to love
I just took the idea and then consumed
and not have at me
but there is something that
unfortunately I
my cock roaches getting this done and
seal of me and Jen is RM the car
different levels like janice was much
much higher level two copies or lower so
federal they were I did sharing and
reviewing the unfortunately I'm glad for
you
but you like everybody thank you
half
think month