II everybody thank you for your patience
I'd like to introduce Greg Ward is going
to talk about
how unit testing Mexico better thanks
everyone
from so unit testing
his more listings that um everybody
believes and everybody everybody says
it's a good thing but
how many people really do it i i'd like
a quick shower and how many people
rigorously write unit tests for every
peace up code the right every
day of their lives production code work
code personal projects
yeah me neither how many you do at most
the time for most code
especially when you're being paid money
yeah that's about where I am
um excellent you're my heroes um
so you know it's kinda like public
transportation that's the joke
everybody everybody things are ever
other people should do it
so I've got a couple assumptions about
you for this talk
um I'm assuming that you either just sat
through
net Batchelder Zacks 1 talk and your
ready raring to go you've started to
drink the koolaid
or you're already actively drinking the
koolaid you're already
into the unit test mindset um in other
words I'm not your did
teach you unit testing magistead back
from
so the corollary of assumption number
one is
you already get that unit testing helps
make your code
more correct I'm not going to try to
convince you that
it is obvious is trying to convince you
that water is where are the sky is big
when I say that unit testing makes your
code better I'm talking on the
a higher plane i'm talking about.
L'Agence
aesthetics beauty back kinda stuff so if
you're honest people
who says al against Sri elegance I just
wanna get something working on a ship it
I want customers or users running my
code now or as soon as possible
that's great I'm a big fan of shipping
code
arm despite what some might pass
managers might tell you um
but let me try to convince you that
beautiful code is better code it takes a
little more time up front
but in the long run it pays off its
easier to understand its easier to
extend it easier to reuse
unit testing makes your code more
beautiful it makes it
better so the plan
for this talk is to work your real-life
case study this is not some
imaginary made up example this is this
is a real live code from my real life
job
that did not have any unit tests when I
started barry months ago
I'm good briefly sketch the process a
batting tests to this code but
that's not really the focus a bit awk
back that was next job
and he did a great job thank you net arm
I'm standing on a trident demonstrate
how in perfect design leads to Harry
tasks and Harry design
her hairy tasks are smelled it tells you
the design is in perfect
and when you modify the designed so that
your tasks become simpler you have
better code you wind up in this virtuous
cycle where simpler tasks means better
Croydon better code means simpler tests
so the background I have to spend a few
minutes explaining
like I said this is real life code where
did that come from why does it exist
are it's got certain requirements that
mandate
a few slight peculiarities about the
code most importantly what requirement
doesn't me because
while the code we're going to look at is
not perfect its
pretty darn good code I'm if you see the
totality of it I'm
unfortunately going to focus on the
kinda smell your bets but the whole
module that i'm talking about. was
really quite beautiful
and it met its requirements all I was
there to do was add some unit tests
because I couldn't resist so from
we meaning my employer and look at her
hyperlink their
are in the business of measuring the
Internet and we do that a couple ways
on one way is we've we paying every IP
address in the world every couple months
more relevant we trace route all over
the world from all over the world all
day long
we collect about 200 million trees
through today
and
and 200 million traceroute works out to
about 3
billion hops every single day so trying
to extract
some sort of intelligent meaning from
this tore into data
and when you're dealing with that much
data
obviously clearly you need a super duper
highly advanced next generation
whiz-bang
data storage in representation
technology which is why we mostly use
tab separated text files arm yeah I mean
yeah we used
Postgres minutes the right to amuse read
this when it's the right tool but
we have vast stores have data in
tab separated taxed arm
there are some obvious I hope our
problem the problem maybe not so obvious
rules for staying sane
with plain text plain text is a very
simple data format
keep it simple stupid on you you really
want to restrict the data tightly if
you're using tabs you to limiter
don't have any tabs in your day to make
sure you filter them out first
if you're using common for your
delimiter don't have any comments on
your data
et cetera um and you want to come stay
consistent on a metal level your
here requirements again of all over the
year to date is going to evolve over the
years
but if you have a road a consistent
philosophy a consistent approach a
consistent metaphor Matt
it will make your life easier and and
that scanner
what were moving to recently over the
last couple years I think
so here's an example taken from are
real-life data
I we have a whole bunch of file formats
with cryptic little names like t3 and
tip 1:
have no idea where those cryptic little
names come from there may be a couple my
colleagues in the room her
I'll probably buttonhole afterwards to
ask why t3 but anyways that's what it is
to 283 file contains one
record or one line for every traceroute
that we sent
and remember there are 200 million it is
a day
so there's a fielder's and these are all
just tap separated field you've got the
name at the data for are you gonna
timestamp
ICMP because that's the protocol we use
and then blah blah blah and then towards
the end is a
variable is to field 22 tracert
sometimes a tracer did he hops long
sometimes it's 15 hop song
so this is not a completely trivial tab
separated text file there's a variable
number records on each line
from kinda interesting a little bit
quirky but this is the requirement to
bed
the data the business here's another
example
are if you've got text files containing
200 million tracer today
bet too much you need to reduce the day
you need to shrink it down extracted
and one other thing one of the things we
extract from that is another format with
another short cryptic name called
tip 1: which is a record each record is
a daily summary of all the traces sent
to a single target
so again and the first field is
the name in the data format and the
timestamp is then for the day not for a
particular second
there is the IP address and the target
there's a network pre-fixed its routed
by
there's some geolocation data to
latitude and longitude in it Tabitha got
swallowed
cuz that's what happens to tabs on you
put them into a presentation in a web
browser
others more geolocation data from
there's information about the provider
and at the very end there's this
peculiar dismisses lasting at the brain
is a rather peculiar looking single
field it's really a key value mapping
from the name of the collector where we
ran the traceroute
mapping to the number of times we saw
this target on a given day
on which is interesting so
again again it's not entirely trivial
for I cuz theres
one single field at the end which is
actually a key-value mappings
210 keys and values in it to little bit
complex and
it but it's an example above the the
metaphor Matt we've gotta love
tab separated values where the first
column that every line is the data
format
every column has a name and type most
types are simple streams and in some
floats
there are some complex types in there
some complex fields
like a comma-separated string in mapping
right the files are all utf8 encoded
thank goodness
very often they're stored on disk be
stepped
not guaranteed but very often we just
want that to be handled transparently
three have a common it's not a common
format it's a common
metaphor Matt we have dozens of data
formats like this that are all
fundamentally the same at a very high
level but particularly details what
fields and what this feels mean the data
types are
while be different so you could go down
there
the rhodium writing a new parser for
every single format me we're all look
very very similar to be very
tedious repetitive duplicate code but
who wants to do that so we have this my
break on generics
line parser arm and there are many
subclasses there's a
8 trivial subclass 43 files which reveal
from classwork tip 1 files in
like 15 or 20 more trivial subclasses
now look pretty much the same cuz they
all do pretty much the same thing
us the requirements for staying I'm
structured data
has to be fast most the time or at least
you have to have the ability to make it
fast because
parsing out a comma-separated key value
mapping can be slowing up to 100
million up from or know that was 1.5
million anyway it's a lot
you gotta have the ability to not parse
those fields when you don't need to
must be flexible enough that it is
trivial to define new formats
to the good news about this code apart
from being
eighty percent beautiful lovely code it
met all these requirements
sorta show you an overview of this class
as it existed before ours
who started reading tests for got a
constructor
mister method parse method course
the line parser must have a parse method
and then there's a communion
read method which strictly speaking
doesn't need to be there
it's not a file object it is the line
parser
by you now 99 percent a time when you're
parsing lines guess where they come from
text files on desk so it's really handy
to have a read method
but when you look closer that
constructor has
rather a lot of arguments and monomers
letter after
so like single letter verbal names are a
funny smell to me
I'm and and I read method
rate should just be a one-line rapper
but it actually does progress logging
sir cash strange stuff so
having an escape this like has not
really helpful so track
so shown you the outline a class
now it's time to writing unit tests for
you start will you
got an object class right and project
class tonight wine purse I can't testing
instant rabbit if i cant constructed so
I always start with the constructor
and usually constructors are trivial
doesn't matter
I still start by testing the constructor
because you can have a typo anywhere
arm in a case like this really
constructor has 45 optional
arguments are which all affect the
behavior of the constructor or of the
class or both
definitely I start was testing the
constructor
so before I show you the test I wanna
show you some any internal structure in
this beast
on and and already
something smells funny from because
F might be a string so it's a file name
own oh no no I might be a file or abuse
it
file so to file or it might be in
iterable so it's
a sequence of something am out gotta
give a game where two sequences lines
profiles a sequence apply to but it's
also a file I'm all but sometimes that
is nine
far so too many kodak's hey if if you
count this up
from the the traditional computer scienc
definition
but I began learned before there is such
a thing as exceptions in mainstream
programming languages so that
every branch near you count the number
of branches in the coding you take
22 the number of branches are like a
branch is an air frame house
22 the number of branches match the
number possible paths through this
function this constructor and I i think
they're in nine
branch points here depending on how you
can try except which means they're 512
pads
through this code 512 ways this could be
executed depending on the different
arguments
so do I have to write 512 test cases god
I hope not
arm ugg another thing
if this class is a line parser why does
occur so much a file names
profile names have to do with parsing
lines why is that
remitted there so it's a line parser and
a file opener and a file reader
and possibly a little overloaded so who
bad rap Inc sorry about that on so it
turns out I did not have to rate 512
test cases for this beast even though
there are
theoretically 512 code pads I got away
with six
which is about five more test cases that
I want to write for a constructor
but I can't fix the design until I have
the tasks
to Tommy I haven't broken anything so I
have to rate the six test cases
one for the constructor with minimal
barebone arguments
one for the constructor with the file
name another one for the constructor
with the file name ending in be said to
you
may have noticed it checks does the
family man with be said to you if so do
other stuff
arm I had there is our are you have to
pass a file object in and make sure that
works
and then got these out of order some our
and in there and after I implement that
those five
coverage told me hey you missed in
except block there is an error
you have to take also I wrote a test
case that tickles that particular
on exception that air conditioned to
make sure that iris hitting all the code
arm so
six test cases which like I said it's
about five more than I want to rate for
a constructor constructor shoot
constructors should be dead simple they
should just take some arguments
store them and do nothing in the ideal
case
are constructor should not do I know
constructors should not pass go or
collect $200 dollars
issue just store stuff from
thrown start fixing that this
constructor is overloaded doing too much
om it's a line parser it should parse
lines
something else should open files now I
mentioned we've got some requirements
like these files often leave on disk be
zipped
but not always and I just want to be
transparent my application Raiders
shouldn't have to care if the file is
busy tonight should just work
which is why there's that specially bet
that special case for looking at the
file name ends with be there too
it's not there just for fun it's there
because %uh village in it legitimate
business requirement
just in the wrong place what we need is
a convenience function that opens files
whether they're compressed or not right
it's just a little bit more fancy than
the built-in open function
and because these files are utf8 encoded
we should do something about that
so we want a function that opens a file
eyes utf8 gives back
Unicode objects rather than strings and
then we need composers to an
yeah sure you could compose those two in
every single application you right
or we could just put use at opening in
our local library and
and the story now we've got three
convenience functions
arm you can open files isley
and now you don't need a line parser to
open files for you it can parse lines
so after creating doing this reef act
during the constructor
gets simpler arm you'll notice
that af is no longer a strained calf is
either 9
or a file or abusive file morning
iterable
and really those last three cases are
really on the same writer file abuse add
file
herbie that file an iterable they're all
just sequences have lines so there's
more work to clean up your butt
who I got rid other opening files
stuff arm that's awesome that's progress
and back was revealed to me or that was
the way to this restructuring was late
with me to open to me by writing tests
in two ways number one looks
yeah I'm forgetting how to myself a
little bit haha
so yet before I star waxing
eloquent look what happens to the tests
we used to have
six test cases summer overture of the
bottom of the screen I can get rid of 3
a.m.
announced that having five test cases
too many I only have two
test cases too many axle in progress
I am constructor is simpler and shorter
and now we've got generic code
anybody can use you not tied to generic
line parser if you need is convenient
way to open be zipped files are utf8
files
so not only have I made this particular
class
more focused and concise have a better
utility library
I have support for G zip files for free
it's not just be zip
have less test code to maintain have cut
the number of test cases
in half and those have you heard med
talk
ruled now realize test code is real code
to the you have to maintain and look
after
anyone last test code if you can get
away with it and there if your code pads
to worry about
on there's lots more reef acting to do
here if I wanted to
I'm not going to its only a 25 minute
talk after all
arm all these things
are more of the same the tasks there's
too many tasks
the tester to Harry because the design
is overloaded
when a make the design simply the tests
get smaller and simpler and
it just this beautiful virtuous cycle or
everything gets
better and shiny ring happier and people
go home with a smile on their face
so what's the big deal I okay every
factor too messy code
now whatever don't we all do that every
day
are no know from what I've seen a most
programmers know we don't all agree
factor messy code every day
arm and what
made this possible was the unit tests I
could not have done this with a writing
unit tests
I would not have known a needed to do
this without writing unit tests because
the unit tests showed me
or the writing unit tests forced me to
read the code in great detail
in to see what's going on here
what is it doing why is it doing it and
perhaps
it should be refactored to this summer
this functionality is available
through another way arm
maybe see both the good side and bad
side this code like i said i IR
kinda had shrunk this down to a very
cartoonish sketch this
class eighty percent of it is really
quite
lovely beautiful code just the
constructors doing too much now as one
or two methods that are maybe a little
overloaded
so in my saw the good and the bad
an what writing the test did his the
be desist this sounds hokey this sounds
like i'm ok
revival tent preacher upon any actually
am revival tent preacher I'm trying to
convert you to the religion and unit
testing it sounds hokey but
it gave me the courage to re factor this
class arm
this is something the unit testing
zealots like me like to boast about
arm you can't refractor code that you
can do you don't ask because how do you
know its
not broken and having written these
tests I have absolutely no fear
about tearing generic line parser to
pieces and putting it back together
again even though I didn't write it
on I'm riche I really why would love to
give you a happy ending to this talk but
unfortunately I can't yet because
we have a lot of coded uses generic line
parser
I'm much more confident in this class
cuz now it has tests
but all the applications that use it
don't have tests I am afraid to re
factor them
I know it's a trivial transformation I
know I can do it if you just give me an
hour 3
but I don't know if I've done it right I
might introduce a typo I may miss some
subtle detail
and I'm afraid to refactor because those
other things that depend on generic line
parser don't have
tests and the best I can do is make a
patch
and ask the maintainer to test it for me
because
to rate things are done unfortunately
and not
reviews the costs have not testing from
obviously the the been one of BS costed
not testing is
you we'll have bugs untested code
is buggy code I guarantee it I have
never
written tests for a piece of code that
did not have bugs in it
because untested code is buggy code
guaranteed
but more subtly it leads to the fear
every factoring for every fracturing
need to code duplication
all code has bugs especially untested
code
when you duplicate code you are
duplicating bucks we need to book it
untested code you duplicate
more bugs and another consequent
services
insufficient code reuse which is bad
thing people have been saying for
arm forty years or so now that we should
make reusable code
so I don't want the last couple was lied
to get you down about the cost if not
testing
arm one single solitary unit ask
is vastly better than 0 it doesn't take
a lot of effort to rate one
and once you've written one you can
write a second wind months you've
written
to it starts to become addictive arm
you unit tests will never cover
everything I
don't try and less well just don't try
cover almost everything and and you'll
be pleasantly surprised by how much
have your code you can test with some
effort
it's not free it's not trivial it is
real engineer
requires work but its usually not even
faster cure you
Herculean effort its work it engineering
deal with it by the way this talk is a
Trojan horse
I've been trying to sneak are sneakily
lead you down the path love Extreme
Programming
test driven development the Agile
Manifesto blah blah blah
this is all stuff that has been said
before people have been saying these
things for
12 13 14 years now I first heard about
unit testing thing in 1999
it's not going away om
I may just wrap up arm course writing
unit tests makes your code more correct
this guy is big water is wet and tested
code is more correct
it is less obvious that has to code is
more beautiful code or at least tested
code can become more beautiful code with
a little more effort
beautiful code is better code is more
reusable
more maintainable more pleasant to work
with in the long run
is less expensive even if it takes a
little more effort up front
arm here are some links are yeah
how to reach me who I work for and some
good books to read
and in a book of the bottom of the
screen that was recommended to me by
somebody else but I
oh well I guess is lost now sorry
on the slides are online
and that link is also lost
Cana
I answer news hang on
no spoiler %ah alright so that the other
book that was recommended yeah I know is
busy the slides works beautifully in the
browser I developed from on
anyway if you want more information
you can find me later or questions we
have a few minutes for questions
I
yeah so I was wondering if you could
talk
about best practices or patterns
to avoid having to change your tests
when you re factor
has that some are coupled to the code
itself some
yet the best way to avoid having to
change your test when you re factors
don't use MOX
but the only thing worse than not using
are going thing worse than using MOX is
not using MOX when you should use them
so my personal approach is
don't use MOX gratuitously
arm this this particular example is a
beautiful shining example of
almost purely functional code that as no
dependencies there's no need to mark
anything I didn't have to use any marks
to
to test this thing it's rare I mean
usually only get that at the very the
data leaves have your dependency graph
the utility modules up higher in the
stacking the actual application
it's really hard to test without mocks
and much make your test more fragile
there's no doubt about it yeah
but he repeated the same question there
a tragedy and I write about it s
I do mine design and then the design
changes and some other chains on it as
yeah that's likely is that same answer
it depends on how big the changes
like if you rename a method yeah of
course you have to update your test
because your test call that matter
arm or if you
make massive high level changes to the
way there
olive your major objects interact with
each other
then the tests that use those
interactions or that
in bad those interactions and we're
going to have to change tester code
test have to be maintained in the
engineering effort arm
that life add
enlightened with tasks in spite of that
life with tests
is vastly better than life without tests
it's worth the effort it's worth the
work very nice thank you I
yes okay ok but we're done okay
I'm sorry thats got a couple of