alright
let's welcome Allison captures she's
going to be presenting on important
decisions
is the idea okay here
great I nelson captor I'm a facilitator
at her school
writers retreat for programmers in New
York City to get questions about how to
school come find me at any point in the
weekend I'd love to talk to you about
that
I'm so with the 30 or so high schoolers
who are here now
here some places you can find me this is
my get have been Twitter
if you don't get a chance to get your
questions answered and this stock
feel free to tweet at me I'll try to get
back to you there so
I wanna see a picture selves in
Amsterdam in 1989
inventing Python for the next half hour
we are the PDF else
now unfortunately I don't think we have
time to invent
olive Python in the next half an hour so
we're just going in at one piece and
that's important
now our hypothetical here is that
everything else in Python already exists
so we can write code that we need to
implement import we're going to start
with a very simple
and very limited solution and then we'll
gradually look at problems as they arise
and try to solve them
will also look at some other decisions
we could have made
and and see how other languages choose
to solve these problems
as a side note import existed in its
essentially its current form in the
first open source release a pipeline and
ground 1991
so there's not record up decision-making
around the structure
this is the days before mailing list
before perhaps before the change line
even
so the main source for and actual
history at import is quite as brain
per and I'll come back to that a little
bit later on so what's your problem
really clearly
this is one of shimmering in reusing
code
so to get some cut up on BART on the
board here that we can talk about
concrete link
suppose on the left ensign we had
written some function
it was very hard work and so very useful
function and some time later
on the right hand side we need to use
that function again so what are we going
to do in the absence import
well the first thing we could do is the
decision
that the novice programmer would make
someone who is very new to programming
they would say this is the easy I can
copy and paste
now there clearly a lot of disadvantages
with the strategy but it's worth noting
that there are advantages to you
for one thing it's very clear what we've
done so if you're reading this function
this file later a useful function is
defined right there we don't have to go
hunting for it somewhere
I'm their love disadvantages and to have
them
are that this is annoying to you by Hans
and if we subsequently fined by
in a useful function we have to go fix
in two places so
at a minimum we want an automatic
solution that doesn't require
manual copying and pasting that's
probably not the best solution
if we can come up with and we want the
code to stay in sync everything changes
so what imagine some kind of magical
copy and paste
so we've got a special symbol the copy
and paste your code for you
and we pass in your file name or
something like that and we can imagine
implementing this without any knowledge
a python at all
basically they just use our source code
as text files
and manipulates them as text files so we
look for this special symbol that gives
us a file name
we go find that file and then replace
the line
in our the file reading today with the
contents of that file that we found
and right now the stakes entire files to
include
so we could just be more specific to say
really want this range
line numbers pasted into file reading
today that has a lot of comes as well we
have to keep the line numbers and sink
that's probably not ideal but it's worth
noting that this is an improvement
who we now have an automatic solution
that's not manual copying and pasting
and we don't have to fix bugs in two
places are could stay since Inc
so there are lots of problems with the
solution still a look at for those for
the course in the next 20 or so minutes
for one thing this is static we can
change behavior on the program is
running
for another we have name collisions if
we have two things with the same name we
can't tell that that'll happen
we're executing our files multiple times
which may be inefficient but has a much
more serious problem object identity
will spend more time on it later in its
very rigid there's currently only one
way to do this
so stick is one in time we're so far
manipulating
are Python files as if they're simply
text files with no knowledge at all have
Python or the fact that Python source
code can be used to make Python objects
that we've invented this really great
dynamic language for everything happens
at runtime
so prison where Inc aren't in clear
import solution here should happen in
time to
so let's go one step better we can't we
can call function
to include I external source code
so this function recalling magical paste
takes a file named as an argument
goes and finds that filing opens in
reason the source code
and then uses the exact keyword to
execute that source code
at the moment we're using exact in the
simplest way to Sir regular way
but i wanna spend just a minute on this
in part because exact is not something
you often see in
add production code and in part because
we're going to get more Cuttack
complexes that in just a minute
so exact takes a string and executed as
Python code
now it differs from even now in that
even dollars for evaluating expressions
and exact is for any kinda I think a
so here to find a function when booking
that function it works just the way you
expect it to you
so now we have a way to dynamically run
python code
and this code s current will work we'll
have a useful function available to us
by invoking are magical paste function
so we can solve this problem a doing
through the static analysis for dynamic
language which was not a great idea
by using a python and native function
what's in the second problem love name
collisions so suppose that we had
another file
the defined another I nother function
named a useful function
one of those would supersede the other
we have to know that would happen
we couldn't tell that it would happen
without reading all the relevant source
code
to how we're going to solve this well
luckily for us
we've had one honking great idea
we can use namespaces to avoid name
collisions just as is mentioned in the
senate Python
now since we're inventing new spaces
what's been a minute talking about them
we could have two objects that were have
the same name that pointy different
things sonya
could have Montreal a city in Canada and
Montreal a town in France
and when we're speaking English we would
add extra information to disambiguate
to you now mean is more convenient for
us to put
order to start with the larger container
and then get more specific as we
progress
and we have this idea a container not
contain or has some sort boundary
energy graphic example we have the the
country in the boundaries are
obvious on Google Maps and will have to
decide
what defines the boundary needs but now
we have this mapping
names to objects now let's are using the
word module for container
is a model just another kind on objects
like a class and we'll see this
is the decision is made in some other
languages but for us
let's make some some different choices
will say that the banners a module
are one file you don't need to use an
explicit keywords create a model
you also say that the module by default
has the same name
as the file containing its source code
so we got a direct mapping onto the
filesystem
which allows us to look at where models
live really easily
the upshot of these two decisions is
that every time a Python programmer
rights any program she's written a model
so we're sort tricking novice
programmers and using modules
right off the bat
so what's modifier our function that
uses exact so the
includes a namespace this is something
tax that is not
terribly common and suggested two runs
or how it works we can create an empty
dictionary to use as our namespace
and then exact are QWERTY in that
namespace
when we then inspect the keys and the
namespace we see that we picked up a
reference to built-ins
which happens when you exact any code in
any context
and we've also picked up ki hai the
corresponds to our function object
now if we try to invoke the function hi
in the current scope in the rebel
session
we got in a manner and this is exactly
behavior that we want
we see the executing this code in
another namespace has protected our
current namespace
from all of those names and objects
we can reach into the namespace using
the key
it is that is the name and get the
function object itself
and then invoke it normally
some modifications to our magical paste
function are to create this namespace
executors source code in that in space
and then return the namespace object
itself
so I'm cheating in one way on the slide
by using module syntax instead a
dictionary syntax which I should be
using
so if we make that change then we have
valid code here we have this
suitor module idea it is a simple
namespace a mapping it means
objects so we saw her from name
collisions
we can you can use models and we can use
namespaces to avoid name question
entirely
let's look at this third problem love
the code XQ multiple times
so this could be an efficient if we had
a module that defined 100 functions
instead of just one function
we probably wouldn't want to run it more
times than necessary
are our model could be side affecting in
some way
or we could suppose that module a
requires bc&d
Marshall B requires CNT and so on so
that as we
hurt step through this these series
models the problem gets worse and worse
in fact there's a more serious problem
with are codex key multiple times and
that's one object identity
in many cases even in most cases we
don't want
just an identical object or another copy
of the object we have
we want the same object so we can
imagine reading a module
that 9 set up some object to control the
server
and then spins up that server if we
include that module in another file
we probably don't want another server
object spun up and running somewhere
we want to reference the one we already
have
so how do we solve this problem
so one way to fix this kind of problem
is that memorization
the idea behind memorization is we keep
a record of calculations that we've
already done
we don't repeat calculations we already
know the answer the classic example is
the Fibonacci sequence
naively workers imitation will make to
riker's calls for each
function call as a calculating infinity
and n
Press two then and function cause which
is incredibly inefficient
mission take more than an so we can
solve this problem by storing a cash
here just a dictionary have mapping an
input/output essentially and we've
already conquered an answer
we just return it and we don't actually
began
so we can use this strategy are magical
peace fashion achieve a mapping
a in a dictionary file names to new
space objects
and we are you execute a file name we
won't execute again
so members asians office from about
eight to 10 any and all since helps our
kitchens
our fourth promise that this function is
very rigid there's only one way to
include other code and that's including
entire model
so we can imagine and what options an
but that doesn't get us very far
and also note that for example on line
14 I have to say useful twice
and we decided that modulus by default
have the same name as the file
that contains our source code work early
not implementing an idea at all
so it could if we had options we get
summer
you get more flexible behavior but we
wouldn't solve this this problem and how
to say things twice
and in fact there's not really a
solution that uses a function that
solves that problem
because it would be very surprising if a
function modified the namespace
its collar there's that that doesn't
happen generally speaking for good
reason
will this be ugly we want to have more
fine control over namespace so we can
use keywords
instead function calls the advantage
that we get is that is more flexible in
syntax
nicer looking at statically we don't
have to remember all these parameters in
what order they go in and so forth
in we can modify the caller's name space
without that being totally weird
function should not modify the content
is let's not change that
implementing this is a keyword requires
more work for massive
we have two modify pythons grammar we
have to teach the parser what it means
to see
magical paste but all these are
relatively straightforward
so we can increase the flexibility of
the solution by using keywords and said
it functions
we're not relatively close to the actual
implementation
know what's take a look at actual
important to give a name and see what's
in these ideas appear
so in actual important first step the
interpreter takes
is to check system modules to see if the
names are imported
if not it makes an empty module to use
as a namespace
then goes and finds the source can
executes that source code
in the context of that new empty
namespace that answers the module
in the system models and finally binds a
given name
in the cars namespace if at the first
step we have already imported this model
we skip all the rest to the steps and
just find the name
of course we're not all the way to
actual import here said abbreviated list
of things we have not done
we have created real models we're
currently pretending that dictionary
support actually look up
to proceed out we have in separate
packages
and in fact packages didn't get support
until three or four years after the
first release a fight on it as open
source
we haven't worried about how r magical
piecing
finds the source code in in our example
we just assume that it lived in the same
directory as the
code that we're importing into but
that's an idea that obviously doesn't
scale very well
and we have been reading all that air
handling so if something goes wrong in
the course an excuse for stern
were not Hannah gracefully anyway
we could make different decisions all
these different points and let's take a
quick look at some solutions and other
languages that are instructive
the first one look at his pound include
and see which was might have acquiesce
inspirations and especially in terms of
the path for learning
it somewhat similar to but we're calling
magical copy and paste at the very
beginning
and peace in the code that is in the
included file before compiling the main
file
now see avoids many at the downside so
is every Python
because she is not a dynamic language so
it can use lingers in compiler
optimizations
and generally can have a much better
idea of how the program is going to
execute
before we start running the program
we did make some syntax in DRAM modules
we touched on a bit
and Ruby for example creating a model is
very much like creating a class
you explicitly use a keyword spartan and
at the end of it
you could have more than one model in a
file and you can a model something
different than
the file name is more explicit in some
ways and less experts and others
we look for one we lose this mapping I
have and
file names too much on ames its if we
see
require terrific elsewhere in our code
we don't necessarily know where that
lives
we also lose this idea of tricking the
knots programmer
into programming this way and stuff you
have to sort
seek out this this pattern and start
using
in 1989 models more to give in and Guido
said that the language nodular
particularly
modular 2 and layer was a significant
influence on his thinking
we can notice that at least in 1976
models were so far from obvious that the
model author chose to name the language
after them
now today I think it's fair to say that
modular programming is pervasive
most languages have native modules and
those that don't
are often looking at them so and here we
have it explicit definition of what
module meant in 1976 and we can see that
we haven't moved very far from
that idea in the current imitation
so I wanna spend just a minute on this
team pervasive paradigm stay
when I'm sure many you're familiar with
this quote from David Foster Wallace
nurse there these two young fish
swimming along and they haven't made all
the fish so many other way
not to them and says morning boys how's
the water
and the two young fish swim on for a bit
and then eventually one of them looks
over at the other anchors
what the hell's water
so I can now reveal the alternate title
for the stock which is invisible blind
spots a Python programmers when it comes
to import
ivan is a mature language today and
unfortunately I think we probably lost
the opportunity to become TfL's
at least Python for those who are native
speakers a python
meaning items are for spurning language
sony's decisions embedded in the
language are so familiar
the company's or how is he going to
address the conference this weekend
and as you continue to use Python I have
to keep an eye out for these decisions
that are hidden by their familiarity
and with that I'll take your questions
if you have a question come over to the
microphone over here or chrome aside
raise your hand and I'll come to you
either arm one quick question
I have there been any discussions about
version modulus
up for example let's hear that I know
that I require
a model to be a version 1.4 how you
would define not whether that would be
supported and are there any good
a reasons why not to allow that to a
know my thinking would be it's good to
catch those are certainly on
yeah absolutely I think this gets into
the idea that
time the difference between a module on
a package I think it makes a a lot of
sense to do you
version versioning at the package level
as opposed to it that
at the module level as it allows us a
little bit of a have
pure Python you at Marshalls while
keeping an
package management and versioning in in
the tools where
that there's already been a lot of work
in that area anyone else
so if you drop down a news exec for
things to springs to mind all kinds of
wonderful
evil things you could do for example
people often
who are new to Python ask you on
Wednesday and shit a new copy of them
Marshall
well that's what people think you can
figure some other is the people we can
perpetrate with this
power a some other third
that people in the audience here to tell
you that I tend to specialize in bad
ideas in Python
time which are the most fun in my
opinion a
now in terms if ways to intentionally
rinsed and she ate models
an I would say just put out a system
model since that's that
the check an inter and then it has other
other bad ideas that you could have an
that the list from leon us
patsy 10 one person I was working with
recently
chose to change the key word from import
to something else
her to Osseo for her Harry Potter themed
eitan
she's overriding almost all the bill
tense but important can over at that
easily
so once you get down in cancer this it
there's basically no limit
sir you talked a little bit at had it
like
right important pipeline and the like
got partly there
on in Python is import really
implemented by them
and doesn't use exactly I think this
site we can all language summit or
someone describe Python as
now that 1500 files around exactly in
namespace
an know it it depends a little bit on
what you mean by really implemented in
Python
I'm so my country in particular you can
look at my import lead and
in module to see all the piper metal
hooks
and Stan everything that import humor
does
is actually architected by the diner
import function as we just had this
different interface to essentially I'm
so in that sense it's really written in
Python
an in circle /url sense of course it's
not
any apart about reload shirt pocket
that's very loud
up so reloaded if you're not familiar is
this
is it will essentially really important
module and
ants its most often useful if you're
circling around in a rebel session
ands want to make some changes in your
in your source module
and want to test at those changes an the
thing that I find most confusing about
reload is that
it if you've done a from important
beginning select from my module import
some object
you can't reload by the model name not
and you also can't repeat your from
import
and says I think back to be very
confusing
especially for for the new programmer
poking around the rebel time
one of the things i think is
particularly interesting about the way
that
important structured is that the from
import almost makes it look like the
rest
a module is not executed when in fact it
is
see you the only step it differs in a
from importance that binding
at no I'm sure there are
I think it's useful to have an interface
to that relay module that's not
him mucking around using exact I think
the implementation
pics specifically with from is somewhat
confusing to beginners
all right now said thank you so much