hello everyone and welcome to the third
session in our security track
and I am happy to present young leave
who will be talking to us about
multi-factor authentication and
possession factors
be hand for young players I
so
hi my name is yang I work at Rackspace
am NOT on authentication
but thank you all for coming despite
that I know the sock is supposed to be
about multi-factor authentication
I'm actually going to go slightly off
script and answered I'm just gonna tell
you a story about two people named Alice
and Bob
bob is a gamer he really likes playing
games
so he built his own an enema MMO called
world to Bob Kraft
it became incredibly popular so much so
that in game items
and gold became worth real money on the
open market so
ceiling counts became a very profitable
business one day
Alice a long time only player with lots
of high-level items and gold
reporter or regular I don't have been
liquidated her gold stolen by someone
who hijacked a recount
bob has to spend all they verify her
story and restoring her counts and
possessions
every day more and more players are
reporting their accounts to one
Bob spends all his time restoring
accounts rather than making new content
which makes bob sad he read about how
companies like get her Google Facebook
and Blizzard at a two-factor
authentication to their services to
increase account security
the seem to involve asking for two
things are like an insider one
Sabah that the second password
requirement to the world a bobcat login
and account discontinue and Bob
continues being sad
why what did I do wrong well
multi-factor authentication doesn't mean
just asking for any two things are like
in
it requires at least two different
factors which
are something you know such as a
password or PIN something you have such
as an ATM card phone or are set again
and something you are meeting something
inherent you such as your fingerprints
are your rental pattern
to the same factors like bugs to require
passwords don't count
the reason they don't count is that
using multiple passwords is like putting
a secret but say the account data you
want to protect
inside a box which represents a password
and ap ok
more compact around 10 for her
the point to this completely legitimate
and legal fair use of copyrighted
material
is that where's the boxes do not protect
against an attacker who can't open
even a single box because they can do
the same to all the boxes
for instance a keylogger was still any
number password as easily is all still
one
without any further cost the attacker
multi-factor of is like placing a
security guard in front of your box
an attacker has to be a to both get
around the security guard and opened the
box
even if they still in the key to the box
from you your password in this analogy
they don't automatically get past the
security guard without having to do more
work
each type a factor has a difference had
a vulnerability is our weaknesses that
an attacker like this
can use a break in it's important to
consider with this attackers going to do
and how your defense will prevent
against that rather than just throwing
up defenses willy nilly with apt
them actually doing anything stress in
some attacks against password
authentication include man in the middle
attacks
when attackers sits between Alice and
Bob and pretend he's bout hours and
contends he's asked Bob and reason
perhaps modifies traffic that tells you
something to Bob or vice versa
password authentication is also
vulnerable to phishing attacks
where an attacker tries to trick us into
giving her password
cute keep key logging attacks were an
attack a lot of the key threats analysis
machine
and replay one attacker may not be able
to read traffic
but he can copy traffic from oust about
without being and understand or modify
and replace the traffic back to bob at a
later point while pretending to be Alice
possession factors are also vulnerable
to men in the military
axe and they can be physically stolen
and then the attacker would be in
possession analysis possession factor
various types the possession factors
also have their own weaknesses but these
are the general attacks against
opposition factors without going into
specifics biometric factors like
fingerprints can also be stolen
people leave them everywhere son
attacker can easily obtain them
since fingerprints to change the
credentials can never be revoked
and they're vulnerable to replay attacks
but the stock is just gonna discuss two
factor authentication
to FA if you ever see this acronym are
using knowledge and possession factors
because this is currently the most
common combination
went to factor are combined the attacks
against a factor of
is the intersection against one factor
and the attacks against the other
so an attack that works only against one
factor is insufficient to compromise
like an
if an attacker keylogger else's password
login is a protected by the token factor
and the way most possession factors work
is that they produce a one-time password
which can only be used once so even if
an attacker gets alice is complete login
by which I mean password
and Pat a RTP they can't use the token
led by as if the possession factor
stolen the law gonna so protected by the
password
the goal is to minimize this
intersection of attacks and that's why
bob has to include at least two factors
at the same factor say two passwords it
is used twice
the intersection of attacks the same as
that for single factor password
authentication
it just because two factors are used
doesn't mean that the intersection is a
smart it could be
after provides after Kan's likable
authenticator of the annual security
can run on phones and make it really
easy for our cities multi-factor
authentication without having to buy a
heart again
the phones are general-purpose computing
devices meaning they can be exploited
meaning the token and password can be
compromised at the same time
so this intersection becomes this
I'm when using a softer going on to
found the intersection contains another
attack which is exploit the fun
as you can see there still fewer attacks
than in single factor password
authentication
so it's not that Allah should not use of
tokens on a fun it's that she should be
aware the other attack
and take extra care the security on her
son
so now knowing what multi-factor
authentication is Bob surveys other
sites that provide it
and find the most commonly supported
possession factors
these possession factor operatives
tokens that are one-time passwords
meaning they X expire after beef time
expire after single-use
or both the most common tokens on
smartphones
which are supported by the previously
mentioned aP's are open authentication
time-based one-time password steer
teepees
which usually expire after about 30
seconds this is 08 %eh not
of this is authentication our office for
authorization
which I know is super clear
2tb again time this one-time passwords
require shared secret between the client
and server
and are generated using the secret and
the current time the TOTP generated by
Alice's ap is valid
if it matches the TAT be generated by
world Bob Kraft
algorithms pressure in simple
unspecified and those are sees
and there are many people either is that
support it for instance cryptography not
only supports it that many other
cryptographic capabilities
OOTP of just supports 28 th and but also
includes a nice example how to generate
a QR code
am from the shared secret so that you
can communicate the shared secret to
your user
many sites also support SMS based
one-time passwords about
be would text else around MOT p and she
must provide a back
this works even if else doesn't have a
smartphone
clear provides a REST API that can let
bob send nm as a nest Alice
allowing him to support SMS based
authentication an HTTP client can be
years but will they also provides an
expert on Trulia client
a commonly supported consume her talking
to the you keep
which acts as a USB keyboard ass just
has to plug it in
press the button and a generator no TP
based on a counter
you go provides validation service as
well as an open source validation
servers so that I can write once run one
on his own rather than depend on you the
cap
there are quite a few Python client
libraries that support access to the
validation API
I'm the first one is the official one
second one is the one that will be using
examples because typing a shorter
okay so what does bob need to do to
support possession factors
he has till et al sad factors her
account yes to validate the factor when
I was logged in
and his lapels remove factors from her
account
but the years out the general pattern
tattoo factor of from scratch to a
general pipe an application
which also placed at using frameworks
such as flask and twisted
the Nexus lies are going to assume
year's model that looks something like
this:
it has a collection of possession
factors in order of preference in Dallas
because bob would like to support backup
devices in case Alice loses her
preferred device
which would be the first at factor in
the collection
all bob's factors will have this
interface arm
has a function to check whether no TB is
Alan a start
because some factors require set up
before every 0 TP
a start function that does the third set
up and a prop the prompt is for later
when bob has to ask alice furlaud TP
so first we're gonna cover TRT peace
the flow is that bob generates a shared
secret communicate the shared secret be
at two alisya QR code
and then one else wants to authenticate
using this factor XII generator TOTP
from the shared secret
which she gets back to bob and bob has
to match against the TTP that he
produces from the shared secret
for the fact occurred and Bob generates
a random Jersey good
and he's though to be of library to
check the validity of the test other
RTP given the secret there's no setup
except on first configuring the factors
so the start function does nothing
to configure the factor Bob send a cure
can like the diagrams as
with her response and if the token
checks out by being at the factored her
account
and they get user input function here is
synchronous
and is also not implemented in the slut
entered imported from the made-up module
for weather maps the QR code and a form
would have to be rendered on appears so
in reality asking the user for their TP
is probably a synchronous stateful and
much more complex
speaking if your records this is the
general form at the right to be included
in the Cure occurred
and its best by the other them use the
issuer and the username
because else that may be generating 30
piece from multiple services
this helps apt label which took emblems
the world Bob Kraft
and which took emblems the world Carol
craft
OOTP of generates this year I when given
the relevant information services what
the generate QR code function looks like
for the SMS factor bobby is truly a to
send SMS's
and the way SMS tokens work is that
Allah's give up her phone number
but generate some random token text the
towers at that number
and the token that I ask is back to bob
has to match what Bob texted her
bob for sneezing accounts really oh so
that he can provide his account ID and
are talking to the rest clients
and he also needs a toy a number you can
send us a message from
because the start function stores the
generated 0 TP
Texas hours at the number she gave them
from Bob's number registered with
William
validating the ATP is just checking that
matches the store 21
and this is a night implementation that
doesn't take into account sending Alice
multiple tokens token expiry
or API failures but this is the general
idea
and there's one extra check in this ad
factor function
the configuration only continues if the
phone number has not already been to fit
configured for Alice
it's already on our asses account at
Bill's that if it is then this
then proceed like the diagram Bob text
Alice ask is back about 30 p.m.
the phone numbers at Alice's account as
a possession packed
so now for the you key factor and before
you begin it's good to know that every
time the UB key button has passed
and OOTP is produced that has the idea
the you keep which never changes
concatenated to the actual 0 TP part
which changes every time and is exactly
thirty two characters
said to get the ID you just chomp of
their last 32 characters at the Ukiah TP
so whenever Allah's provides an ATP Bob
checks in with you because servers
an extract also extract the idea the UK
which is that cookie looking thing
am I D matches the one that hours
previously registered in
then alice is using the same you be key
issued registered
and if you go also says that about 30 P
then
yea alice is authenticated
to validate against you care about has
generated a client ID and secret magic
key for all the Bob Kraft
the keys used by you Curtis I and the
responses to the partners
responses from you cannot spooked by an
attacker
let the 2:30 p.m. the start function
does nothing cuz there's no setup
the checker TP kar dan just as with the
diagram am
described it validates 30 P and the
client validates the signature
extract the Bahia de cheques it against
the store and I D
and again this is a simplified
implementation does not take into
account
API failures and what happens if their
signature failures
when adding a Yuki else needs to provide
30 p.m. and if the factor that the
with that particular you be here I D
hasn't been configured already
and RTP validates the Bob can add that
you pick your ID
as a factor for her account
soon after validating a token I log in
despite a simpler because most the work
was already done in the factor
obstructions which is what made the
previous part time are complex and
lengthy
am the logic is that Alice gives bob her
username and password
Bob checks that the user exists that the
password checks out
sees a palace has a second factor
configured and if so he asked Allah's
for the second factor credentials
arm then Alice gives those credentials
back to bob
and Bob validates those credentials
hear about stop-start start off with a
leg infection which checks the user
the password in the possession factor on
bob also made it take a post login
argument which is a callable that
executes post login logic
am will see why in a sec
checking the possession factor just
means that bob sees when Alice has at
least one configured possession factor
as though he asks for the RTP validated
using the preferred factor which is the
first factor in the collection
if everything's good postal outpost
login logic executes
I remember how each factor has a start
function for set up an impromptu asked
for these are stoking
it speaks so that this function could be
factor independent rather than giant
nested
Elstree
to spur backup devices but asks for both
the type a factor and the token
the default factor would of course be
the preferred factor but ass can pick a
different factor
on her back to factors if the ticket is
validated the talking is validated
no matter what but if the factor she
picked as a backup factor
then email sent to her warning her that
a backup factor not her preferred
accuracy is
because the should be an unusual
occurrence and might be an attacker
so now is perfect for its actions and
login implementation established
revocation is even simpler there's not
even a diagram
removing a factor is just a leading from
the collection but since this could be
an attacker trying to decrease account
security
a warning email should be centel's any
time factors removed
even better would be if I privilege
functionality like this would require
Alice to log in again
I remember how to login function took a
purse login
callable so up for a more secure remove
factor function
and back our book can be the non suited
remove factor function
sup that was adding to factor out from
scratch due to application the full code
is up I'm I get a beeper 30 run as a
little command line demo
the made-up module is actually
implemented
for something more flask specific the
200 block has a very nice example had
TOTP is an SMS factors
to a flask ap but certain parts are
ruled by Kraft use Django
and there's anger middleware that
handles to factor of free in
where the most complete plugins as
Django TP it's a framework that provides
support for all the previously mentioned
authentication methods
although trillion you be key supporter
separate plugins on that has models for
the devices
and it updates the user model to include
whether two factor authentication is
enabled
all you need to do is install them and
at the middle classes and install the
app's to
a dang good on tap Settings tab by
there's another project gender to factor
of which integrates tango TP
into jaggers built an authentication
framework and makes it really easy to
pass the login here to be a multi-factor
like nvm
and there's no US support for Yuki
devices yet but there's a park or if
there's an issue out for that
Bob just add some more install the app's
an 11-year-old to Settings app I
along with his credentials First Folio
account
and yet the two-factor your own route as
the login routes
and alice when logged and can now enable
to factor authentication
and configure her preferred list at her
preferred factor
if the configuration floods went by
really quickly don't worry I'm the docs
for Django TB describe the installation
and configuration
in detail more than the slides do
and Django to factor of has just as
extensive darts and also comes with a
nice
example Django out that demonstrate its
use which is where the PB screen shots
came from
example app is available to train line
and of course Bob Rowe dollars own views
and themed everything for world but Bob
Kraft but I gave them a good idea what
to do
but could also have used a device like
to the security or of the which would
handle
else the second factor completely Bob
just has to register with the device
and let them know about Alice and the
service does all these things about how
to do before about stuff
house has to register her devices with
the service and cerebral the Bob Kraft
but then when she logs and Bob validates
your password
the service handles her second factor
so now authentication is secure and bob
is happily ever after creating content
Alice never loses control for a dungeon
loot again rates
well there's other ways for them to be
needing a player to world the Bob Kraft
not just log in and login has been
protected by Bob using multi-factor
authentication
but not every request made world by
Kraft requires a password and token
an attacker CSO an attacker can use some
other form other than to cation
for instance after login world bypasses
the session key for Alice to
authenticate ran subsequent requests
until she lives outs an attacker who
eavesdrops the ski
then has a full access to Alice's
account
is dropping can be mitigated using TLS
also known as SSL
I'm sorry to encrypt all traffic however
include to traffic won't help with alice
is man in the middle with an attack who
pretends to be well the Bob Kraft
so but has to provide a valid till
certificate and house is quiet must
verify it
very important in order to mitigate the
threat at the man and millet ac
but as we've seen from this year
learning from a Nextag
earlier on TLS um libraries that provide
tailored support can have on our
abilities
summer which negate the point of using
it in the first place so both Alstom Bob
have to respond immediately to any
required patching up the last libraries
and keep everything up today okay
something else is vulnerable to man in
the middle attacks and is not anymore
another tether that occasion is API keys
access tokens
such as of: not 08 %eh this time
for applications that need to
authenticate in the background without
any interaction with the user
for instance the world a bobcat mobile
app which allows als checker auctions
and in game mail
but make sure that every app has to
request a different API key
so they're all revoke a bowl and
auditable independently of each other
and he also limit how much access each
API key has given it only as much
privilege as it needs
so that an attacker who stormed hours as
mobile API key doesn't have full access
to our account
but makes use agenda ATP's go to be
required decorated which behaves like
anchors log in required decorator
that requires that these are have to be
logged in using multi-factor
of I'm potentially dangerous changes
like changing passwords token factors
are emails
can compromise the security on account
so changes like these would be good
candidates for acquiring
that these are be logged in with not a
factor of even better would be to
require hours to provide credentials
again
as you would for if you are executing
pseudo commands at all such dangers
actions
should result in a warning email being
sent Alice in case they're taken by an
attacker and not her
and Alice much more careful now because
our account had been stolen
his careful attention to these emails
even though they might seem annoying are
kinda spendy
by doing all these things bob protect
access to Alice's account as much as
possible
while keeping usability is a back says
hi
as mentioned before world Bob Kraft
provide the recovery mechanism in case
else has to change her credentials
account recovery is just log in again
anyone who recovers an account is just
resetting the account credentials
recovery should be audible and rear all
such changes should be live so that
malicious attempts to reset credentials
can be identified
and research should be difficult at
least as much as regular login or all
attackers will just go after the lowest
hanging fruit which is account reset
which is why Bob keeps obsessing over
this
so bob has provided backup devices so
that asking is a backup to open to login
and is in disable the primary token
which
is supported by Django to factor of but
bob could have also emailed
hours with the reset link forcing hours
to prove that she's in possession of the
email account associated with her
account arm this is a standard mechanism
that services with only single factor of
provide to reset passwords
but even services with multi-factor of
fall back on this if the user doesn't
have backup device is configured
unfortunately emails negated by
multi-factor arts so it turns into
something
you know something you know that bob
started with so
what has Elliston alice is set up to
factor of for all the Bob Kraft
she set up backup factors that she
doesn't have to resort to in our set
she's chosen different strong passwords
for both world by Kraft and her email
account
and she set up to factor of other e-mail
too because she really wants to receive
those warning emails
and gary said he knows I'm she's careful
about what he does your phone
she set up a lock screen and promote
white so that she could keep her soft
open safe
and she keeps our systems up to date so
that any vulnerabilities can be passed
as soon as possible
she has not had any more incidents of
account that and is now the highest
level was its neighbor and while the Bob
Kraft
bob is implemented in saree promoting
multi-factor of two of his players
you provide secure and auditable
recovery options includes all traffic
and limits privileges have less secure
forms authentication
I'm he keeps all the crew to libraries
needed to provide said security up to
date
and now account that is down world Bob
Kraft not gone because not all players
are careful analysis
um but he spends much higher percentage
of the time designing contents
sorry it's not moving
ok whenever so and they both lived
happily
and it visually ever after thanks for
coming everyone
thank you so much game arm we don't have
time for questions right now
but there is space out for a hallway
bomb if you would like to ask you any
questions about her presentation
we are now taking a break for a few
minutes
please feel free to go down there is
still some swag laughed
in the exposition hall with all the
sponsors please check them out
and give them a moment of your time
thank you
story