right good morning everyone i'm so
welcome to for soccer today
I am please give a hand for speaker just
a a
Jessica hamrick who will be talking
about games work science
creating interactive psychology
experiments in Python with
Penner's 3d thank you
am one
ask so
I'm so yes I I I'm a registered
at UC berkeley and I'm gonna be talking
about some research that i've done with
my colleague Peter Italia
who is research scientist at MIT and
unfortunately couldn't be here up icon
amber has been like I really enter a
part of this research he was my mentor I
was an undergraduate at MIT
and actually I'll be talking about an
experiment that he's done since I left
and I T
on so to start out with am
first let's talk a little bit about
games so the Rams have
and become increasingly popular recently
as irv
May 2012 apparently Angry Birds had been
played
a total of 200,000 to get two hundred
thousand years
an with an average of 300 million
minutes
a playing time every single day I'm
which is a pretty big number
our TVs and how big it is am their 109
minutes is approximately equal to five
hundred and seventy years
so thats five hundred seventy years of
playing time
I'm just for Angry Birds every single
day
I am at the huge amount of human efforts
and time that's being invested into this
one game
so wouldn't it be cool if we could
leverage that popularity
in order to do science I we could do so
much science
if we had that much manpower I'm so
that's the idea behind this talk is
doing you're creating fun games in order
to do interesting science
and to give you an outline have 1 I'll
be talking to you about
I'm first gonna go over the research
question our interested in at all then
tell you what our hypothesis is
that we think is going on on and I'll
tell you about the experiments that
we've run
I in order to test this hypothesis out
and it was that we used to make those
experiments
and you know the
the tools that we do you spend his
experiments they're not too difficult to
use I think anyone in this room
would be able to pick them up but fairly
easily we have some Democrats online
am you can go and look at it and so
I know have in mind for the talk it this
is interesting to you
you could probably do something pretty
similar if you wanna on
but aggressive for small with a question
are interested in so
we're fundamental interested in how
people reason about the world
and a particular have little reason
about the physical world so
from the time that you get up in the
morning and tell you go into work you
party interacted with the physical world
in ways that no computer can even begin
to rival so you got up
you made breakfast got dressed I am you
put things into your back you have to
work
a computer can do any of those things
well I S maybe they can
you know drive now with the growth of
driving car but
a computer I can do all those things
that I can't do it as fluidly
and it's like the way if people can and
so you might think well maybe that is
because we have a lot of experience but
the world you know if
you get up and make breakfast every
morning so you just you know easy
because he do it every day
but I think that our ability to reason
about physics is much more flexible a
much more powerful than that I'm going
to try to convince you of that
I could show you eight people with some
blacks on it
you probably never seen this table
before or this particular configuration
a box
yet if I told you to imagine that know
maybe there's some kids running around
and they bump into the table some box of
you probably have a pretty strong idea
have watch
colorblock is more likely to fall off so
I'm to shout out what you think
do think it's rather yellows more likely
to fall off right
act right how about this one Brett K
that's what I red the Sun
maybe me lol huh how this one
yellow okay this %uh red
right so you know just promised you seem
to never seen these before I get
you all have a pretty no strong opinion
about what might happen
and in general you agree with each other
you know the level of agreement
no can vary from scene to scene but it
seems like that's produced
there's something pretty systematic
comments really powerful flexible
reasoning going on
and so this is exactly the thing that
we're interested in is how is it that we
can reason about these tapes
scenes I think that's really interesting
am so that's a question
is how people be done about the physical
world I'm so then
now I'm gonna tell you about what our
hypothesis is that going on
so on they feel that a man is called
computational cognitive science
and in computational cognitive science
review the brain as a computer
I and we're interested in how the brain
generates thought behavior
and a particular and publication of
cognitive science
we are interested in how the brain
software works so how to suffer prison
behavior
our colleagues and computational
neuroscience are interested in the
hardware that's more like the individual
neurons
and so our scientific approach is to you
come up with the reserve how the
the mines software producers thought
behavior and then instantiate those
theories in a computer model
I'm so that might be a robot or
artificial intelligence but it's
something that can produce behavior just
like people countries behavior
and then we can compare the behavior
that the model produces with
up the beer that people produce after
the test our series and fine-tune them
and come to a better understanding of
how people think so
how do we create a model up how people
reason about physics
well luckily for us there's already a
lot a software that does PhysX
so for example the physics engine and a
video games like Angry Birds
on and moreover you know if read take a
look at his X Games The Sims offer us a
really nice platform for studying
have arisen about his ex because it
requires the same
you know types reasoning faculties that
you need to interact with the everyday
world
on so this is rated you know were
restarted what you're thinking about
and retook this you know pretty far in
what we hypothesize that you actually
have a physics engine
in your head I'm so you look at the
scene you form a representation over in
your mind
and then your mind actually performs a
simulation
have you know simulating for the future
together outcome
you can use that how come to make a
decision about something in the world
and and there's two components that have
high pop says the first is that
this is a vengeance approximate meaning
that assimilation that runs aren't
exact and the second is that its
probabilistic
meaning that if you run the same
simulation twice you make it a slightly
different
answer and the reason for these two and
components
I'm is because the world has uncertainty
at the for example I could show you
this picture up these rocks which you
might think maybe was taken just at the
moment they're about to fall
or perhaps in photoshopped by actually
it neither does a a real photo that's
taken every of stable
structures this is a sports car rock
balancing and the goal is to build these
crazy structures that look like they're
going to fall down
I'm its prequel a but you know
if you're actually stable but we all
have this impression that this must
be about to fall down you know our model
needs to be able to
account for that and so we think that
you know you take so many coincidences
I am for the structured actually be
stable that are mine says
that you know a combination of
confidence is so unlikely
that anger into you know said probably
going to be unstable
rather than assuming E all these prints
dances are gonna happen
and so that's sorta important you know
approximate published a component
I can handle these types on certain
situations I we can extend it beyond
rock balancing
to maybe a tower blocks again Jenga
order to a a 3d model Anna physical
stimulation
like the tape that we're on our
experiments as it is is the actual
stimulus from our experiments
that am is actually stable but it looks
very unstable all of our participants
always say that unstable I and I
our model also says that its unstable
because I had this approximate published
a component
so I'm the reason why we take a physics
engine is a good idea is the same reason
why it's a good idea in games and
graphics
so first bought it affective like it can
produce simulations that are
sufficiently realistic to fool you into
thinking that it's you know
at you know not if maybe not a real
scenario but
no good depiction ever else now it
sufficient
so it's made to run in real time
similarly the you know for the engineer
had has to be able to run in real time
you can't just sit around all day
waiting for your simulations to complete
before you know you make a judgment
about some seen I'm
and then finally and I think this is the
most important one is I have to be
general purpose
so are the fecundity your hat has to be
able to apply to many different types of
situations
because the last thing that you'd watch
is to encounter situation
but you didn't have experience with and
not know how to act so
apparently this is a sign somewhere in
the United States am
if you look closely an you'll see that I
guess it's a little dark
a sorry but this is a not rockets a cow
so apparently some where the United
States is the danger
house falling off a cliff fun to your
car I'm
I hopefully not if you have been in this
situation an
but if you were in this situation I I'm
pretty confident that you'll be able to
do something reasonable
and you know deal with this thing area
despite the fact that you've never been
in that area before
so there's a ability to reason about
things that you know we've never
experienced is really really important
am so you know that sort of motivation
behind why we think this is engine
idea is a good it's a good idea
okay so that's our hypothesis the
physics engine in your head
i'm for now I'll finally we can get to
the actual experiments that we ran
on so good you know
the way that we are going to test this
is by taking
the and two other people have used to
make video games
and actually use them both as our
theories so we can use the physics
engines from his game as a period how
people reason about physics
on and we can use it to create is really
rich and engaging experience
I'm so our general research pipeline
goes like this:
first we can create a computational
model and you redo that using a video
game physics engine
for example bullet am then we can
generate stimuli detached
are model and also people
I'm using a 3d modeling program like
blunder and then we can run experiments
using a video game framework like Panda
3d at all three of these trolls that I
mentioned are
open source they'll have python bindings
out so they fit really nicely together
they work really well together
I'm and it fits into the larger picture
of Python and science as well because
we can do all over data analysis using
umpires type II
et cetera and then rehab is really nice
powerful framework for doing research
all the way from the level of creating a
model to running experiments
to doing the data analysis so I'm
press the Talk I'm just going to focus
on how we did the experiments are not
gonna talk more about the model or the
results
but if you're interested I'm we have a
product page and we have a
journal article published in PNAS and to
you popular science articles
I'm if you want to read them I am I and
you know be more other details you can
go do that and the fights will be online
an so you can look at them at your
leisure
okay so on for signature you wanna the
simpler
experiments that we ran to give you a
sense have the types of things out
you know we're testing I'm so in this
experiment am
we had people look at these powers and
blocks and then again has a little dark
so it's hard to see
but an %uh so you this house the blocks
on and they all fall down and people
have to decide what direction they think
that our all fallen
I'm gonna do that by moving this way
line around the table
in order to point in the direction that
I think it's gonna fall and
art show you a short video what this
looks like
so here you see the camera spinning
around the tower
and the video is now playing
our
well thats unfortunate am likely
I have a damn hour after that that am
ok
so am okay
cameras and around the tower and now the
line appears and I can move it to point
in the direction that I think it will
fall
think it's gonna fall there and
up so this is a general idea and just
repeats from
from there on an and a
but this is it you know traditional
psychology experiment usually you
well just like us about to say like yes
I think it's gonna fall or no I think
it's not gonna fall or
you know give a rating on a scale from
one to 10 this is much more engaging
than that because you can actually make
a judgment in the three-dimensional
world
in real time %uh so it feels like you're
actually
you know making a judgment about a real
scene as opposed to something that's
you know just on your computer am so
okay how do we do that am so the
senator of flow out how this works is we
first
and create graphics model of to depict
objects that are seen so that's
know the blocks I actually have to
render those models and we do that using
rendering engine and we then cad
physical dynamics using a physics engine
and then we link the graphics and
physics together so that when his ex a
simulated
the graphics will move along with a
answer it you know it looks like a
realistic simulation
on so not gonna go into like the
specifics of the code here
I am I was gonna go over conceptual
overview the steps but
I have code on line for the demo that
i'm gonna be showing you
on in addition to the other demoss an
and so you can go look at that if you're
interested also can it really has a
really good
on hello world tutorial thats I'm going
to get started with your
interested okay so step one is to create
a graphics file
and you typically do this and a separate
program a separate 3d modeling program
my plunder
so have you am the problem you might
have heard a blunder marv you may have
heard a
a buyer for example but I plunder
because it's open source
and its python script herbal am and so
where you end up seeing here is
on the bottom are these are different
views have the our geometry
on the jargon term is like mash so here
is I
view from the top down these are two
different side views this is a
camera perspective you've got the
preview look like over here we have the
tech sure that we're gonna apply to the
match
and then here is the final rendered
preview and water Graphics object
actually looks like about this is a
static rendering so what we want to
surrender in real time
am so what we're going to do is pilot
into a our graphics engine rendering
engine
bike and a three-day and Kansas City is
written in C five spots
but it also has python bindings even do
everything a python with that
an and add to the way that panda 3d
decides what to render it has a thing
called a scene graph
and other at the scene graph is air
special
object called render and I this is a
hierarchy av
are objects called no pass and no path
basically points two more specialized
attacks
like models are lights or camera I am
and add to the way that you interfaced
attacks
said the rate we have render everything
under under will get rendered
had it's called render am and so we can
load our model
Sophia saved the the previous model that
I showed you for example as what block
to eg and Ag is just the extension that
can it really is a sports models
on 3 like that and we created no
passcode lock graphics to point out that
so we can interface with that
and then we add a blog graphics to the
scene graph so now if we were to run
panda 3d and look at it
we would see a block an its
number interesting at this point it's
just a block and all the screen am
but it is being rendered in real-time
which is what we want
so we can make it more interesting by
adding in physics up so
to do that re are going to use it for
the center called bullet
which is also written in C pas plus but
also has python bindings
and are more importantly it's actually
included in panda 3d
so I it has built-in support for
interfacing between had a 3d ample
objects the same way you interface
with any other you know peta 3d objects
like the model
so on the way we render physics RR
tonight for sex is by creating an
avocado bullet world
and this keeps track of all other
physical objects and it computes
office XO if you do i won time stop for
the physics
to figure out what the next position if
all the objects needs to be
if any of them are detected as colliding
it will figure out how they bounce off
each other
et cetera and so I the way
and that we represent physics attacks
are 30 components
the first as a shape orkut and geometry
automatically specifies
how the other than that computes
collisions works so on
depending on you know what object is
that you're trying to stimulate you
might want to use a sphere or
a box or maybe a con all these are
collision shape
primitives on that your money is here
and other thing is the body which
actually specifies
their dynamics themselves so this is
stuff like math Center vast fiction
I'm so you combine those two and you get
a full physical object
so we are gonna create our physics world
arm
and then we can create a shape here we
use a box-shaped because we're doing
blocks
I am and then we create a body reset the
shape is a child of the body
and then we add body to the world so now
we should be able to simulate physics
on and and backed hopefully this video
will work this time
am so this %uh it might be hard to see
in the back
but this block now has a rat outline
around it this is actually a special
d-bag heard that had a 3d has
well render like a skeleton are a
wireframe have the physical objects
which is really useful and telling where
they are or
what size they are and this blue line
sticking up is just
a the the access there's also a green
line which you probably can't see which
is
am I did axe for the y-axis am
so if we run this we'll see
is the physics after falls down
am but they cover objective not act like
that more time
that well fast
abs this isn't exactly what we wanted
and the we actually probably could have
predicted that
because if we take a look back at our
graphic an
on this two-part are not connected so
like
pedigree doesn't actually know that
graphics and physics should be linked
together so we have to explicitly tell
it
am because bullets infinitive can a 3d
wreaking created no path
and point it at the physics object and
then every Sat
the a the topic to be a parent up the
graphics
now this is a really powerful party the
same graph is
because it's a parent at the graphics on
the move it around the graphic to also
move
and you can do this even with you know
like empty node path
so do you have a whole tower blocks you
can have a new path just for the tower
and then you know individual notepad 32
the box if you move around
the big note path for the whole power it
will move around all the box as well
so if we set it up like this now one the
physics moves
because at the physical stimulation
graphic to also move
every take a look at what this looks
like
now see that the block calls for physics
and graphics which is that we're on
so this is a pretty simple example I am
you know it's not nearly as a you know
interesting as
the demo that I showed you where know
you judge the direction that it's gonna
fall
but is really like the basics that you
need in order to do this
once you are able to do this at the
physics and the graphics you can do the
rest
am fairly straightforwardly so
I show you two more demos am NOT
experiments are done
so this one is an I tried to come up
with a
a short cute name for and I couldn't so
blue box together to make it are stable
am and so that's basically the idea is
you can are create attachment between
blocks to hear the green block and a
purple block are attached because it has
a slight white glue stuff in between
on and you want to try to make us your
passions as possible in order to make
the tower stable
and in enough for this experiment we
actually added in the idea of having a
score so you get points for
every block it stay standing and you
lose points every block that falls down
he also is points for each attachment so
really motivates people to try to add
make issue attachment as possible and am
as it is really a No a much more
engaging interesting goal oriented
experiment in the previous one
I think it's a lot more fun as well am
but had a video
hopefully it will work we'll see
so that's what it looks like without and
any attachments it just falls
obviously and we can make some
attachments that might not necessarily
I'm work but you see the objects there
are
attached arm every can make attachment
that actually make the tower
entirely stable and so he rerun physics
and
doesn't bother I'm so that's the idea
behind this experiment
am the next experiment
is in my opinion the most fun I am I
so you the you might notice this looks
kinda like the table so sure you at the
beginning with the reading a box on them
we actually did run that experiment and
this is the next version of it
sensitive saying that the tower ordered
cable will be banned were saying
that you have to but the table in order
to knock out the yellow box
but not the red box so you get points
for every hour block tech falls off and
you lose points for every red light that
falls off
and you get to choose the direction and
magnitude of the arrow
to specify you know where'd about the
table how hard about the table
and said this is really fun am now
jokingly I a re can call angry box three
day because it's
I you know it's not exactly like Angry
Birds you know with
in that case you have to throw
projectile this case you are putting a
table but you're still trying not cover
the structure
I am and said it's really fun to do I
you know I
often 1 I'm talking about it president
saying like I'm doing it experimenter
you know whatever your terminology a
normal user I'll say like
I'm actually playing at am such a year
video
but it looks like
so there's a camera spinning around it
am
I yeah it's these videos now I also have
a demo this
okay so there's a camera spinning around
and here's the arrow exchange the size
make it smaller make it bigger
an turnabout here and
mostly a box full of which is good
an at do this when you can also change
the viewpoint
if you need a a better view
them so on and so forth I really like
this one its it's so much fun to do
like I feel like I could do it all day
I'm and actually so Peter
my colleague ran this experiment on
people at MIT
and he said that people reported to have
that they be willing to pay to do this
how where like normally we pay them
money
to come in and do the experiment recon
armor like psychology experiments they
needed an incentive to come do it
but they be willing to pay for that of
I'll
so I am third that the idea
and other I'll be experience I have time
to show you today
if you're interested in doing any of
them personally even come talk to me
afterwards and I have the demos on my
computer so you can run them
I'm so just to wrap up I'm
we have the question of how people
reason about the physical world and
our hypothesis is that you have this
physics engineer had and I sure do some
experiments
that we built using these tools blunder
panda 3d and bullet
I'm better really fun and engaging and
really are a good way of testing
on you know this hypothesis and I didn't
talk very much about the model but
we use the same tools to make the model
and we find that this model is a pretty
good account of how people reason these
situations
I'm so you know coming back to the
beginning a little bit assure you this
code about Angry Birds
am an ass to think about you know how
much science you could do if
if we have a temper popularity and I
think that with these tapes if
in Beijing experiments am that you know
if that doesn't seem impossible that we
could do something that
pretty popular like Angry Birds maybe
not quite at that scale
but I mean if people are willing to pay
for the last one
like you know for got it on the iPod or
something
I think we could really scale to stop
and get a lot of data
and that's a really exciting possibility
to me so
I saw to thank the people who have been
involved with this project
are just her mom here is my advisor ira
and I T
and is a car author on the paper that we
published about this a Tom Griffiths is
now my advisor at berkeley
the lab I was in both MIT and now
berkeley and of course all the tools
that made this research possible
Python itself and the 32 also been
talking about today panda 3d blender and
bullets
am I Python umpire after the five high
stock and despite actually were created
using iPad for notebook
am and two converted to revealed that
dry ass
ASO really know python has been an
integral part of this whole research
from the very beginning
all the way to presenting at the end
down and
again here are some links if you're
interested in learning more thanks
okay
so now we will be doing Q&A I if you
have any questions please line up at the
microphone in the center there
thank you
good Thanks for interesting
I'm just wondering abode
the what could be the possible cause for
the engagement
what makes it so I D
go to similar the physics engine in our
you how many you mean like what
I am but what's in the brain that lets
us do that know so what
why why is angry bird so popular why why
doesn't make it so I D
what is that I fear an a question I'm
you know
I I don't have like a super great answer
to that am
I think probably because partially
because it's
challenging am and partially because am
Mike it requires us to use machinery
that we don't normally have to use but
that we r like good at using when we do
use it
but I that's like an open research
question
so good question thanks to talk
arm i was just wondering about the
capabilities have bullet for example
like if you were to simulate damn and a
really small scale staffer
really large scale staff the physics
have been very different right
cell yeah I know how capable it is
so bullet bomb do like super large scale
stuff like
am you know what do like gravitational a
fax
beyond just rigid body gravity I
super small stuff like better add-on
I don't you mean to say I gotta love
Mike Adams stuff but
no can't do that am in general I am
like if you get too small or too large
it sometimes runs into instability
issues
answer requires a little bit wreaking to
get that working quite right
an but it's pretty robust for like
you know things that are the size have
you know people
about active and also can do things like
costimulation on which we haven't done
anything with yet but at has
other capabilities that are really
interesting to you hi
arm first on I I love the enthusiasm
with which you play with your experiment
them easy on a brief academic side track
I I was working with probabilistic
models
for educational about a year ago and I
stumbled across your MIT group
researchers are where causality and and
vision entrances
played a huge role do you to you work
with that
stuff in this particular physics engine
yen if so on yeah I mean you did mention
some
in the beginning so how would you
structure your
a brief I mean obviously yep I'm
repression
sir I so the way that the physics engine
works
and in terms of like making predictions
about stuff is thats
if I really busy and on you run some
probabilistic
samples and then you can like samples
victim you have them
am but I've been doing some work and i'm
looking at how people
I actually confer physical properties
from watching
like these types of simulation so like
if some other box for heavier than
others and that cause the tower to fall
in a different way I can people make
those types
inferences and that requires using no
immediate model
thats you work in progress
but am yet but definitely that 30 paper
modeling that we're doing here three
legal and and so what actually
but me talk about ask you about this is
with every successive I mean
it's an obvious every success experiment
you see the more detail like believe
updation
and whether this particular one is so
using this is not a graph structure
inference
in particular but there's other
researcher and
so what further for stuff with by
conferring mass we can definitely do
things about point updating and in this
particular these experiments what I
should do here
wooden require about ok
up baby how to talk to you more about it
later yes sir thank you
up
our pressure I had more questions about
I'll and act like can it do you
cast simulation like object on ok
and I I
pre-christian I so it an
I can I think you can do
add deformable objects I'm not entirely
sure
we haven't done anything with that yet
an I
in terms of probabilistic first classic
simulations
bullet itself cannot but that's like
that essentially like what we're
building on top a bullet to create a
model
and then in terms of a as I was the last
a question but yes adding fourth alright
yes out
I so you actually you can set the
gravity to be whenever you want
it's not you know in a diaper and a by
default your to set that so you could
absolutely shattered be nine-point
and there's a really interesting
experiments that people have been doing
in
in terms like having people reason about
situations in which the gravity is like
put up side down father 5.0 but it's
really for every search
thank you