okay
hi everyone i'm happy to introduce this
wasn't an who will be
speaking about biking in the browser an
intro to brighten this
welcome her with a with applause and
higher
tight morning an
said is is my second I can and I'm a
first time speaker by time
so I'm really curious about the type
that saw for occupations in his audience
how many here
are full-time prime and buckle up
developers who use
jobs get day think
a said gee changes myself my name is
Susan am a recent college graduate
I ma Sudoku search contributor to number
pipeline projects
%uh in particular I open hash out our
Islamic era by jacks
I've previously a bus in May commits to
Django to a free market the iPad new
book
in which I redesigned E many bar in DUI
in the look and feel
I pine iPad dunno but version 2.0 I
previously I worked as a web application
engineer
at such terrifying two meters which is a
movie technology company in San
Francisco
so I every wish to retire to working
with John that over the past year
so I free was right before I can I love
my job so
now I hope I find out for higher so I
so if you are right on software engineer
in sears is going to talk to me after
its
gonna so it does it will be the first
presentation that you're here to talk
about a JavaScript library
in a python conference as you know
python is completely missing on the
client side
were JavaScript dominates jobs can is
appear exported in all browsers every
browser is a JavaScript compiler
so about half a year ago I discovered
this
brand new experiment a library card
berth on and here's a quick live dunno
so here I can
stored just a ball by numerical order
I can sorry my alphabetical order XO
by a twenty inspector omit up
at see 'em
ego to describe tag
instead of seeing a javascript script
tag you see a Python script tag rating
has been interesting
so I should engineers from France
decided
to create a new concerns Stice brand new
JavaScript library
because refrigerator they can use Python
to do client-side programming
so the this animated library
for people who dislike dogs cats so I am
very
early new user and this friend library
corporate bond
all talk about the use case for why
Piper your browser give a strong case
for it
I'll talk about some existing features
our breath on at compare
a to do list made in javascript and no
one made a brief on
over there is also some simple speech as
and comparing breakdown against both
Javascript
and Python all goood limitations upright
on a white
it still needs to work on and also talk
about the future of plants I Python and
jobs can
as a disclaimer I am NOT accord upper on
Python
nor do I use a slight for induction so
this is not going to be some adage about
why you should or should not use by time
duction
this talk will also not be about at
different architectural approaches in
making a Python implementation a browser
he's all really interesting topics but
free throws in this talk is mostly about
broken from a user perspective
so
who are the people who are most likely
going to you really want to have
Python in the browser I think they're
going to be friend and engineers I think
they're going to need a scientist and
engineers
and they're going to be engineers were
working in the intersection
as well and data have been
so indie scientific research
fields at the scientists are hilly
evermore
increasing amounts evita and the need a
way to
look at data in didn't in tractor way
and be able to visualize data
and in a meaningful way and overall
I'm this will really push the boundaries
of what can be downright fun and
what development as as you know dead
JavaScript d3 library is the most
a popular JavaScript visualization my
readers out there
and at its I'm a huge fan of the d3
library however I feel that it's fairly
limited to doing
a study expands and styling and of
course d3 is not
crew it was not created to do heavy duty
computations
a python it %uh trip up by that is
really popular ever do numerical
computations
so so why not in the future at can we
leveraged
pipeline scientific libraries to perhaps
create in
a competitive alternative or a
complementary tool
to the three JavaScript library so what
are the goals of this
Python your browser topic is 10
eventually create
instantly interactive our clients I D
wise like
that's power by Python and and why
should we need a live server
when potentially d entire
on computation can't exist on the
client site and just how to run in
browser
so this is a very challenging topic and
there are no
DR number of projects at a popped up to
solve this problem from a number of
technical
angles and so I'll be talking about one
of those projects
okay so just give some context DR number
%uh paid ninety dollars for compilers
these are yet the a listed some
stand-alone compilers
in a they're all in different stages of
completion and success
I dare to do it in browse
implementations us called
and bright on d32 JavaScript libraries
dot parse out
and do sources stores compilation
love I thank God at Scott is fairly
limited to running Python inside
a web browser consul in school does not
come with a damaged
yeah I to read that is the only project
and is less tax
not only has a DOM API so that we can
manipulate Asian art yes
elements but you can also
at have it load on peace out and said
the entire compilation process happens
directly on page lead
so I'm going to present a case for why
Python all images
she should be in a browser so by
valentino is more fun to read and it's
more readable than jobs good
and if you're in jobs given any capacity
you know that it gets messy and
unbeatable
fairly quickly even when you're writing
for medium-sized applications
at so fun is a search is urs compiler
dot
translates as high a level dynamic
language to another high-level dynamic
mileage
at break time has support for a good
subside at the Python programming
language including
features such as decorators list
comprehension is generators
programming in deep browsers possible
imprint on because
it has support for Don for a CG for Ajax
for
website the connections between the
client and server
also by program you buy than you can
circumvent the problems are losing jobs
care such as
at global variables and functions get up
and I think the most important
are powerful feature I thought it is
Donnie PI because without it on the PI
you can really make any blockages
so I'm just going to go over how to get
started when first time so
for should get the profound ideas file
Fondy source repository on the bucket
and then you include s brought on by
Jess file into a script tag
NiSource rectory dan you in bed I think
a inside the script tag
is the reserve does this reply damage a
python skin tag
danube I'll include aid I thought AP
body tag
that then invokes deep breath on my very
which then replaces all the perpetrator
in with JavaScript code
soon as I read it as a minimal sample
what you need to do to get right on up
and running
so not nixon just going over some a DOM
API methods and Python and compare them
against a Cray
an easy jQuery as a reference because
this is a really common JavaScript
library it's very much use in just
every model lineup occasional well so
indie cory Kennedy
selected on armies and attached I'd
syntax imprint on
you can import the doc model from the
browser package and an
ice lactis Donna amid using the back in
addition or you can use to get method to
do that
in Jaipur you can add or remove CSS
classes using the Add classroom if
possible didion proprietors Rd
names at the CSS classes in Perth on as
almost exactly the same syntax
in Jaipur you can append down on issues
India Penn function any
that can function takes 10 the name and
the new dad
at delivered don t want to create
in breath on you can create a new
development using dis is she a model
which comes up a number of methods such
as
did our table ally and all these methods
can take in
as a primary city name at the closet in
a min baad
then you can append a new Dave to newly
created a sound that uses
at rocking education
suppose you have a but in on a page and
you want to binding on click
event handler on this but how do you do
that
IndyCar you can bind you that using D
bind method
in which buying tix nd type other than
handler and also
the function to get invoked when an the
bite is cracked
so this case when one is like at to
hello just gets printed
to Roger birth on it's exactly the same
sit and you can use the Find function
local storage is the key value
client-side database
stars that persist for that particular
machine and ProductID tubular browser
in JavaScript you can use the side of a
method to static Ian value here
you can Gandhidham you get D
value by you speak enough to remove the
item
a in Python you can use a storage model
to you it accessible storage and you can
see the syntax is surprisingly similar
to that is
500 cherries
in primetime are you can also ask such
different JavaScript object in my
version brittan
using this jobs you might also this is
how you access the G core labor if you
wanna
right Jacory are some other library just
library along with friends on
got so so now I know who ventured on the
planet it's
and if you're familiar with double scat
d quintessential hello world application
in the JavaScript when is the to do list
app and if you go to you it to do NBC
dot com
thing is he did a whole lot of examples
and different US after implemented from
different jobs can be /c frameworks
so here's a live demo
get so dizzy is it to do the job I can
added a number things
I can check them off I can delete items
because a clear to do items citizens the
jobs conversion
at the top
this is the brittan version at the I can
do exactly the same thing
and he can see a bad care but you have
to take my word for it
this is a rent an apt
so pretty much in is a recon at whatever
you can do with Javascript jQuery to be
much impact on
okay let's go over some result for the
time to us I use the iPod Nano Doug time
it module to run dis
my pump engine for a dozen times and get
the average up
in in Python there's no time in mind
also had to use the thai model instead
tad at to get the time it takes for some
children and then I use a for loop just
at a rate reduction
a dozen times are birth on is pretty
slow its
is Lord and either jobs report or Python
by 23 times
in another example operate on a slower
by
financial spread by 117 times in this
case
and is a serious limitation up it takes
time to
for president you do compilation from
500 jobs get there take time for jobs
get %ah so
interpret the JavaScript code
perhaps it is this year's limitation
because and this makes a huge difference
in to perceive a poor performance
have how long it takes for pages to load
and when you have
a very slow page load time dan bounce
rates go up and it's generally bad user
experience
this is the output Rd Brampton code from
the
up that first function agency did its
there's a lot of good I guess generated
from even a very simple for lip because
the
that for example Python uses its own
number object instead using javascript
native number object and an overall up
by thought is really slow
because it does not do you any
optimizations that you would still
expect
a compelled to do
okay so if a slow I use it
it having a slow jobs your labor can be
a big deal breaker
biting that breath on is the first app
or is it opens the door to
trading true for stack but applications
entirely in Python
a many examples that have seen in Python
are typically fine and
data-intensive visualizations
and at Burbank really supports a number
of core by the models such as math
daytime ijs on
at car models but and there's there's a
lot
murdered many other models that doesn't
quite a point yet
so because all the compilation is done
and %um page lead its
this makes for a very slow library
another's years limitation is at break
time
has no support for deep as scientific
Python libraries because most the
library's
are for in and see dealer in for trying
to make API calls to C Python
come is a disease really big limitation
because
if you want to have eventually to have a
fast
scientific Python in a browser dan
veggie somehow you had you'll have to
get the scientific libraries in the
browser
so so one potential solution may be to
just be right
old number I and i thought id and
included in incident proton
30 Traci any an
so I was annoyed at the fact that while
I was making to do list and I had to use
print statements everywhere so
I really wish there is so serve debugger
jewel like PDB in Python
Rd bug which one JavaScript like you
just like parts coder executions that's
something I wish list
for offers new library
okay so whether or not you want to
convince her employer to start using
this
new experimental library is really going
to be up company-specific
what is the business value and well as
engineering and project
to take it ballistic centers for
mean questions that much are usually
when I ask
as general guidelines 10 difficult what
how do you evaluate this brand new how
do about any brand new toy library or
premark
and the first question I ask is what
problems that's all
for Python at it's all been a problem
with putting
a it so many problems using dolls
favorites is neither additional
a friend and option to to code and
is it easy to use and learn I would say
it's fairly easy to get back on are set
up and running so
an says that I would say is it is really
easy to use and learn and
the documentation does contain lot
examples
who else is using it why and says a
brother is a very new library discreetly
in my knowledge no
up the bobek using Python so if you have
a user base at 0 it's kinda hard to get
other people to also use this tool to
and engine in general people the toll
that have
a larger Jimmy behind it will have
people who have more experience using an
art
be you'll have more documentation to go
along with this to a library
is in active development at for bright
on its it's just an
the releases come out once or twice a
year there's a breadth angle group for
people to
sign up and read what's going on and ask
questions and follow its development
and is required for it a library or just
any neutral to be an active
about me because you don't want an dead
the new tool to just fall over become
deprecated next day
okay so I just a talk about what's
coming up next for JavaScript
at .javascript six is coming up by
Ginobili
at but into the air to Firefox
and if you read the specifications I
love the syntax but in new dollar strip
sex
unit is that there's a whole time new
syntax a particular interest is the
syntax for
the JavaScript list comprehension
generators and the syntax rat looks
strikingly
similar to that to Dalit Python syntax
and it does not a coincidence because D
writers a job sex like directly ripped
out of from Python syntax
say JavaScript ecosystem is a very large
goings ecosystem
Dr subscripts a javascript and
up new languages that are trying to
solve the problem I've
how do you create very fast ap
JavaScript applications how you create
very
skillful jobs can applications
there's a wide your number up MVC
frameworks for doing client side jobs
for programming
and and they're all trying to solve
problem I'll how do you maintain
really massive JavaScript bases
right extra if you try to google top
fifty dollars go by various
ya got very many different options it is
a very crowded
messy ecosystem and it's really hard to
predict
what any day you will replaced all the
step in the future
but I'm I wanna make the claim that
if any labor o'toole were to replace or
complement JavaScript it would have to
be compatible with
the rest at the Johns computer system
and I also wanna make a claim that
dollar spent
but still the main issue and a point for
yet another five years
yet so the efforts own putting a fast
scientific Python in a browser is just
story disses ex super early stage
field and I think that all the efforts
to put
eighty %uh Python in a browser are
really going to push
what's possible left fine and web
development
operate on is just one project amongst
many other projects that are
in this at relatively new field I want
to mention
very briefly a number other interesting
projects
that are also trying to solve the same
problem
there's this new anti ld3 library dot
combines
both D map hardly a Python library with
died
deep three so it basically at generates
decreased JavaScript directly from
are not part led generated charts and
graphs
there is this very brand new pipe I dot
JS which combines
d aspects to de pie pie
compiler project a very fast Python
implementation with TM script in
at Seco to JavaScript compiler and
the person who's treatises its busy
trying to implement a.m.
de pie pie interpreter ref the jet
and distress we all die in JavaScript
with the help of in Skipton
a so so if you've ever used
matplotlib and if you try to plot a
hundred million day a poison apple at
Live
you read into memory she is and
do this new project out called this the
a pipeline project that aims to you
up solve the problem at how do you
officially handle extremely large
datasets and how do you
generate interactive visualizations fan
at both
static data and real-time data is
extremely light
said this be is based on the open GL a
project
a and its utilizing the computers cheap
user graphical processing units to
due out in real-time parallel processing
and data
and as you know the iPod Nano bug isn't
super popular it's
a game changer in the Python ecosystem
and I think the iPad the new book itself
represents a major step forward in
moving Python to the browser in version
1.0 it supported
static plots in the current version 2.0
people can now creates JavaScript based
visuals
banana bach and people can now
prototype JavaScript budgets and editing
and 43 into it
so does is pretty exciting times and I'm
really excited to see
like how these products will evolve into
next year
and when for his all brand new
and uncertain options but but when
Python finally comes to the browser in
which
ever she performed I'm I really sure
that the state
a friend about the bomb it will be more
richer more attractive
and be drastically different than it is
today
thank you
if anyone has any questions please
built-in microphone whether
any questions so i IC
a lot of talk about their compiling
certain things like pipe on into
JavaScript and having the JavaScript
engine in the browser on the image
is a clean solution because it can stand
alone but
I'm there are other approaches for
example he can there are
some a.m. projects out there that
interface
not a plugin to allow the I am a
a pipe bomb interpreter real type an
interpreter to run
in the background in actually can
interact with JavaScript you can export
its classes to JavaScript akin
poor JavaScript any jobs predominant a
pipeline have you explored any of those
kind of options
i havent exploiters options but a few
di haven't your name on those projects I
by I started one another another 1i
storm in a while back I think Tom
its own get pub in reply work at three
its specific to the I'm
WebKit ecosystem so that you some
drawbacks to it
but it's %uh it's fascinating because
you can interact completely with the
JavaScript environment
back and forth between Python and
transcriptome pretty seamlessly
I'll out thank you for sharing and your
okay on
hi thanks for talks is in arm question
goes into kinda similar action
in all the examples I've seen on on
Brighton so far
arm I don't see what the advantage as of
compiling Pythian
in the browser as opposed to pre
compiling its
to jap scripts and not having to deal
with that
on the client sites from great 0 about
the options and looked into
known as a stand-alone compilers have 8
da maybe I
that's built into it and and so I
handprint on is
it's really easy to get set out and like
running
and I i feel that it's is doing days a
little bit differently
then what the other comply project today
thanks
so on
you talked a bit about the performance
UHV are brought in and held serve
can sometimes be really slow and do you
have a sense of
love how much of that is kinda
fundamental limitation of the approach
this is how much of it is just well we
need to put in the work to generate very
JavaScript
others more amenable to the digital the
sorts of things
hmm I A N I'm not totally sure about
whether that's a fundamental limitation
by golly Kent Kent
is a possible today after mines first
hot front on to be really to be much
faster even daily
did semantics up getting pipe and it
just keeps exactly perfect
and Gnasher d exact answer to that well
perhaps a
sort of like questionentities is that
something that the broth and developers
a
working on adding those optimizations
yes yes there aware that
I'm
a thank you for talk arm us have a
common
about question just ask a like to
mention a
project that I contribute to its called
rapid script and it compiles
large Python JavaScript but its
has marva it's basically Adina
Python syntax is oscar's so you don't
need a EPI to
talk to the DOM I saw it has kept that
question
bypass I'm us have a question about
performance
compared to the other libraries a
Jeff numbers for skull Tom
pajamas the Jacka I and you have numbers
for
and performance at Firdos other
libraries and partially
thanks I
a thanks to talk on so the
I'd are you one of the biggest bears for
people using these news for
that's rough interpreters and
interpreters
is ours for the better debugging tool
for them so for example
on target at like the inspector for
dollars but doesn't want the best
angels out ever planted programming give
a sense that where
on things like that stand on the right
on road map is their plans and
one on at visit the things like
understanding what the an interpreters
doing my cat load time anything like
that I like really useful things really
for dollars I think up share so up
on on the user's ID can pretty much set
a debugging lovell
on and then at the pure bred Concord
itself
up and and other dorm or debugging tools
but that's really like where
that the limit debugging is really a
richer more debugging tools
in broken cool any more questions
okay thank you very much to send
the above