I'll go ahead and asserted marina 0 him
scared it will be a while she is
I a good friend of mine as well as an
the main organizer for the known
average program for women which see
pipeline is contributing front camera is
participating in for the first time this
summer
on his on aboard the note and Asian any
aid initiative
I'm says all kinds really great outreach
with red had are so please I join me in
welcoming renowned for her talk
on Irish program for women lessons in
collaboration
hi everyone
I so we're good redhead as a community
engagement lead and just got fed
I'm in a border the ED initiative and
implementation and need initiative the
organizations that
works in supporting women in open
technology and culture
and a deacon opened Asian a is an
organization that supports
as it known destined for Linux and as
I'll be talking about the outreach
program for women
and it has its origins in 2006
a when going home received a 181
applications for Google Summer of Code
and none of them appeared to be from
women and Google Summer of Code is a
program where Google paid
a stipend for students to work remotely
was a mentor for three-month
are on have free software project and
I'm when and Chris Bowen Hannah will
look at %uh so this was a key that we
didn't get any
applications from women say put together
and two months program
are just that very seen summer that
invited women to participate directly
and had an
a more collaborative language are so
instead of an
thing prove you're a rockstar show
you're the best
and it was talking about how this is an
opportunity
to work with a mentor and learn and the
received about a
100 applications and six women
did internships with known that summer
from
and then nothing happened for and
a couple years and in 2009 I find myself
to be wanna
that eight women added numbers and
annual conference
and I'm I was perhaps one of the most
devilish
female developers in going home at the
time and money
outnumbered approached me to organized
as the
outrage from for women or renew our
outreach initiatives to
and before a dead bin
into how the program works
this is like a very strong much meeting
for the program
and things like this happen this is a
from this year were
one of the participants the in a picture
of a woman was approached to 10
I for them bowed western wear while many
men
told her that they were surprised to see
girls there and
this is why it's very important to have
support communities for women
am to I'm kinda showed each other that
yes we
do belong here and also it's important
to have a bomb
people working on I'm
in a dedicated way on provided in best
practices
resources such as wood at the ED
initiative does and the geek feminism
wiki and
I like to encourage everyone to him read
am a recent blog post by the eat
initiative
are called break-ins a unicorn mom Anne
you know carlos know that any woman in
free software will sooner or later be
asked to do a talk about being a woman
and free software
and so I II EE we r
break-in the them already
but this blog post also provides great
resources
for how you can find out and about the
experience a women in free software
without approaching new women in your
community
directly and asking them to represent
all other women and where
like how you can get more women
participating so instead recommend
reading this blog post it had the
resources
arm in particular supporting initiatives
such as that which room for women
the aid initiative I'll paying attention
to the Korea Development
of women you're working with and takin
as the ED initiative allies workshop or
going over the resources that are online
art that can I'm that cover how to
respond to sexist incident and how to
best support women
be so in terms of the outage from for
women
it is them there are similar to Google
Summer of Code we have a
paid a three-month into am
remote internships from and as they
happened twice a year one run happens
from May to August
and now they're around happens from at
December to March
the difference ours that it open to all
women that have to be students
and we also learned that it's important
to
state explicitly that its open to
women that I'm to people who have fun
there is gender identities so it's open
to women who assist entrance into
gender queer people and the default
language I'm is a exclusive
Inc exclusivity fold so which is why for
example it is important for us to say
that it's open to women
this entrance in all our major
announcement for flyers
and also and non-coding projects such as
documentation and design
are available as part of the program in
addition to the coding project from
be and we've had a seven rounds have
internships
130 participants was all those
organizations
and be the sum of the sponsors that I'd
like to think a big thank you to you
well and also redhead contributes my
time to organize in the program
and Ropes & Gray the law firms that
health helped as drafted
contracts for participants and mentors
so how we do it M in addition to address
in
a purchase a band the audience that were
true targeting directly
and been open to non students in un
codice a very important part of the
program is that it has
abt a collaborative application process
to so all the mentors
for particular organization are listed
online on the organization beat and what
we ask %uh
applicants to do is to connect it was a
mentor during the application process
and a meek contribution
and with as mentors help that is
relevant to the project that they're
proposing
to work on and that really serves as
them
something that allows all the applicants
to learn how to contribute to free
software community
and also served as a very important
selection criteria for us through
and during the program at the time at
to focus for the interns and to build
their experience
contributing to free software and
very importantly we ask %uh participants
are
to blog every two weeks and we
incorporate
other blogs on me organizations planets
and also on the women
increase of Triplanetary which is it's a
great planet I recommend reading it it's
I find it very inspirational I also
as part of the program we have a five
hundred dollar
travel alone and the participants can
use it
to travel to a conference for to an
event where they can meet
a mentor in the community do
and up to the ProBook after the program
I the mentorship continues and we have
I'm I will talk to participants about
their career interests those
as someone her hers were has done a
tremendous job
talking to two people participate in the
program in talking to the mentors a bad
how we need to I be proactive about
address in as the participants future
career plans
and be we encourage
as the participants to go in and
presented conferences
and here for them politically cues from
Jessica because the
she has been just done a tremendous job
getting
people I'm I'm getting women to
presented
Aiken by asking everybody including me
in
I took a cue from her in for example for
a lot
aquatic I A have aft women who
participated as interns and other women
in it numb community
and and that helped produce dramatic
results for how
the number of speakers increased I am
forgot ok
so as good it's it's it's extremely
important out to ask women in your
communities
a.m. to propose talked to conferences
and also one thing that I'd like to
touch on is them often when we talk
about the internship like this
am people talk about return on
investment arm
how dole I'm whether
the people who did the internship
whether they stuck around and this is
something picked up from
Leslie howitzers dog which is basically
it's okay that they
if they have moved on it it was a
privilege for us to have been able to
share our values with them
and people are exploring and they will
carry on those values but it might not
be was
your project or I'm
with the same kinda field but is just
very important already that will work
able to influence
I how they think about the world and
what's possible
I'm so we've had about forty women it
lies to help
noms conference
and we had ten women speakers and this
is a
for be on a CMOS and she's them talking
about how to rip
work your user experience bug
based in her masters I see sleuth
and she was them a participant in the
program was going home
also of course at the Bison community is
a leader in
outreach to women as well and I'm
the /url by Tim project has joined arm
the outreach group for women for this
round and
I'm the were 14 applicants who worked
with the mentor
are to complete a contribution and if
you would like to help with this effort
going forward
please join the choir mentorship list
which is where all the
our communication with the applicant's
happen
and I'm the project that that people
will work and I
in three areas: it them graphical bison
am male libraries for bison and also
improve in
experience documentation and features
for biting on Windows
and of course the number women I'm
given a toxic by some health risen
dramatically
well and here's some project that
people have done in Python as part of
the outreach program for women
so those are just representative over
bomb
in sir abut typical
a project that interns complete during
their internships
and not surprisingly for the people have
misled
on my plate here are they are by
couldn't so
up Stacy Marta Terry in Sindhi
artbuy can quit because the they done
projects and bison
those days it'd a terrific I am talk
about
twisted on Friday here and during her
inch
internships she worked about honor API
documentation for
I'm twisted am meal and she also wrote
am SMTP client and server tutorial them
I Martin ilene I worked in no and marcia
did
am a beginner's tutorial for writing
up no obligations in Payson and she has
also presented
a poster about that I can last year and
the theater poster
at pagan was them but how to go to from
a beginner
in buys into an intermediate level
what to do and Elaine worked on them
I it for getting things going on which
is the task manager
foot known and she added geolocation two
tasks and tender than allowed
I am soaring tax tasks based on the
proximity
to the user I tasha Reign worked
on now um gazebo Robert simulator for
outdoor environment
and her project she rodin OpenStack
plugin
the a ser OpenStreetMap plugin and it
took
the information from are OpenStreetMap
I and up elated out in a simulated
environment so she'd represent
buildings as polygons a street signs
three Clydes
roads and including as a tech sure if
the road in the number of lanes
houses there was her project and several
interns worked on OpenStack
and Victoria did I'm user interface
improvements
i'm for the horizon dashboard Terry
worked
on them 13 absurd API options
our fourth la mettre metering module
then a
Sayali I'm to the data from the slum in
a murine model
and did graft are to represent the data
in the
in the presidential board and Cindy
worked on them
improved login and error handling
out for the team out for the
a application messaging API called
marconi
though all really cool project very
successful
and I'm or Linux kernel community is
also produce Peyton
in that age group for women and here you
can see how
7 interests who worked with the kernel
out last summer
I'm did more contributions then some of
the industry leaders
well and this is a summary ovum
interns accomplishments people go on to
do talks find employment with sponsoring
organizations
I'll good do Google Summer of Code a
hacker school
I become mentors I'm really cool things
have
happened I was a alarm is star in their
own initiatives
Mac fourth started at Chicago and hiking
and gone group
Martha too much started in a row be deaf
school which is similar to hackers cool
as the tub dedust hurted are women in
free stuff for a group in India
are and you could during the caress
mother became at North addition board
member
and also improve in arm on ramps for
women in
in the ban on community have helped us
improve on ramps for all newcomers
the for example the are mentors list
that was started for the program
has grown to be a general resource in
was over forty mentors that
any newcomer can approach am anytime
are to get started with the project and
also are we took such lessons there them
engage in participants I during the as
the
contribution process during the
application process
to have the make a contribution and work
was a mentor during that time and also
have in them blog am at least every two
weeks about their work in
aggregating blog post and planet known
and and and that improves
the engagement of the participants with
the
community a a lot
and am so we're almost done with the
selection process was this round and
will have
internships from May to August and then
the next run
attended a little have an application
deadline in October and
internships from December to March
and beyond that so we have a good idea
of how to run
a program I for women I'm
to help them build this experience to
start contributing to free software
I'm and I'm would like to see like
who else that we not reaching an to the
value that
I'd like to mention two initiatives that
are I'm close to my heart that
I i doing a tremendous work I'm from
other directions are so the aid
initiative
works in I'm helpin conferences adopt
anti-harassment policies
organize in he did camp switcher
conferences for women
interesting in her working on improving
when power
improving participation of women in open
technology and culture
it are runs them allies workshops
the Chiefs to cheat teach Alice kills
about how to support women
and help sexism and it also creates
best practices resources other blogs
just fantastic
they already mentioned and open hatch
om has an initial words the
I'm have a curriculum for open source
comes to campus workshops which a
full-day workshops for students
to learn about how to contribute to free
software and
um they often work with women in
Computer Science Group on campuses
so their workshops typically have a
lotta women participating in them
be I silicon and dad
I am other metric that we have
I'm when women participation in Google
Summer of Code has
outgrown over the years and it's a in
producers outreach parable: women
because
we encourage women who are called urs
and
students who qualify for Google Summer
of Code to apply for Google Summer of
Code
are also initiatives such as open hatch
an aid initiative
help create a supportive clomid
and Google's own open source OfficeTeam
does some outreach work as well up but
also google has the Google Code in
which is a program for high schools
students to contribute to free software
and out ovum forty grand prize winners
in the last two years
only one with the girl and and when I
saw this
data I was like I work is cut out for us
was at risk for a buoyant
so I'm I'd like to do something about it
and I would like to do is the
I've been talking to open hatch about
how we can I'm
try to tailor their curriculum are to
take those workshops
to up girl couldn't group
I am so would need others a group to
have already
I'm learn some code is a reasonable can
work with that girls a black girls code
and I introduce growth there to
contribute into free softer and also
offer a
in person mentorship I just in general
in contributing
a two-fer suffer but also in
participation in Google Code and once we
figure that out
I'll we can ask other people in our her
program alumnae and mentored network and
just general the broader community for
everybody to just go to
one high school class 01 to girls group
in your area
and am offer this workshop
an offer in in person mentorship or like
you could need
are without the student at a library in
can help her
contributed to free software project and
hopefully we can
we can change those numbers and and also
said
mention that I'm there have been at 10
percent girls participate in
in Google Code in in last year but jazz
at nine of them
went on to to be at grand prize winner
well so looking at some other statistics
I'm a lot a bomb practically
all are participants in the last year in
at Richboro for women
have had a higher education away pursue
in one only
only two arm had some college education
but were no longer pursuing it
so we're not reaching people who are
less advantaged
and don't have access to higher
education
also looking at the geographical data at
the country's here are the countries
that had more than one participant
in outreach from for women so that it's
a little bit of an arbiter list but
I'm the point is here to show that all
those countries are
indifferent but ways am are represented
in phnom others for for women Google
Summer of Code Ann
of lost sir be I'll but the I'm
you know they're all fairly well
represented
on other hand we can home
look at the countries that were not
reaching at all with them an opportunity
to contribute to free software because
they have been barely at represented in
in any of those venues well
and also I'll we don't have data for
this between on a daughter lizard
sir few people of color in our
communities and
one interest in our point is that in
United States
um the number of people of color
getting computer science degrees is
roughly similar to their representation
in in the general population but we're
just not seen them in our communities
and legs disparities in the way similar
to how
other 18 percent over bob women I get in
computer science degrees in United
States
but before all the outreach efforts we
had about 23 percent are women
are participating in free software
I'll so average from for women we are
thinking about it
I'll in ways to expended
to make it an outreach program for
under-represented people to expend more
broadly but would
do need to figure out like how we
expended in gentle ways because
right now we typically have thirty to
forty participants around and
and we need to know how to grow gently
I'll
a very cool initiative that a look at
the block has started at Muslim
is them the send project and inert
hershey's them targeting people that
I'll are underemployed I'm lesbian gay
bisexual transexual a queer
latina african-american First Nations
basically people who are
underrepresented in underprivileged
and its them the they're gonna have a
stick with six-week pilot
in Portland and the new orleans and
the goal is to make it manageable for
people who live paycheck to paycheck
and they're gone accomplices Bay are
having a fifty dollar
birdie honorarium for the attendees
providing laptops
providing food add and transit passes
and the successful participants gonna
receive a laptop
me and has it that they can continue
building on a skills
and the goals I'll all bomb this boot
camp
gonna be too see two participants
JavaScript
are techniques hour for contributing to
free software
build automated tests for Mozilla and
talk about what opportunities are out
there
what are the next steps introduce them
to people
arm and as in this is terrific and
one is the ticket was for me for example
that are
after going through this program people
will be arm
very good candidates for the I fish room
for the underrepresented people which
have which is like the format the same
format as at Richboro for women that we
wants to all voters prefer women into
and
you can watch this basis and project at
work if you I would like to know more
about this initiative and the ways you
can help with
that you can be a teaching assistant if
you were in Portland on New Orleans so
you can come and present
about your work %uh so come find me a
Lucas or
I'm arm there will be us on an
com than project at work email
address available and home
so you can help this way but also their
look into I
and document
I the results of those two pilot
programs and I'll be looking for
partners to replicate the season in
other areas
in other geographical locations
and here's how you can help with the
outreach program for women
firstly can apply to participate you can
become a mentor if your organization is
already participating
you can get your organization to
participate you can get
your company to sponsor internships and
right now is a really great opportunity
to jump in and help because them
we had 120 applicants for this round
who completed a contribution and works
was a mentor right now have funded for
if your company interested in sponsoring
some of the applicant that we already
have we definitely have more great
applicants would love to accept
hours and 37 °c couldn't you can make a
difference at right here
Lake read this week and you can also
donate to the confrontation
art to help us build the infrastructure
to support the program
and all this information is that admin
on that work session would be W
and these are just some of the
references to the a
deter in articles I have provided I am
in a talk an awful are the a Creative
Commons share-alike License
and you can find me in the program on
Twitter
and I'm just gonna go back to the
previous lied about how you can help
then
well good for questions don't thank you
so much
and we do have time for questions
there's only one my kids over here so
please cue up
over here
question um
high action a buncha questions but old
just us one right now
I am an order something really
interesting your stats about the number
participants but by country
no India overall was huge
but it was smaller I mean the
proportion between the the top tourism
reversed
between women in and the and general G
sock
yeah is it the more interestingly it's
there's it's even more drastically
rivers between who's a flaw serbia
reached
yes so so as I think I'm the way I can
explain it is dead
Google Summer of Code is our hugely
popular in India it has
Google brand on it I and
are also the stipend as if fifty five
hundred dollars stipend is
is a very substantial amount of money to
to get in India
%uh so which is why I think it's I'm
the Google Summer of Code is I so
popular in India and
and is a little less popular but so
popular in United States
on the other hand I United States has so
many participants in at risk from for
women because we have so many
support group Women in Technology Group
that
I developed more much more so than in
Europe there are definitely some in
India
I'm so i think is just that they are so
developed in the United States
but also kinda looking at the number for
how many people participate in the flow
story which
I do believe was spread widely to the
different communities and I think that
shows us how many
people consider themselves on
established receptor contributors arm
in so up basically how many people I
relatively image country go on
to continue contributed to free software
and and be connected on als me llamaste
that the survey was sent in
in hi my name is vetoing allow
on one quick question is on a slide you
said you can
by the state as becoming a man don't do
you have the
them stab Saudi have a document many
chills
how we can be contribute ASM becoming a
mentor
said to become a mentor right now you
need to be affiliated with an
organization that participates
though if I if you're affiliated was one
of the
sorry was one of these participating
organizations
I you can become a mentor it was damn
and if not you can get your organization
to participate
and you can talk to me about it more
okie I'll come back and talk to you
later
share lol I'm sure it
I'm pair December and drink it will be
for North Carolina we love Red Hat
home you love your new building school
have you seen it
enough that the miracle Eiman Boston
area well i met your mother all about it
yeah legalese and check it out I am tho
I have a possible question period in the
Bay Area's have put me Theo
with the mail is we're trying to get
people who are underrepresented into
something
he need to have representative I'll
them as the ambassador yeah
it's helpful yeah and so how is you
help more under-represented people
become ambassadors and do it
have great power them yes it does so
this is why I have my
sorry to play commuter are you doing my
slide
this is why I have as the request for
anyone who
who on feel that people like them are
underrepresented to please come talk to
me
on after the talk I
a and its I'm actually really glad that
your question panel led me to
to to mention that I because at
yes at the me and Mike organizer Karen
Sandler
we had as explained that we had to be
able to
is at risk from for women but it we
really need are
the advice in the leadership of people
out who are from other underrepresented
groups
and and Lucas who started the program at
she felt that she came from
the place where she was working from
paycheck who death and project
she came from a place where she was
working from paycheck to paycheck
and then she went into technology so she
has the kinda perspective to do the
center project and it's actually a
always have a question that we have but
let's definitely move this to be how a
track thank you so much right now be
outside
thanks awesome in a Nextag here you
suffer injury research for hackers
bridging the two solitudes wat the taj
Armstrong