so this will be last talk for the day is
going to be a talk called
Python plus geographic data because to
be a bus
please give a hand for Miley sacks Ben
Burnett
there is this fabulous bitly link to my
talk
and including everything that I'm not
going to have time to say in markdown
format
cell there's that for your reference
thank you for hanging out till the end
of the day
and I'm really excited to share this
with you
so why do a thing Python and geographic
area gonna be best friends forever
well I love maps but making them can be
a real pain
and it the reason is wild card harper's
don't just trace stuff anymore you have
to deal with
the dear and an
that can be really really really awful
it is usually not in the format that you
need there's like a hundred different
formats at least
several obvious errors everyone with
sinbad data has created their own now
island at some point
split up into fifty different files from
and is definitely in the wrong
protection so on
sometimes you even have no metadata so
you don't know what protection it in one
including its then
it can be pretty awful cell you can
point and click all day and you're outta
the box yes software
or you can bring Python it to the max
so a little bit about vector geo data
and before we get started it can be made
up of one or several files
it will have a cordon it's a steamer
production associated with it to show
held their ground earth ends up on a
flat surface
and it can be made up the one or several
layers have data
each of which has one or more features
and each feature has to have geometry
and that includes both the type so
whether it's a point line polygon
and of course its accordance themselves
and then
each feature also has berries other
attributes and properties these vary
widely depending on the data
so now we can talk about some my
favorite paper on packages to use to
deal with this problem
of the owners the first one that I
really like him
and what can be an
really awesome when you're making a map
there's great free data all over the
place national earth is a great place to
you
get and simplify made world
data and country is nice nice car to
graphically
mind out and a lot of interesting
attributes but it's usually not
in a format that I like cell but say we
wanna change it to dr. Jason
so after you download your data
you just create a really short sketch
and with Fianna
you can open it up it automatically
figures out what it means in the open
part but then when you open up your
output file you need to tell okay which
coordinate system agony use what's the
schema so that includes a geometry and
the attributes
on and what do you want to turn it into
you so here we're saying we just want to
use the same
as the input for the corner system and
the schema and but we want to change it
to GA Jason
and then for each feature in that
original file we go through it one by
one and say okay
the sizes on Antarctica let's keep it
and you can also filter by bounding box
if you want
the eastern hemisphere Western
Hemisphere much smaller or bigger than
that
you can do that really is Lee with your
own as well yea data
another great Python packages pipe
wrench so say you I am
projections can be a problem that last
one
actually not super pretty especially at
the top and bottom and
at the polls there an if you're tracing
great circle routes
if you are and making a map at the polls
you definitely need to use an
appropriate protection
and pay pride works really well with the
honor to do that so in this example
we are gonna go ahead and polling in the
schema from the original file
but then it take the coordinate system
and put it into production
object and then after we open it up
the new one and say okay I wanna get
I want it to be in projection 2163
that's a code any PSG code you can with
peace out these are well-known codes
felt kinda different productions
and then get ready to go and by putting
the output protection
in a projection and while
this is work it's kind of weird on
natural earth data and some other is
polygon something that's multi polygons
a multi polygon is kinda higher level
they can contain a number poly irons
South in either those cases you need to
treat it a little differently cuz the
corn its themselves will live one level
deeper so depending on whether it's a
polygon arm of the polygon
you use the yeah you you can a stack it
up a little differently but in either
case you used chance form which is fun
pipe Raj
to change every single core net one by
one
from the input production to the output
production
and then you can get something like this
spree awesome
one last year an example so I am a real
I'm quantified self
ke Kai & Bike Wear fit bid at Taconic
like Ryan's
I've never bothered to visualize the
mall in a map before
which is kinda silly colette make maps
all time
I'm one of the biggest problems is that
have all the separate tracks in out
download the all separately
and I just wanna do it once it on do it
over and over and over again
sell this example takes a whole bunch a
GPX tracks puts them in a single file
makes a lot easier to map and
so here what I do is a gravel one
example file
and grab décor nitsa stem in the schema
from that and then I said that your
normal kinda directory walking
operation pull everything that ends in
dot GP axe
and read through it an at it to you this
final file
so that I'm able to make appeals Asian
like this where I find out that I really
don't do much but go back and forth to
work all the time
and but that's okay I'm but before we go
any further let's talk a little bit
about your Jason to why do I keep
turning everything in GH a sign
it is Jason for geo data it's super easy
to use for web app being when adding
libraries and early love it
and it's really easy to perceive Python
because really it's
just dictionary
so here's kind im a weird example add to
talk that OpenStreetMap because
I'm on the board I love it an
OpenStreetMap is great because
it's a lot of free data proud source
that you can get from all over the world
they can be really hard to find a
scanner data anywhere else
on but the data structures really weird
and you get everything all at once so
what's am planning a trip to Japan which
I usually am planning 1 1 I'm going and
I
an and I wanna check out all the
buildings in this area them interested
in
you can just download them from the
OpenStreetMap website
but you're gonna get everything all all
that you can get streets you can get
to still you know the country of Japan
you can get all this by selecting a
scary it's kinda crazy
I N there are a number of ways to
convert it over to GH a sign
on but really it's just XML data see you
can dig into it with your favorite XML
parser
if you like it's while and then process
it so
the reason why I love JJ sign and why
pick this example
is you can just play with the dating
keep exactly what you want you don't
want you have to use
anyway I resolve really iron
you just load it up by using Jason lutes
I'm here we're creating a feature
collection dictionary that is going to
be valid year Jason when it's all done
and then we're going to loop through all
I'll features in that dataset
Shack all the tags in it to the way
OpenStreetMap
represented attributes is by
having tags for everything cell a
building with the name
is can have been building tag with some
value and a name tag
some value seldom I say that that's what
I want it so I check if theres
building Mary if there's name in there
let's go ahead and move on style
then we're gonna grab the ID pulled the
name out of the tags
grab all the other information we need
and then create on with those variables
the final Goga sign version that we want
cell
you put the geometry revlon's the
corners where they belong
keep name outside of tags and keep all
the other random tags
in this separate tactic sherry and go
ahead and add it to our final file
and all you need to do to create that
final Jason file then
is do jason Thompson then you can get
cool stuff like this
and he's all the buildings are at
Shinjuku I am but I shoulda got the
ramen shops instead
that's what I really care about now you
can also do some more operation with CSV
or XML data to you all you need to do is
put it in a dictionary
and then put your duties on together so
I do this when
organza datasets from all over the place
an and unable to make it so at the end
and only the features in the attributes
that I want
at the bench other stuff that I don't
that I don't need
if you have a lot of data that you can
switch to reading and writing line by
line by keeping kinda dictionaries one
line at a time
and I've done this with the whole
OpenStreetMap planet before
several gigs is probably not a good idea
but it worked
it's great and because it's just a
dictionary it's really easy to create
test for the data
you can check for required he is cell
say an your database that's gonna keep
the steering use it for something is
expecting certain keys to be their knees
had the boundary type string that
represents the datasource
you can check each key is and
value is what you expected to be you can
check against the listed known values so
say they're only a certain number of
trusted sources
or your filters are expecting certain
values you can check and make sure
that's also had a time
you can check the structure you know how
deep did the dictionaries go
and check to make sure the geometry is
allied so you don't end up with no
island
so this is a really important if your
system is expecting a very very
particular format will your data comes
from a Grady of sources so
at UA we get data from all over the
place we get map on exterior week at
OpenStreetMap data
we get a bunch a random stuff the
customers give us
and it all needs to be in exactly the
right format every single feature
or production incident and after I did
that once I was never again
no more protection incidents vacated the
said over and said it s really easily
and just by going to the dictionaries
and checking for the things that matter
also on you can you speak shapely for
spatial analysis India manipulation
cheaply as a super powerful
would but a library and there are tons
examples in the manual I made this wall
tax just a que native
show you how many things it can do you
how powerful it is I N
you can construct geometry is simple
fire create buffer areas
murders Union check distances between
paying this
gets a magical dear friend see if one
object contains the other object on and
on and on and on
it even works with 3d data and numb hi
all kindsa stuff that you can do with it
so remember the GPX tracks that we put
together earlier well someone then it
turns out
I didn't show them but I have a bunch in
California I don't deal with a man on a
deal with my flight to California either
I want just the ones that are in
Portland
and I wanna go through them one by one
by hand
so what i did. first time you just get
your city as Judy Sun
and an I read Portland on an
and put it in a shapely shape object
its geometry that is and the same thing
for each had the tracks and that
original file
I read them into shapely shape our jacks
and then I was able to do this really
easy
laying here check if their geometry on
that track
is within the context whole of Portland
yet we're gonna keep it I use the convex
hull because there's a little-known very
small city called Maywood park that was
formed when nobody wanted a freeway
built through it
and and my Ajax would have been excluded
that that passed through there
so I got the context Hall which is the
smallest polygon that would contain
everything within it
menu just to write it out
so it kept all the stuff in pink not be
plane tracks in the in beige their
that I didn't whites that's great
on another great option for
geoprocessing without GIS software
is posts s and that is an extension to
post guess
an as you many you probably know it
already well
I'm you can talk to a psycho pg2 it
works really well and you can run space
operations
directly with that and it works
surprisingly well
I finally GIS software love despite
on our GIS on
Azria I think it's actually sponsor Pike
on has on early
cool papon community is set section set
up
and they really like using our Python
for scripting they set up their own
arc pay module on that does all the
tasks within
I our GIS that you can skip to end other
create tools in Athens with them
cue Jess is kinda the closest open
source alternative to RJs
and it has it similarly it has a Python
console
it also has a cute this module that you
can
import from outside Azlan
outside a few to sell you can have a
third party app
that brings in the huge issue i
or or geoprocessing tools come without
actually having a Yankee jisne at school
on and development to cue just is
written in C
and input on C can contribute to the
development of it directly
there are more than 250 plugins already
for teachers and there are written in
Python
you can do you all kinds really really
interesting stuff this one is a
3d export an helps you make a 3d map in
a web browser with but GL
actually I talked way too ass i think im
over i think im we enter my time
so i think im just gonna open up for
questions that this plane
pincus I'll there's a there's a
microphone over there
if you need and
hi thank you very much I'd like to
ask if you would mind bring your first
slide back on so many copy your website
yes
sorry say their ego
thanks again for the talk home I've used
to own
no GRN GDAL am not familiar with the
owner can you
talk a little about the differences and
yeah so OJ
on the on actually uses ging Tom
armored kill people say either way I am
it it's just a paper on it kinda
interface to them see do you still have
to install the man you are actually
using them
just in a panic way
night arm great talk thank you think
arm I'm working on a project that
home SOC in modeling so the results that
we get
arm Havlat long date in the move also
got currents and stuff
we want work a social scientist that use
GIS so we've got beer in net CDR files
ok I N they watch shapefiles okay do you
have any recommendations on
I'll do that so so Oger
I am what that the guy in front of you
brought up came to you
almost any translation if ya know
works with a lot earlier she earned arm
sorry now and the words escaping me a
lot about your drivers
an piano works with them but it doesn't
support all them
I i'm not super familiar with the format
the
let CD after yeah i i'd I have used it
before said well
I don't have a particular tips for that
but yea I think I go to you may go to
his own gr
I'm which the only uses I am but doesn't
always support all the drivers I love
and that's just really is a command-line
I mean not really easy the people that
are free to the command line is
definitely not easy but
months you can to practice with a I'll
trust that I'm usually does the right
thing
okay thanks I'm
hi a I'm not sure the address the
spectrum
i was just curious about the biking data
like what format was that in
and also what did you use to visualize
the
yeah yet totally I can talk about that I
skipped
past six hours like I'm not gonna have
enough time in the head at a time
I am so this is actually not by King
David this is all of my data from
walking all around and traveling around
portland is an app called moots
and it basically tracks me all the time
in this is like a few months is
have news data and
so moose likely has a pretty friendly
API to plugs into a lot of tools there
said
an at a tool called moves export to use
to download a weak data at a time
because they didn't want to deal with
having to download them all individually
so once they had every week on as GPX
data so they will the download them as
GPX data
I'm fianna
can read there are actually several
layers in GPX data
track sir just wanted them see actually
have to tell Theon okay beat the tracks
layer
don't read the waypoints and I think
there are a few others
I am but once you have bad
and it's all thrown together so this
isn't that what i'll know
which is a knee I don't it's not
I don't know if it's open source I think
it's open source adds put up a company
called map box
and it's on top of their tiles here and
you use act something that's actually
cop car tow CSS to style
up and you get some composite operation
cited a
like a multiplying composite operations
that would be darker the places that I
want more
if you want to know more about town I
can I think Kansas
Google pile now a Google Map box and
it's really easy to get started with
them I'm
big fan map packs K thank you in
ppl
thanks guys thanks for coming out to
talk way
ok