hello everyone
up before we begin I'd like to make two
announcements
um if you want anything API yesterday's
auction
you go dancers research and ice to pick
them up
about the reception desk will be closing
soon so I would
highly suggest after the talk to you
gonna meet olympic it up
the next announcement is about I
tomorrow will begin the developments
Prince
arm the developments prince will be held
here at the
a palette conga 'em so
if you would like to the be part of it
it's open to everyone
I am and if you have any ideas ice
a high I would suggest you announce them
at the reception desk
arts so that could be could be announced
for tomorrow's development sprint so
so our final speaker love the day I like
to introduce arm
brought angel I am Bright Angel
you talking to us about employing pipe
on to report real time
resource bills in the to operation
managers picket topics are one now
tired enough closing would be good or
bad but a
think it's great telescope II wanna
have a word of caution is that I'm not a
programmer I'm actually
trained up and on architecture but I got
kinda into
a position where we really had to employ
pie part to do a project we're doing is
he said occurs
sour surfed for those that don't know
you see said occurs as the University
California attackers are about an hour
away from sepsis go south for
on the Central Coast is a picture
whatever dumpsters are
that gets a Monterey Bay View love the
ocean
which is really nice there on the bottom
left corner as our
happy have but at a slug which is the
mascot ever see
and and the rest the campuses has a lot
to read words
and as a you know quite beautiful our
doctors
of course material evidence showed up
this magnificent trees
here the casey et that there's this is
kinda typography graphic power
topography map apps are at the actual
campus in augusta two-parter felines
other
white-out but you could see they were
very hilly and over
it's a constant hell site for the entire
campus we running a fleet of about 10
trucks
I am we have that's on the left is what
you call a front loader in the middle is
what you call a role of box and then on
the right is a box truck we have
10 trucks all we have a roughly 300
dumpsters every run on campus
overall in house have a very robust
takeover
we saw paul Fisher at the bottom is our
own sort line
over 18 only you see schools to have one
and then on the writer some the bins we
have to hear a
to maintain and terror work on and
there's over
is roughly 300 pence are been set for
speaker that we have to run run which
takes a little labor
so for those that you know that don't
know and the state of california all the
municipalities and counties have to get
to hear what they call
75 percent landfill diversion by 2020
that means that
only 25 percent all the waste is
produced waste is produced in the state
can go into landfills a for the UC
schools
the the terrorists we have to hit to
over we have a goal to hit
zero waste which means less than five
percent waste by the year 2020
the same time frame so Dustin schools
are we're really working hard
this is a a graphic of how our way
stream has worked in the past
a well since 2000 almost ten years and
you could see it the very right hand
corner
the red line is refuse and then the dark
yellow line is our diverse right now 62
percent
so even though you're supposed to hit 75
percent last year I'll we r
far from that in our operations and we
also
very far from my 2020 a six-year golf
outings are West
so have to think bigger well we did when
I started two years ago
like a few weeks before I started I they
installed what we call the load been
system which
actually ways are refuse cardboard other
materials as being picked up
this allows us to actually I no
which customers have deposited what
materials where
and we can start doing data analysis on
our so we have been doing that else's
last year
fiscal year 2012 4:13 and we can find
our for worst
I refuse users with a pinpoint them and
say okay
that the big tall one else family said
housing
and we say to them pay you know we
haven't really talked to them yet but we
know that that's where waste problems
are and we're gonna have to really it
doesn't
the pic the big fish speak her
so we have a lot of pressure to increase
our process capacity
even though we're at about 70 percent
I'm we really have a difficulty
and achieving a high in a 95 percent
because most that stream has to come
from architects
so right now we write we have about 30
per citizen refuse about 15 percent
is cardboard another 15 assorted
recycled
but this other 30 percent that it's
gonna come to refuse
is your soil paper your food waste
mostly the stuff
if you look around at this conference
center you know this is not an organic
then
but if you go to Step Cisco a lot I'm
sure they click their soul paper and
they said click their food waste
sepsis go Vancouver are some the only
cities are actually have
taking this animal on and all the season
after all try to figure it out
and it's difficult nothing I wanted to
make sure to mention here is that since
2008 since we had a great recession
i'd of its all the ISI's but definitely
are you see
they want to hire anyone they want to
keep labor at the minimum a two-step
2008-2009 level
where there's I mean we barely have
enough people to drive the trucks much
less
at capacity what we're doing and even
like my position which was
for time with overtime sometimes I'm a
part-time
at best so well apartheid
so that's a big issue we get we have to
figure out how to do this whole the
stream
with less with basically the same labor
so I the a had no idea is gonna be
getting into this when I got this job
but now my cup
this whole system has to change in order
to to achieve what we're looking for
if you look at what they do attempt to
scare what they're doing it back over
what they do probably here
and everything is built and money is
made based on
largely emptying empty servicing empty
dumpsters
their load man has a that the other
program talk about has an entire
I a graphics metrics analysis tool that
tells you
if you have too much density in your
dumpsters and
if you have too much density than you
have a problem client that means it
they're putting too much wasted well
that means that they're covering their
labor by
dumps use it you know emptying servicing
into dumpsters
but for us but we have a shortage of
labour we would like to flip that
and have every dumpster as far as
possible when we pick it up
which is different than almost anyone
else out there
and so that's when that we started
thinking about well how do we do this
had a way if
wicked do just the traditional route
what we do and we were inspired
her I was inspired by a of course the
Internet of Things
type movement I guess you could call it
and we also had a demonstration by
big belly which is the top struggle
after the a side the canister
on the left so the big belly they will
come to your community
they've done Boston Boston University I
think enough to have any overseas
on the west coast certain Canada but
they'll come to you and I'll say okay we
can basically cut out ninety percent
appear
waste pickup from this from these bids
using this on-demand
their own autumn and technology and when
we talk to write but he had this for
dumpsters cuz we don't really have a
an issue with that we have a issue with
dumpsters and the right now the site
we don't have that for copiers so we
decided to do it ourselves
and what we did is we we stock to
different
a companies into things kinda companies
and we came to digi was the one that was
very
cooperative with us and they had
somebody that they put their
but there are actual communication
devices and and
this is that Massa a sonar in three
Sardar and they said this would be great
for your test
pilot and it runs on ARM
you know the communicator died devices
and you can get one tomorrow
mean expensive but where like okay let's
try it out
and this one the so what we did is we
actually installed
a well first I had installed on my home
my my my office
trash can see if it worked headed for
the record on a dumpster that about 15
feet from my office
and that's what looks like but when I
installed it all we really had as the
data was being
deliver to DiGi's proprietary
in a cloud location and they could do
some
graphics for something like that but it
was pretty intense for an operator are
sorry that's managing our crew
20 I have to go to this and try to
figure out how to decipher
it wasn't gonna work we needed something
much more pedestrian to speaker
user-level
so a as talking about this so here was
the concept that
I had originally thought I haven't
thought I could handle on my own
to actually deliver this in I had no
idea what I thought was a time so we
would have the dumpster
that sexual dumpster with the the thing
at the Surana
anywhere talk to you pass some sort
interface I thought the cloud could do
it but it didn't
and then it would put it on that website
so I'm Meyer heavy equipment manager can
look at it
well they didn't work out what we ended
up doing is that we had a
intern come in I'll not intersted worker
and you taken a single class and by fun
that a semester before
in our stock game he was our data entry
for a while for us because our
is gonna have a hard time with the
recycle Kors so they can after I'm on me
and active call kinda like developer
tight kid and so
he came in NE Ohio I love to help you up
so this is the kinda systematic we came
up with
and a we have the met the sonar talks to
a gateway and everybody's is this a
wireless router shit this wireless
systems but
them the sonar talk sergei where the
Gateway put a cloud and then from the
cloud way
I'm I co-worker don't actually wrote a
Python script that word
retrieve the information from the cloud
and then it would deposit into spots
around prefer a text file
for me and then an Excel spreadsheet so
we would have a record of every
every soldier reading and what I did a
you know I am a group I went to college
in the 90s so I knew nothing HTML to get
us by on creating a website I would
actually show whatever's on this text
file that's being updated with each star
rating
so it's kinda the way it worked out so
that we end up with we have a website
that I run to left and we ended up with
two files
in we're able to use the website to
check it every hour whatever it was
updated
in the naked run out to the dumpster see
if it actually working or not
network for the most part and we're
getting great data from it
so this is how the data kinda looks at
after using this for
what is that two months ago if yep so
we already had our load man data which
is the gray line and it's telling us how
much weight is being polled
are picked up every pick up from the
dumpster so we have the virus is 66 in
and then the Green Line is the actual a
volume how much
the sonar was actually reading how much
of it was for also
went from you know 5 percent to your
seventy-four percent 34 percent is the
highest number what I thought was
interesting there was great about this
is that we actually start picking up
a mistakes so the red dots across the
square
dots across the middle those are driver
locks
so the driver will actually go and in an
Excel spreadsheet will mark which
dancers they feared
and then I know from this top sir which
is labeled
by specifically that that's when they
pick them up those are the days
succ could see on a number day are
I'm sorry incident a have marked that
the
a driver noted that they actually picked
up the dumpster
which means that we actually would bill
that dumpster you know cuz we have a
recharge system for
for clients but if you look at the sonar
and if you look at load man nothing was
picked up
so that obviously mistakenly picked up
with a digital with the two systems
but if you look at the a you'll notice
that
the sonar dots out see how in the lines
go away the bar let me set the
volume is empty a.m. the sonar don't
doubt
and then the driver noted that they
actually picked up but load man didn't
pick it up
so you can tell us are double-checking
who what's working what's not working
on the far right it also gave a secret
service
a straight line which was never good
and that was only had a battery battery
failure for 6
almost a week I'm and we didn't realize
until
we can I like when he was working with
adequate looking at it when I just come
back and see if it s still working
and I was wife and I we had a better her
so this kinda has huge implications on
an entire
the whole system love waste hauling her
resource recovery
so we can I can probably go through the
deferred if
for people are from so there's the the
traditional system is what you call a
biometric service-oriented work %uh
research recovery that's when I your
like pro everybody's you steer you have
a bit and it's a particular size that's
one
1-yard are it's a if your household you
know the size
they charge you so many dollars per
month butter a picture just 55 bucks
to serve in a row service it on a weekly
basis so that a biometric system
that's the dominant system throughout
the at least North America
and is to go to zero waste with that
system can be very troublesome
I'm except Cisco any space are working
on it was recalling G
but and what they've done is by they'll
pick up the charger for the refugees
picked up
and then they'll of couple Metairie
kinda like
at and a researcher at the recycling any
other streams
in addition but they base all their
money on the refuse
but what happens is you keep having to
increase you refuse charge
and you have to make the the buying
smaller as you get closer to zero waste
so it's like a self
I it's it doesn't its economy a logical
system to continue to follow
what other cities like Vancouver have
done is a at least the city of
Vancouver's on buildings they have set
up a contract with
there holler waste management based on
performance
they say okay for the last ten years we
had this much volume
and you charge just as much money and
we're going to pay you for the next 10
years based on that allocation of cash
how much cost us
and you will serve assessed 20 way said
they will come to the table getting
what's the contractor that still
difficult because
I has it that a very difficult to
thing to go by is to say well
historically we had this much by am
and we want to keep making money based
on that I am but does that really
in directly induce you to go to zero
waste how does that work in a scepter
be with a community that really wants to
do it they're not gonna do it because I
financial
reasons so we're proposing that we don't
know if anybody else is doing this but
for proposing a weight-based resource
recovery system where
if you we're gonna charge by the pound
right now we think it's really about 22
cents a pound
for refuse pick up it will charge less
for our recycling pickup
and we'll be able to monitor that with
our login system
will say okay you know you paint we
picked up 700 pounds yesterday from your
so the seven hundred times twenty cents
US for the next bill
and then but the only way that really
works
for us operationally because you know
a ideally everyone will discontinue
using refuse the hill
go down to five percent no need us less
I don't need is in a different way
intro what that works for us as we have
to find a
efficiencies our operations to make it
so that we still can
keeper budget that is cash positive
suspect
so in order to do that that's what a
smart dumpster comes in we were only
pick it up it's for
or after a two-week time period and then
we can
use our guys for other media day
organics line that we need ur
introduce our cardboard all the other I
diversion activities that are necessary
that we don't really have time to do
right now because we're spending so much
time picking up
empty dumpsters so
some are smart dumpster was successful
we loved it
it would work we were able to say okay
the
the the script worked we had a record a
powerful it got
how often we could how much we could
reduce our pick ups based on the actual
weight there was an
or the actual volume when it was for and
as so we found a company to sepsis
counter
capacitor Cisco found us and asked us if
we would like to be one of the first
clients
and their Harbor company at an incubator
answer Cisco that are actually building
were kinda like building is proposing
building one
on their own and they're called Cup
ology and their system isn't
you know it's there prior system so I am
care I talk about it much more other
than they've kinda realized the
dashboard that we had been talking about
for almost a year and a half
and this is what it looks like in our
actual guys we have a third over
refuse a dumpsters are rigged for
fiercer
with these with their sensors and we use
them now
every day to see which ones to pick up
up the forty-three when therefore
before we thought 75 percent would be
good and now realizing that if it's
about 60-65 percent by Terry pick it up
it's falling ready to be a ready be held
but what's
this our relationship with Compal a GR
comfort quest
doing a with going on with such a huge
contract with these guys that were
very new to the business some anime no
fair I understand a hauling works
I mean I don't understand three years
ago but we were on board with all this
because that little python script that
was written
that gave us the daily reading up what's
going on and
to be able to bring the real world a
values to your desk you know and to you
our
our own not system so their summer
different concerns and drawbacks with
the implementation first I had wrought
we
had RT RT sure the battery life and now
is we're going to release after the
campus maybe next year have all of
campus
up so worried about peer errors because
the battery life
I know that's not a big deal with Python
but that's the these are like the
reality
for bridging the suffer side with the
actual harbor in the field
second is that I am we've always been
worried about communications out of
anybody
has heard about the controversy with the
smart meters RP jimmy's
I'm energy year me here electricity
boxer
electricity meter what occurs everyone
is extremely worried that they're
causing cancer
so a lotta times a whenever you're
proposing
these new technologies especially with
communications
if it uses a cell service IRS cellular
service then we start getting people
that are upset and
well show up and do things that are you
know
difficult operator on so I the thing
that we loved about the Digi is a radio
frequency which is not on the radar as
being
a bad thing and the resync apology
a meter sensors right now RSL system
and we're hoping that other WiFi dosing
that wish I was a big deal so that's
something to think about it
you actually try to poser look work on
mister Probert project
the third thing is that as we start
doing more zero waste
I'm a actions like these are new
canisters that were gonna prod deploy
next year
throughout the next four years is that
the when you start bring the technology
and we had the same even the one sensor
I'll when I had it on the dumpster
caused by office
everyone sir talk about all operators
the building up for it at the building
managers
now that we have 143 people are actually
afraid
the sensors which is I mean cuz the
technology is just like this
weird thing they they were it's like a
big brother type thing
and so one thing is that they we were
worried about vandalism
because the sensors are out there I mean
we know there
not destructible by the way story to
people with just actually having bats
and doing things like that
but the second thing that was actually a
positive about it was that people felt
like they were being watched
so they actually diverted a lot better
it's almost like a camera that doesn't
work
on the wall well there this whole thing
was like you're being watched
people were actually pulling diverse
materials out the dumpster after they
solve a camera
they were thrown in there to the care in
a report out so it's been a really wild
on a how much difference this is making
but on a slight I wanted to make sure
and make a note that I am
the benefit a actually using from moving
forward with this type of
activity could have extremely positive
economic outcomes so
wanna see what exact number was sided
the numbers and if we actually
actually apply at this a smart dumpster
to the entire campus all
turned 50 dumpsters we have on campus
there is
and then we actually do the savings I
expect based on the low demand data and
based on our single smart
smart up sir we expected like reduce
a at least two possibly what we're gonna
produce growing up to do one out of
every three
pickups or services we've had to do in
the past and that equates to you
253 thousand dollars worth of labor that
way
death labor alone aside gas satires the
star stuff
so doing this type from this type of
activity
actually could have extremely positive
economic benefits to people like me
operators and for us
it's not that we want to get a fish into
lay people off which
I heard happens at other places for us
we just the more
labor capacity to do the other streams
you know so
that's why I think everybody's on board
so far and then XO we've been successful
with the smart up sir
and and with this whole idea but at the
all the UC's we all have our
sustainability plans
and everyone on my side is like
how the heck here do we start really
changing behavior
and that's what the great thing about
the sport after was is it had immediate
changes to pave your
with the drivers for one and also people
knew that they were doing
something they were being watched to
make sure that they do the right thing
well we have these are all the different
topics every have to cover and
sustainability plan by 2020 we have
RF anybody is from a with california's a
drought when we were turning spigots of
right now
on campus I'm and they don't they have
to make estimates they don't have exact
meter numbers custer it takes time to
gather all the numbers and I'm
so if we were able waters the 1i think
would be the next
loafer to actually put the sensors on
and energy
should be something we should be able to
quickly because you already have kinda
smart meter devices almost
sup there's this the meters are out
there and then there's
a sitting operators at the desk but it's
very difficult that bridge
that it's critical that Piper
programmers could provide
is as a def away something that I'm
trying to your
that's why i wanna talk today say hey in
are we really need help from an operator
side to make this happen so that we can
actually give
dashboard readings on all the different
categories that we have to me and then
even
in a in a past life actually did
California recall the Act
activities and you had your medication
issues you have to constantly monitor
things
if you're you're disturbing them so to
speak and this is a total no other area
that I V
the pie phone type of bring the hardware
to this offer and bringing it together
cocktail you know in in good competition
could really be helpful
and I feel like anyone is really
addressing it I felt like when we did
the smart up sir we had a hard time
and getting really any help I expected I
guess maybe I didn't breach as well but
I'm working on it so I think that was
the main thing I just want to say is
that a I feel like it's really important
that professionals like me
we need your partnership and moving
forward and and this is the whole growth
area that's beyond just the strike
software
type data and management we actually
and here we have things that we could
work on time i'm looking for to your
professional career with you okay
I want to make sure think my pass rusher
and burqas he was one there
story pro all the stuff and I must say a
worker
don't and I'm ready for questions are
answers
comments thank you
you have any questions jiska approach to
make
and area
I have more cell there
and coming up on me and temp
yard am I'll hockey and it specifically
for projects just like that
bring it there and here at Cody's
like Google a cap Yahoo are coming back
to work
the core down anyone else like any you
highly your project I'm I'm working on
that
I can pick okay
cool yeah as next week I me but make it
occurs get the cracker okay yeah
differing pet
you
but thank you