a good
ready okay
hello everybody I'm up next we've got
Catherine John Moore he's going to give
us a performance
accuracy with you at the top I've been
scraping my PC
please welcome our hi everybody
I'm here for papon scraping showdown
hopefully you are to you if not please
see the directory in the hallway
my name is Catherine Jarmo also known
fondly
as KJM on a little bit about me
I've been using scrapers since 2010
after sheesh inspired me I went to his
QB tutorial
if you get bored of this talk is giving
a rather fun talk with Karen over a
couple rooms down
evidently my Google delay
is a little delayed I a little bit more
about me as I am the pie ladies
cofounder one the pile is cofounder I'm
happy to see a lot of Pi ladies here
with me today
chided
move us along apologies
evidently everybody's on the same
network imagine that
I am let me a if I can
and
maybe
apologies again
well mack you have failed me
much there's a better way to go about
this
them
basher
Siam you 1
K
right
see if I have better luck year
apologies again
yeah
alright let's get started here apologies
again for
that delay hopefully I can speed it up a
bit
and I get it going okay so I have a pile
is cofounder
I am relocating to berlin in a couple of
days
so if you live in Berlin or know
somebody who I should meet please come
say hi
so why scrape the web on this is
becoming more and more of a question
there's a lot of public API's there's a
lot serve
rest or Jason enabled endpoints both
public
and not so public but easily found
upon investigating website there's also
a lot of well-maintained
open source API libraries showed those
you know again allow us to scrape
Twitter Facebook
I'm whatever it is we're attempting to
use I'm without
a really using than traditional
stripping libraries
i'm for Python selenium is still your
best bet
if you need anything that does
JavaScript interaction
or that's loaded after the DOM so you're
kind of a little bit shackled there
there's plenty of node libraries out
there but
in Python that's really our are you have
and albeit
with all those caveats I still think
that there's a lot of sites 3 could
build a traditional scraper and scrape
content that way
and I still find it very fun to build
those for my own use
so what this talk is gonna cover I'm
gonna look at
a different performance with an LX
Malvern and beautiful soup
I'll go and to a little bit more why I
narrowed it down I'm going to
talk about finding elements with
selenium sell a lot of us who've you
selenium there's
many options for finding elements I'm
gonna talk about which is the fastest
and I'm gonna take a look at scrapie or
scrap hi I'm not quite sure the
pronunciation
and see how fast we can go with Python
and scraping the web
so a bit of a disclaimer when I first
was putting together a test for this
I want to screw use quite a lot of
stripping libraries
when I found as I begin to look at it is
a lot of them are using similar
dependencies
it so I decided that it might be but
I've best used to hone in
on some of the most popular ones and
most widely used ones
which is what led me to LX Intel and
beautiful suit I also in this I kinda
wanted to find some broken pages
I've been scraping using LX and now for
some years now and
it often would happen to me where I come
across a page where r beautiful soup was
truly my only option to accurately parce
page
I think html5 is changing this landscape
and hopefully allowing us to have more
standardized web content which allows us
to scrape the web
utilizing the elementary API's and other
things
similar to that if you find of course
broken pages beautiful soup an html5
live also have
quite a lot of helpers for scraping you
know truly broken pages that don't
follow any sort of
uniformity attacks and all of my code
for this talk is available at my get
home
so I created a repository I believe
called web scraping
speed comparison and
you can please forget downloaded am play
around with it
prove me wrong with my own test I'm so I
wanted to compare
LX Nankivil soup a lot of times these
are you know the commonly in most
popular used
on DU's distinctly different methods to
unpacking parse
HTML so I wanted to kind of take a look
at those methods
on and both of them I find to be
tremendously accurate with the right
level of detail so
I feel like a lot of it is up to the
developer the onus is on you
to kinda write your scraper in such a
way that your accurately finding the day
a
but I find them fairly easy to
manipulate for this purpose and
l/xl utilizes both X pass and CSS
selects I decided to compare that is
me myself being a developer being lazy
a lot of times are just rely on CFS
select rather than write out the entire
expat
and I wanted to see whether I was losing
a lot of time
okay so what was my methodology I'm
first I wrote accurate scrapers um
as best I could and then I try to find
similar ways to parse it so with a lot
of my functions I tried to follow
a similar method find and search
said that I could continue I to compared
the library is rather than my own code
I'm fairly certain I could have written
the sparse is to be faster
by employing different fast message
methods at the library
but I found that maybe this might be the
most accurate way
then I used I'm see profile & key stats
to kinda analyze how much it took
for each function to run um and then I
aidid over a number of trials
ranging from 10 to 500 so the first
thing that I decide to do is they want
to strip the NHL scores
I'm an avid hockey fan and were about to
enter playoff
and we're in Canada so I figured I might
be amongst hockey fanatics
and so I went to on their scores page
and I personally and Big Twins fan
so I wanted to see how miglin's were
gonna do in a playoff
this is the only code I'll show you n
apologies again for trying to fit it all
in stride
again the repos up on my get her back
page am on but basically you can see
here
I have my LX now with XPath LX now with
CSS
and beautiful soup and I attempted to
employ
similar ways love on you know I'm
packing and wrapping the content
finding the scores body then finding
those game boxes and then going within
the columns to find
but the key names and the scores
and hears it were my results so as you
can see
LX in our next stop was a clear winner
here on
it was away under even point 06
per run as well as beautiful soup was be
took the longest it was up to nearly
point2 for
seconds per run on you can see that elec
smell with CSS was just a close second
particularly
as the averages got a higher
and we could take a little bit have a
look here at why and where the speed
might come from
to PCL XL with expat has 238 function
calls
a far below the 280,000 that beautiful
soup average
so we can start to see maybe on this is
where some up to speed up
x-pac is coming into play again these
buried by Ryan up but I didn't see a
large disparity amongst friends
um and so then inaccuracy review all
love
the different a scrapers were able to
accurately find all the game scores
and just so that you can run these as
well in the
repository I also included this source
the initial pages I was scraping
so the next thing I decided to do is I
have benefit e-commerce background as
well
and e-commerce site are notoriously
messy and so I decided to scrape Amazon
deals
so I can get my di love the day in my
email but what about these Lightning
Deals across the bottom
what I wanted to do is grab the title
%uh the link and the price
and what I found in running it is again
LX Mel with XPath
was the winner but we see here that
depending on
the site content and how quickly can be
parsed beautiful soup was only several
hundredths of a second
slower cell we can start to see hey you
know what all these are pretty fast
options
on yes l/xl with XPath is the fastest
we can start to see that depending on
the page we're gonna have a variety of
time
but again when I looked at the function
calls I saw just far less overhead
with expat I'm even then with LX now
using CSS
select
so inaccuracy review this oddly enough
beautiful soup was not able to properly
parse using the same sort of sin taxes
others
I actually was having a hard time even
getting to that part a page without
using a whole family tree
crawl and so what I determined are what
I did is I modified it so it find the
top deal so it could be
at least comparative I wasn't going to
sit there and compare
you know twenty to thirty lines a
beautiful see you with 512 Velux now
but this is actually interesting fine
for me site that I checked
the third and last case study that I did
in terms of scraping
was I looked at New York Times mobile
site I definitely wanted to do mobile
site because mobile sites
as we all know are generally more
lightweight they load faster
on they usually have less JavaScript and
other junk running on the page
and what I did was I grab the headline
the link and the blurb if it was
available
at the New York Times mobile home page
and again I found
that we had tremendous speed with all
libraries if you can't see from across
the back
even beautiful soup is clocking in at
four-and-a-half hundreds
a second um but l/xl with XPath was just
super super speedy
and what I found here again with the
average function calls XPath with a
little bit more than Iowa had expected
given the other runs
but regardless on it's still was am
much fewer calls than the others and
again in accuracy they all sound 17
articles
and there was an all set at the bottom
I'm assuming New York Times uses it for
some sorta styled writer
cell LX a mallet expat is the clear
winner here in terms of speed
on but at the end of the day it's really
not by much
so I would again a I would caution
against saying something like beautiful
super slow that's just not true
and I would caution against saying l/xl
expat is the fastest thing in the world
but it is pretty fast and if you're
looking at scrubbing quite a lot of data
it would definitely be worth
investigating right so I'm gonna take a
look at selenium
arm selenium by far if you're using
Python
is the best for page interactions or
after download elements
especially anything that has like login
flows and things like that I find
it's just really useful arm flame also
gives you a whole lot of ways to find
elements on the page
and I wonder to myself when I coats lady
in things I mean MRT losing so much time
loading a browser including three things
what's going to be the fastest in terms
of finding elements
and so I'm gonna compare I'm find
element by tag name
finalement bike last name and find
element by expect
there are others to compare but I find
that I used to use the most
so I decide to go to yahoo dot com and I
wanted to find
on the search box and I wanted to find
this little trending now section
I'm its training across yeah I guess I
was curious as to
what was there what I thought is maybe
this might be a good start script
for going about and searching different
a
search sites and seeing what they came
up with how many results are similar
or different this just will compared
find now
and what I found is that again we're
dealing with
a really 100 for the second difference I
found that with the
shorter runs CSS sometimes be expat this
is why the times that it did sell
I wanted to show that and but still we
see the XPath
over the average have many runs arm
comes
clocks in as the fastest and tagname
actually ended up being the slowest
which was surprising to me I assumed
kind of that tag name
used expat underneath the covers on but
that might not be the case if somebody
works on selenium or
understand selenium better than I i and
maybe you can
best explain this on but when I looked
at the function calls I found an expat
had quite a lot more than I expected
this probably has to do with the fact
that selenium is
most likely using a rendering engine
more similar to the browser
rest I was CSS had a very low number a
function calls in comparison
on that made me think that if you're
running quite a lot of selenium maybe
CSS is going to be the best way
tag name here was the clear loser I'm
CSS an XPath are both great
tag is clearly slower and with more
calls but
similarly to my find with web scraping
libraries
it wasn't that huge a difference and
again you wanna think about
what you're comfortable with what your
team is comfortable with and what is
readable to you
and use you know what makes the most
sense for your script
so I want in investigate scrapie
on it uses l/xl XPath to find elements
or as they call them within the library
items and it uses twisted for a
synchronous crawling
I'm so to me arm it seemed
that it was going to be really speedy
also
scrapie i've seen. evolve a lot over the
past two years I've kinda been
following it out watching it grow and
its
just become quite powerful in terms of
crawling inspiring the web
if you haven't used it yet I you know
cannot encourage you enough
to go about building your own crawler
and they just have a lot of really
robust functionality and helpers for you
and so with our speed knowledge I was
wondering
how fast can we get
cell what I wanted to do is I was gonna
Creek Google with pagination
I'm for search results within the search
result I was
fine be titled the blurb and the link am
I didn't worry about saving it to
discover I don't want any right setting
up my speed tests
so again this can add some time
depending on your script
so I Google Python because about I
and so here's a bit of my stats and you
can see my see profile tabs at the
bottom but I was having to use a command
line
caller from within the scope the library
to get it running
so but you can see I'm the item scrapes
count is 306
if you look at the start time compared
to the end time
we're talking about slightly like a
shave over
three seconds to get 306
result cell escaping Google
the spider was averaging almost a
hundred result a second or around about
sometimes little over sometimes a little
under
I'm to me that seem tremendously fast
and it was really
exciting to see how powerful it could be
also Google hates me
cell II caution you against
running the script at home during
off-hours I was captured it to death
on but I find that if you run it during
you know the busy time for the day in
the morning hours whatever your time
zone is
I'm maybe Google hate you left a lot of
times okie get through
up to you at 340 results and about 300
sixty mark or whichever one with twisted
finished
bill last I would get captured
and also escapee has a bunch a different
tools
very similar to what we saw in the
mechanized functionality for those are
you that are familiar with the
mechanized
library I'm to get around capture blocks
you can use different user agent strings
you can use different IP's and other
things like that so
on I for this test I wanted to rather
then see how quickly I could fool Google
I wanted to see how quickly I can get
the scraper running
cell but its its easily for couple or to
write your own and use some love
their logic to use great Google even
faster and at more length during
of our so in conclusion
on L XML using XPath is the clear winner
when it comes to speed i'm for
readability inaccuracy though both
in the code and the content that you
scrape you know it's really
the time difference was not as amazing
as I thought
it was amazing enough that if you're
parsing thousands of web sites
it's probably gonna make a difference to
you but if you're just
writing a scare at home for your
favorite restaurant or
on to finding local Deals near you or
whatever it might be
arm then I don't think there's a big
difference and it's gonna end up being
you know what is easiest for you to
install with easiest for your team to
use
and your code again might vary so there
are ways to speed up beautiful soup
depending
on the way that the pages parse on and I
would advise using those
if you are set with like a Windows
operating system are something else
where LX now becomes a big pain
in the rear to install on MN if X
Factor's too confusing or limiting
if if you're really into Webster being a
strongly encourage your expat I'm it's
really fun and super powerful
but if it for some reason is too
confusing or limiting are you feeling
lazy
CSS select is obviously a close second
choice
cell I would say to use that cell
I'd like to invite you to ask questions
again thanks for staying with me
apologies for my technical
difficulties I am KDM on Twitter if
you'd like to hit me up later if you
want to explore the repository first
I also idle on freenode as KJM
and thank you so much for coming to my
talk
and if you have questions there's a
microphone right there a high
my guess is kinda a comment and then a
question
okay by happily use lame quite a bit my
job
OEQ on so I think that you live in
punching causes the way to determine
what the form is a slim looks like is
now actually a fair representation
%uh mainly because slam team is actually
a protocol
that communicates with browser netscape
telling with not sick all the pipe on
interface is doing is just calling
on the remote interface that
communicates with it I'm so
you pry wouldn't it few figure out why
the performances
on you know lacking or you know they
perform it that way
okay on and also the various calls that
were driver actually
incorporates what drivers the underlying
infinite piece for a slim
on sign a disconnect but on actually
depends on how the browser chooses to
implement
protocol okay I'm some use to see the
existing jobs for attention others
utilize more
built-in functionality these have do you
have advice on which driver is the
fastest
ya its a pansy ass is actually a
headless browser
worse on and you can run into thousands
and processing as we do my job
and it tends to be a lot faster than I'm
guessing
me most people can't use Internet
Explorer Firefox mom in Yachats
if found yet 10 times depending on work
at st. running
there's also a headless chrome now as
well yes I am
i'd have a spot a headless chrome
browser 0 their knees
nice I will I was wondering just if you
need a comparison between the headless
chrome and the Phantom JS
haven't tried to help grow om and as
curious but Press reach us use for your
slim test
up for the slain to just use Firefox
area is fairly slow
usually I use Chrome but I wanted to an
example that was easily portable for
everyone
that I thank you thank you a
thanks for the talk um just curious what
was the most interesting and are useful
land or cool I guess think you scraped
on
in all my time scraping I yeah I'm up
probably
at one point in time I was using a
service with my company
we're utilizing a service to you help us
to some logging
and I exposed a basically a heated API
at some point I'm I just pinged the dev
team and said hey I found that I can go
back
like a year but if I wanted to go back
more than a year what can I use and
they wrote me back saying our closing
that API and points
apologies I didn't mean to be evil
any other question
all right thank you so much and I have a
happy
icon