during obscured
publicly
I was I was hoping you would actually
sorry
can target I was hoping you'd stay dark
and gloomy in here because James King is
going to be talking to us about
dungeon generation techniques for
robotics in Python so it can be ground
robot
alright think you are
for settlers like to thank the park on
organizers for putting on such a great
event
thirty-year running coming to the event
and it's just been really well
bigger and better every year an awfully
think the volunteers for
run smoothly us a bit about me happen if
I come programmer
since a 2006 professionally but some I
really expenses go back on we have a
I am my day job is mostly
telephone operations with applications
systems storage
things like that but at night ira
weekly D&D group every Sunday and I
liked it up design dungeons
I also have poured my heart and soul
into thousands of hours a broke likes
I'm who hears played any sort road bike
games
good crowd saucer you know like
Road that hack Korea and Banton
on my personal favorites dungeon crawl
Stone Soup and
in order to get a better player
eventually maybe if you're also a
program reserved in the source code
figure how to make levels workplace
economies things like that so
I'm today's talk is primarily about
designing
procedurally generated content for games
I say designing
because I when people think maybe random
generated levels if they don't think
I've Lake carefully crafted gameplay
experiences
and they don't think they think maybe
like it's just gonna look the same after
a while so it's gonna be
aqui here but in my
adventures in in exploring the robotic
space in reply development of come
across many ideas
I think akroyd sure if you today
so the first step baby staff is how do
we represent
attention in a computer and for our
purposes today we're just talking
aerobics for two-dimensional
top-down I'm trials
I think we paper you might think cruelty
in the tiles
one common way of representing them in
Python
is usefulness to do to readers construct
I
list lists the server
very hey we're approaching and we
get our left and we use two indices to
index into our
dungeon and look at the different tiles
that are there
I one approach that I like is
packing everything to multi-dimensional
array into a single list
found sort house he lays out its a
reason memory in
budgetary multi-dimensional arrays as a
single array as he gets just listed in
economic numbers
and you can index into it as if it is a
multidimensional array
isaacson cover major artery which looks
kinda like this
and if you can imagine each
row I love the grid being laid out one
after the other in the street
linear array that's basically what this
and excellent you get into each
part by giving action why I usually do
with a library wrote a while ago to get
help me out write some
journals and things like that called
Horton I guess you agree to our church
and then you can just into action to the
greasy from their ex-wives
a pattern in think so
first steps with random little
generation armies
I think it's a good start for anybody is
interested in getting into this topic
the reason being that they're very very
easy went but there are a lot of them
and its seeing a result very quickly on
the screen out the first kind here's an
example of the
depth first search backtracking
Jefferson child
I'm what you do is you just start off at
a random point summer in your grid
and do you start searching as far as you
can
until you hit and to the new backtrack
and start going as deep as you can again
it's worried if its name
and c2c like oh there's a little bit a
helper code in the background that I
have explained here just for
I was just where it's at the core of the
algorithm their
sister of a stack and
occurred sell you choose randomly from
you're starting grid
I'm the cells by the way are the
elements inside you're already there
I just make them like notation ritual
objects that have for
walls I guess and basically we're in a
tunnel through each cell as weak as we
come across so
we start of a forced acknowledge the
limits in the stack
we just get the incident neighbors for a
current cell
if there are some great we take a
a random choice from those neighbors
removable wall between the current cell
phone that
at random even we selected so-and-so for
sandwiches appended the consulate attack
choose and so forth when a camera
happening is that you get to
the a place where there are no new
neighbors in accys
and interest are popping things office
back backtracking to get
I'm well getting too much details
approved for anything like that this
alan's guarantee to touch every single
cell
in your grid and then you end up with a
measly
this was a long line between recorders
different example I just contrast the
different methods available Scott Prince
algorithm
the Wikipedia definition scudder dance
I'm
reforms it so this is a formatting a
minimum spanning tree
for connected undirected weighted graph
defines a subset of edges the connective
rivers
implementation I miss little bit more
dense than the tougher search
but if anybody seen you star search
algorithm
looks kinda like that we have a frontier
cells you haven't visited yet you have
and interior number cells are you have
and TVs we keep adding
I'm new cells to from the frontier into
your interior cells and adding new
neighbors
exactly because interspace
on so what's really interesting there's
that
just by switching the younger than we
get two different designs for maize
that's really the first nah we can just
as in encoders designers
levels is in these games is that I'm
because tweet the album GRMN
triggers results to notice in the Des
for search it was a very their long two
corners I find that
in order to find as a player like which
branches are not worth following
you have to come to follow it a little
bit your eye or as you're playing before
you can tell jurors about branches
whereas with the Prince our own version
got lot of short little tiny
quarters in a very blocky sorta look
which makes it easy to tell which the
differences are right off the bat
but I'm because it's so dense looking at
blocking looking it's actually kinda
little bit hard to sort of see that
flowing movement through the level
hours a day for surgery fixer gives away
the star position start sleeping
but we're not here to talk me amazes
specifically am
at a higher level we want to generate
levels for games tensions
and there are many many approaches to
doing this one
more naive ones i've seen I'm one of the
ones I think are a great place to start
and a teacher just how complex you can
get
is gonna open grid I love
just walls and I make one random room
inside that creating a place it
somewhere randomly inside
got one room place on the map now and my
next step would be to choose one of the
walls
I would take out from that while I'm
start scanning ahead until I could find
enough room to place the next room on my
list
and then if I can I place at room
connect them up
keep going you can have branch you
looking
dungeons works work like interconnected
hallways are some but
Tom other that can waste a lot of effort
cuz there's a lot of cases and there's
backtracking there some checks things
are going to have to do
I wanna show you today is a technique
that
I will guarantee that you won't overlap
in your room so you don't have to do any
searching
and it generates levels pretty fast
called
from of first reserve the data
structures I'm kinda review for those
who
have been in computer science for maybe
you haven't seen this before her
relatively new to programming by a
binary tree is essentially
Pfizer notes likely to be a empty
or be consist of a route with two binary
trees so it's a non-linear structure it
forms a tree initial
Michael clear for them is left right I'm
so and so forth we're not we're not
concerned level design with
balancing the trees or anything like
that were mainly concerned with
space partitioning was a space
partitioning algorithm
we start off with an open grid we split
it into
randomly horizontally vertically where
we split it
you know we can could be anywhere in
there and then we worker summer some
parts
and so on the left side we've split that
went into horizontally and we keep going
to reach either
I'm maximum to or I minimum size for the
space is depending on how we want to
terminate the offer
us for the Golden Rule recursion always
have jewish commission up front
once we have bad have much relief now
it's meant to replace all the rooms
kind of interesting and the rooms
overlap guaranteed
I once we have all the rooms in the leaf
nodes I'm
this is where you want to look up some
the I'm
by her tree traversal
methods because we want to go up through
tree in level order
so going from lowest widest part in the
tree up through
and connect all the speakers together at
each level
as a guarantee that all the reserve
actually connected
I am some people in mind talks to listen
to nasa so
course I'm noises cover stickers
actually two parts to that
I could decide which and turns out that
power and practice for a bit of a gap of
time to talk to cover them
doubt but what I did mean was poised
time
discs Perlin noise
and sell your Armada is ur I'll mixer
techniques for
placing things and also for generating
different types
of train fare levels for example silly
raw tomato their
Conway's Game of Life everyone from
there to roughly
so you have an initial state have some
cells are on some other of me a couple
rules for turning on/off
based on a occurrence to next year's
refutations about
and you get keeps time
cooking cape systems I am place on
discs I'll that is taking a
distribution of points insider for to
the spacers
artificial space per for to the space
I'll
where all the points are equidistant to
each other based on some minimal
distance space flight so that's really
need cuz you can use that to
likes a fine job rooms where you want to
place
special features different enemies
bosses things like that keys whatnot
kind of I could be used for other
nefarious purposes we're on
minimum distances are being equal could
be use you can use a preliminaries
function there
Minister king tartikoff to reheat
together and graphics we use that to you
do things like place petition
for example Picasa probably doing it
gives here
Perlin noise I'm Spurs we want folks on
simplex nice for games just cuz it's a
little bit more efficient than the
original
growing algorithm that generates most
cloudy
textures answer each cell have agreed in
Crowle unit based on
all the other cells green values into
the histogram those
and if you have a %uh interval function
iserror takes like a high end of a fact
you can't have
pits and things like that tear four
points with his plea
broke awesome roguelike
I'm it has what a cool little pet a brat
bridges that span bombing
and things like that finally
I'm one of the more interesting things I
saw
presented at GDC effect last year was
using constraint solvers for game design
so constraint solving problem is
where you have he punch
love variables whose values could be
within a certain range a computer
continuous for discrete
continues being sorta like a for a
corner like
I'm going over that never has a separar
fine art thing was just a sec
have numbers like a fixed settler
there's no I'm I'm we want to focus on
finite domains
for games it's a lot faster it's a lot
easier because in
constraint solving problems is are
really large search spaces lot known in
Pekan
Inc np-complete problems in their I'm if
you try to make it perfect so
the fortunate thing is that we're I'm
with games without constraint solvers
we can come up with
an algorithm that is specifically
tailored to our problem space
and we can cut away invalid branches
research base before we get
too far so naive version of a constraint
solver will
look at all the variables and try to
reach all the way down and check
every possible value from every
combination
hand we can do little bit better
so what does it look like what's
involved in constraint so
solver well you have first a variable
games more than one usually the have
a each variable has a demeanor values
and first thing you need is a constraint
on the tix one or two variables and
enforces the constraint on them so think
of the a queens problem you've got
anybody play chess a religious some
people put receive
probably fairly familiar with what a
queen does on a board placed on a board
and the Queen's problem on a place a
different by
none other Queens replace can be in a
position where they could be attacked by
a quick
I'm on so the thing about this kinda
constraint problem in
dungeon design its more a very well I've
got all these rooms here's the exit I
don't want I don't care where the
impasse is but i wanna be with in one
room at the exit
I'm I have all these monsters the place
they could be placed newsrooms
and I want to make sure that the room
after this one has a health potion
ok exactly which one has what bo those
constraints must be satisfied in order
for this to be a good room
from hiking and so
we can do that biking she was on the
call dark
consistency so I'm instead of the naive
way of searching all the way through
every possible value in the domains for
all the variables ago saying before
in the Queen's problem you might say
well we don't need to search any role
column or tag know what we push the
Queen and Mac
placing there's no future possible
configuration where
placing aqui ni Spartans going to make a
balanced solution so sick norrell
on and
and
our consistency were going one step
further saying listen that while many
dollars possible eyes across all the
variables
often constrained personals for all the
times that also means come smaller
research narrow down the demands for
each variable
as we go along until each variable has a
single unique value
and once we have all that we know that
we have about solutions we can use a
slow
how I would have a car like in Python
welts actually
not too hard to implement a very naive
version of this
I am just to learn about the general
problem she was and how to go about
so we might start raising a variable
class is
producer your eyes
if you're actually using is unreal
engine you might actually you probably
should use a bit mask for
for used faster
each variable hands he Nero function
and the narrow just takes
a new set of values answered with the
current set of values
and then you'll see some weird returns
through this kernel get to that in a
minute
but the idea is that if we have values
that article the new values
that'll save business again another
optimization step
were implemented on Tuesday but the
important parts the folks at the bottom
there
and so we gotta reach constraints in the
concerns variables
involving we propagate the new values up
the constraint
and constrain base class is actually
fairly
nice small this is entirely a
I just has to have offices variables to
request
and a property acid has been committed
somehow
to propagate message is responsible for
taking the new certifies propagating
that out all the available
constrain as a from a
sir sonny's ok posh I'm
the from ipod propaganda from
hypothetical inequalities
string nothing too special there were
saying that
when we've got a new variable if the
variables you need to make sure we
remove it from all your
possible constrain players so this
variable X very quiet can ever have the
same to sticker
unique for
was worried it the summer the the
excuses we have to handle
so this offer just as the next look
through to make sure that all once I
have all my variables
have unique value i cant stop turn my
values
however decide to do that are you want
to have someone to stack management in
there
as an optimization step I'm
there could be a point where I'll
you get to know her I'm a very much
narrowed
down 27 which is involved problem can't
be
ever reach a solution so what we can do
is implement
stack that remembers where
I'm each value changes in variable jury
cycle and
do those appear forget invalid states
that we can try
maybe again 100 I am doing things
lost connection I think some people over
here
so is the optimizations to make this
problem tenable I'm in Python you want
to make sure the representative basques
you want implemented undo stack I'll
you want to use and when you're actually
composing your problems you try wanna
try to use as many
or as few summers few variables as
possible and
stay within if I scrutiny as much as you
can
for a safe thanks again let me just talk
com
I really hoped to you some more games
using these techniques because
I actor large more space to explore
and I really hope that there are more
road bikes written in Python
future I'm Cesar summer
valuable resources are found time are
worth working out particularly had a
bill to construe proper gear
weekend really good papers that was what
was presented at GDC last year
there's a are quicker on some person
took sampling these two books
sometimes book for agree
I'm if you wanna quote and start making
your own road bike games
out specifically the Dorian library
provides a lot of support that area
the sea possible I bernard has a nice
Python interface I'm gives you actually
a
Beyer Speed partition tree I'm to total
levels with as well as other things like
lighting and other literacy when
implement parts by a little after that
I've been using
doctoring a little bit for some mind
about demos
the researcher stock and crushed by game
time
there's I'm so think
I might actually went a little too fast
but free
nope Florida questions
me go
a ton hoops
sign nerves
a I don't think I can today
unfortunately
sorry
as a list this I will be uploading on
with all your
talks live you get those winter and you
shortly specific patterns lies but
Hotpoint resources try anything with
thanks
adjoining thing with multi-user dungeons
multiple players in a dungeon
they grow the dungeons it each player
gross tons in different places and
trying to unify them in
that's our thing rain I haven't yet
about a I've been studying broke source
code very closely
really cool so that that
that means like keeping track if you can
start doing pets
and broke for example you can actually
go to the agent go over
fall down and go to a new level of
attention and
so it just kinda making us for
consistent you imagine putting layers
and layers the single sheets min
remover talked earlier holes go
my now you keep falling are you hit
something
I
arm it on the
slider you were talking about building
the like the capabilities of
each room and what not that to keep the
constraints and
undo stack it seemed to me that you
could run into a scenario where
it was in a possible problem how to you
war
work around a like
racist so another optimization technique
is to make sure that you only implement
constraints for computationally feasible
you can get in a situation
in general contrs like search problems
of this nature
tend to be I'm exponential
in the general case the journal
worst-case which is why
we're trying to kill the algorithms to
with things but if you're
coming for the constraint can't be Sol
at a tricky problem you have to try and
avoid clichés
down there are many strategies to by
first checking that constrains could be
solved you can run this
Nelson as per haven't gone to just yet
but there's a good no threat include a
link to
larger labs library has assault her
already built in part for me
experiment with and
and see all times just kind of running
after a while to say one quick after
this and trying
strategy
how how you arm worked
the like how would implementing
or using these techniques be better then
saying spend spend a a weekend or so
when
creating and prefab
rooms and and and and hallways and then
just shuffling them and
connecting them together yeah I'm that's
very popular technique coming down
across as a hobby have
sort of Sammy constructed thing to the
dungeon the connector
star bound as a where their Dutch
generations actually 2d side-scrolling
but
Somerset a lot of the same techniques
apply for these pre constructed bits and
connect them all together
I think it's more of a style preference
where you want
like a hand constructed made sure that
it looks like this type of experience
whereas the constraints offers more be I
really
care what it looks like as long as it
remains within these parameters
I can I'm so it's more of a stylistic
choice
you can make you mix the two for sure hi
thank you whassup um just to mention a
few things I've been
having fun with I'm also working on a
procedurally generated game
on in my case some making a became the
second to these other
the game boy para and I have the great
advantage that there are already
existing the other games
so in my case have had a ton of luck
with Markov chains
arm for those not familiar the mark
chains are basically finite state
machines
a except instead of having heart set
rules to move between states
you have probabilistic transitions that
is state aim at heaven
eighty percent chance meters TB or 3
percent in something to STC
and you couldn't do look ahead on cell
so you can have one cell
I look ahead Markov chain or two
self-worth reseller
hover crazy you want to be so with even
one or two cells to get really nice
results
in generating landscape things like that
so of course you have to have
on existing data but on just something
about you can have fun
kinda making simple rooms and running
Markov chains on those to see what Jenna
what gets generated
on and about the previous
questioners idea doing prefabs
for the viewer from there the games
belong key and there's an article online
that kinda explains how they did it and
they did it
in a way similar to that by just having
prefabricated rooms
a few dozen her world in an arranging
them in different ways and having
constraints on them like mentioned
and you get real Nationals on that so
there's definitely a
a large body of were above work are in
generating content procedurally and it's
worth looking into
aerobic bro basins a very good genetic
resource for a lot of those kinds of
articles
on Kingdom Donna things like that star
about guys also have
your blog post but I'd prefabs thanks to
talk
picture II may do it
I need to get something presentable
running and I might dueling tana yes
more games and play time
so another another question I
have a how would you transition
summer these techniques to generate
3 3d world's
or generate or layered dungeons
up door fortress
world comes to mind right so a lot of
the
our group so mentioned are international
generalize
higher like on
the price index disc slashing
a lot of noise over those even
its even something as little as how you
store all your
cubes are knows a river in three
dimensions
I'm so those
hours will scale up with you when you go
up to
three dimensions things about like
minecraft for example
use no noise generation technique to
curb the
caves your
interpolation went so the silly
automatic thing to do for dinner in case
you can
interpolate maps over to my over top of
each other side you can like some
to crime police or affect parts of your
dungeon so thinking with
the Perlin noise generator kinda take
the
the only the highest values above a
certain threshold and use those cells
as see pits Arkiv sir
just floor just comical Mangion
like it's sort of sad be destroyed
crew
tons talking's all day
I'll try to repeat the question ok
so more on the on the generation
up three worlds ish
have you generated
any sort of I am ruins kinda
like more over like variations on the
on on on rooms structure
maybe using like creating a room and
destroying it a little bit
reading it right so you might use a
noise function can destroy a little bit
or change the tiles
with the price on
disc sampling and using the Perlin noise
to cost for the the toss together things
are gonna visitation placement
things like that and
for feature selection you have
to construe property make sure that
like this aqueduct flows through
rooms and is always connected and have
used
the this these techniques
for map generation I for
like generating other sort of content
maybe creatures generation I haven't
touched on creature generation or
anything
astoria it's mainly from maps from
with a little creativity could be
explained
expenditure that area research Korea
and just out of curiosity
what's water the dimensions of the most
complex
map toward the one that you feel that
most prouder
that you've generated I am
there's a new technique for the poison
disks sampling the king at SIGGRAPH
like 2006 and it introduces a new a very
special it is a structure
specialty structure for fast sampling
that's actually pretty slow oven
but it does have a very fast sampling
like them
like seventeen house in eighteen
thousand points
on a very large image a pretty quickly
really quickly actually report within
seconds really talking to you general
hospital
would
him
good
it
you