welcome everyone
to Python packaging simplified by sheesh
law Rep
hi everyone
wow hi everyone higher grade
so I'm here to talk about Python
packaging simplified
and as fifth title fight to death I'll
provide information useful to end-users
app developers overt or contributors
this talk is focused mostly on people
who aren't the one
packaging things out there will be no
talk after this
in more depth I can talk about that and
also are
there's not a couple of micro changes
the most they don't care about sometimes
in the
in the %ah in the description I promise
to tell you how to debug
complicated conflict between Debian
install packages
and pick installed packages if people
really want to know that you can ask me
the questions about in time defeated
to fit in and do it justice %ah for that
third
I will explain to you the tools the
stalk I want everyone to attend this
talk to be able to install python code
on their own system without needing to
use root privileges or admin privileges
or pseudo
I of you want to have a basic
understanding
how to distribute pot bunker DU Britain
and I also want you to know how to learn
more because there isn't
%ah time to do justice to everything in
part on packaging land
to tell Paul if you know the basics
and what %uh the right questions to ask
and then you can do the right research
to find out the answers
let's talk about installing Python code
if you have a Python interpreter
if I look something like this: and if
you're lucky your Python interpreter
come the batteries included
one of those models as the numbers model
and women here imported
the numbers model ever yeah I just found
in a minute
in the pilots at a library article so
%ah
when you import anyway it give you think
you can print
and if you put the numbers module like
any module corporate the path
but it came from this is what are the
most important thing to know
about type of packaging that the model
object we'll tell you where it came from
if you let it tell u this can be super
useful in debugging
and it's driven by allister directories
that are searched when you import and
that left is an assist module fist up at
I it to lift it looks something like
this: the kinda long
the numbers model definitely came from
one of these entries
and the purpose again to stop at if so
that you can
if the Python interpreter will certainly
to these places
for a model or Sunday chemport untold
satisfies your request
fall highlight second one here
this path usually Python 2.7
is in fact where the numbers model came
from for that great
if you want to use papon Cerda comes in
a standard library you might want to
install things
artist and a library for example if it
around the time hurricane sandy
and you've been reading this website the
Greddy you might know
that these cookies are hurricane sandy
special
the you might wanna buy the handmade
available for you
on a tee and so if you're lucky you can
important at the module
by doing something like this the photo
here is a
snapshot from the cheese shop sketch
because that is where you can find
Python code to install the website name
is cheese shop
although its two main dispelled PyPI dot
type on that already
I think there's some history about it
being used to be called the cheese shop
and an outdoor called the cheese shop
but nobody thought that except in
record atop the icon but if you search
their
as you search on the cheese shop for at
the rapper
you want to find something in Iraq the
at the API then
%ah you put in that search to find a web
page that looks like this this is an
index packages mattina trapper
all zoom in just about where the mouse
pointer is on this first hit
I thought that at the so great they're
fun code on the cheese shop
the let you communicate with the at the
API this week but
itself pipe on that at the is the name
of the package
some love you might have already noticed
that if you try to import something
called I contacted at:
you get a syntax error this doesn't make
sense how conducting the call pipe on
dash at the
there's you can put a hyphen in a model
name so
the neighbor thing on the cheese shop is
not the model you're installing
if the so-called distribution happens
again tamper module
and who knows what model to contain
likely this would explain
on a cheese shop entry which you can see
here this is just
pat on the head the page on pikey I dot
tight on the target
and if that great it'll make it easy
interact with the at the API
that information on how to install it
and in the initialization section down
below
it tell you that it'll make a model
called at the the great
if you have this you can import at: for
review astute readers
might have noticed that the installation
instructions safe you know people still
at the anymore stood will noticed
itself sub P
if install at the so this the photo
other guy named thank you you know is
part of a band called world world order
they make fantastic robot ask
choreographed dance moves and the music
to back it up I recommend finding some
other videos the point is this what you
should be taking over me think it's you
know
you cannot be thinking setup install
because seato is extremely powerful way
to run any command
the result a bit are short on
recoverable fear system something you're
on a Mac or Linux system with Tito
can totally replace your operating
system
and if you're on Windows it'll give you
command not found
so this is sub-optimal also I wanna take
a brief digression to say hi first
got really involved in programming in
Python in 2001
I A wanted to write some code to convert
the high school newspapers
PageMaker 6.5 multi-page printed but the
newspaper
and generate a national website to the
web can be the future
and I newt a pipe bomb the great
languish right programs then
I've been learning to pop art in high
school but the
computer in the traffic light of it that
with the high school newspaper
I didn't have admin privileges on
privileges on it locally at the Teenage
Dream Katy the spot in a big deal
I downloaded a local privilege
escalation vulnerability so that I kid
get a cmd prompt running at the quality
admin username system
so that I can install python two-point
to
or something are people don't always
helps you don't take it home a run to
know
and they can't can that
likely there is a way to install python
package let me text you know and
I'll bring you back to the stop at in
particular want the entries in 5th up at
is inside your home directory or users
directory on Mac OS
or a Users folder or
documents and settings depending on the
version of Windows Iran
there's a place the pipe on have it will
look if you insulting
in the right way and there is a right
way and that way is this
if install double hoping user papon Nash
at the and I'll take this
type on that at the thing look it up on
poppy i
it'll download the source distribution
from party I
it'll succeed and a clean up her white
print cleaning up I get to remove the
temporary directories
art so after you do this you'll be able
to import at the
and when you do that that the model tell
you they came from inside your home
directory
so things look great I wanna pause for a
moment to reflect
we've seen module like at the model
we've seen distributions which what you
get from piper guy
I'm eating tools with Justin 12 or pic
install double happened user
we haven't talked about any useful
reason you through know yet
we haven't talked about virtual and get
and thats fine for now
so I'll pick
and pie PI are tall %ah
don't always work the way you want a
time you talk about a few the failure
mode
there is by the way a brand of ice cream
in India called quality felt this way
actually they stop being allowed to be
called ice cream because they
fatten the milk without vegetable fat
for the Al quality frozen desserts but
anyway
if you pip install double having user at
see
where the different distribution the
Python dash at the
to the totally different thing made by
some totally unrelated people
it happens also create a model called at
the eff you install it people give you
this helpful error message
and the reason to give you the specific
help where message is that the author
up this distribution uses read me file
would have a square bracket
inopportune place and the square bracket
means that pip not knowing what to do
like a little look through the read me
for length hoping they can find
a place to download the source code from
and of all I wanted the link
and a half square bracket to the other
definitely not be version 6 URL
and that is not numbers and fix our
Olympic exit
%ah so one problem by PI for some time
download URL
wrong or the army thing and in fact
there's no automated checking that when
you try to people stole something
from high PI that'll actually install
likely the first have these is fixed
with Pip 1.5 pip 1.5
and going forward will only install if
you pick in solving
along a little look for the distribution
only look for tar tar GZ or zip files
hosted on the Python package intact on
the cheese shop
so that text nothing does checked though
that things will actually install
adjustable only look on the cheese shop
another situation you might find a stop
running into is the bit obscure
%ah is if look for your installing them
by Concord
anything compatible with your printer
pipe on Python 3.2
and injured two don't get along 3.3 plus
great 2.7 great
not 3.2 but you might try to install it
not knowing any better and Pip
not knowing any better will try to
install it people run into this
contactor that doesn't work for
diversion a pipe bomb and of a great
I've successfully installed into two I
put in the right place I removed all the
temporary file
you like came life of some stuff school
by 15 imported
in a pot entrepreneur be like what are
you talking about
can run so at this point it might be
worth thinking about
on installation so
if you want to uninstall something but
the you install this module
called at the and you try to uninstall
it it might tell you
there's no requirement called at the
that because pip called
distributions requirement as a
distribution stalled called at the
at the at the module came in from the
pipe on dash at the distribution
okay began on a stopping for uninstall
and this by the way the huge improvement
for the past
there %ah used to not be any uninstall
from stuff from my PI for this actually
pretty good and
the uninstall process is driven through
this thing in pipe on on it eg
so there's %ah data directory that
contains information about the package
then rushed to distribution up in a min
the distribution
possum stop dot eg info and a thought
the file package data
is information about this particular
distribution
actually the getting renamed can be
called it in turn on again for but it's
not that important
if I the file is information from high
PI
I actually not I P R combat second I
information about the distribution
anyway
and when it gets filled in this
directory I should say also contains
information about what files were added
for that way pick and use that to drive
on installation process
and as nervous index so if you install
the module
pic doesn't really know where it came
from it hack
it but it can go from the name
distribution to the list if I'll
niggardly ball anyway at this directory
gets generated
because pip runs their head up high
command hang out and fight are not easy
to get downloaded
with this argument against info and that
generate all their
metadata I mean it run supped up I
this important point that up I isn't a
configuration file
the Python program happened to contain
configuration about how pipe on
distribution are should be installed
and through a common feeling about
people have they wanna
not repeat himself for the fair I missed
or the version number this
code inside the code and then in the
setup I
the import the project but this means
anyone elf
when they run the setup the pie because
they don't have the thing imported yet
a break in half the lovely is that for a
pipe programs can trip you up
%ah keep in mind actually programs
furthest up so far
the stock so far works great so long as
you have PEP but if you don't tip
well we've talked about how to get it so
if this is like
your life because you just installed
Ubuntu machine or something
then you'll need download it somehow
according to the pic website
the best way to do that is to download
the file get picked up I
and run that program on me knowing what
I said before
you should probably add data user to
that and if you do that
then great people get installed and you
won't be able to fight it in your shop
bad that okay because you can
at your shop at and how to do this
varies between shell
buried between when it distribution the
Mac OS and Windows
but you need to add something like this
this directory is the analog up that
directory your home folder this is where
scripts or programs are part-time
programs will be installed
so once you've added that yourself
search path
you get great so
let's talk about how distributed code
and I wanna take a bit of an example to
talk about at the Republic shopping
after Hurricane sandy
%ah I have the sweatshirt here like a
few kinda falling apart
it does have that cool octopus on it
though withholding the boats
I want another wannabes so I'm gonna
write a program maybe by wannabe
every year funded automate the thought
never forget and
will call it get occupy the name the
project but
because we're allowed to inconsistency
will make Python program called occupy
getter
rather how to model the Connacht I gotta
and I'm packing and unpacking
and it goes great from time passes I
read somewhere
but I need to start up I and a license
in order to make this
real open source product 5 at those an
hour's time
to register but the Python package index
other people other
octopus legend fiftieth can find a on
the Python package index
to do that you run the register command
which like print some stuff
and exceeds a great and then I if you
need a couple discovered
to the bottom package intact you have to
run these to command
at once it won't work to run them
separately
but if you do then it'll create a source
distribution
which'll be named after directory actual
will be named after suffering a startup
I'll come to that second
are and then a lot about the pikey I so
it all do something
little print from paying and will
succeed
for great %ah that works a long as you
know what to put in your set-up ifile
here is the simplest one that'll work
for the product I've described
the product is called get occupy so
it'll be available on
the cheese shop under the name can
occupy version 10
one up and had the one package occupy
getter
but actually above you may know there's
a difference
in core pipe on land between modules and
packages
and the little one file Python module
you have to spell it this way
high modulus I don't know why it'll
probably be
maybe that'll change Sunday we should
talk about that mean we can pick those
prints
%ah also this is the Python programs
that kind of weird that
if he does run this thing %ah
it'll print some stuff out normally with
Python program the way that people
structure them
if they had a little our protection for
that
it only runs I intentionally run it
papon's beat the program name
if you try to import set up we had
before
it would execute the setup I call which
is weird
I think most at a posh files written
this way
the people just don't do that they just
leave out the if name
main thing for great motors write them
the standard way
also by the way artist you till dark or
comes from around papon 1.5 and even in
the modern documentation you can t
remarks about how
did you tilt is great and in Python 1.6
things will be told the better and if
you tell and you can see that in the
carter Ham the pipe on three
documentation
not just the two thousand tho anyway I
may wish Elijah Smith after that so
I think I'm funny myself up some work at
Sprint so
you can add more information to this I
can talk about myself
more importantly I should write a
summary and description up this
particular
distribution I'm applauding the pie PI
I'll tell you how to find information
about that later
long story short you handle that stopped
you the fed up to par call
you think your argument for this is
great
I now have I thing on pipe yeah I called
occupy
have a model call up together don't
think it doesn't have
the program actually get flattered and
eventually I might write that I might
call main here's what it might look like
but what I would really want is way to
run that for the command line
little bit odd his python is really
about important things bring them inside
pipe on
likely there is a way to make people
command line script using them up the
pipe I'll
and it is using the every points keyword
argument
to the setup function this is
I a really interestingly complex line
is the key on the outside the key inside
consul script
and then there's a key/value pair stored
inside a string
but that's just how it is for that just
how you have to do it
the once you've done that %ah you can
run didn't stall
double hyphen user dot which means
whatever direct ramen
by the fed up the pie file their and
executed
and that will put the get now
program in here back so
you might run it this way and others
showing up here for good measure
so if you did run this inner shell after
running dip install
to live in user dot probably want to get
a command not found the key to pick your
path once you pick your path
you try again you'll get get now
I like naughty maybe it'll search for
the kind of things wanna buy
if you configured properly it will buy
them and tell you how much is spent
perfect and on the Internet can now
automate
their acquisition process so you upload
just by PI
again and somebody else read about that
but they're likely to see
when they run it is an error message so
we should probably talk about
dependencies
on your system you have an atty module
because you installed it
you think installed a wife and user
fight on their shitty on their system
they don't so we'll go back to the fed
up I file
going from there add one more
keyword argument install requires and
this year's the name
are the distribution that your
distribution depend on
so there are other ways to specify
dependent the panel does mention the
very briefly
there's a well-known one named the C dot
build-out there's another well-known one
name requirement that act
this lot built up is really good for
setting up
not just not just dating how to install
this particular part on distribution
buffer describing the state an
application including
rank-and-file down off the internet and
put in need to put into the right place
and so on requirements not taxed is a
good way to left
the specific distribution you have
installed
and at any given moment that you really
think your application works with
and you can pass that to PEP in a way
that I can talk about later
for this is all good we can now upload
think spy PI
we can distribute them in a way other
people
know about and can install based on with
the dependencies that directly
let's talk a bit about this development
workflow so we have mentioned it
you run this command ap you make it and
it's just up the pie about to start that
copy it all occurred
into your local five packages directory
which means that if you make a
modification and find the directory n
you have to go run pip install the hype
in user dart
again for them to show up but a bit
annoying sofa instead
and the double hyphen edible flag it
install
then it'll actually use the module from
right here
rather than copying them into your site
pat is rectory and link them
for this issue for useful by the way
that have an old name which is set up I
develop
I having tried both the can now say
defense all to live in user alive and
editable is told the better
but as always is that don't use that up
I develop if you mention other people in
your
development by ministrations you set up
the pie develop go fix that
so you might have also seen as a few
different places the provider setup
function we talk about the futile stock
or
but there's a thing called up tools
there's a thing called distribute
what are the which one to two years so
distribute is an old for conceptual
that is now merge back in few setup
tools
for don't use that and in that case your
these two choices
you can you use the wanna come for the
Python distribution digital stuck or
or you can use the one that sort it
seems cooler and have more features
called her up tools
doesn't really matter that much to me
just don't use distribute but also
I recommend using digital decor since
that way anyone who runs a pipe on
code in a startup I is guaranteed to
have
the requirements needed to execute that
set up I
file so
%ah if you're going along you might
discover the pipe on dash
at the version that you need the pipe on
a
at the module had a bug in version: 0.1
point zero
so you know that they operated at they
fixed the bug
you money to specify versions dependency
is like this
and if your code that relies on the spot
on the head to distribution the newer
version
conflict with him suck you already have
installed relies on the older version
you can have a bad time further is a
tool for separating these out
and it is called virtual and bushel and
for the way to separate out
Python packages are installed so that
you can get a fresh
empty Python for better or for worse
hopefully a better
that means that you have total control
over what's in there
and then once you've done this source
been activates tap
which will add these parental I
to your path to your cell
prompt rather the friend indicate what
the name and a special and is but it
sort of death is based on what directory
the vessel and then
%ah you can run usual to install
commands to you
make your code available in 5 a special
and there is by the way a shortcut for
defense all happened edible it is that
he
if you think this way they all drink
some water
if you think this way you're probably
gonna have a good life
fly you don't have to live in user to
pip install inside virtual and because
then I'll tell you that obscure error
message and
you just have to not have to live in
your inside virtual and okay
another doctor with virtual and it but
they are hiking along one terminally
over climate
activated so if you run python 5 death
terminal
and on the other stuff from you your
virtual and that if you open a new
terminal window
virtual on won't be activated and now
you have to reactivate it
or get totally confused
so I think that the active its grip is
kinda confusing
you can use virtual and that you can
activate script all by just calling the
particular copy a python that it put in
that directory
the virtual and tool will create a bin
directory inside that will be been five
papon
you can try been firefight on every time
and then you'll never have to
have confusion another problem I ran
into you
is if you need to install nada Georgia
Tonga the punker with some tea depending
how many people seen an aromatic
like this yeah now we're getting
somewhere so
%ah if you wanna see compiler nothing
tell you exactly need to do here
it's just like so what I would do
is I would involve out now module from
the oven to you or the debian package
because
those have been today many people are
gonna compiling stuff
I'm other get a composite Fatima Devin
developer but you might not be is going
to compile it up and I am
so in that case I
you might Afghan ball python it'll be
great you can import Alex Mel
will be right there and to try to pick
up all Alcatel it will actually
satisfactorily
day our channels already there I'm not
gonna try
as good doesn't try the data might fail
but if you do this in a virtual and you
won't have the system I like to now
available
will be like nope and if you really need
to you
compile virtual and compile look for now
or another python package that have few
dependencies
then you can use their
Debbie and functionality to get the
particular
bit the code on your system needed to
compile
the debian package call pipe on dash
Alexa now
the Khyber way to abuse the pipe thought
the Debian packaging system
of these four have been too because what
you're going to do is not
actually build the official debian
package you can use this to build a
different
version of the same I tonka
we'll have all the stuff you need in
order to do that so when faced with
these are two problems
a lot of people think I know are you
bigger and we'll talk about that
vagrant is I great virtualization system
it takes like half a gigabyte upstate
you need
have a great need to have powerful
machine tool like little bar
need to download from for have been to a
Debian image and when you do that
on her to live by a day and a half ago
for me you know that you're in for an
hour and a half long wait
and then %ah if things go well you can
type this command
the competition vagrant will
then look for a file called even file
it'll look for all the steps
in there needed to turn this instruction
set into
working virtual machine image that
running on your computer
because as far as I can tell Mac OS
people find it hard to install software
we have to install folder to Linux
distribution in order to install
software
once you run this command then I
vagrant will run lever provisioning tool
you have configured insider bigger
file for that means waiting time for
puppet or staff rentable
or shell script or make files or who
knows what to build your VM and if that
worked out
it'll be great you took a long time ago
so
let's think about things were different
perspective if you're that guy and
you're staring out into the distance
knowing that things do not happen fast
enough
horrifying things will occur if you new
engineers your company you wanna give
them a good time when it first happened
on your code
or give new ovens or contributors your
open source project
or you just want to have a speed your
life
you might want to come out other way if
to handle these are two problems
so I'm gonna tell you about the way that
the open have product
which is an open source web app for
helping fittingly you contributors find
open source project to work on
an offer so we have a setup that allows
us to go from nothing
dust to pile entrepreneur on your
computer to a full running Django app in
five minutes
we do that number to land to do it up
install we do about it. compiler
we use the database for on with pipe
bomb too polite
and I get in Fayette but we don't use to
know either
unfortunately Django actually sorta
requires some
compiled code it requires the Python
imaging library modules
if you're going to use turn
functionality the you might think that
you can
import image but unfortunately images
not gonna love the Python interpreter
for that's fine you might out except to
the import
and what we do if we do this crazy hack
well we take
it only random unrelated model and we
stick it insist on module
for that way import image you will
totally get something what you're
getting at
outright lie
but this is important because the Django
image feel otherwise failed to
initialize urging a web app
we need to manage my run server it'll be
like know your models don't validate
and the new personal be like to dominate
the compiler
190 compiler to make a web app don't
understand
so we also have some tricks that has
weed I the filing showed you is a model
call based flash depends up I
for then we can check if they thought
the pen but images non
and if so do is get the stuff
I mention we do this all but %uh
personal and so what we do is we
just argues Pepe to install are
dependent these into a directory called
bender
and then we modifies the star power
which is that directory of places Python
will go search for
things to include all subdirectories
we've had in fact the vendor directory
and if you wanna learn more about this
we're using a trick created by them as a
look at the project
for you know what an idea you can search
for that here
finally in terms are the jagger settings
to make sure that the
databases don't require complex up we
use
seek a light as the default database we
do have on environment variable the you
can't that
so that if you want to use the database
for use in production but in our case is
my tickle
we keep that information in a different
dictionary in the settings file
and then we dispatch based on the value
this environment variable
for forgetting Terry we won another
really worked in practice
and snow that we have an automated bot
check are stolen truck and every day
and this is that but talking and I see
telling of to over the
that things will work if you contribute
a shows up and also to take about two
minutes 51 seconds
so if you're human you type slower than
a bot I think it's fair to say that
it'll take
about five minutes for the kid that's
how we
make new contributors on a process for
one drink a bit about
really easy you can apply from similar
tactics to your app's
one other thing of a that this pop
helped us know that all the dependencies
actually work against the version of the
website the bundle
a tried we want people to use so a
common problem as I mentioned before is
people
require one person or something I in the
dependencies files
but then happen to have something else
installed in their own machines
so they don't find out that it would
fail for you contribute and I think day
I mean we we failed when you consider
this way if I wanna not build any more
the robot check it for these you don't
have to
there's one other before the topic I
wonder stuff
so some Python modules are pretty
Florence all twisted has won the pic but
41 seconds on my laptop a few days ago
that party to the compiled a bunch of
stuff
when would be great if the second time
you installed it
pic just knew oh yeah how to download
that I already
compile the seeker I'm just gonna story
on copy and place
and it can do that now thanks to the
school thing called we'll
which our way to take the result the sup
I build process
snapshot it and then whenever you redo
the install process just
unpack that we'll into place a required
thing is complicated environment
variable
there is a right way to fight them and I
can tell you that here
but I am going to tell you instead is to
go to cliff left how its website
Feb 2014 a comedy set up about a day ago
which contained a shell script
and a Mac App you can use to you
that these things up for you correctly
it's really awesome
I recommend reading a shock at the
plantation it
I complicated and get the and kisses
right back from your testing he did with
me
and some other people so you can go
there if we could be beatified
also along the problem the talked about
therefore
come from compiled code against combined
with Python code
so-called Python extension and we over
one way to solve that
another common when the pot they're fine
to the community is a different package
manager
other than Pepe called Honda but I don't
wanna mention to make sure people know
dick death
it has a really active user base in the
scientific world so consider using it
there's another way that you can use all
these tools
pipe yard dash install the program kinda
like pet
that in federal going into letting
things from Pepe running setup I
and putting them in tears I packages
directly it'll do something very much
like that
little first make it up that file which
if you're running Ubuntu or Debian might
be awesome
for me it's totally awesome I can use my
package manager to find out
which distributions from pie P II
responsible for which by the models have
installed
but he's in my package manager search
tools our Quick Shop and how many people
here run Debian and Ubuntu other main
workstation our Wow okay more than I
thought
many have have still if you like it I P
I dash install a few that now
because Paul tightly Monte sitting in
the front row here
fixed it earlier today is broken you to
change in the
back on the right website which has been
fixed in does offer to let us talk about
the conference in a different fashion
called %eh petrol and it'll take a
requirement that text file
to the long list specific versions to
install and make a virtual and
you can then install with about that
file
so but actually a half million have to
take some questions of summer I've
now I hope you've seen the you can
install software from the Python package
intact
the cheese shop I hope you've seen how
to distribute it at least
in the broad strokes and you know how to
find out more
the best place to find out more is
packing up I pondered Oregon
unless you just what happens work at a
bar I mean packing the pot under a good
grade
it tell u how things work Feb 2014 dot
com
will help you in Seoul pip and from
shell configuration
or Mac App if you use Mac that will set
it up for you
double having user by default my raps
type that again
out a box on no account with after death
is giving a much more detailed look
how pat on packing is going to be even
better in the coming years
thanks and apology sleeping tenors I've
attended
please join me in thanking issues do we
have any
people that when asked questions I'm not
a question for small great talk thank
you very much
on another I was afraid it is something
else I I've now now I
just one thing that I find use for on
that you left out was om
pip dashed ass system site packages
virtual and yeah I'm sorry yes right so
that allows you to create a virtual am
that uses some good stuff that's
%uh apt-get install or whatever your
package manager happens to be
and then you can add stuff from the
cheese shop into virtual
yeah yeah thank you for theft and it's a
totally useful thing I
maybe added to defied for that people
after it can see that
petrol and have an option where
it will let you use code: installed
system while
left okay go ahead that that's the
thanks I get for setting up a website
week look thank you so much also click
bought pic dot works but unfortunately
is not ready yet will be available soon
as I understand
but work to the pound it up a little
demand now yeah I'm
Irish that but there's an SSL
certificate and everything you can
actually download
happen this from me on one thing I want
action point out another
suggestions helpful since so many people
unpacking here
of outreach and education this is a
fantastic talk
Charles classes internal the workings
happens tools this Charles all those
things and it's great and all that stuff
on many have you might
be tempted your introducing you people
the Python
to explain all of this intricate
interesting detail I
having been present many workshops help
on I'm just caution not
hurts anything about any of this up
truck reason like I'd brought the shell
script eventually
domain was that it's hard not to learn
to program
and if you give people instructions
station work
and that shouldn't have to know why
especially cuz all it's actually
happening
type South tools all these things is its
dollars in
computers use it and the so they can
uses all
locations distributions taxes so use
this knowledge
good and don't pass it on to people's
the first
about variant so hofer that's useful
yeah it's a beautiful this domain as
great I tattooed on my debut
machine other people tested it on Mac OS
just to add to that
according to echo what cliff said that
if you're running
introductory workshops that you can skip
talking about this
so the you talk about things you have to
want to talk about %ah
I received some method by
on a website recently that if you want
to give advice to people
you probably want to find out for that
this further this talk
explain why you have to do things the
way
that the shell script recommend that I
recommend here but I
explaining why isn't always the most
useful thing so
thinking about moving back to somebody
new means you just didn't explain that
go ahead yeah I a
I've I'm a question like a I maintain
some Python packages and I've
some trouble getting set up to pee like
work everywhere in a
work work right for example I don't want
to include a long description so I just
with Read Me file but of course that
breaks for some older version setup
tools or something so
are there is there some were definitive
to me
the definitive guide right to PP license
bulletproof
thank you so I don't know either
died for how to write have the highest
bulletproof but I'm
I author is one now okay %ah but
I will give you a few quick tips one is
never run set up top high directly
unless you have to you so if you tell
people to run pip install
whatever doc or your thing people run to
the pie for you
and picked up some crazy magic for that
unique you do from this year till dark
or
important up will be like haha nope I
put the setup tool set up there instead
and this means that people don't need
any particular britain effect on their
systems people for to make sure that
happens quickly
I think so actually
it will still if you have set up tools
and but it older version it will still
use that so it won't break so it might
remove some of the files from the
package but
that that's beyond beyond the scope
thank you very much okay I think the top
one more question
%ah this is probably also getting a
little bit
a beyond scope but on does open hatcher
have you had any experience using pi am
up which is sorta RBM pipe a python for
managing different versions of Python
things like that so a question about
different versions
papon thought your system perhaps
manager I and I don't have any
experience with that
I sorta win at the idea of order in the
pipe on the bottom on one machine
another other people for to the person
giving a talk right after mine
winter that the idea have not having of
over
the Python on one machine but I just in
too many users confused
by I open a new terminal and I couldn't
import this thing
and the answer turned out to be that the
bring a pipe on the running here
not a virgin running the height on the
running their and why do I need to
explain this
so where possible I try really hard
never have to explain that bind refusing
to install more than one Briton a python
minimize the use a virtual and and buy
back many papers although I can user
again a please join me in thanking and
she's for a great act