alright good morning everyone
us of our last talk in the morning we
have julie le voy
who will be giving a talk about
analyzing rap lyrics so please go ahead
for Julie
hi everyone
I'm I do you want a minute your name and
on 5th ed
a minute talk about analyzing upik
season papon I'm a little bit 6 a.m.
probably not gonna speak super loud so
please let me know if you're having a
hard time hearing
I just a heads up this talk a swear word
like a lot of her room and some
depictions of violence
most of them are censored are some of
them are not I'm be offended if you feel
the need to leave in a
so I really love hip-hop
last summer and the new york city to ten
hikers cool new york com
into the home hip-hop and rap I love
that kinda music because I was really
great for them it's really good for
dancing:
but as women have issues with a lot over
there
and here are some examples and I'm not
gonna read it out loud
but good
I want a guy
I'm Yours them lyrics from the song
goldie by Aesop Rock You and so
I was kid can we quantify be measures
sexism
K on this is obviously kinda a complex
and so question so as a kind a first
approximation when I start looking at
was
well which proper uses the B word the
most
and so no one goes to Google Talk being
confused by the word I mean if it wants
an on-again I mean the word bitch
fancy you and though
to talk about this while we need some
rap lyrics and where can we get them
on this website corrupt unions and it's
like Wikipedia for wrapping has lyrics
from a song that you can imagine
and you can go on an atty them from
eating so for example if you didn't know
what those lyrics meant you could go
look it up on Oct
there's a there's no API so we need to
scrape
through the day side with was I got
on 32 artists from 5250 some each I got
a mix of
East Coast West Coast Dirty South rap I
got on male female black and white
rappers for total
2600 or so songs hope
this is for my friend it was like a I am
super way what is this for
East Coast West Coast Dirty South rap
they're talking about so
user some eager to list two-minute
history rap
it's not completely gratuitous because
like difference on the rap
involvement in contacts it does teams
like what people talk about in this
Tyler
so it does a fact like what we're gonna
do into
rap started on his cock on the East
Coast our new york is the best way to
rock the birthplace of hip-hop
and what you really need to know about
these costs rockets at its what's really
important to is
rebel cleverness an offensive virtuosity
I'm examples artist that you might have
heard over GZB small Missy Elliott
s up rocky would think I'm I'm gonna
play you a quick sample just to get an
idea what I'm talking about
is where I'm not sure if this can work
about that
cases we weren't 0
I do not think no idea with of
with inevitable so what's up
Bracewell yippee week did
up
best be you know with chip
jump
gonzo you he quit you can notice is the
B is quite repetitive it's pretty much
just one sample loop over and over in
the background and america clearly the
focus on the some
so rob was born on the east coast but
then it spread to the west coast
only in the beginning there was a lot of
jealousy basically because
on east coast rappers refused to
recognize that west coast rappers could
be any good so there was a lot like crap
feuds in the wild jealousy
on their allotted like shootings between
the coast which might have heard of
and are well you can but West Coast rap
is that it was the birthplace of gangsta
rap after releasing the concurrent come
on up there
I'm gangsta rap came out over the
situation we're in the
ease in the United States crock hit the
inner city really hard
it generated like an incredible
non-violence in terms of people
committing crimes tribunal two for the
drug
in terms of farm gangs fighting to
control who had the right to sell it
and in terms of the police response been
brutal to the point being militarized
on as I quickly this little video where
the police had tanks
Sophie firehouse was like a crack ho
Stevens like knock on the door and
arrest you they would like ran into your
house for the Jain tank
of course people are upset rain arm and
soaking struck him out of the centre
Blake while it's going how this music at
about dancing around in like being happy
imparting
but our lives are terrible like were
forced to sell crack to survive
arm the police's told the owner case
really unfairly this so much violence in
desperation and this is what we want to
talk about
and so this is kind of the the broad
themes with gangsta rap pins
and I'm gonna be a sample colors tree
and Compton by NWA which you
quite possibly heard before sorry for
the little
weird T
that's right on Compton
I'm two-week notice is ugly like a much
more aggressive field and the other song
from before
that looks a little bit hard to make out
but if we look very
aggressive on examples are listened to
not all
West Coast rap is going struggling
examples are just like Snoop Dogg doctor
dre A&W that we just heard Teague I can
really Kendrick Lamar
and finally the most recent style arm
is kind of called Dirty South and
refocus their substance cochran contract
I'm
we focus on work that's what you're the
most likely be here if you go to clubs
on
it's the more as a sub most recent style
and it's different
from the other ones in the sense that
the emphasis is really on the BU and on
creating offensive energy the lyrics are
basically secondary
often it's just kind of nonsense
repeated over it like if you know your
littlejohn
is very Lake archetypal love the style
I'm and it's very well suited it has
become very popular in clubs because I
mean a club you wanna sit there
analyzing complex poetry you just wanna
kinda you know get hyped up with your
friends
and so if you go to a club today that
cling hip-hop
most likely as we're gonna hear and so
examples or dislike littlejohn the Wayne
36 mafia TI to change outcast and here's
an example the song called up but in
Johnsburg to me
you hard
huh said
but just ok
just missed
much
again I kinda want
scoring hum so any luck I'm so any luck
from
said there is actual coding in Stockport
arm so
okay so what we need to do now is
getting word from we're gonna do this
and be free for parts rate so first we
need to download image to more followers
than we need to extract lyrics from HTML
on count what we're interested in and
we're going to be some more such as well
you into
script is not like having a nice clean
EPIA where you can say okay
you know I look up in the dark is the
function call I need to do it I get the
data
its it's very troubling here and it's
very messy problem every time it's
basically a new problem and you have to
look at the structure what you're trying
to scrape and to try to understand at
first
so if we look at rap genius we seize for
each
artists there's an index page that looks
like this with a list of songs so uses
up rocky
and you see on the locked is pretty much
like that a list of all his songs
and then so if we click on one song
other sung only that were looking at
earlier that was are so charming
on hear the lyrics we see there's a
header there's a sidebar there's a
widget
on and there's only a small part from a
page that we really care about if we do
you view source we get
basically 1500 lines a beach in mall in
CSS and Javascript and so on
on and of these fifteen hundred lives we
care about forty
you so at first the scene really
straightforward way I was like ok Ill
just he's beautiful see you can already
Lupino use your 11 which I've been told
like cocaine
no one call does that anymore like use
request on
and get all the files and not simply to
let things be safe or in
except nope so the first problem happens
is that I only get 20 file for each
artist
and doc seems like a problem because for
JJ's he probably has
a lot more than twenty some sort
something is going wrong and
the problem is
think
it my fear today
99 problems in getting all of them
actually story of my life
so if we if we look at the
the real page on rap to use what we find
the problem is auto scroll
and so how r school works if if you have
an in camera is basically
it looked up the first twenty songs and
then when you scroll to the bottom the
pages like okay
I need 20 more songs and then it kind of
goes like this: this is to avoid that
doosy probably has like 300 songs and
then maybe just care about the first
three in the have a huge page load for
nothing right
monarchy sweetie $1,300 song so how do
we kind of defeat this
so what we can do is we can load up look
far bugger chrome dev tools
and scroll down to the bottom of the
page on trigger the event and then see
where is it making in Jax request
and so when we do that we because the
pictures at the bottom at Sapphire bugs
so you can see it's like calling your
own we get the worst throw lever
60 discussing so okay this isn't about
at first cuz you like will
Parenthood has a pagination primary cost
route so we can say well
r8 pagination because of me all the
songs but
doesn't work either so it seems to
ignore this
and talking and then it's like while
there's a a primer call p.m. so in
theory I guess you could break the Euro
into like three parts with the first
part
the page into generator without in the
loop in the second part
at three in the third part and then just
like all the successively in get all the
pages one after the other
except that could even ask because we
also this for our did
for artist page ID here going on so now
for each artist we have to somehow get
this
and now it's not nice cleaned on parsing
it's like some giant regular expression
monster
gross thing I'm until then it's going to
take a step back and think
in was my goal to write the best creeper
whole time or was it just to get a bunch
rap
n this Irish like
packages tied to this on the handover
every programmer know which is
one is important for something to be
perfect for something to be done
and in our case it's like take it
thank you
on and in my case was like whoa you know
for nuclear submarine downloading rap
lyrics on like map Firefox plugin
so is a plugin called down on the mall
into what I did is I just like 12 the
peach trees up rocky and I click like
schools gross gross gross gross gross
gross cool download the mall in many
callers
and I did this for the next for 32 times
and was incredibly boring but I was %uh
and so
okay so where we are now now we flake
use down on the mall in two for each
artist we have a directory
with a buncha regional files represent
like one person for each artist and so
what we need to do is take this HTML and
for each song
internet into lyrics rate so we have
your party for problems we have you
tomorrow now when you mix
and so that we can use on initial use
beautiful soup which is really like
a nice straightforward screen scraper
are written in Python any channel purser
and I weed or use pattern which is also
an inch to more per sorry but it has a
lot of fun
natural language processing I
capabilities I think it's pretty New
Haven
her too many people that have used
before and yeah beautiful to this
fantastic
registered using pattern more just
because Dennis reading more on LP and I
who's a simpler to use the same tool for
everything and two
looking at the structure what we have
I'm we want to do is turn a tomato is I
get these things under the given
looking very quickly basically lucky for
us all the lyrics are just in this Big
Dave call their actions 0
we just need to do that I'm and using
part in this is rushi forward this is a
six lines of pattern including two lines
for opening the file in printing it
into you open the file you read the file
kid I kid in one line
you done if I the whole situation down
you get
say give me that dear with the classes
lyrics turn into plain tax which means
text album two new lines like
unknowingly
Nichole details an imprint and their
there are the first three lines have
called the
ever so charming sup rocking and there
you go
so locks thing we need to do is we need
to count the numbers be
arm and so pretty much for each artist
like count how many are in
each file told them up and then what
we've done is the average over the
number songs to make up for the fact
that he jay-z has a lot of songs but
like Queen Latifah has like it
small number of songs and but this is
not even a library a parchment I mean
it's just the regular expression library
just basically pretty much counting
matches in
their school one-line so result
on rappers are using the B word on
average twice for some
which is good about a musher Enzo
the robbers are the best you had like
I'd easy Missy Eliot encontre kalkaska
on you
looking to build a prize I suppressed by
Connie and easy cuz I don't think I've
them is very positive toward women
arm I was the women was really
interesting II with
thank I was happy to see that the women
did pretty well and then the socially
conscious rappers I was happy to see
their politics were kinda been mine with
some
the usage of the word up from one to
three
whisper song the STI be small fifty
signs
I mean I am Kendrick Lamar I was really
surprised they begin I'm not talk about
the morning second
arm and 323 three more those little came
Foxy Brown and whts up rocky Snoop Dogg
I was surprised because
basically a little complex in honor of
female rappers if you don't know them
and them
they were like amongst the worst Mike
that's kinda interesting
I mean so bad
so lucianne so bad he merit in his own
category
with 9.7 times per song arm
at which point I'm like it's time to
learn more words
littlejohn home
and so what going back to original
question which is a good matric for
sexism rate
and everything about this artist the
biggest montana a very violent lyrics
towards women that talk
about the killing I'm assaulting them
mining murdering
I said already that squirrel a Tivoli
law so
I mean I'm sick twice per song in the
small three times per song so
him okay to fuck it
help on and overlook examples alerts by
littlejohn in the small
I'm not going to say this out loud in
and I didn't warn you that there'll be
some I'm
on like pure
examples have lyrics by twine and the
first thing that you cannot miss his
little Jon Diebler
I needed to bleep out a whole bunch of
words but big a small arguably what he
saying it
much worth but you know there's no swear
words in it
into let's think about this so big a
small I'm number
the recognized amongst the greatest
rappers of all time biggest mall in
particular is known as
probably the greatest storyteller in all
rap the painting very vivid pictures
with his words
on both of them are known for their
their local talent a very clever
and I ok I have more songs about you mom
and so does example over a song called
party and bullshit by the small
map
them
and so in the also you the lowdown from
right and who's the
to compare a song by Lil Jon day
Mac
me
and so you can definitely see it like
you and I told you nothing that
the to flee from different styles and
was a little bit the whole
you can see a little big is very famous
in from the east coast model John is
very famous
from the those who can see I think in
those samples pretty clearly the the
different styles but they're coming from
as well
into it seems to be that mike Beebe
smaller
a human enzyme refuse to play any songs
on but this thing done more vocabulary
just more skill to describe things that
are worse so
it suggests that the counting word like
the B word or some other derogatory term
for women is not a sufficient matric to
really evaluate sexism in
in music so it's like mmm hop
on not sure what to do next in so what
about
when dealing with data is if you're not
sure what to do next anne like wall
cannot didn't work out how I thought
good thing to use to play with data and
look for useful patterns to see is there
something in there that I can exploit
so one thing I thought of doing a small
okay you
I was really curious what are the 20
most common words in rap into
what's this is worse are really falling
in love with pattern which is basically
three lines a pattern which is
is the compile all your things into a
less than calling docs like that is the
function I wrote
on basically do this legal document
thing to it
I'm gonna talk the I'm excluding some
weird was all talk about in a second and
I basically just saying give me the top
20 words with a frequent account and
there we have it
so the most 20 common more than 2700 rap
song
antidote 1500 line each I'm not so
are basically the N word then we'll
prolly /url arm
morse wearing afterward the B word time
love
wanna Moneylife tar baby gotta magazine
real girl hit call look in the B word
perot
there's a problem with the pearls was
all talk about in a second
into
on the the list words I was taking out
earlier and as well
that like this whole thing exclude
rappers the issues are interesting in
person rappers dispersing other tax lien
friends i do research in this kind of
topic
using like French literature and
psychotic I had issues that they hadn't
on into I in our language processing
Stoppard's words are so common that we
basically don't I'm not the popular
arm are words that are so common that we
don't care about them
so it voted on and profitable on a slang
I'm into we need new stop weren't so for
example had tied job
damn Johar come on that and
so those words have to be parsed up
because they fear so commonly and
another thing is
I'm robbers often referred animals by
nick names that appear in the tax so
whole if I look to the top twenty words
for Jeezy was which is nick name for
himself with the top 20 word
on so you have to add those as well in
person so
and in rap it's also common to have
guess robbers
on diverse are to have like many
different rappers in the songs for
example
arm wu-tang clan the top 20 was all the
names of the members
and Enzo
a man so I can also when there's guess
rockers will see the name and the person
as the outsize the
to attach the first to the right person
into
one interesting thing that came out of
that was I'm in an I was really
one thing and is accounted Lee coming
times are people using the N-word I was
really surprised because I'm is a white
rapper that he was using it at all
and I was like hmm house at 90 and I
wanted to look into the song it was
because he had a guest rapper who is
black that was using the word
and the other thing is stemming
something is
the kind of I'm sure allowed remember
it's basically the process by which you
make Apple count with Apple so we saw
Lexie the B word in the B word pearl
that should really be one word in terms
of what does it mean to the tax
by like right now pattern
isn't dealing with this cuz I for
example I want ho to count close but
its thinking a cartoon home so it didn't
really work but
so so for for
arm so but you can pass in a custom
something function which I have yet to
rate
but this is probably a good thing I'm
gonna do sometimes really quick and all
what so what's even more interesting
than the most common 20 is
what makes wondered one artist different
from another for example are they really
weren't that
only big a small size and so what I did
is the added the 20 most common words to
the exclusion wordless to see what what
is big he saying
other representing I'm gonna go all you
can
look at the Kool Aid on site I'll go
quickly through is that we're running
out of time
into for big the top 20 the Ramada
really negative words there's like mad
mofongo hose afterward I
I hard game like a lot of cum sad words
and then a man on the earth on the F
word little boy
a sick bad mean so-called
before love sad words and if we compare
Tribe Called Quest which are more band
so she looks kind of like a
African pride in my partying in kind of
happy things
love the words have to do with dancing
like move rhymes be
people lyrics really qualified to live
in a universe I would sort of per for
the tribe call quest universe than the
M&M universe
and another interesting thing was I
socially conscious rappers that weird
people
arm was at the top %uh all over the
counter all them suffered a prize for
moral technique and for Talib Kweli
again up with the slide up on one can
look at them a bit more well
think on into I still have so many
questions so that the next thing that I
want to do is look at groupings weren't
into to feel like the windows a five
words if there's a word for women in a
word for
a harmful weren which is kinda suggested
would be a good approach by the
prominent to those words and stuff like
are Eminem's lyrics or begins lyrics
and then as well what I'd like to look
at is the sexism correlate with the rise
up gangsta rap because they found for
example that street harassment
correlates very strongly with
armed police harassment over minority
men
so when the final the police's like
randomly stopping and frisking people
and people are really upside
how they react to that as a way you
feeling getting a sense of power dock is
the only cross women like
in their neighborhood so interesting to
see if if sexism correlates with the
rise of Kings
in Eric's correlates with the rise up
gangsta rap of course
or or if doesn't correlate with the rise
of Club orient its really
bling bling make it rain kinda rap on
where
you know it's like to have my fancy car
and I have mixed rental car I have like
my hot girls
so these are questions and images in
continue to Texsport
I'm if your interest not come prolly
gonna be ready to pop some
please come check it out if you're
interested arm
and thank you so much and now I I'd be
happy to answer fan questions if you
have time
so I'm gonna start by confessing a bias
as old white guy who has training and
sings Ian routes based music I've always
found
rap to be executable arm and I wanna
thank you
for a fascinating talk that opened my
eyes to a number aspects of it that
I was unaware of um the
and the little disturbed by your
characterization
that they were forced to sell crack to
survive
but OK let that one go be poetry
go back in history all learned a lot
more about rap by studying
the history that involved it and not a
question but if you're looking for word
grouping
the term you're looking for is in Graham
rare and that
there are libraries for that that will
help you do that data analysis with
awesome thank you very much
and yellow thank you for the comment
will as well but be poetry II
are you had wished that there is a time
to go into him I
longer history Iraq but i dont wanna
talk about rap for half an hour
icon but let's definitely got one other
things are really
other properly came from thank you for
putting hi I just like to thank you in
some way
hands talk is shaping up to be a
probably the best one other day
it's going to be a much of an imposition
if I could go ahead and not some more
than one question
like a like
I'm number one I was wondering if
how which Rafi like the best and if you
tried running your analysis on
a a.m. practice from the midwest
and number two if
use founder I if you've managed to
conceive a way to
to analyze poetic meter and
finally one more question if I can I was
wondering if you've met
if you've looked into automatic
transcribing so that you can find a way
to analyze in school I freestyling
mom well a lot of Britain
arm okay
I have to remember all the more I'm
my little cue very short you
arm I'm are you sure which went to enter
I guess maybe is there Canada is there
one in particular you want me to answer
in on you can talk about the rest
after I'm know okay to be tried running
this on on the Twitter
Mitt Midwest rappers like ideal Chris a
crane
home months as crew brother leaders with
people
I did got much I kinda focused on these
guys but I didn't want to start work on
this project
I did get a lot of requests from France
in can you run like it was a from the
requested type Tribe Called Quest
so if you want me to like from the stats
on them I we can do it after
on isometric call and we can talk about
the other question doctor I'd be happy
to answer them
I there
so alive my name's remmy and I'm
professor Russia receives technology and
eyes when I commend you for a
this is this talk did I was most excited
about I'm
I really in interested in India
overlap between these things on there's
library called place while I say is you
may be able to analyze in this Sat Mar
by
looking at synthesizing the lyrics as
well like training in using some tools
like Markov chains
there's a I recall mark opted
use is powering a blocking games
programming
good mashes up the Bible with
programming books Chris very interesting
interesting
therefore give that mashes up Tang Clan
Eric Swiss
speeches by President Obama it's a lot
of fun will polish that tumbler dot com
just shameless plug
okay secondly I'm very interested
mistake research I've done some like
rhyme scheme
now sis kinda stuff with LTK I loved it
and
data office stuff so Myford question
really is
is their code somewhere that we can
check out on
how we contribute on how I get people
involved program
RIT Osher I guess I should um
from the corn it's not on my get home
yet but that might get them handle right
there
II will warn you the code is really
kinda Matheny focused park on preparing
for the talking
really bass and dirty coal on
beautifully welcome to check it
an eye out for should I come to their
the tip off once we will prolly put in
the open spaces dancers me I
you definitely very welcome to to come
hi
our awesome talk possible question Mr a
statement
I have some experience with scraping
web sites and there's a Python library
called scrapie
and also if you really need
for like the infinite scroll issue you
might wanna check out
headless WebKit browsers like phantom
JS they can help you handle that issue
well thank you I'm script the three
months one member the things that I
looked at
essentially I sort of people see I read
the doc first maybe there is too much
stock rating from you know is really the
impatience I
just went straight up with beautiful sea
could are a doctor five minutes and I
got started
arm but I i do understand it is a very
it is a very good tool as well in a good
alternative
thank you very much
all right let's go ahead for Julie