are we have to talks in this afternoon
session
the first one will be a forty
five-minute spots so that will translate
to
roughly 37 and minutes and 33 seconds
for talk
II and the remainder for questions so
I'd like to introduce Greg Wilson Craig
Wilson is the creator software carpentry
a crash course in computing skills for
scientists and engineers
his work for 25 years in high
performance computing
data visualization computer security and
academia in
and is the author or editor several
books on computing
including the 2008 drawer wardrobe
up winner beautiful coed and two books
for children
great received the PhD in computer
science from University vendor in 1993
and presently runs the software
carpentry project for the Mozilla
Foundation so %uh let's welcome
upgrade for his talk about softer
carpentry
and the lessons learned thank you
so there are the boring details what you
really want to do is hop on that if your
pad
arm that's what the pad looks like
please come join take notes and ask
questions collaborate
so here's what we're gonna do we're
gonna recap a series of conversations
I've had and I'm gonna do both voices
because I have a little kid I've had a
lot of practice doing funny voices
I'm and also singing the chorus love
the song from frozen over and over and
over and over so
1997 hi I'm a program I'm starting a web
company would you do
0 I'm a designer I know how to select in
range text and images in ways that are
appealing informative news about hot
that seems pretty simple to me I mean I
know how to use a fine selection dialog
I don't think I need to hire you few
years later
pumped into the designer so I just are
not go and tanked
people so that my site was agree in
confusing I guess I've learned my lesson
2014 hi
I'm starting an online education company
what do you do when a teacher
I know how to select and arrange
learning materials with repealing
informative interactive
har that seems pretty simple to me
retire you
welcome to my life here we go are in a
project called suffer carpentry
we r lab skills for scientific computing
this project started because I was
working
with his assistance to run misusing
first-generation parallel computers
and they would come into my office with
the 50,000 support when asked me to make
a zillion times faster
and they had never heard a version
control and we're
really sure why they should be writing
functions because nobody had ever talked
them
and his unfair to look down on people
who aren't doing things right if you've
never shown them how
I did anyway it's difficult to look down
on physicists but I managed
I'm but I realized by the mid-nineteen
ninety's that I was doing more harm than
good
if you give a supercomputer to the
average scientist it is rather like
giving a Ferrari to the average
sixteen-year-old
and the crash rates are similar so
starting in late 90's
we begin running classes to teach them
all that stuff that is boring
but works version control shell
scripting
how to marginal rise a program how to
manage data I'm
we don't have enough DT yet
to publish but the feedback we get is
that a two-day workshop
will save most scientists day week for
the rest of their careers
no to any faculty members in the
audience this does not mean they will
finish the degree earlier they will
still go to end the funding first 10
percent
but they'll get more done in the publish
more on the contactor problems that
could not tackle before
we teach the UNIX shell
get you can get help Python were or
ins SQL but what we're really teaching
his task automation how to track ensure
you work
had a modularized your code how to turn
it into functions that are readable
testable in reusable one that does in
fact all the same thing
we teach them a skill but what we're
really teach teams with structured data
is
what's a key want to know why do I care
so it's beaten switch
we advertise the things on the left
because they've heard those and will
show up
we teach them the things on the right
last year
103 instructors 97 two day event in 12
different countries
about 3500 people went through we're
going to increase all those numbers by
about 50 percent this year
so we're not huge but we're not small
and we're growing
that's where we've been and you can see
the numbers in the yellows but were
everywhere
and if you want to help community showed
but that's not here and
what I'm here to talk about today nor my
here to talk about all the volunteers
who make this possible
our instructors are volunteers post for
the workshop is the travel and
accommodation but they volunteer their
time
partly to make the world a better place
partly because it's more fun to work
with people who know these things
and partly because it's a real boost to
their careers
the academic job market is pretty tight
right now so if Trevor raise your hand
Trafford
who's one for instructors wants to get a
job at MIT going down in teaching a
workshop in Boston showing people just
how useful he is
gets his resume over the big stack and
short stack right away
so first thing I've learned
most scientists think a programming as
attacks they have to pay in order to do
science
this idea that we're gonna teach
everybody programming other organ wanna
learn
is wrong and we just need to get past
that
how many do home run apps I'm if you
enjoy doing home reno's
hey Chris out we put up his hand this is
a guy who enjoys refactoring make files
like
we're talking about way here on the bell
curve for most of us
hanging drywall is something we have to
get done not something that we really
look forward to
similarly if you take the average
chemist she could have chosen to go into
computer science
she chose to do chemistry that's what
she wants to do
programming something she has to do
along the way in the same way that
statistics is something she has to do
along the way
so we say wow this is really exciting
let me talk about recursion
we're not helping her I'm
the number two and this one took me a
long time
the curriculum is fall
every time we want to add something and
any level
we have to identify something to take
out
and right now I use this as an acid test
if you tell me we should have more
programming in schools my very first
question is what will you removed to
make room
if you're not willing to do that I'm not
interested in talking to you because
you're not being honest
yes I absolutely believe we should be
teaching programming in high schools
to give them less Jim so the more obese
do we teach them once about French or
English depending on which part of
Canada red
about we teach them once map right
we give them was music every time you
want to add something
you gotta take something out and if you
want to do this evening or weekend the
new cutting into all the things we
currently do with that time
and if you want to put more computing
into the undergrad program in mechanical
engineering
you have to convince a product that is
more important to mechanical engineers
education
to implement an Amex turn
if you're willing to do that the new
being honest about the challenges we
face
and this has been a real struggle for me
and this is why we run this two-day
workshops
outside the normal system our goal
is to reach graduate students and in
week fifteen years
so that they will rise up through the
ranks to their sitting on the curriculum
committee
and they can decide what to take owed to
make room for the stuff
this is how statistics became part of
the education in the life sciences
medicine
the generation that had to learn it
during the second world war
particularly in the UK under Norman
Fischer
fifteen and twenty years later when they
work on the curriculum committees at
Oxford and Harvard
and Cambridge in UC London they said
right we're going to take this out
and this was different in every school
so the people have to learn stance
you gotta play alone game I'm
I hate that idea I'm not by nature a
patient man
but this is how it works on you booking
police line
science advances one funeral at a time
Kirk but all the stuff is in the paper
go read the paper it short I think it's
well-written
and its open access so let me tell you
something useful
let me tell you some things that are
really in the paper
victory comes from the accumulation of
small advantages
if you want your workshops to work if
you want your teaching to work
there is no single slam dunk there are a
lot of things that can go badly wrong
but in terms which you do right it's a
collection of small things
how many do live coding when you're
teaching could no slight you plug in
you start typing do you know why it's
better
reason number one this the script why is
that better
they can see how to diagnose and recover
from mistakes
collateral knowledge transfer they see
what to do when it goes wrong
because that's never in the textbook and
that's never on your slides
ride they also get the reassurance of
knowing that a
if that the teachers can screw up it's
okay for me to screw up
you giving them permission heater pad
we always run a need to pack when we're
teaching there are students who will not
raise their hand for whatever reason to
ask a question but alas could
on any three-pound because my shared
note-taking recapture way to share
snippets of code
either petr something like it is the
best teaching tool I found in years
except for one other how many if you
teach was sticky notes
okay the next time you teach go and get
two pats a sticky notes
one red when green everybody gets too
sticky notes
when things are going well you have a
green sticky note on your laptop
when you need help you put up a red
sticking up
people who will not ask for help when
they have to do this
can just very discreetly say am as if
they were building a high-priced auction
from the front of the room you can
immediately see who's finished in neat
open redirect people
people's people with the shells it's
cheap it works incredibly well
it's a poor man's clicker do this
and you'll never go back we are teaching
workshops here on Monday and Tuesday
hands up if you're actually gonna
teaching one of those are helping have
one of those and we've got a few people
in the room
okay we are going to be handing out
sticky notes
and most of the people who attend those
workshops will then use them when they
teach
I'm it's a wonderful little technique
minute card is Tracy here
i'm looking straight into a bright light
tree city on the back introduced me to
this
so you've been teaching in the pin doing
sticky notes to ask for help which
number status
yes sir no we're ready to go on however
you use them
coffee break comes around everybody
takes the red sticky note and very
quickly jots down one thing they didn't
get one thing they didn't understand
in on the green thing one thing they
learned we put them on the table on the
way to the room to grab coffee
in room forty people pick Super two
minutes to go through those
so that when they come back from coffee
you know which part of the Western you
need to repeat
they won't come up and say I didn't
understand axe
and if they do it's 10 to 40 you don't
have that's representative
but if they do that on the way out and
they come back and say let's just go
over coal stocks one more time
they will thank you for it and you never
go back to the old way of teaching
signing up with friends we discovered
this by accident
and then I discovered the people doing
educational psychology research have
known this for about fifty five years
watch what I do with my hand so
our workshops used to have the same
crappy gender ratio that you see in
computer science undergrad class
12 to 15 percent female by accident
sort have we ran a workshop in London
where people were supposed to sign up in
groups
don't sign up as an individual round up
a few let me to friends and come as a
group
gender parity why
you but when I guess
you know the answer in bed in the back
there
less scared because you know that you're
with people you trust
even if they're not also from the
underrepresented group in somebody's got
your back to somebody you can turn to
for help
you're not going to be the dumbest
person in the room cuz come on this
issue let me
you know they're stupid issuer in so
the work on this was done in the early
nineteen fifties trying to get
recent immigrants particularly Jewish
kids in New York to sign up for sports
activities in neighborhoods
even if they're not signing up with the
Jewish kids the fact that they know
those people in trust them
makes the at risk under-represented
groups more likely to show up
and I hope of the size but cannot prove
that one of the reasons we slow down or
teaching over the last two years
is that we're actually finally reaching
the people who need our help
most because the underrepresented group
in our workshops used to be
the people who really didn't know how to
program
and they were free to commit to
programming workshop because nobody
wants to be the dumbest in room
but now they're showing up with other
people who are just as backward
through their K so do group sign up
I promise you will increase diversity on
several axes
editors are hard things that
we take for granted are really hard for
them
into the biggest mistake we make
is to use the word just
how many be used the word just when you
teaching
really please stop right it's the
passive dismiss objective
oh yes you just install a virtual
machine and you just installed Ubuntu on
topic that would just make sure it's the
right version of Ubuntu and then you
just synchronize the
network card so you can just transfer
data network
getting editors to run getting to
understand
a text editor which is different from
something with word
and how to save files in the root
directory so they can find them to run
them
is hard because it is intrinsically hard
it just we've been bitten by the so
often that we've got so much scar tissue
we can feel the teeth anymore
with production that there was something
there to learn and this is part of what
we do with our instructor training is
try to remind people
that there is something there that needs
to be learned we are one other note if
you're organising workshops
make sure the russians remarked
cuz it the you can dress that story
tells itself right
the other party that story is make sure
the campus security knows you're
supposed to be in the room
you can fill in the rest about brief but
exciting story as well
his lesson for and have I could send a
tweet back in time
five years a ten years Intel myself
something
this is what i would tell myself as a
species
we actually know a great deal about how
people learn how to teach them
there is as much evidence-based research
in education has risen medicine
the differences you're probably more
where if the research in medicine
when you are the research in education
if you can do one thing after the stalk
going grab a copy that work and read the
learning sciences group Carnegie Mellon
put this together
this is a summary as of 2010 for
non-specialists were willing to read
dense taxed up what we know about
cognitive psychology educational
psychology instructional design social
forces shaping
learning this it's the everything we've
got boiled down into one book
it is not an exciting read menachem back
to doubt
it isn't an exciting read but it's a
really useful when happen if you have
kids
please yes and the kids in the back put
up their hair
excellent working I really like
knowing enough about education to fact
check my daughter's teachers
in the same way that I like knowing
enough about medicine to fact check my
sisters oncologist when she was sick
how many here in a startup do you like
knowing enough
a boat tax law business legislation
commercial property
that you don't have to take the Warriors
word-for-word
you don't you don't have to be an expert
but corman
250 pages that's a good investment of
time
so footnote to this lesson is most
programmers
and most people in business and most
people in government even ones that are
really excited about teaching
don't know that this knowledge exists
it was a lotta social forces around that
we can go into in question period
but the ultimate answer is that we have
heard work on some time so you never
fart
most programmers would rather spend a
week remote hacking on a new mic website
Fernan our reading research papers to
discover that the pedagogy embedded in
the website
is actually useless I'm not mentioning
any
platforms by name contradictory but
what too many people are doing
is taking bad teaching an accelerating
it by putting it on the web
rather than finding it would good
teaching is and then exhilarating
that
let me give you some examples and the
slides will all be up
I'm sorry for the long URL but I'll come
back to this and watch the piston to pad
really good slideshow from a few months
ago
from John Hattie in New Zealand what he
does
is collected Studies in Education into
the mysteries on top of that
so his database has almost 200,000
studies from the last half-century on
various teaching and learning techniques
and what he does is look at what is
called effect size K basically
what fraction of a standard deviation
can you attribute to this thing
now for those of you who don't know as a
very very rough rule a farm
each grade in the public school system
is about one standard deviation up from
the one before it
so think about these numbers as
fractions of the year
in public education his primary looking
at k12
he's not interested in tertiary
education adult education
so with those caveats let's have a look
shifting schools cost you $30 per year
with nothing else going on
moving a kid return prime sticking to
another cost members third if you're in
the education
it's disruptive could web-based learning
the effect is so small that it's just
not worth worrying about
teacher subject matter knowledge turns
out to be relatively unimportant
misery love farm you looking for bro 2.4
to get excited anything below 0.4 your
not to worry about it teacher subject
matter knowledge you don't have to be an
expert to teach
and in fact we from a softer carpentry
is it's better if you're not
because experts don't remember when
officers don't know
what about class size people get really
excited about this
it turns out there's a week a fact
when there are problems that are
attributed to class size they're usually
do something else
take a look at the bottom one there
strongest effect found
to improve learning is to get rid of the
disruptive students
and much love the miss attribution to
class size
is simply a reflection of the fact that
a larger classes more likely to have
disruptive students in it
if you can control for that the class
size affect goes away
that's interesting motivation
K motivated kids
learn faster
I'm we're a concept mapping to simple no
picking technique where you draw
pictures and the ideas the relationships
K would appear to drink getting the kids
to teach each other
I mean if you care program can come in
if you pair learned
even informally look at the price you
happy year
that's a pretty cool thing formidable
valuation for teachers let me give you a
scary statistic
in the canadian and american public
education systems
the average teacher has another teacher
in his or her classroom four hours a
year
in the Finnish school system the average
teacher has another teacher in his or
her classroom three hours
a week a movie play a musical instrument
how much to learn from having another
musician listen and give you feedback
how many feet do a sport even if they
know better than you getting the
feedback cleanup and repair if I some if
you get code reviews
the rest if you please don't record for
me okay
it's a normal practice in some school
systems isn't in English language school
systems
look at the effect size right it's one
of the top five
how canst teachers improve if they're
not getting feedback on the teacher
there is a commercial site no could be a
smart cookie dot com
teachers can post videos of themselves
teaching to get feedback from other
teachers
this is brilliant this is absolutely
brilliant it's like
YouTube where people posting videos and
songs playing guitar to get feedback on
their playing not on how good the song
is put on how will be doing the keyboard
in from work
K this is what the internet is for
to look at some other things
there are broadly speaking and I am
going to generalize my father taught me
never hesitate to sacrifice troops for
clarity so I'm about to do that
basically three mental stages with very
clear divide between them
novices do not know what they don't know
they do not have a mental map it the
terrain
they don't know what the key concepts
are with the relationships are so if you
give them what's up know what you were
actually pushing them further back
because what they're going to do is take
those facts and put them into the box is
that they've got
but those are the wrong box is how many
viewers 38 a programming class you've
been wondering helped us okay
you know the people coming in and asking
the questions and the questions just
don't make sense
that's why they've taken the knowledge
and they try to fit into the existing
model of the world and that models one
but they don't know that it's the only
one that got
so the most important thing with novices
is not to give them information
its to give me correct conceptual model
in or have to the introduction to Unix
we teach them exactly fifteen
Unix commands in three hours but we
teach them the paper and filter model
we teach them history we teach them how
to read a for loop in the show which is
not to say things in shell script
we teach them the file in directory
structure so now they've got a map above
the terrain
they knew where the pieces are in how
they're supposed to fit together in them
they can fill it in with knowledge
faster than I can talk and you're
discovering
I can talk pretty fast
second stage is competent competent
practitioners can do normal tasks
normally that's where most people stop
how many be drive a car look at you
probably a normal drive
ride I mean helicopter gunship comes
swooping in but a bit about you don't
know what to do
normal situation right happens in the
movies all the time was come also
restore
happens less often in Canada right
summer Europe from the state's drawn
capital of the world okay
competent practitioners are the middle
to curve
what distinguishes experts from
competent practitioners
it is not how much knowledge they have
no but how's that reflect what is
experience turn into because you can do
things over and over
what different sheets the expert is the
density of connections
in relationships between the fact that
they know
think but in terms of the ground if your
graphs personally connected to go from
the idea you've got
to the idea you need to solve the
problem might be five parts
but for new me who got a much more
densely connected graph it might only be
one or two
and this is why experts are usually bad
a teaching novices
because for the expert idea a an idea no
are adjacent there's a link for the
competent practitioners
a two-seater hope LeBron opposite aid to
be
overdue said to cuba y back 2c 2d
the can't see the jump they don't have
that link
K all you teaching has to be based
around us
you have to know which group you're
talking to
the most important thing to get from
competent expert is self reflection
as far as we know you do not become an
expert with the reflecting on your own
practice
again how many few code reviews
pic I do not believe you can become an
expert programmer with ok
reviewing your own code any more than
you can become an expert musician
without learning to hear yourself
so if you wanna make that transition
what you have to do is teach company
people have to look at each other's work
how to read and critique somebody else's
movie review how to tell somebody
that their shoulders with rushing on the
swimming whatever it is
so that they can apply that technique to
themselves
close the feedback loop and become an
expert
okay everything I have to strip told you
is backed up
by hundreds and hundreds of studies this
evidence behind with routier's more
quickly
how many can appear instruction peer
instruction is a teaching technique
which probably produces better results
in less time here's how we do it
thing number one i ask you multiple
choice question and you all have to poke
you got
you know ABCD or colored cards were
clickers
case you poke committed to an answer
step number two
you talk to your neighbors little groups
3&4 trying to persuade them that you're
right
step number three you have to vote again
stepped in before I tell you with the
right answers and now they're step
number five
you get to talk to your neighbors again
if you interrupt this process after each
state you discover that almost all for
learning happens in step number five
wine because in the discussion with you
three
you realized why he believes the wrong
answer
so in the second round of discussion you
can correct his misconception
it gives you the power of 121 tutoring
in a scaleable fashion
look for a written answers work we have
twenty years
evidence to back this up but Simon's
work at UC San Diego has replicated two
studies with several hundred students
over the course of five years none of
the existing platforms directly support
construction
and most if you don't use in classrooms
when you teach because you've never seen
it yourself
okay this is kind of cool
I got him is what I have to accelerate
multimedia channel company persons for
concert extra some was mostly okay
here's the most importantly I will come
back if there are questions train your
trainers
K I now run it class to teach people how
to teach programming
the next one starts in June its online
tell me
this is the one thing i really wanna
showed about not only
do people learn how to teach they learn
how their colleagues are going to be
approaching the problem it doesn't
matter what your PlayBook is it matters
that everybody's
on the same page i'd and yes there is a
great deal you can learn it does improve
things
you can go there teaching to suffer
carpentry .org or
you can go there we are running a class
on Monday
gonna try to squeeze a few key ideas
down into one day
they're still succeeds open if you're
interested I will put the Euro up again
but I to speed up here's bus number six
by country didn't matter
okay I've been teaching for sixteen
years I have never met anyone who
switched appointment because I anything
in Python 3
it did not bring us a single new user
what we could have done that would make
a tremendous difference to my teaching
other than fixing the installation
problems which the working on we should
fix the standard library
watching novices try to find things in
the standard libraries
Weser always stop after maybe assure you
tiller maybe it's I don't know fred
ride string I oversee string I on the
list goes on and on
most importantly we should have done
some usability testing
under stuff etc published a paper in
my love this work can sorry about the
crappy formatting
there's the borough are posted up what
he did
was compare how readable programs are
to novices who've had brief instruction
in three programming languages pearl
quorum
which is one that they're designing and
one with a randomly generated syntax
people given pearl performed just as
badly as people given language with a
randomly generated syntax
in the internet responded as it always
does
people went to the trouble with looking
up his students names in order to some
hate mail
and one of them drop to the program's
result you can guess her gender
k if this is how the internet response
to me doing research promoter K
what's interesting in those comments is
the people who are saying
you result in statistically significant
twitches response is yes they are here's
my data here's my statistical analysis
beauty is less than 0.05
it statistically significant where
people really means I don't want to
answer the free must be wrong
so he went back and he read it that
study
but he turned up the volume step in
seabird
are you can find copies at that if you
google for it
the idiots abuse him put everything
behind paywalls
you can read the so let me give you high
points
step number one is go through with lists
of words and terms and symbols to ask
novices
which ones have these do you think mean
the following things
interesting discovery in a list of 20
words
the ones the place bottom for meaning to
this multiple times
or four and while they are the least
likely
to novices to mean repeat things because
for means do it for somebody else in
while mean something to do with time
nobody guess is that means repeat if you
change it so that the key word is
repeated
people find the concept easier to learn
because they don't have to unlearn the
old meaning
that's a step 1: bus to step 2 once
people have had a big construction
language
let's see the accuracy with which they
can identify construct in
rebbe Java prepay fun random 0 that's
the round one and core
note that every feature in corn has been
a be tested before two-putting for
language
languages will see style syntax do not
go perform a randomly generated
languages
pearl in Java both sucked as much as
random
Ruby and Python who performed in Coram
outperformed both
gosh isn't that interesting how many
people web sites
how many to usability testing and web
sites how many to usability testing on
your language
how many people were seen a usability
test attached to a PAP proposing a
change in the price on language
why the hell not we can do it
and building more usable language k last
thing because it's time for me to wrap
up
would you like me to buy you and the
person of your choice dinner
convince me that you have an answer to
the following question:
why the hell do we write lessons that we
read software encyclopedia is
how many you contribute to an open
source project
okay so we know from hundreds of
projects that you can have thousands of
people over the course of a decade
contribute small bits and pieces to
improve something
how many if you have ever edit Wikipedia
page
okay so we know that we can have
thousands of people over the course of a
decade or more
collaborative we create something which
is complex
and readable read the Wikipedia article
on the causes of the American Revolution
its beautiful prose it explains concert
complex things and had several hundred
contributors
how many people have ever seen a lesson
or lesson plan
that had more than three offers more
than 10
more than 50 yep olivia is a note lawyer
here I'll be talking to you later sir
why don't we do this
now I can understand that this was
nineteen ninety-five nobody at flattered
but we've had Wikipedia as an example
for what a dick in hand
you can't say it's because the
technology is hard been teachers may not
be programs but they can edit Wikipedia
articles
you can't say that it's because there's
no benefit to the teachers themselves
I really like being able to take
somebody else a slider can't we could
use other peoples exercises
you can't say that it's because people
are afraid to put themselves out there
on stage this is the Internet
right it was invented so the people
psychological disorders could get jobs
right get respect from the community but
every single thing every single reason
you can think of why
teachers and other educators don't
collaborate on the construction teaching
materials that we we collaborate on code
with other people collaborate on
Wikipedia
every single one of those points equal
to these two cases
and yet despite dozens of attempts in
different countries
and by different communities I don't
know with anything
like Wikipedia los materiales things
like CNX
are up with the slide decks with the
people can download it there is
no merge there is no culture of
contribution
if you want to change education but
really change education
expand right
that would be cool so this is me
and there's apparently some 16 updates
available so one should just ignore them
thank you ample okay so I suffer
carpentry dork
all of our lessons really get a free
porn we get people talking K
there's another protocol the
architecture open source applications
and we are current lease looking for
technical reviewers for things call 501
zealous let me wrap up
please ask me but the scraping sprint
with just me but the turtle sprint to
please ask me but indeed if
please ask people 500 lines thank you
very much
okay thank you we actually have even a a
minute or two more for questions so we
have a mic back here
anybody who wants to ask questions arm
maybe about why there is no
are Wikipedia for to a lesson plans any
of that please go back to that
microphone and will take questions
and also scripted MacBook should put
those on one slide
certain time pipe
how can I make you look better hi Greg
you already have
but %ah um you how you can make my life
better
the whole send me right here thing only
kinda freaky go ahead
trip %ah
I think the first time ask your question
%um poke fun at my glasses services
par for the course um
are so I was wondering if group sign ups
could be used
as a mechanism for addressing the gender
parity issue
with our regards to conferences so I
propose this first type II boat
up for various financial reasons I
wasn't able to happen and could be a
play that their
I could it don't happen up I can't do
the experiment in report back
quite quite seriously yep we can make
arguments both ways
more and more a pensar que no te
Scottish verdict is
okay juries in Scotland are unique in
the english-speaking world in that they
can return one of three verdicts
innocent guilty or not proven
increasingly I think that we should
adopt Scottish for two more cases than
we do
we don't have evidence it's plausible
argument try it and tell us if it works
get rate literate okay who's up next
hi thank you for great talk I I teach
programming to teenagers
I have been so for about a year with the
number from the Bay Area we recently
tried adopting
pair programming one of the main
challenges I fine with teenagers
is are so none of them know each other
before the course
and teenagers are very much iz they're
very hard to mention pair sometimes one
will get
stuff at the speed of light yet when
will struggle uterus which bears around
but then you just
have to lay the problem other group is
kind of hell to measure teenagers
and used you've already identified the
problem we don't know each other coming
into the room
yes okay fix that and the other problem
go away
and thank you pictures hidden bolivia
so I disagree with the statement that's
known the on-screen
is so if you go to math Academy don't
org am
that's a website that's powered by get
help on the back and
soup anyone can contribute and that
shows
lesson plans in a graphical qua and you
know
you can plan your course so many people
here have seen math Academy .org annuity
just make Academy
sir meta medicare to me my apologies
so that's my first attempts at getting a
free dinner okay you you don't have of
of winnowing you have to explain to me
why this isn't normal
ready shown that you can do it with
heroic effort and you have put in her
work effortlessly don't know prolly
eight
he deserves a round of applause as well
but none you have to convince me you
know why this has not
normal is just starting its just people
figured that's the right way to do it
Paul anyway this is just a temp number
one you can leave lol we can decide
attempt number two will come when this
being that is film now will be put up on
YouTube
or and then later on someone built a
course on course era
that tries to get lots of people to use
tools like that so at that stage
out of tens hundreds of thousands of
people
maybe you know a hundred 200 300
teachers
actually start using those tools K and I
first heard this is just around the
corner
in 1996 right K
and so I don't believe it's just around
the corner I believe there is a force
acting in the other direction that I
don't understand my model the world
predicts that this should be the normal
thing
it is not a normal thing so I'm wrong
about something there's something I
don't understand
K and people again and could just
convince we have the tools now to make
your we had materials
we have the tools as long as it's been
Wikipedia stay tuned for a temp number
two perfectly sir
so I just went in open space just before
his conference on education
and I am amazed that's you brought up
the same point that I
brought up where and concerning
translations actually because
agreed that we don't have any with book
as programmers its easy to collaborate
but as educators and fork on and we
don't have any platform any good yes we
do
it's called Wikipedia the other will you
just work on its not for education
course appeal earn a period the end the
Learning Commons there have been dozens
attempts to take exactly that's offered
popping up in the teachers to do this
and that
all failed at least all the ones in the
english-speaking world I cannot speak
for the communities I would love to know
if this has worked in
you know Brazil South Africa China
someplace else that I can't see into
because my language disability
well I'd say that to him worked at all
because we don't have any platform
translate actually
into have any good plan from a Trembley
content Inc on
demanding okay okay that's a possible
technical issues go
um so I wanted the Python code ads and
one other things we have is for love
this stuff
if we want to take any of this feedback
we have to go hunting for it
in academic papers all somewhere else
come talk to us the and mailing lists
are open
yes we can be an asshole sometimes but
sometime in yes something I'm on the PSF
listener
the BSF is not my thing that
a and and BSS getting better too to al
but it it's the thing I love okee its
there is wonderful stuff we should be
doing um
but we have no money we haven't known
resources but we
and but he beat you coming to us for
teachers to
so I heard teachers why aren't high
school math teachers
who have rock-solid curriculum in
fixed-point problem
doing this now they opted to the same
text books a white card
the doing this rights not just for
programmers why our social studies
teachers not
collaborative billing West plans because
they're used to using other people's
material
you really have to build raw material
most people teachers don't
they take standard material improvise on
topic then with jazz musicians improvise
on top
score so the idea that we have to build
all this ourselves
I with the idea that it's a technical
challenge I'm still not buying dinner
but yeah I think you permit incentives
II back it being in sentence
okay I might like to take a crack at the
dinner the case of all the arguments
saying they don't have incentives
applied equally well to open source and
I was there
in the eighties and nineties when people
were saying open source will never take
off because why would anybody give away
software
they have disincentives to via the
Internet okay
please
but
absolutely
we point
social studies teachers in Ontario apt
an instance the week
the week media software and sister
Camille pin their I'm not
I'm not looking at this is a
programmer's or programming problem
I it is routine now for teachers to
not just use that headed Wikipedia
articles
in the process a building course
material take a look at who the
contributors
are so why are they not taking exactly
that and doing it for less it but it's
not about programs
yup
in again we can find point solutions
why is that not normal okay
okay and that's the challenge is why has
this not already become just the normal
way of doing things
okay I'm sorry she's got a couple
examples like CS unplugged
where there are people clambering on
curriculum the open source text book
that
different you know this contributed to
there are a few points solutions that
are a few instances there is nothing
that has been widely used for has spread
I'd it says that the only open source
software
in the world was going to you max okay
now I'm depressed
ok that was a bad vision I
okay the argument that was the teaching
us to localize
I'm sorry have you looked at the Common
Core might have you looked at sent we
mandate a teacher
okay I'm so we're gonna have to go to
the next one but argue with me
afterwards I'd love to buy you dinner
that came out so wrong go ahead please
please his microphone please use the mic
yep okay so I'm at the chart but I miss
you then
and I can tell something up from a
different perspective
a because at my school when I lost high
school
I am my teacher muffs the shower
deter organize something like math comp
and it was like mmm dark done by
students by us for us
it was like we are totally into it I
mean we take we are seeking part into
not signed yet it was also like a
in computers in computer science but
the we students the just found out about
the topics want alarm there was a group
of people
could I mean those students it was not a
school it was very important
and that we went somewhere with our
teacher
it was like free as calls from
my country and it was like from them
a very morning deliver evening enter its
were
running short on time so is the question
were proposal in
know is like it way well internal to
bury you
call us: well minotaur so the book that
has changed my mind about teaching the
most is seeing like a state hands up if
you've read this
hands up if you work in a large
dysfunctional organization in those two
words are the same
okay this is why over and over again
large organizations prefer the allusion
a central control over productivity for
success
think booklet device for me understand a
priest 1:20 a.m.
as much food brigade Moscow the Aleutian
that everybody's doing things the way
they wanted think about softer
development at IBM
I lived through that was
indistinguishable from click device for
me
so this is a really good book and their
case after case after case and what we
see with centralized curriculum
is that we have to squeeze out the
individuality which actually leads
to better performance so I'm so I
understand bad as a possible argument
what I don't understand is when nobody's
managed to break past that an amount of
time on time
okay ladies and gentlemen thank you very
much at all just burning rubber