right good afternoon everybody
you for coming I'd like to introduce not
bad
other who's going to talk about getting
started with testing
hello everyone
on so this talk two starts at one forty
but the printed program says 155
there's gonna be some people coming in
late and you can all make friends by
palling up with them later in explaining
what they missed in the first 15 minutes
I'm gonna live code on the screen it
might be difficult to read your two
options are to move forward or to use
the Billy you are at the bottom which
will take you to a page on my website
which has all the slides in the code
and even the text if you want to follow
along so my goal here today is to show
you a way to test your code
I'm assuming that you have not written
tests before and you are
just curious let's say and that you want
to figure out how to do it
arms on going to show you a way to test
code there's lots of different ways to
do it
and if you talk to testing experts-- the
public and tell you that this is all
the wrong way to do it maybe but this is
a way to get you started I want to
remove the mystery
from writing test first a little bit of
philosophy about this wide test
testing automated testing is the best
way we know
to figure out if code works when I wanna
hope
10 trying to show you in this talk is to
look away look at tests as
a solution to a very important problem
that you have your written some code
and the problem you have is that you
don't know if it works and tests are the
solution to that problem
some people approach tests as a a check
of
on some sort of form that they need to
complete before they can go home at the
end of the day
it's just sort of paperwork to get done
and that's the wrong way to look at it
you'll be very unhappy if you write
tests that way
testing is a very serious problem too
threat
it's a serious solution to a very
serious problem and if you approach it
as such
as real engineering you'll get a lot of
benefit from it it will save you time
because you won't have to go back and
fix problems later and I'll give you
better code because the tests will
actually help you write better
more modular code to begin with most
importantly for me it removes fear
from the drilling process if you've ever
approached a large piece of code and had
to change it
and thought that you were certain to
fuck things up and
make the code not work anymore testing
as a way to make sure that you will not
do that anymore
it turns fear into boredom as a way that
I've heard it but
be and the other way to think about is a
debugging is very hard but testing is
easy
so testing is a really good way to rate
really good code
this is most developers first impression
up testing
they know that they should be doing it
but they're not doing it
and so they feel bad and and just like
our poor developer here
they're paralyzed by this feeling of
inadequacy
and uncertainty and doubt about what
they should be doing
and and and they feel bad and I don't
want you to feel bad
testing is hard
it's a lot of work people and by people
I mean you
will not want to actually do it but it
pays off
so if you approach it as and engineering
task to solve a problem that you really
haven't you want to solve
it will work out for you the reality is
that the universe is a chaotic place
so here's another poor developer she vet
recognizes that the universe is full of
chaos that is trying to attack her code
okay you know how it is you write a
program it seems to work great
and a week later who knows what's
happened to it some gremlin has gone to
it and it no longer works
tests are the defense against us our
developer here has thus
us a spear and shield those are the
tests I'm gonna teach you how to write
them and use them
our goal for this talk is to get these
two developers
happy and confident that the ant so the
road map there are three main parts that
were gonna talk about today
the first part was we're gonna grow some
tests organically will take some real
code
and we'll just start testing it serve ad
hoc making up as we go along and talking
about what we like and don't like about
the way those tests are coming out
and then we'll bump them the main piece
to the talk is talking about the unit
test library in a standard Martin Stan
library
that is the way that the right way to
write tests and I'll show you that some
key bits and pieces of the unit test
module
arm and show you how to use them to
build your test
and then I want to get into a kind
advanced topic mocks
which is something that you don't often
see an obvious talk but it's a really
really powerful tool for making your
tests
much more powerful and flexible
so let's start from first principles and
grow some tests so here is our stock
portfolio class in again if you can't
read the code there is a billy link at
the bottom
Billy um slash hi test 0 where you can
see the code
so there's a stock portfolio class is
very simple we define a class
it keeps a list I've bomb to Paul's name
shares price
you can buy some shares for certain
amount which will append that
I'll stock lot to the list and the later
you can ask what is the cost to the
portfolio original cost which is simply
the sum
I've the shares times the price for all
the stocks in our portfolio
very simple code how do we test it well
the first test is
be excuse me just launched the
interactive interpreter and you start
fooling around with that you make
an empty portfolio you can see that it's
cost 0 and then you can buy 100 shares
of IBM stock and you see that the cost
is gone up and then you buy 100 shares
HP stock in the cut the cost is going up
some more
so this is really good so a good thing
here is we're testing our coach let's be
honest
their developers who have not gotten
this far right be
so right off the bat let's just
congratulate ourselves that we are
actually testing our code
but the bad thing is that this is not a
repeatable process if we change the
implementation
we're gonna have to go and do this again
and and we won't remember what it is we
tested it will probably miss the case
and that's where the bug will be
it's also labor-intensive you have to
type this out every time
and you don't know if it's right you're
going to get your calculator and see if
the risk you take work separate
so let's fix some %uh those problems the
second test will write a python file
and will importer portfolio class will
basically do the exact same things we
just did in the interactive interpreter
will print out with the cost is that the
empty portfolio and then after we buy
100 shares of IBM
and that's good and we can see that you
know the stock price is going up up
for the IBM stock and then after you buy
the HP stock goes up
that's good we're testing the code it's
now repeatable we can run that Python
file any time we like
it's very low effort it doesn't take
much to run that file but we still don't
know if it's right
we have to look at that output and you
know is it right that comes up to 21 263
if to get the calculator again
all right let's add some more to our
tests so now here we've got is we got
um a portfolio cost where week print out
what it should be
and then we can print out what it should
be and can print out what it should be
and here we can see that it's printing
those results
apologize for the code going up the side
of the screen
now it's even better we got repeatable
tests with low effort we've got x better
its be better because we got explicit
expected results we stop to check the
results ourselves here the line of code
if it were wrong we just have to look
and see if the two numbers were the same
or if they were different
by the computers and telling us whether
the number was right it just showing us
the actual result
an expected Brisbane expected result so
again let's add a little bit more to our
test
keep in mind these are not the way
you're supposed to write test
K this is you exploring the the problem
writing good test
I'm gonna show you with the unit test
how to do this the right way
but here now what we've done is we've
taken our cost and in addition to
printing a message about what it should
be
we use an assert statement to assert
that the cost should be zero if you
haven't used the assert statement before
takes a condition
and if the condition is true it simply
carries on executing the next statement
but if the condition is false it raises
an exception
so here we can make an assertion that
the cost must be zero
because our tester passing the assertion
never happen so now we have a repeatable
test with low effort
we have explicit expected results and
results are checked automatically
good be the problem is that if the test
fails
arm it will actually throwing assertion
error and
the tests will stop this blue coat is
actually incorrect it should be an
assertion error there
so it if one of those assertion fails
the entire program will stop in you will
run the rest the tests
so if you with this for a real program
the word doing many test you have a
hundred or thousand reading 10,000
checks to make
at the second one failed you'd never
find out about the rest of them
well we really like is for each check to
be run completely independently
so as you can see this is getting
complicated right if we wanted to
approach that problem of how do we make
the tests run independently of each
other
that would be yet more engineering to
put into these tests
that's gonna grow its gonna become a
real program with real engineering
typically engineers when they find their
encountering problems that other people
have encountered the gaunt find a
library to help them solve those
problems
that libraries unit test or get that to
that in a second but first let's talk
about the characteristics we want from
test
we won our tests to be automated so
they'll be low effort
and they'll be repeatable because if
they're too hard to run after too
confusing to run your not gonna run them
we want them to be fast for the same
reason we want them to be reliable
remember the point of a test as you want
to run it and have it tell you something
you don't know
if you doubt the test then you haven't
really gained anything
now you've simply move the question from
tips to Mike just my code work
to do it to my tests work and %um
release of anything
so you need your tests to be reliable
you need to you need to believe them
when they say the something doesn't work
and when they tell you it doesn't work
you'd like them to be as informative as
possible because if you think about the
workflow the workflow as you run your
tests
and if any one of them fails you're
going to immediately try and figure out
what what is broken in your code and so
the more clues you can get from your
tests the better off you're going to be
doing that the bugging exercise
and lastly they should be focused your
tests should exercise as little code is
possible
which is a little counterintuitive
usually be one any line of code we
right to do as much as possible but with
test 31 each test to be as focused as
possible
because if it fails and you dive into
your code to debug the problem
the less code it runs the more but
narrowly focused you're debugging
caskets
so this is what we want our cast and now
we can talk about how unit test actually
gives us these properties
to unit test is a lot module in the
Python standard library
it is the infrastructure that you use
for well-structured test then it is the
lingua franca for tests it is based on
the same
arm patterns as J unit and an unit NCP
key unit
and a lot of protesting libraries across
many different languages
for that reason unit test has kinda job
a flavor to it
which a lot of people pay finished as
don't quite like which is why there are
alternative ways running tests
but we're gonna talk about unit test
here because it is the it is
the way everyone starts out running
tests on all the test runners in test
tool support these test
so this is an actual unit test to write
a unit test
and by unit test by the way I just mean
an automated test
you import the unit test module you
import your caps your code
under test and then you're going to find
a class and your classes derived from
unit test that test case
so all your tests will be in a class the
drugs from test case
and the test themselves we methods will
be methods in this class that start with
the word test so here we have a method
called test by one stock
and its gonna do the test we did before
we put make an empty portfolio
we buy 100 shares of IBM and then we can
make an assertion that the cost is what
it should be
the way you run tests with unit test is
that you
use Python basham unit test if you
haven't seen the dash implied it means
instead of running Python code that you
find in a file I'm gonna name
you gonna run python code in a module
I'm gonna name and so by running
you the unit test module as your main
program it knows how to actually take
the next argument test port 1
important that and find the tests in it
so we will automatically find the test
class and the test methods and run them
this week single dot means that iran one
test and then it tells you that around
one test
and everything went okay so that ran
your test and the test pabst
behind the scenes what actually happens
is unit test
instantiate your pup portfolio test
class to get a test case
object and then it runs the test method
inside a try except block if you got an
assertion error
if your assertion failed: then a record
the failed test
but otherwise a record to success test
so conceptually it's very simple
and this is perhaps how you might
approach the problem if you're building
on the earlier examples and trying to
solve this problem yourself
wrap each a certain a try except and
catch the assertion error in print
something out for felt
but unit test will do all this for you
art let's add some more tests so here of
course there's more conditions that we
have to test so
will also test the empty case the
portfolio should be zero
here's the buy one stock that we had
before and will also test buying to
stocks
I'm so we buy two stocks in assert the
cost is that
now you see we have a dot dot dot dot
dot dot dot is not me leaving things out
of this code example that is literally
three
dots that unit test prints once for each
test to get a dot for every past test
I'm some people who are really into test
talk about being dot addicted
the just wanna see lots not much about
because every dot means a test the past
and it tells you that ran 3.8 oz it went
okay
under the covers what happens again is
it makes a test case object
and it runs a test method and then it
makes a whole new test case object to
run the second method
and then it makes a third test case
object
to run the third method this is a very
different way of using classes usually
with classes you make one object to
represent a thing then you call many
methods on it
here gonna make a class that has many
methods each method gets called once
on a separate object from each other
every other method
but you can see this gives us test
isolation so not only do we have a try
except blocker on every test method
so the run independently but because
each one of them is running a brand new
test case
object it's very difficult to do
anything in the first test with going to
affect the outcome of the second Test
test isolation is all about making sure
that every test
is independent of every other test if
you do something in test one
and it passes and you then but its side
effect is visible in test two
how do you know the test two is really
testing when it suppose to test
so the idea is to keep the test
independent of each other and to make
sure that failure doesn't stop the next
tests from happening
so we keep them all completely isolated
in theory you should be able to have a
10,000 test test suite
and be able to run any single pass out a
bit all by itself
and have that test passed just as a
four-run along with all its nine hundred
ninety nine thousand
up however many it is brothers and
sisters
it's hard to do arithmetic on stage p
now what a spill you look like so
suppose we had a
either broken or test code or broken the
10th product code itself
when you run the cook the test still
getting seven dot will get an F
the F means failure okay so here what
we've done is we had a search in that
was wrong we had the wrong
price in there or something and it
raises an assertion error so
what happens is all the tests run you
get an F for every failed test in a
doctor every passing test
and then at the end every failed test
Prince a stack trace to get a full stack
trace
it's not printed when it fails because
that would interrupt the whole field of
dots thing
to get all the dots naps and then you
get all of the failure stack trace backs
and those trace back to very useful
because thats part the debugging clues
the hell to go and find out what product
code has failed
so this is better because the failed
tests didn't stop the other test
but it's bad because we don't actually
know exactly what field you're right we
can see that the
the cost was not seventeen 648 we don't
know what the cost actually was
well you coulda been zero it could have
been seventeen 649 we don't have that
information
so instead of using an assert statement
about units test a test case objects
could you methods called a certain equal
for instance
so here you can see that we've got our
test by one stock method
and instead using assert statement which
called a method on the test case subject
itself
and instead of using an equality
operator we pass the two values and to
assert equal
so this is kinda stylized compared to
what you're used to
but the advantage is that when the
assertion fails
they can actually print out the value it
got and the value expected
so we can see the assertion failed
because 17 600
is not equal to 17 648 and that's a clue
17-6
17 600 is the thing that went wrong week
and now we have a piece of information
that can help us diagnose and about the
problem
so the unit test module gives you a lot
of stuff assert helpers assert equal not
equal assert that this is true this is
false that that isn't bad
that this is almost equal to that for
floating-point et cetera et cetera et
cetera
are reg X matching all sorts of
interesting assertion helpers
for you to write your tests in a way
that the test runner can give you lots
information
one pro tip that BP large projects often
get to but people rarely do with the
very beginning
make your own base class to drive all
your test cases from
so here we have done is they've created
a class called portfolio test case drive
from test case
it doesn't have any test methods in
itself a test method remember starts
with test underscore
but it has this helper assert cost
people and here instead of passing into
numbers to assert equal
I can pass in a portfolio and a cost and
then this method will assert that pitot
cost is equal to the number was passed
in
and so now I've raised the level of
discourse up into my own domain instead
reading tests this yr two numbers are
equal I can write tests that assert that
the cost of a portfolio was able to
something
so here can I can say a professor cost
equal love p is equal to 0
and I still get the nice assertion
because I'm using a certain people under
the covers
and I get the a ser cost legal method
because I've derived from portfolio test
case
these base classes tend to grow over
time and especially if you're focused on
that kinda base class then you have an
opportunity to rate really good
domain-specific helpers
for instance it's very common in web
testing to say I got a response back
I want to assert both that it is a two
hundred response it successful
and that it has this word in it well why
not just have a method that says
assert word in response and do the 200
check in there as well and you have one
line in each of your tests rather than
to
because your helper method has taken on
some that domain-specific knowledge that
arm you can use over and over again
this is one of the things I noticed
about tests as people approached them as
wrote boilerplate rather than code to
engineer as if it were really code you
cared about
you're allowed to refactor tests and
move common pieces and two helpers
and functions and classes to help you
build those tests
by the way there's a third possible
outcome besides dot and F
and that is an he and he happens if any
exception other than assertion error
comes up
so here for example you see that for
some reason in our test we called this
by xx method which doesn't exist
it doesn't have that ought to be to
roast brazen act to be there that test
ended with an E
and the reason that's distinguished is a
good test should either successfully
pass
orchard fail in an assertion if it fails
and some other way
that really means that the test dropped
the ball write the test should have a
thing its hands and say
it failed err it succeeded but if
another exception happened then
something is truly wrong with your test
and you have to go and fix the test
by the way this brings up one imp are
tricky thing for beginners which is
negative testing
let's say you want to call a function
method a method and you want to it
test that it raises the exception you
expected
you can just call the function here we
are trying to call the by method with
the wrong number of arguments
so it should raise an exception if we
wanted to test that we can simply
run this test method this way because
that will actually raise the exception
will actually get an error result
because the type there'll be raised by
the by
Tigers exactly what we want to happen
but we haven't managed to a search of
the exception happens we should be
managed to make the assumption happen
unit test has a way to do this there's a
self-taught assert raises
method that you can use as a context
manager in the with statement
so that you can put the key dot byline
into the with statement
and you can assert that it raises the
type error and that with statement will
catch that exception for you
and it will check that the exception was
actually the type where the you expected
and the test will pass
let's just look while another method to
our portfolio o'clock class
we're gonna add a cell method so the
cell method is going to take a name in
some shares
and going to find that holding and its
gonna subtract that many shares from
the portfolio to test cell we're gonna
make a portfolio we're gonna put some
things in a to it we're gonna try to
upsell 50 shares a Microsoft just cost
should have gone down
I if we try to sell Microsoft but we try
to some more than we had this going to
get a value error
if we're try to sell IBM and we haven't
even bought IBM we're gonna get a value
error
but notice there's a lot of repetition
here and again just like any code that
you write if you see repetitions if you
can squinted code and you can see a
repeating pattern
that means that there's stuff that you
can re factor and the same is true of
your tests
than anything else just because you feel
like you're tester boilerplate that
doesn't mean they should be boilerplate
you should make them as expressive as
possible so we want to reef after all
that code out
likely the unit test gives us a way to
do this a class can define a set up
method and the setup method is invoked
before
each test method so they hear the setup
method is the finding a self-taught
keefe which is a portfolio object and
we're gonna buy the three stocks we
wanna buy
and then when the it within each have
our test methods we can simply access
the self-taught P that was created by
set up
so here we can't have much shorter tests
that are much more descriptive what they
want to do
what's happening under the covers is
that for each time that we create a test
case subject
we're gonna call the setup method by the
way it could fail and give you an he
alpert
but if it succeeds will call the test
method will record the failure in the
air and success as always and by the way
there's also a tear down method that
we're getting booked at the end of olive
you tests
arm to clean up whatever the setup did
we didn't need one for the previous
example because I was just creating in
memory objects but if you were creating
files on disk you clean them up in the
tear-down method
to set-up and tear-down also give us a
great way to create isolate it s the
established context they have a place to
look for
common pre and post work to live and
they give you a solution even with
failures
and as a pointer of two something of a
look at if you find yourself creating
lots and lots of big common data you
want to look into a thing called
fixtures
which is a term art in testing but it's
also the name up a Python library
p again tests are real code you're gonna
have helper functions and classes they
can become significant and by the way
you're going to write tests for your
test helpers
because you want to know if your test
toppers are working so that you can
trust that your tests are working
and you should not be sent to that that
is a good sign your project is going to
level of maturity
and a level of testing that you're
really good software engineer so pat
yourself on the back
all right let's talk for a bit about
Mark's
as I mentioned before it's really
important for your tests the test small
amounts of code the less code each test
tests
the more narrowly focused you're
debugging task will be when that test
fails
but we always build system so the
components depend on each other right
we're all used to building these towers
obstruction
so that the top level you've got all
these things are depending on right
how can you test just one component in
your code dependencies
in your code are good because you're a
little building on the work of others
but dependencies in tests are bad
because it puts more suspect code in
each test
in addition some %uh those components
might be slow and remember we want our
test to be fast
right the problem with me testing
missile launching sites is that if you
test really launches a missile that
takes a long time
you want your tests to go fast not only
that but your tests might be
unpredictable
right if you were flaky component that
isn't really the focus on your test
you want to get it out of the way search
contest the code that you do wanna test
this is the wake systems are often built
with the code under test is depending on
all these modules
which wanna do is one replace those
little combat those big component with
little pieces
that you can reduce the amount of code
in each test
lets out a little bit more to our
portfolio stock portfolios are all
interesting because stock prices go up
and down so let's add some code
into our portfolio that's gonna actually
go out and talk to finance the young
adult com
to get the actual price right now %uh
are stocks
but we can find out what the current
value of our stocks is
so this value method is very cool we can
actually buy some stock and can actually
get the current prices for IBM HP stock
and by our current value is
nothing from in about how we're gonna
test this code we cannot write an
assertion that says
I assert that IBM is trading at one
hundred dollars right now because we
don't know what I demonstrating at
that's the whole point to this code
is to get information that we don't have
how do we write a test
the test that this is working properly
right its live data
it's unpredictable that its entire point
it's slow
right it's actually pretty fast to go to
finance that you have a common get a
quote but
it's probably slower than you wanted to
be maybe it's an available maybe ya who
goes down right to try to fix the
Hartley bug you can when you test that
day
that's no good so the question should be
for your code
assuming ya who is working does my code
work
and the challenge now is how do we get
ya who had a picture
right how do we remove that dependency
on that server so that we can just be
talking about the peace accord we
actually care about
we don't wanna test all up yahoo dot com
we want to test our code
one way to do is have a fake
implementation of current price
so here's a test that we derive from
test cases always and have a method in
here called fake
current prices not remember from our
product code: current prices simply
returns a dictionary
with the keys are the names of stocks in
the values are the prices
and this is going to be a fake
implementation about the just returned
some canned data
and my setup I'm gonna make a portfolio
I'm gonna buy some stocks
and gonna actually monkey patch the
portfolio to change its current prices
method into my function
and this works this is a little odd and
if you haven't dug really deep into
Python internals you may be surprised to
see that you can just replace methods
like this on objects
but it works and now when we run our
test and we look at self that Peter
value
they will actually call self that Peter
current prices which is our method Vic
current prices which will return that
fixed dictionary
and we haven't made any network calls
and we can assert that with the values
we know it's going to be because we know
what we
what lies we told about the program
price if IBM and HP stock
so good the test results were
predictable
the bad thing is that there's some code
is untested so he refused the coverage
to all
I'm which is a way of measuring what
lines of code get executed when you run
your tests we have testing your tests
the theory of your testers at their
testing all the code you have how do you
know
you run coverage it tells you which
lines are could you haven't actually run
on your test
and here we can see the lines 53 53 356
have not been executed
and 53 356 are exactly the lines of code
we tried to snap out of the system which
were the lines of code the talk to yahoo
dot com
but this is code we wrote we need to
test this code somehow
right so we've got a good system here
but it doesn't estar code
so we can try speaking your lip that you
are eloping instead so here we do is
make a new object that's going to be a
stand in for your lip for us
and it's got a method on a cultural open
and in our set up we're going to save a
way we're gonna we're gonna jump right
into the portfolio 3
are module which is our product code:
and it has a reference to your lib
were gonna say blown away in our setup
we're gonna make instanceof are fake
your lip and monkey patch into our
product module
and now in our product module your liver
first or class in there for your liberal
open refers to a method
and when it gets called its gonna return
the data that we want
appear this your lives returning a file
like object which returns exactly the
CSV data that ya who would return
I know the details here don't worry
about the details about the CSB and all
that stuff is no we keep up with me
right now
just keep in mind the idea here is to
make an object that works exactly like
the component you don't want in your
system anymore
and put it in place so that the product
code will actually call your code infer
that code
and by the time we get down here and we
call self that Peter value
value calls our current prices module
but function our current prices function
calls you are Linda you are all open
which it thinks is a standard library
much let's talk so the network but in
fact
our fake object we put in place it gets
back that file object that parses the
CSB
makes the dictionary computes the value
and then we get what we want
and by the way at the end the tear-down
method is going to restore the real you
are limits going on monkey patch things
now over code is executed but we've got
a 100 percent test coverage oliver code
is executed the standard Libya sup
stubbed out
and we made no web access during our
test so this is really good
I'm the thing is not so great is we had
to do a lot of syrup handcrafting
engineering there there's an even better
way to do this which is a thing called
mock objects
mock objects are these amazing things
that are I call them automatic
chameleons they will act like anything
you want them to act like yours an
example where r
from Makhaya import the mock class and
make a thing called funk
which is a mock and I do all I say about
it is the return value should be the
string hello
and then I call it as if it were a
function and it returns hello
raided it just said overturn that sure
you time your tonight that's fine
and by the way the 17 the something it's
a stored them away and later I can look
at that and say funk what you called
with
that says oh I got called with 17 and
something so this is great this is
perfect for putting in place as a mock
as a fake object
and it's really easy to do because the
mock library also has a patch
decorate our patch context manager so
here we can do is we can say
to the mock library I want you to Ma
Chau your lip that you're all open
and give me the mock object that you
made and then down here what we say is
I'm gonna make you are eloping have a
return value up this
fake Yahoo data and now when I costs of
that pitot value
it goes through all over cody gets the
year old open which hits the mark which
gets the return value that we gave it
and it gets the fact that data and comes
back up and kiss me that all you want it
now by the way down here
I consider you are all open I a search
that you were called with these values
because by the way in our previous
example we didn't actually look at what
our pick up to got called with maybe
your old got broken in some retract a
ring and the actual code and
would have failed were a mock would have
succeeded here we can actually assert
that we're getting called with the world
we thought we were being called with
so now we've got mocking with no
explicit set up with enough to write
and implementation is something we
simply had to make one I did this magic
mock module
and tell it what we wanted to do
the word the more comp the the
overarching term for all these things as
test
doubles which college stunt doubles and
a movie if you take that star out and
you put in
some guy the young care about as much
and let him do that hard work
so this is very powerful and isolates
our code right we've we've
removed dependencies and focus the
morning on on smaller code it focuses
our tests
and our most speed bumps and randomness
lotta times will take this do this
approach not because it's not your
coding you want to get it out but just
cuz that code is slow
the problem is it makes your tests
fragile if you think about what we did
the only reason are mocking worked is
because we knew that the product code
was calling you or a loved that you're
all open
if someone reef actors that product code
to use the requests library instead
these tests will of L and
by the way the product code will now be
running out to yahoo dot com to take a
long time before it fills
so we'll have lost all the benefits so
the only reason we could mark the stuff
is because we knew enough about the
implementation
that we know exactly how it worked
inside and that's a dangerous situation
to be in
also by the way there's another way to
do this call dependency injection which
you should look into
so there too many things we can talk
about them all testing is a big topic
but I want to give you pointers
and plant some words in your head about
some other things add cleanup is a
method on unit test a test case subjects
which is a nicer way to do things then
tear down
doc test is another thing you hear about
the standard library only use it for
testing code that's already in your docs
if I hear about anyone have you using
doctors for anything else I'm going to
be mad because we spent a lot of time
here together
and I expect you to listen to me
nose and product tester better test
runners the unit test they have a lot of
cool features like plugins
DDT is a largely let you do data-driven
test so if you have one test method but
you wanna have 10 test cases I do it
because of these different data
it will do that for you coverage is a
really awesome
thing and you should use it selenium is
the tool you use for in browser testing
Jenkins and Travis are continuous
integration servers which a way of
having
a place that you can put your code in
ages runs your test every time you make
a change
other topics TD is running tests before
code which is very interesting
BD is aware reading tests in a way that
to do business people can perhaps writer
test to focus on external behavior
integration tests get at larger chunks
of code which is home
way of testing more realistic scenarios
in your product low testing positive
about their so much
whether you have enough our capacity
pure traffic and lots of other topics
I'm sure
so summing up how do we do we learn the
testing is complicated
it's important but it's worthy and it's
rewarding
remember the two developers we had at
the beginning the talks we want to be
happy and confident
here they are if you think testing is
hard
these drawings the two original drawings
were drawn by my 16-year-old son
if using testing is hard try getting a
16-year-old to draw you a third picture
any questions
how much time do you have questions but
five min thank you for it out
I'm what happens if financier you I
return strategies and instead have
see is be a
if ya returns a the G's up Days Inn is
to see a 30
will then that APIs change your code is
going to have to change
okay so Road SR gonna pass but the
application to fill
right exactly so that's when the
failures are the mock rate is that we're
assuming that we understand big
the interface to that mocked component
well enough that we can replace that
at that mocked component changes in this
case our product would also change
so we're gonna have to fix it either way
but yeah there could be scenarios where
it changes in a way that your product
could would've been okay with but your
testers now
mimicking the old behavior and you've
lost track that that's when the ways
that marks a really dangerous
yeah thanks for the talk
I one of the things that I've run into
is a barrier to getting is just
are into testing years getting all the
pieces together and are
in the right place so hold a blatant
self-promotion at me to get a hub repo
that house are
Python Unitel skeleton with dashes
between them you can search for the
house a bunch of camp will take code you
can take to
to get up to speed much more quickly
great so %ah
I find out super helpful to make the
burden getting into testing as small as
possible fabulous
thanks Python unit test skeleton great
II
arm so when I'm aiming for 100 percent
coverage I often have trouble with the
main method
give any advice on testing on make your
main world
first ball in in the if Mitt Dundurn Amy
caused under main
yeah you should have one line of code in
there which should be sister exit of
Maine
obsessed RB and then your main function
is now a pure function that takes a list
of arguments
and returns a status code and you can
test that right now just
attics arguments and fixer I'm return
value and in all your connection to the
external world happens net one-line
inured under named under main and it's
hard to mess up that line so you can
just leave that alone
arm that's my advice hope
thanks to questions on my part said the
dry doesn't apply to testing but
when I see my coworker just cut and
paste
when tested the next arm to go back and
something changes the test
it feels like it should be dry that's
silly yup
what I have no idea what people would
say that russian applied testing
um I testing is one of those mysterious
worlds where you will find experts and
they will
they will say things to you I'm not me I
can be trusted but they'll be other ones
who will say these mysterious things and
you will believe them because testing is
mysterious but maybe the wrong
well I mean in one case we make sense to
me is that
once you start making your test drive
your test become more complex than that
you have to test a test
yeah you do rest but testing all the way
down
yeah so I know why some time but why
they say they should be dry because some
people like tests as
serb almost documentation on how things
should work and the like a test case to
be completely self-contained
but if that means that you have the same
10 lines setting up the same
fixture that you can use in sixty tests
that just seems silly to me
okay and in the second part um a sewer
problems with my reusable test data so I
put some ovett in the setup they put
some other individual tests in a little
bit and fixtures which
I see a lot about talk about pictures an
experience that sometime so any advice
on way to be reasonable tested it's
really gonna depend on me like I said
testing Israel engineering right if it
if I were talking
you're talking about web performance
people wouldn't say to me
so what should I do to make my website
fast rate ever knows that making web
sites fast is
like serious work for you have to really
consider all these complicated factors
testings exactly the same I don't know
what your test it is are or where
up you know I can answer the question we
got to sit down and really think about
what problems are facing what the best
solutions are
in a well-tested system it's not unusual
to have more lines have tests
then you have a product and why wouldn't
that could be rich and complex in have
thorny problems that you're not sure use
of the right way you're going to go back
every factor at cetera et cetera
its engineering okay so Jason fixtures
thats I was gonna be there yeah it
sounds great hi I ever
pretty essential question and you said
that it's a a good idea to reduce some
other models that you're testing
like if you got a pair of eating into
one test do you just mean to
and just still the code somewhere else
briefly and throw a pass in there so
it'll just
know through return okays and the reason
why is because that makes your test hard
to run
right you don't have to edit your
product code before you can run your
tests you need to have an automated test
that you can
run with the push of a button some
people have it happen automatically when
they save a file in there editor
every time they their control est which
comes n like that ethanol run
like one like Jenkins are traversed your
even know even more than that
every time literally the file hits the
desk their tests run
so you want your tests ago as quickly as
possible and it automatically as
possible so when I say removing code
I mean engineer the tests so that it
reconfigures
the system and fines just the code that
it wants to test
thank you but the test the the
session runner went away so we're going
to be here all afternoon
this was a very good talk thanks very
much on I saw a recording of a talkie
gave
a few years ago also intestine yes but
in the the issue of testing
the missile silo yeah I'm what have you
learned in the last few years about
testing
what if I learned I've learned if
anything I've learned that it is even
more complicated than I thought it was
before
that as your system gets complex your
tests the test seem to get complex
faster than the system gets complex
and that the more work you can put into
attacking that problem early the better
off you're going to be
and I've learned about the downsides
love
marking thank you sure
okay I meant a great talk and thank you
for the permission to refactor test
I can't you test tests yeah try that as
soon as possible
yes I'm soul I my question
is I've been starting to unit testing
and stuff and I've been and suddenly
have been forced into dependency
injection land
hmm and so I wonder if you had any
thoughts on
make sense since when by Tom and here we
can have multiple inheritance
verses dependency injection and what the
if you have any the you know global
thoughts on that me a concept well so
dependency injection
for for people living in Canada term
means that the things you depend on like
your liberal open that we used in the
product code
instead of it being an explicit
reference to a module that we would
monkey patch by name
it would be a good thing passed in
explicitly into the portfolio class on
construction
so the portfolio class when when it was
constructed would know it when I need to
talk to the network I have been given
this thing and it will it's the thing I
used to talk the network
and that means when you do your test
since they're doing red monkey patching
you can just pass in a different thing
and you defaulted to the world on your
love and so that your real callers don't
have to think about it
um the downside it depends injection is
that your cluttering up the signatures a
few methods with all sorts of weird
stuff that starts with an underscore in
the doc says don't ever use this and
weird stuff like that that's unfortunate
and by the way it's hard to even get all
of them in a big system to 100
dependent injections that mixins I'm not
sure how you do is make sense for that
because mixins are things that give you
give you flexibility at the time you
define a class
but that means you have to define a
different product class to get
a mix in that has different dependencies
so I I guess we have to talk about how a
mixing console that maybe you can teach
me something about it because I haven't
encountered that as a way to solve the
the dependency problem for during task
love for instance you you know you have
your
your hierarchy of the thing you're doing
and then you just mix and URL live with
it
I C but its health but how do you get it
out a bit that's the thing that thing
that you've derived
from both your product code on your old
open your lip
now is the thing that you need to test
or are you driving a different thing
that mixes in something else
in which case you're creating new your
grading another right ready let another
way to do it right you could define a
new class
in your test which is your product code:
mixed in with the
our defenses yes a chance call
I'm the learned something he did I can
talk
was known over there go alright it mean
it ojai to the runner
night ASO we're at a time but I'd like
to thank you
thank you for great talk and they get
all our questions