ladies and gentlemen just a quick
reminder before we get started this
morning
if you have a device that makes annoying
noises while the rest three silence
probably save your favorite harassment
few made silent now
side please do that but you can keep
documents
not
ready
hello everyone welcome to the morning
session of the Friday of
icon 2014 here in Montreal it's great to
see so many
this word up so
ralph is presented today is here 7 icon
he's been using Python Saints 97 or 98
he's not quite sure and tries to shake
everything he learns
with the community that is given such a
great programming language chosen really
good
presentation presented to come to see
first-year
icon please welcome Brandon Roberts
well thank you welcome everybody to Pike
on up by I'm glad that y'all
made it safely and I wish safe travels
to any haven't arrived yet
I'm Grandin Road this is my talk
all your docs in a row data structures
in the standard library and beyond
I is sorta beginner to intermediate
level talk because very often
people complain that they don't hearing
talk very much later about useful data
structures
hiding in a standard library there's a
lot of them that I didn't know about
and so this tries to get them all into
one flight deck
and all into one place what are the
purpose
the stock you know in case you're
thinking walking next door to one of the
other extreme
talks its good for me to put this at the
beginning three main points
how to data structures work how are they
actually implemented in memory and why
does that make some operations efficient
and some slow what can they do
efficiently for us
and then finally I will reveal which
data structure is High Times most
dangerous in fact I will reveal it right
now in case you really want to be
listening to one of the other excellent
speakers
does the list to find out why don't have
to wait a few minutes
computer memory
is an array of byte little integers that
can have
eat binary digits and all the value from
0 to 255 by in memory
are named by sequential integers called
addresses in your processor in your
laptop or tablet
asks for by number five in gets it back
for memory
to save space all be writing by seen
rosa
8 but there's simply a continuous
sequence with no break
in the computer's hardware avram chips
are one massively parallel computing
device in your computer
which is what provide the random access
to a billion different locations without
having to wait for a billion
locations to be visited it has agreed
are I am outlines the uses
when you throw in address at your memory
chip
it makes like billion simultaneous
decisions
so that all $999 million
I locations that aren't being asked for
their data at the moment kinda put their
heads down
and don't wanna location with address
line for just all that up green
put its value on the outgoing data bus
in massively massively parallel
computation
does a do again I'll give you a billion
answers at once
that's how you can get relocations I
with equal speed
this talk will ignore a lot of the
complexity that now exist
between the chip your processor and RAM
both the question of compression the up
bus tour and is now so slow compared to
your processor
many researchers are compressing their
arrays
in memory a because the processor has
Aegis to decompress a block that gets
once it finally comes in from RAM am
going to ignore memory hierarchy but I
strongly recommend you seek
stoppard marks what your computer does
while you wait
blog post and damn lose blog post very
recently
how miss aligning your data can increase
performance 12 times
along with the sample script for you can
see that work wide why ignore those
issues in
supposed to be a fairly technical talk
because the standard library
does lists and dictionaries don't pay
attention to memory hierarchy very much
at all
and so I will follow suit RAF talking
about addresses these numbers that were
used
indexing relocations since they are
integers you can add and subtract from
one address to visit another address
that sits near it
address arithmetic then is used to
support the two fundamental
data structures at the machine level
which I will call records
and to raise a record is just when you
put them feel
some information in an agreed order in
memory
every pipe object in you your
see pipe I memory store always start
its record with eight bytes reference
count on a 64-bit machine
and eat by address of the type you know
the integer type that has all the
integer methods are the floating-point
type that has all the floating-point
methods so this
years I checked this is how I'm and is
actually laid out on my
64-bit machine at home 24 by
which only aid actually contain the
integer load
are laid out similarly but use a
different formats they can
story floating point number in their
payload in some
height on data structures are variable
here is one way of storing string it has
fix different the by fields before
then actually includes the payload the
actual string
that I want to store given
a record you retrieve the field by
adding
the record started raff with the of
offset again
very simple arithmetic involving these I
addresses
so if I wanted to get the address at the
centers type
I get the beginning at the record
address in at eight
by wanton grab the integer payload I at
sixteen
and if you know the layout of the record
a simple addition
will let you get any element in it
instantly
this is used to create a data structure
at the sea level that is also exposed by
pipeline
call struct in this is the name the
module you can import
it lets you use a little formatting
straining
II at in this case for integer integer
float
to describe the structure the you want
to build and
actually build exactly that fee
structure in memory
and less you get those three objects 29
in 20 in this case
rebuilt later abstract can be very
useful
for having a binary conversation with
the C library
were doing I O work packets require a
certain way out
on but it's typically only for very low
level operations
are the other one level om data
structure the Python exposes
is the rainy how did the work
in an array unlike a record everything
in it is same
everything in it is the same link and
sell
in a simple string if we want to get
character I
we get the address for the first
character and had iight
the address if instead it's a unique
code string
and is using four bytes per each
character then
the additional characters played a plus
for
8 12 16 and 20 and in general with an
array I didn't is
be bytes long you can instantly get any
item I
simply by not applying be times I its
random access
instant access just like your computer's
memory and so
these r us for a complimentary
approaches you know record
you add the of saps that you've
memorized
to your field to get heterogeneous data
where everything means something
different
in an array use multiplication to get to
homogeneous information each element is
the same way
both by writing on top of that memory
chips massively parallel architecture
gives you immediate access to the data
what
their is an array module inside a python
that gives you a tight similarly named
the array
and not get if you get them I
information will pack it into memory
as long as they're all same type I you
can
mile-high the elements in and pull them
back out later
very useful again for binary
conversations
libraries are I L it taxed at a very
tightly
and so python has a lot of specialized a
raise in addition to you
a plane open our res streams unit code
and number of other data structures
probably use every day are implemented
the machine level
as a simple arrangements white indexing
is fast
but accessing be items up an array
requires repeated building objects to
represent the values
if I'm going to iterate over an array of
floats you can see down there at the
bottom
icons gonna have to build a fresh load
object to let me
see each other's values to summary of
100 floats in Python
icons gonna have to build more than a
hundred load objects that were then
thrown away
all I want is some this is my the
invention have an incredibly powerful
library called
numb hi which is now the basis up nearly
all scientific and data
Python computing height andre is
they're very simple for see you right
now number higher res what you use when
you're doing
not higher res or map operations
directly between a raise from scammers
without needing to build intermediate
pipe on number
objects so if I make a ranger 5 numbers
and ask for the psalm Python only had to
allocate
single aunt to give me the answer of the
computation occur internally
and he writes been up two additional
arrays
one bill multiplication and one with
addition night there up those
even created a single pipe on number
object they happened directly
apt sea level use numb hi were similar
I library more the data orientation
of called Anders if you need to do math
on millions numbers with out meeting
millions a pipe object
there's also a replacement umpire it's
on its way
might also want to look at call plays
note that if you use pipe high as your
interpreter
it can auto-detect if you have built on
list with only cancer
look Senate and might if it wants
substitute a faster rate for it
up icon itself now
now work and sir have it here
it can't use rar records a raise for
mister your data structures
because it's a dynamic language where
everything is an object and we're not
required to build lists where everything
is the same supply palms mean data
structures
are gonna general-purpose the need to be
capable
holding any object I the two people for
example which will start with
I can throw in float strings into it
without hearing how big they are
how are those three objects going to yet
when they're
up different sizes how am I going to
find them in memory of their
each different way array address now
that we looked at a few minutes ago
which is very fast depends on
every elements be same number of bytes
long how's this going to work
we all remember David wheeler one said
all problems in computer science can be
solved
by another Obama indirection so Eagle
added
a triple does not store your objects in
line in the data structure
it has an array out headdresses instead
tell a critical book in memory for each
of the objects
that you've stored this is indirection
when you store an address rather than a
thing itself
you can say to your friends IQ's hike on
the language that gives you data
structures
without any of the actual take all of
pythons general purpose data structures
will see
shaft store addresses and beef the
objects of somewhere else
this means that moving an item in one of
these data structures
only means copying an address your
actual
floats are strings never have to get
moved around which is sufficient
it means that there's only one copy of
an object regardless of how many times
it appears in a tubal
yesterday if you keep ur using that
string it's just the address that's
getting copy
each new data structure some given the
way out
the tubal we saw grabbing it linked or
grabbing an item
is just a single patch and so
arm and there is by the way in the
collections module
be named to people you want something
with the efficient storage a tubal
but that gives you something more
convenient than integer indexes for
accessing it items
two balls are read-only a sequence
objects
zero-based simplest pipelines
general purpose data structures and
now it because a triple knows its link
it can do pounds checking
might be important to you someday
the next data structure up is called the
list lesser like triples but they're
interesting
because they can grow and the problem is
that once you've allocated
your esten probably put some other
objects subsequent to it in memory
its India it has data already allocated
in both sides a bit
in that radio your computer's memory and
it would now need to move it needs to
grow by another element
because there's no extra room well you
know there is this guy
maybe because by the way to beating you
can't easily move the last
is all of the other data structures and
names reference it
are just hold its address so if you move
it they won't be able to find it anymore
so there's this guy name David wheeler
and he once said
that all problems in computer science
can be solved
by another level of indirection so
that's what the list does
all it whole is it from link the science
its storage and be address a block where
it puts the
real addresses that then point to your
list items
so two levels of indirection can solve
the problems one
level does not now white at that list
bring it up on the screen here again
have an extra work for what
a-listers is is a twink 3 white wires
Python wasted space by having a blank
element
the answer is that if a python list
reserved no extra room
the every single hand you did choir
reallocation
reallocation is expensive each I can
address
have to be copied to its new home in
your reallocate to a new free area
memory Surrey allocation every append
would add up
if at the second element I have to copy
the first address
if at the third element I had to copy
the first and seconds address
the you concede a link the chaff West 10
10 depends would cost $45 address copies
a thousand element list would require
happened million
operations and E know again element last
would require half trillion copies
at that address in memory this is my
standard by the way
thousand and million pot experiment that
I do to check with a mild rhythms are
going to slow down
when their data gets pic I think what's
the cost doing
this operation thousand times and a
million times
if the answer growth zeros at twice the
rate
up the question I lose
because the trail again if he bad bad
number
and in general as you watch what were
you how many operations would you do
with a thousand and how many
million objects your computer science
friends tell you that there are
remains for what happens if additional
three zeros
gets the time 3 0's 40 rose
or the very horrible 6 extra zeros
why is a trillion horrible a million
seconds
as an analogy is twelve days icon from
set up to tear down
out million seconds it billion
seconds is 31 years there are people in
this room
who have not yet left billion seconds
a trillion seconds its 31,000
680 eight years if a true if you
at if it really can seconds ago
you went to the Bering Strait
where dress warmly
you would be waiting 20 thousand years
before the first band hunter-gatherers
would walk past you
from Asia and become the first humans to
enter
the new world that's how long a trillion
years cell has the best get out of this
problem
and append on a whole left doesn't just
at one fly
it at several and the list goes through
a series up expanding
sizes a designing a data structure in
this way is called amortization because
it spreads the cost
reallocation over a lot of time just
like a mortgage dust for a loan
and so if you build a thousand a million
or billion element list
you the number free allocations stays
under control
and national notice the number address
copies %uh
only grows by about the number it zeroes
you're adding to the site secure data
set
that's very good performance amortized
cost
do tend to be bumpy when you add the 990
first item
the West is gonna jump up to 1120 flocks
and
particular tend to be a bit slow the
list gets copied
new on your location but in return the
next 130 items get appended
at no additional cost that's called
amortization
the Python last than illustrates a trade
off to save time and not have to do a
trillion
things we have to waste space in almost
every one of our list
fact that there'll be some unused slots
at the end this is the classics
speed versus space trade-off all of
Computer Science imposes on us
and requires us to think through hype on
left I did a little measuring on average
use about 94 percent after slot
their slots so they're consuming 6
percent more space
in order to be very fairy fast
will be calling your time in computer
science so why did I say
West is pipe bombs must
dangerous data structure it's because I
think
in the new programmers mind they tend to
look at whether an operation they're
doing
involves one item were many here since
single item operations on a West
here are some several item operations on
a list and it makes sense to us that if
we have
on eat character uplifting do something
to ollie
characters at all take about eight times
as long as one character
last problem
some up single item operations have to
touch
every single item in the list with how
the ninth program are being aware of
this
if you in to the list for example very
fast
if instead you insert at the beginning
you'll be waiting the Bering Strait
420 thousand years
reading for your algorithm to finish
if you pop from the end of a lift very
quick because that's where it's built to
ingest
P pop from the beginning the address at
every
other item has to be shifted over one
fly every time you do it
are that's why I often see people trying
programming for the first time
what is it the items in reverse order
like this and wonder why a simple
a few thousand items you know take 18
minutes or something
this is how we do it idiomatic Python
instead
to avoid that penalty the left is played
on
most dangerous data structure if your
friend comes to you and says I
started burning hike by and on
you know my program is just sitting
there waiting for the next ice age
look and see if they're using a blast
slicing desserts brief mention because
the slicing operation
a tight can choose whether it wants to
copy the data
were generated view normally in Python
with
I we use life an entirely new list is
created
but that's expensive and that annoys
both scientists with lots of data
and data scientists answer no
high and pamper fleiss's are simple
Venus copy no data
there like a little be classed when you
ask for element 50
really goes and grabs element 450 if the
original sequence
therefore they're very fast and very
efficient
all right now we come to protect which I
won't give a lot of detail on because
%uh the talk I did earlier
I'll just say that while just doesn't
give you any choice
names they're going to be integers the
dictionary that's you
shoes the keys you want to look up data
with behind each dictionary to implement
this
is an array because that's the one thing
the computer does efficiently
in which keys are stored it integer
index
that built from something called the
keys hash value
so that translators translates worse
from something complicated
key to something simple an integer so
each slot
the dictionary has to keep both the key
to remember what it was
and without you see my icon 2010 talk to
Mike
dictionary for colorfully illustrated
into higher
guy how the dictionary works at
amortized cost
I will say here only that it grows
because I know I should be with with
to worry about this it grows by doubling
or quadrupling its size
so the resize costs are amortized as
they are with the list
resizes it two-thirds full so there
won't be too many hash collisions
and therefore it's only ever one-third
to two-thirds
fall art the slots in your dictionary
at least one-third of them are empty at
any given time
this classic speed versus pace trade-off
if you want to get to a dictionary
item instantly you've got to get
something up in space is what we give up
in Python
given a key addict hashes it usually
jump right to it slot
of dictionary operations are asked and
therefore safer beginning programmers
takes one you did time to get one
element in units of time to get all of
them
very obvious and simple and well-behaved
common tasks that we do
are joining counting grouping whenever
we have an order dated
we gonna get associate instantly
incorrectly
and because this is such a common
pattern you'll find in the collections
module
a default decked so that you can just
for example append
to wiki without even worrying about
whether you put almost there yet
you can at the default pic to put your
left there just in time for you to
him to the right when they're created
and a sweet group these
animals by there mother mammal a reptile
I their is because it's so comment
do that with integers to count there's a
counter class that you can give it a
phrase
will tell you the most common letters
you can get a list it'll tell you the
most common items
remember you can build compound
dictionary
he's with the two people if a simple
integer left is in its sophisticated
enough key for you
if T order at the items doesn't matter
same looking over a
wat projects to see what languages tend
to be used together
use a frozen set because those are not
sensitive to order
or coursework turkeys before turning
them into two pools but
I prefer sets because the deck to signs
each key to an array index by a hash get
always forgets its order eatery in
arbitrary order
nasty see the list in Dec to kind of the
opposite to each other
Booklist only does order task really
passed in well
the dictionary only maintains the
association and throws out the order
to data structures two superpowers what
if you want both
then their isn't ordered decked in the
standard library
you'll find it in the collections module
and you iterate later
remembers the order that the keys were
added in if you need that
at great for things like header fields
Jason data that you want print back
out in the same order later that it came
in
there is a set built into Python it's
just a dictionary with only keys but no
values
and get support all upbeat set
operations you might have learned in
math class at very high speed
very obvious very little danger
classes I should mention are by default
implemented with the dictionary
each attribute is a key in a hidden
dictionary but you can turn it into a
record
you can turn it in one of those really
efficient data structures I showed you
at the beginning
by pre specifying slot to let you pick
that up in the documentation
if you want to know how to have millions
of objects that are stored a bit more
efficiently
well those are the main data structures
those
are workhorses those are what we use
what's left
a few other little topics all touch on
here
first dictionaries Leicester great for
grabbing one thing
or iterating over all the things but
what if you want to fetch
Ranger things you can sort
a list or array in use the bisect module
you can say let's say I want all the
numbers between three and four
and it doesn't really efficient binary
search
at narrowing in very quickly on where
that range begins and ends
so that you can pull it out of your
lester earl Ray
sometimes we want to list that can be
modified both ends instead only the
right
there is he Dec built in the collections
module
that instead of just supporting a
pending pop at the right
and which by the way kids you what's
called stack
which is a very natural way organized
tasks
inside half you need to do Dec
lets you modify both hands with an
append
and in a pan left a pop and a pop
laughed and since you can put items in
one hand
and take them out the other very
efficiently is the data structures
secretly behind the Q which is a Dec
with ox on it so that your threads can
all cooperate
send data or messages to each other
we can you do a popularity contest your
lot from what elements and you trust
deed the top ten are the top 100 with
out the expensive sorting the entire
sequence
their is a heap cue that lets you fetch
the top
in Afghan t getting items in only when
your time
on TNN om you just get some sequence
you keep a fire it does a little like um
tournament elimination contest to it
get them ranked into tears %uh more and
last sorted
I information and then can pop and push
very very quickly and the II
model goes ahead and get you in and
largest and smallest callable
that does all of those steps for you to
get that
100 biggest objects without having to
sort all million items in your range
there's a priority cue also I believe in
the queue module
which is a heap cue with locks so that
threats can cooperate
on might work highest work where the
work is labeled with priorities that
make some items come of up that cue
earlier
and others there's also a scheduler
module
uses the cue you can get items on your
calendar
or events on your server that need to
take place and it'll tell you how long
to wait until the next one
triggers using again this really
efficient PQ
cell where all of the old fashioned data
structures
all the ones you read about Donald can
use book 3
linked with doubly linked list in all
the trees
my suggestion is this you don't see them
Python code
because they make very little sense when
our data structures
no longer campaign data but only
addresses you see back in the old days
you would go bombing
left by actually putting the links in
with your dad
which wasn't that big a deal what cost
one extra link when you have to speak
record-setting there but in Python where
everything is an object relinquished
only consists of another address
together with the links it's much more
efficient to just have a list and put
the address is
altogether both Dec Andy
work decked do secretly have EE linked
with inside
for their accounting but all the other
linked with you're really using in
production
are hidden in your memory allocation
player since you're I
objects are already allocated by Malik
inside at the secret linked list
it's just kind of redundant to try to do
memory management
all over again by your own level
modeling left
trees only really exist where our data
is tree shaped
like my messages inside another my
messages
X in elements inside others all the old
traditional uses trees
and this is the last thing I'll say
trees do besides representing tree shape
data
they are used very often to represent
sequential data
that's constantly changing has stuff
coming in and out
needs to be kept in order we have
outsourced
trees to our data persistence layer to
our databases
they all have trees inside and for
indexing
the data systems have your own
long-running I keep a data structure
around in RAM for weeks
and meet the maintenance that it really
gives it but our programs today
tend to be episodic concerned with a few
an update
a report which turns us towards a
functional programming style
that involves quick right wants
throwaway data structures that we create
with comprehension
we don't very often maintain a data
structure you don't very often
keep a list around keep modifying it all
day long to keep in shape we need
with outsource that to our storage layer
its
some simple data-centric how'd
functional code is indeed the future
as Uncle Bob Martin Gary Bernhardt
recently suggest
see my eye 2013 talk between
architecture in Python
then simple elegant lists and
dictionaries
are exactly the data structures will be
taking us there
thank you very much
alas there's no time for questions of
even hallway
please thank Brandon again right reagan
agenda 10 minutes we'll be back
it's a half past for next talk see you
then