good afternoon hike on and is a couple
announcement before we get started here
am just like to remind
auction winners to pick up their
winnings ago right down to the
registration desk now
if you won an auction last night and I
would like to mention the sprints
will be holding developments prints am
from tomorrow onwards anybody wants to
contribute to the
live in the north as acceptor I am
please stick around for messages
after their lightning towards an
introduction to the springs and if you'd
like to lead a sprint
these prepare a short twenty seconds
only
description your Sprint I am and be
prepared to give that after the
lightning talks
okay and I would like to present hi new
crossing
and he's gonna tell us the PostgreSQL a
really is web-scale
smiley face
so
hello nice to be here last talks I think
in this conference time
going to talk about skating post sir
hearst how we what the peace how was
stated that Skype
what your ways to scale it cannot be
unseen
and also I have
tight pussy some more stuff about using
from Pike so why me to go already cost
in some places fortunately creko
already year spoke about some things
I had prepared so I can skip over these
really cost
and so let's get started so
her undercutting ok
your con the word I
by feels her since about version 1 maybe
edited before post she also sings
course before it to us SQL
it someplace very ok suppose cuz
she was telling was called post players
sorry essentially a new SQL database
here though it was already a friend
relational database
your swat at Pacha
contributor do both high command post
Chris
both her small amounts of Michael been
I Ross first PBA and they have is
architected Skype
it's the newspaper had
fortnight most risk consultant second
part on
secular say say company that the bros
most largest number of top space cadet
up
got social support 2013 some
high-level help them come to us and they
are so
think the code
investment company of this tone and
holding yes Skype so
they have some very interesting stuff
night help them
evaluated I have also
to books under PostgreSQL it'd
who okay I see that they're
under echoes sure what to do about it
one of them is have a close guess good
administration
Ohio together simon rex police their
hit KO for second car truck or so away
with this
both discussed several programming a
book which
physically tells you how to write stuff
insight
both Tesco server that turns your see
B&B just let it be a python
see the art auction skating and so on
so what this python
okay actually know what that by Tony so
I'll going to bed
but its really I sent universal language
is
for almost ever Fink what is no escape
know it's girl is usually yes mostly
it's a storage
some thanks it has some language in it
it can be a secret keeper Justo riches
the structure values Press databases
distributed
she's some do you use
it's good so already somewhat
for what I am discredit late skating
can also lets the West Center not
the only esker so
why people used the West its pissed it's
simple to
implement its quite often the
really a great variation other team that
lets use fights for Speed
which works small-scale and doesn't work
very well
large-scale now they somehow less girls
adroit
to play large
your city's it such a cheap to get
started
see for the initial development and 80s
skoo storage layer what a pink shirt
no SQL usually sacrifices compared to
we'll see Korea
database test the that
for be things that databases offer
relational databases are Tommy at the
message the consistency
isolation and durability at the mission
it means
that everything guy that happens
at once so does it happen doors most of
the West but they did have some form of
it quite often now
most often it's done just by looking
ever in the collection
and solar you can
happy daughter cell and enter you should
at least have a single
statement told back some so texan's
but again have multiple come ons
multiple updates on
back together if you didn't like them
consistency is something that
most know it's good that the device is
by definition don't have
they are she must resolve that was
nothing to be consistent with isolation
again which means that on bus I the sea
ever seem to be intersection or see
nothing
again quite closely
paid at the Mississippi and meeting that
course
your door he was blocking and
usually having by X doing evasion
everyplace database for the duration for
time
and the durability the many
year he newest the database is actually
replaced by your application
make tend to have some kind of local job
elite day
but day usually BC limited
quite slow passionate I this week but
in my date every few seconds already
for some type of like the head low
usual again not not to any cost what
this post
this the database I most to work where
then haven't allowed buscas curly hair
to relational database management system
that the changes
it has been in development almost thirty
years
last twenty years
search an open source project very
active community
its from the
the beginning it has had a highly
concurrent design
and it asks for donations
and it has also and she's done to this
girl language implementation
it's not ever cheat cell and if we want
to get
already to some
sacrifices for PostgreSQL Ben
there are things that they can switch
off all it without
at the mission the always fun
you'll on comet
Hall of the work or it never happened
said
for example of the crash some of your
work the city sums not
you can do well consistency
you can eat out point should be
XQ in Orlando the checks
Hill don't want any they protect
on the models and you can use chase next
reached or
so you have toward freedom to store what
they like to know that the bases
isolation is always on again other
paralyzed
sconce he your Hoffman work today either
by the sea or or nothing but depends
which of
for durability in many levels
Japan your subsequent scummy which means
that you have a few milliseconds self
Taylor window express happens right
after you did call me
you may lose some data or
for much more speed
and their but do with the
at you're gonna lose or the date though
you can use on low papers which means
that the day
papers are written only once there are
no guarantees that day
will be there after cash but under
normal operations
the the although I was just trying and
also follow orders
no mentors
so Bush cassius much more than a story
slayer
but it has very good stories layer been
and a penalty as a separate storage if
you so wish
if you want to like Joe applications in
that to become the West Coast night
and which will usually be said to have
to create
the complex parts like locking for and
comprise a controller
and and joins there and
more lot of complex stuff no application
it easyer there it would be her big hard
cock
but there sometimes it's support for
scalability
issue and their publisher or moving
from an existing no SQL
database to post this then you can start
exactly as to where I'm
mortal mall perform on mall consistent
way slater
I did some tests compare memcached
radius
PostgreSQL but the the
top lines care all
men has set records they are this
command Kasey Kahne consistent
ABC's not non-durable Medicis kind of
two-electron
their its doors at state tower
every few second several tens of seconds
and it gets forms like this this post
discuss
repair for months basis PostgreSQL
mister quite stable write performance
not favor doable eighth under our sink
order
which means that tomatoes a few
milliseconds
if I would have been almost there non
log table the same
I guess their performance would be I
don't care
and these two planes are among the DB
again this maybe
very with additional nobody be because
it's a single
E database Mongo DB
what the Easter present at the their
lowest line
would cease their durable storage Mongo
DB
which is summer around here unit 64
I'll clients sit still only a few
thousands
Russ her both processes for the house ok
inserts were all the sex and gets a
second tape she says
good primary key year
we won running backs NB and Jason
Baker so
familiar Craig already went over these
her all kinds of
called and technical features a post gus
has a piece rarely
it doesn't act former not till my tester
just a database a kind we define
everything
you can
entrance how it works everywhere
and when your sink papi pipe n you can
ne'er
or so do weight BC
or like things for example
it's not very hard do like the smaller
paying let's chill replace your
select a year
some meta programming and Bender
can make papers look like they wear
are 80 or collections of for
classes policy collections of rose a
very small but now let's get the scaling
which we
will tear have door have time to talk
about
anyway at the old so what they're for
once expected to grew
hun it happened about the same time s
Amazon and Google develop their large
database solutions
except that we did on-base done post
Chris
tested or somebody cascading speak
binary
functionality at some point this doesn't
work any more than just our shot the
papers especially
if you have like most adults like we had
Skype
are but the beasts things that way more
than ninety percent right
because they are seldom read only when
you go to any water
your computer other way all
all our time they're just 3.2 and wants
you will have gone to shot think you can
on
do lots of your original casey ten
people aboard water-related 8.2
tapes Hartzell you still have
consistency inside the charger can write
simple SQL
simple programs in other languages still
work close to the Baker
and we wear able to no basically
your maintaining from clients
site the US Equal had a single big
database
butter and their we had their
one of their way through the dross coded
all access to their
tables or to the databases as functions
which means that the clients that I saw
or so any papers
visual contact the supplier usually
ordered you Miller paper Texas store to
see our
functions in which
here and do
would basically just their which we need
to call another database
spend a year yours Pitre like W
the used take a PT connected to other
database query their
it on nurse red
to treat me seconds so daughter
performance problem and their
ok and then ok
that the first one was for vertical
scaling limit for example just big door
look at some place a call
from another database at
horizontal scaling States took whether
Polanski
tapered paper missing that they can
raise anymore
there we started selecting
fractured database connection inside the
function
and where there and for Easter
after under often enough we
maybe the special language which
basically the source code about
where to run the function and
we had two iterations of it first of its
kind of
one big block of code then
mockery voted speak out
be a proxy connection for our and and
PO Box Hill and was proper cook
and after that almost everything
get Skype us week in shot at Manor
you have checked it's a function written
in
I that the ambitious girl Plesk
sometimes be a fighter on the shots and
then how the talks
functions on many proxy machines which
can be the same machines this
service as the database to a concert by
can be separate machines and then
you connect to any point and they'll get
the data from was actually stored
with ca
basically like export function at the
preschool
their
hearses with a security source a good
for me
dance bet really tree the separation of
interfaces
you need to pick something you don't
need to shut down plants it just
redefine
function glance continuous before we
you don't need to settle down type
upgrades
on the way to Bayside of course need to
test and also a shiney
to some kind of peace to meditation at
the dole database
vanity easy to add two functions and
decir the lesser found out the man
it was all too easy to skate because to
easily by
developing a language be a proxy and
then
stop Inc using it forever
ok ok
and we've heard from problem with your
punches being too limited we initially
let our web developers and
or to apply their own functions and only
went
product was deployed then it went to be
BK stuff
forward pics stuff to make more
performant need
ok and the court thing care about the be
a toxic skies harding key step in the
end we still can
like for go with that
only once in one accessing the database
can those tough told many many related
papers
it or consistent its Texas controlled
the tests for your AC guarantees there
and the show
to running from place and then you can
might be silly decorate their cell that
the basic
you know go and just poor
the database functions as if notable
attractions
sees or so I have done it a few times
it's not hard its just look up our the
code is work
it's done here is a sample how
be a proxy works it can
just proxy course and be for an extinct
another database
did also can select the database
based on charting say has text of your
surname
or select job and get closest database
already basically can be anything you
can also have function that
identical Nexus think based on on the
they have time and for example if you
want to take some
mustered a touchdown for night good
Alexis still read on a database is that
sometimes
it's easy to set up
fuel tree functions partitioning
function
which basically returns the power of two
next remix cluster vision functions
which is the one that's always consulted
and exchanges
then the partition function board again
and cashed
and there is also possibly to the parlor
have across the Conficker rate from
function their
first addition function troll two
partitions
can be your and usually more than 20
various class division function
basically of they have changed by
stationing just
redefine this function to attend another
number it must be kept on
last month so that configuration would
be reloaded and if you want to set some
options
news said options an owl
because this this function know the
cluster name your toes
then you can easily Chester seder
yours cluster your service on has tix
no surname and when your money
to the end function get scored in the
light shot
does whatever the fight to and then it
comes back
and their mother fast to networks
basic stuff hope at Sir
usually less than a second to the hell
country of
of the choir so
before us how you already have a skate
database whole we
scaling heater day or would be fine
more then more shots in the beginning
thank you have actually met critical she
took his
databases first developed break lotion
up
each then we need to move
you'll move only sure shot
and separate from to for politicians in
a few steps
this is how you end up and basically
babys actually moving just under budget
replication
the to really develop these say in the
back to Skype Dorsett scored
lungfish which is name of
to your left hand from in Estonian to
this book
because everything both Chris has his
somehow related to defense and
basically said that occasion and then
wat how it takes
how long it takes and then you have some
pic
so but Bishop don't have function
interface then there is a nice
think info stress for point data purpose
basically you can invite function
additionally see what's presents
tapering shapes to post Chris and
the some nice people have written to
record multi-colour
which led to the sea pipe so we'll
like the pika class and expose s
papered posts it comes 15
no Escala comey TS yet I tasted funny
they develop a sexist I'm at to assess
help the samples that expose
cooperman mailbox as
tapered so you can query them
from database for shopping
Europe for anything to basically the
right
close in Payson there
and then expose their make the store
that database
that Bush Chris pastor Craig extension
multi-core
page you don't need to talk it because
it didn't exist
from Mexico they don't create the point
they cover
her and then you'll create the point
table using
its wrapper and then you can just query
from me
that's my sister like this class has a
few functions
issue 3 only then you need only accepted
method which esquire is headquartered
columns column to column name squalid
cell actually
day XXXL ColumnName operator and value
you can use the story me told Mike they
title
week that how much they don't get from
external stuff
external database in this case I am
doing again
think very similar to be a proxy
physical a select their
based on for on the radio coral
and then directed only rose that been
and then from his petition I dent does
that they needed their
say fights hit update DB you have or so
to section controlled
at the end of detection kantle commit or
rollback
recommit if you want to do two-phase
commit so
the Pacey basic blocks out there
and the nice thing going they seized
kind basic different from BL Python
be sexually Kendall Street at the
financially stable and then select ok.
hearst and those from me and it doesn't
blow up database
stars the L fighter
said action okay or
most type
okay we do have three or four minutes
for questions
no takers okay thank you very much I
know way
me