I really want
sore neck stock will be so you want to
build an API
by megan's fear if you have any
questions after the talk please use a
microphone up front other
I have Gabriel Pratt lunch tickets so if
you're gay
releasing after the talk thanks please
give making a warm welcome
hi everybody
let's get started I magnin fear
and I'm currently living in San
Francisco California am a software
engineer and most recently I've been
building a company with my husband
where and I became obsessed with API
design and implementation
this is technically my first icon and
I'm really excited to share with you all
hopefully everyone in this room has seen
the movie good burger
or the sock is gonna be a bunch of
nonsense with some API information
on the side so you want to build an API
huh well this sounds like a good idea
an army moniker the creator a flask says
if you're not building an API
you're doing it wrong so let's get
started what we're really going to talk
about today is a Web API using the rest
protocol we're going to look at the best
practices in designing a web
API and the patterns and flask we may
use to get there
and will actually be creating
to API's as you're likely building a
RESTful API for your JavaScript client
you're also building your own pipe on
API for how you want to code it
we are doing that by leveraging patterns
because no one framework
has everything you need see at that
to API's leave from but first
where to best practices come from
they come from the same good artists
copy
and great artists steal and this quote
from Steve Jobs
actually explains that popular picasso
CWA ultimately
it comes down to taste it comes down to
trying to expose yourself
to the best things that humans have done
and then try to bring those things
into what you are doing and where do
patterns come from
research for me this was a favor
trying to find out how things are
currently done if you don't know what
current solutions are
how do you even know that you need to
build a new one as developers we value
laziness first
why do something that has already been
done so you should know what other API's
are out there
and how to use them learn how other
people do rest
and flask and stretch the imagination to
guess at what people would try to build
using API
this is kinda like the old adage have
am knowing the rules before you can
break them
but patterns also come from
way the developers who are smarter than
you and me
basically learned a lot from everyone
else learn from these people
and you too overcome leave the in smart
one day
this is why there are so many frameworks
and forks
everyone wants to be lazy but everyone
is lazy and their own way
so in the end
choose your own flavor and your own set
of tools may be really want your API to
be written and go or something
but you're all here so I assume you love
Python as much as idea
developers in patterns are subjective
decide what is important to you
decide how you want to be lazy
try all the tools sample all the things
it is only through this process the
you'll find what tastes right
but you must design DUI 1st
I think it was Kenneth rates he said
right the read me first
this talk isn't going to make all the
problems in a current implementation
i've a web API disappear
but it will help you build better ones
going forward and create documentation
that is intuitive and easy to understand
right off the bat and this is certainly
that
best practice and helps to not make
mistakes to be in a
otherwise your documentation and code
might look like this:
bad burgers spaghetti code it's
important to stay organized
but wait what is a Web API I haven't
really said that
yet its rest
rest a representational state transfer
as described by Ray feelings
dissertation
which is still kinda the definitive
resource on the topic
is the architectural style an API
consisting of a handful of key elements
including data and then our actions we
can make with that data
the first important part everest I'll
webservice
is a buncha resources exposes you can't
see the resource
it doesn't actually exist you just have
to trust that it does
it is the intended conceptual target a
hypertext reference
your API does not near your database so
far good burger API we might have
customers
menu items and burgers but our party
menu items
resources represent the idea of things
that will generally be a part of your
API which we can reasonably assume
will be everything that I just mention
next will be the binding and identify
rare the other resources
those resources are exposed a resource
identifiers
this is the first thing to design take
for example
the good burger dot com address which
represents our base URL
that we can now build out using resource
identifiers
this comes down to naming use your words
I manson
mentioned that we probably have a
burgers resource which you want to be
consistent clear throughout your API
another example would be how
people popularly have Flash users
resource identifiers
where we have burgers currently but I
think person in that case not users much
more clear
they are users to everyone else a.m.
or their users to you but everyone out
there percent
be human and respect the people that use
your service this is an example of
something that's just my opinion my
personal flavor but once I've chosen in
I have to stick with it so use your
words to describe things but I
understand that you yourself may not
know what they are
at first something card and be concrete
now we will look at some other patterns
in which we apply these best practices
in code
one of the first things you need to make
a decision on is what kinda routes years
the regular old definition based fears
fairly simple
and the apt out route here you would
clearly define HTTP it
HTTP method you wish to perform an
action on our burgers restores
and what resource identifiers are your
I'll we can access the data
but this can get a little unwieldy when
you're defining multiple methods
and resources along the way
another pattern if class-based years are
pluggable beers as class refers to them
which have the built-in method you
allowing you to create a single class a
very sorry
menu API in this case which would be a
classic definitions for each of the HTT
P methods to be used on the resource
finally
kill you add URL role to create the
resource identifiers
you still have to register each one but
this is a little better because it's
more expensive one allows you to use
some the core functions and fast
including decorators
and things like that
but neither these options was exactly
what we were looking for
so we created restyle by restyling these
patterns in code
to consolidate them cleverly named
resource top identifiers because this is
literally what it is
they identify rare representing
specifically
resource
another thing you're going to run into
is consolidation and separation and
services
don't create latency and packet
behavioral that with httpd
redirect make smart decisions decisions
up front so you don't mess with your
developers
avoid collisions between your variety of
services
prefixing is best practice so here are
prefixed with
API that good burger dot com slash
beggars
it can help you test different versions
of your API among other things
so mention versioning best practices for
versioning
means no dots use v1 not be dot line
is major versions only view 19 V 1.1
don't get overly creative in naming
versions it's basically a more granular
version of what you're doing with
prefect thing or creating a sub-domain
you can move on to a new API and still
provide support for an old one
but these 57 clear when it comes to
deprecation policies
after releasing a new API
so this pattern shows hard coating the
version directly into the URL
but this makes it too hard had to change
cheap versions more like a variable and
keep the route short
encode
you can do incurred with flask
blueprints which make it easy to say
about
different versions for different
resources doing it in a blueprint will
allow you to change it
in one place with friends can be a
little confusing
am but I have a pretty simple blog
percent on my blog
input button here but and against iraq
on
if ed here can save the day it good
burger you can't you
you'll eventually have a complete
resource identifiers
head with his mountain burgers is a
metaphor for all the exploration you
should do
to find your way in building thing
sometimes experimenting with surprise
you
next you'll be concerned with how you're
going to deliver all this information
all the burgers tear and user ill be
through what is referred to
as a representation feeling says
other commonly a bit less precise names
for representation include
document file and HTTP message id
entity instance or variant which
basically means it's what you use is
going to see
again use your words naming and
representations relates to a schema
which allows you to make decisions about
renaming elements of your database
models
grouping data and a logical manner for
the elements in the burger make
consistent
the name have the burger and its
ingredients which you could extend or
remove
based upon an the table burger that
someone so here we have a bye in
to patti is and sauce for a
double-double
let's see how the folks in code this is
a template for the representation from
code
you can create public and private
schemas which allow the data a PI to
scale beyond that if your data if
this involves creating logical chunks of
data to talk about data Alamance
a little tip don't force your users to
live with the mistakes
you made before you knew how to name
things properly in your data if
for the show that says code name in the
database
which isn't as clear as burger name
which is an
the public scheme
next show airs for humans if something
goes wrong when your API makes a request
status codes and messages will be your
friend some going to Heather
which we will talk about a moment and
showing airs for code
and some going the response body showing
areas for humans
I'll show you what to do and what not to
do
first the is a real error messages
they're useless give the developer no
information
bailing out sorry did wTF just happened
that something you might expect to hear
when you see this
but you want their messages thats patch
here can understand
don't confuse him he might just be the
bug
first batch be you want error messages
whatever both
and provide much more information better
airs
explain the problem that is actually
happening
metadata is another important aspect of
our API
metadata is what allows rest to be self
descriptive
returning raw data to the recipient
along with metadata
allows the recipient to work with the
dead as they see fit
so use format feeling recommend for
conversion a resource into a
standardized format based upon the
capabilities
the recipient well not necessarily
supplying multiple formats
and some believe ambles bus far I V is
Jay fun but there are others like XML
an and use relationships
relationships our source links that may
point to the rock format the data
in cases where it may have been
converted
alternates may indicate other forms and
rich data may be transformed
for example intact from our txt files
otherwise
control that a control data is data
relevant to the transaction
have as you're making it describing your
ability to use the data at a certain
point in time
it can be used for parameter as request
and override default behavior
but it is not the resource
representation are metadata
basically you're just telling your user
yes you can use this now
no this isn't available to you right now
headers evolve things you need to
familiarize yourself with for an API
headers are extremely important HTTP
headers
me hold the bulk of the meta-data and
control that an act as a chance for a
layer
relaying information either partially in
the case of status codes
for computers an error messages for
humans
are completely in the case of
authentication cache-control:
what you may wanna but what you might
not need their Punia patterns to deal
with these headers are containers
one of the most popular being the
decorator however
the deeper you get into the
specifications have headers the quicker
you realize you're modifying the header
in so many places it's hard to keep
track
it's also almost impossible to control
order they are appended in
and difficult to very responses based
upon HTTP method
is further requests which is correct
so if you decide to go out in earlier on
solution for better decorating
consider this pattern it is useful if
you want a nicer way to handle hatter's
it allows for the Hatters to be ordered
and can star the same key multiple times
and you can attach her at all the haters
just before you dispatch
a response so this is kinda using a
dictionary
lists less structure to at
cache-control: you might also consider
cashing API requests
which would also go into the header to
help load balancer API
so refrigerate after opening cuz you
wanna save it for later
okay wrong after here but there are a
few things I'd like to mention before
you walk out and go build your own API
rate-limiting goes into the header let
your customers know where they stand by
telling them how many API calls they can
reasonably make within a set of
constraints
paid or otherwise this will help you
detect problems with your API
quickly if someone is trying to abuse it
which can happen
even if you're not a public-facing API
so beware
and please please put a heavy emphasis
on security fate
for your API if you're really so lazy
you don't wanna bother at this
please don't make my heart Leander
anyone else live because they're
API services out there that will handle
authentication for you
but really just put some code in the
header to get authentication up and
running
quickly
something made I'm not really going to
expand upon here regarding our own
implementation
have restyle is that we've considered
open source in the API
am that's a lot of work so if there's
demand
will do it because we bout to share
secret sauce with you
the pretty much I have I hope you've
enjoyed the talk
whether or not you felt an API before
I'm currently exploring new career
opportunities so if any if
this was interesting to you please come
talk to me
thanks for the tech happen
this is a little bit and I DEF I'm
curious whether I've heard a little bit
about self documenting
stds was wondering whether they're in
last extensions or
recommendations you have that helpings
yet
yeah totally and thinks every two years
that for one that I've heard have been
used before
yeah X
I thank you for that
expect is really cool I was wondering
you want
more about the authentication options
that are out there I'm
yeah I don't have any specific examples
with me but
I I recommend using a service I think
like storm path or something like that
might do that for you
and so I would do that that's because
I'm a little sleepy
right
I thanks I was wanting any comments
about may be scaling in EP on
have any requests you can scale
problems yeah I it personally didn't
have problems with that because we
didn't
and up releasing this are using an and a
full production form so I actually don't
know
time about that but yeah
I'm WD My more research before I
let it go
a good talk thank you and you have any
tips for doing the
client libraries client iris like
yes I like if you have any one
people to consume with I libraries
suggests jean-pierre Esther
tips suggestions for our retirement like
using requests or something like that
yes okay yeah
that would be my number one okay okay
yeah
you very much thank you