I will come again 20
continuing our Harward centric om track
we have covering Scott she's the lead
developer for temple
automation I G is here to give us a
crash course on the
internet Internet of Things so let's
give her an okay
um so a quick and dirty guide putting
things on the internet
you guys having fun it's a bit dated and
at the end of the day sry have
ton of fun again right so
in Cincy I wanted to write an intro sir
tutorial where
I I talked about shouted do
different stuff with hardware and
improve promise is when you go and look
at some of the
tutorials out there there's a bunch of
stories and how to do little tiny
20 things with her and there's lots of
tutorials but how did the web stuff
and it's because people tend to break
off used right there's people who do
massive let's kill stuff and then
there's people who
tended the bill more hardware stuff
robotics and computer vision and that's
what items I'm and you know every time
I go and build a marxist grow and build
some is a hardware
almost immediately as he was a stunner
as it's being billed Italy you
give it away Hugo doing something with
it cited
think yes gotta figure so I wanted to
rate like a really simple
introductory experience for building
something like that how do I take a a
simple object nicotine
so the brew the problem is is that you
have to
figure out what you want put on the
Internet
and stuff that sells really well stuff
that deals with pets
so I decided to put pats on the Internet
and I don't have cats I don't have hogs
I used to working in neuroscience loan
and I kinda fell in love with rats
cuz you can leave them for a week and
they have all the best qualities dogs
and cats and their
compact in is a deal with so I decided
to
put rats on the internet which is rate
because
rats support all sorts of wireless
protocols in interface standards
and
and you know they're just they're super
easy where I'll
wat they are totally not easy to wire up
on anything
they have no standard interfaces except
for one and that standard interface
was thought up by this Harvard
psychologist
and his name was BF skinner and shaky
and so BF Skinner's will back was it
sees a psychologist and he wants to
train animals a cute ass so we can see
how will
how they were from this house and how
they change when we changed their
environment
and so he built this thing called
skinner box
it's also public operant conditioning
conditioning chamber
and so the skinner box you you guys may
be familiar with this from work
is that it's either a light grey buzzer
and the rat is supposed to hear the
light and buzzer
and its post to respond to that by
pushing a lever
and then it gets and there's an there's
further
other way you can train routes where you
elected by the bottom the cage any shock
come in and they personally for and then
you stopped the like
occasion I wasn't gonna do that cuz
that's not cool on
so from the street just basic
conditioning you
you build a primitive to do real science
you real biology into
the owner science and you can also just
play with your pet so I would go by on a
six in their
their ten thousand dollars I'm not even
kidding you it's a weaver
a buzzer a computer it's ten thousand
dollars
this is the quote I got for doing and
this is actually like a huge problem
because like
the NIH and the NSF he people to do
research like this and you can't just
have one rack know you have to do
massive parallel
Brett testing at scale to get your
doctor so you're looking at like
tens a skinner box on
so I decided books you I can use for
herbs I and I totally did and it's it's
super to do it last year
Europe icon everyone got a Raspberry Pi
you know you get a Raspberry Pi for
30 bucks I got a Raspberry Pi IR camera
so I resplendent like night vision it's
like the poor man's night vision camera
and that was right there as rip my 30
bucks a
a couple of metric bolts on couple bucks
hardware store
five-dollar she stepper motor a resistor
a buzzer
and the Shipholding Ellen 2803 which is
like a stepper driver
autistic little signals that have our
current make me the pic signals but
what the current and a switch and then a
lotta
really awesome 3d printer parts I had a
friend from the internet help me do some
chemicals I'm
and we basically started building the
pits skinner box so
is a food hopper in the hopper basically
stupid streets the rats
others the mounting brackets to hold up
to wreckage there's a lever in just a
simple not the camera in this all goes
inside a Tupperware I
to get my kitchen on in so inside the
choppers were in mount it all the harder
so the harbor is super easy it's just a
Raspberry Pi
a breakout board and this controller
circuit proper sisters
switch in a buzzer and so the mounted
all in you deploy it so you have to
deploy her dislike me to play soccer
so I deployed it with my pets & wanted
see how they would do
so once the heart was built like know
how do you
build the software to do T interact with
it right and
such as interactive it but interact with
it oversee yourself or over web browser
process just like
running a simple script so first the
plaintiff spec out what you want to do
so what I wanted I wanted to display the
images on the camera
a record the activity over time a
be able to remote control feed the pets
that's a pic excelerate
and then I also wanted to run in record
actual science experiments ripe
buzz the buzzer iraq responded pushes a
lever and I record whether it did so
correctly or not
and finally I wanted to display all of
those results
a you know in something I could I just
so like it daily digest
results so to do all the second half
with you can figure out what tools from
the paper ecosystem IQ's
so to run the motor in the buzzer in the
switch that's simply
GPIO library right repin and a friend
I had to run the camera I just used a
library hope I camera which is
just simple Raspberry Pi camera
interface open CV which is a computer
vision library
and number I which is a numerical
processing library
during experiments I have none pie
which just this manassas Mongo which
store the data and map but limb you he
an
bill Mongo on Raspberry Pi I'm just
gonna warn you it takes like 12 hours
and it doesn't really work well but it
does run
and then finally to display everything I
just use a simple
Python by a lap dance and bootstrap
gobble up seconds
I am so roughly how does this all work
so
from Inter perspective how do you put
all these parts together make an
interesting
so you start off by building the harbour
interface which is just a thread
running and you you create a couple
methods to get into that threatens a
here on the motorway enough to feed the
rats he
has a switch impressed a similarly you
build a camera interface and its entire
job his trainer Fred
grab an image once a second and I
actually wanted to monitor activity
so I if the image edition is processing
right def it
from the last image received in see if I
can measure the activity the rents
and then with you have that done you
just do
a it little tiny science threat right to
this shut
the search job is to watch say okay how
long has it been since are an experiment
it will look at its watch say okay I
need to run it's very three minutes now
it's time so
run the buzzer went for the rat
responded if it doesn't respond in
30 seconds while the experiment to fail
and then
to tie all this together remember what
happened you created date: interface to
rendered results and save your data well
you just sorta low this all into
about a web server set up some call
backs and it runs
okay so you guys wanna see code say yes
you have Cinco today right stockpot
alright so this is the main web server
and so this I don't going to want to
show you guys
an actual demo the hardware so built in
anticipation
on so this is really really simple I
just import the four models I just
talked about
and I'll go over those on detail but
I'll give you the over here
there's a simple Jason encoder for a
message scheme that passes to Peru
WebSocket to the front and the page
um then I have a pilot all tax rate and
so these are basically there
tour Ron and say whenever an event
happens and hardware
Hall up in toss this either to
a locking interface among new or push it
to the website
once it's done with these in place I
basically create my objects me for
objects
on and for all this project user really
really simple call back mechanism
so this is just lists love first-class
functions being passed back and forth
so I say like hey here's my a political
writer
the run experiments he's really like
your data whenever you get
something that you want to save like say
a passive interest a love interest our
experiment
said it there as a toilet hey whenever
you get a pass around
say polyp the front end and send a pic
and so I go through and I i said all
these fence right so PASOK spirit-filled
experiment some early on from the
hardware I say
whenever a button is pressed whenever it
comes up
notify the front end I log data to the
database
and also tell the experimenter that hey
a button when up so
if you're actually trying to look into
burma with my blog
insiders analogies for buzzer and the
feeder and some relief for the camera
motion so whenever the camera motion
it's a motion update
everyone's a sec senator division
updates to
you basically tell everything to start
sterile your friends
and so you go through in its after this
it's a standard bottle webster
so set your routes for your images
JavaScript and CSS a split strap
in this case just make it look pretty so
if your air pigeons
on note actually get the events to
happen so one of the things you want
rightist have a controller so you wanna
be able to click
burns and have the box buzz you wanna
pick buzz in your web page
have the box but so all I did as I set
up a row
so whenever you post to this route you
just called a hard winter faces a bus
and Ike is all true and how I do that
works well
some early on running the feeder you
just
call this you post to this feed them and
it'll dispense
pictures same thing and a lot of the
stuff after this is pretty cut-and-dried
way this is a mighty the generate
activist this
generates your plot right this is this
is the rats activity every day
just simply polymath it'll see file to
your image map
which is not great but it's a quick and
dirty way to get this done
and render the bottle template
similar again for a past bill
table stop that generates statistics
on the everyday is wrong and a couple
more to surf experience
here's a little bit me so this is gonna
be
here where we actually set up the
WebSocket to push data to the web
front-end
finally and this is just a little bit of
a helpful thing is that you set up a
signal handler so when you post on the
web server
you shut down all the hardware threads
their setin Damon mode which
should kill it but it's usually good
option doubt it nice clean
orderly way so then we can also
look at the hardware interface
that looks like this and this is super
simple
wrote it in afternoon and basically what
you do is you initialize a threat
like I said he said it is a Damon so
that it dies when you kill the web
server
then you have some pins the sets on
Raspberry Pi have
I think a dozen or so maybe GPIO pins
so you set the GPIO pins to oils that
are going to be used to
run your stepper motor or the quarter
the
pin that'll be used to run your buzzer
or the pin that is connected to
your switch so I said all those up with
the output
set all the ones that are up at the
buzzer and
the stepper motor and I set the input
for the the trigger switch
and then I certain internal state
variables to the way this is all gonna
work
is that whenever you wanna
dispense food or run the buzzer you set
a flag
and so at the flag inside a mean we'll
be inside the Fred
you just say you countdown so you do it
we know
roughly this is not completely time
accurate that you say
roughly five times a second I want you
to countdown
and keep running the buzzer seastar you
sir at 5:00 p.m. ring the buzzer five
for 3 to one in the trip
and that's in this year threat am
along with that I also set up some some
call backs
so these contacts are there to notify
other either models or the NAP when
an event a prince so like whenever I
dispense food
somebody can accept the call back to
sleep immune function
itself was called back here and whenever
adjustments but I'll call the function
and say okay
i'd dismissed it as long as everyone
does is relatively quickly
it's not a big deal so you can see that
here
so when a cop spence this will check if
the flag for this meeting is
up if it's not well so we searched reset
our step
we bring the bike up and then we just
call up years
similar for buzzing same deal
this is where we set the call backs and
this is where we actually set the
stepmother so stepper motors are to send
there
basically two pairs oil and user
alternate how the quills running in that
causes it to step
so you need for pants and you can filter
so here I have a basically a single step
where I say that this ban Hien this been
hyping this pen hei
is go through the employer and they
stopped another
and I have a nice interface for the
buttons and finally a shutdown mechanism
just that sets all the Pens hi if
this is just a good point for building
stop if you're
using 03 hire some other interface
to to build hardware what are the
greatest things you can do is
run the iPod notebook and bring all your
GPIO pins
in is and you can interactively bring
them up and down really really easy and
as your
you know if a circuit boar a reporters
at the new trade but what's going on
can bring them up and bring them down
and actually you know put your
multimeter on the inside
yes came up okay sort
um so then you just run everything and
the space which exit see if the plans
are up does the bookkeeping
and sends it on its merry way arm
and finally there's the bitter logic for
the button so but prices are actually
really you're just looking for a higher
low signal but
usually don't want to detect higher
locus is affects what you actually wanna
detectors the derivative right gone from
zero to one or 120
so I basically have a little method here
that looks without and then
does the public
so that's a now take a look at the
camera interface
so the camera interface is is again
super simple
seem sorta idea running Fred
on in this case I'm not really gonna
basket for anything it's just gonna go
run and take a photo once a second
and every time it actually gets a photo
it's gonna save it to a regular
director in wet saree and it's also
going to calculate the motion between
the previous rain
so this calculation right here
miscalculate motion
basically what you do is you say okay
here's last image I to
used to initialize it but you say here's
a last-minute and here's the image
you're just a
and you you literally take every single
pixel in use a proper planning other
if things are moving activities going on
that difference will be
if nothing's going on if you the same
image and if you have the same image
twice
the difference is going to be really
really small so I do as i convert
of the images the previous one and the
current one to grayscale
subtract them to one another take the
absolute value
and take them you know that and that's
my early promotion or be here
movement I also do a little bit of
temporal filtering
as if you do that rebbe
Israel really rough mechanism so few
average this out over a couple frames
you get much better results on
getting images of the Raspberry Pi
camera is a little bit different than
say a standard USB camera what you do is
you create a stream
and you basically pipe the PNG
how to the Raspberry Pi into the stream
and then you can use numb plated decode
that stream
push into you a data buffer and then you
can
then use that data buffer inside the
open CVT binding
to either save the image do some
processing or
but every need so once you have
basically these two functions get image
and Capulet motion that the mean for the
becomes C breezy
get an image accurate motion wait a
second get image
Catholic mission with them so how we
doing on time
at so
X so here is where the science Apple's
as I'm gonna go through this really
quick so
same with primitive same sets a call
back
and the only interesting thing here is
that I pass in the hardware to
I'm so the hardware basically are the
hardware interface and so all this thing
does is it basically
looks for two things it which is watch
every few minutes it does this time did
says this happen Rep
or it's been this long run another
experiment were it has been a sponsor
running expect government experiment
and if the experiments running and the
Rev she's a lever
and stop experiment record results
and final aim we have data interface and
this is super simple
it's just a connection to Munger
determines on
and a bunch really simple functions that
shoved it in the Mongo
whenever you call them so it's just and
this is a extremely primitive but it's
just
login experiment lot abuts and reporter
timestamp
to display video you basically go
unanswered Mongo pay has it been
give me all the data for 24 hours that
is just buzz presses
or for is button presses or just buzzes
or experiments and
to generate from this for the user you
just go in clear all that data
and use map partly to render so
just release a full partnering no
if you really want to be fancy should do
this in javascript but the Python
comments 0 that's been pipe problem the
other thing you should know
about using matplotlib have to set the
back end
it met but we've actually usually once a
runner interactive mode see have to
change this flag to get around quickly
okay so is it enough you custom you
wanna see
some demo and have some fun so is my rat
my human rat assistant
alright so I'm gonna
basically months ago to you this is on
the high side veces station
alright so we're gonna pretend that it's
regular day at my house and i've left to
go to work and I'm sitting around and
what we grab a rat just kinda have it
have a crime is rule
should run around in the cage
and so we will go to wreck
so we are now connected to the web
server on the Raspberry Pi with the rat
up rat will you push that lever right
there
we thank you
so than a button press they came up to
the website and maybe we should
would you guys like to take a look at
this rap and see what's going on
we can just do that
at least
up you're buzzing an experience running
we hit the lever for
excellent we go
so live feed %uh rack
arm we can also look at your activity so
caveat here I just kill them on a daily
basis is not all day it's just
units the past couple minutes the sex
abuse I can surrender
but so this can this is just the
activity of the rat over the past two
minutes what's been here
we can you actually revisit this in a
second on
we can also look at the experimental
results it a buzz again here in a second
so and fail
okay so you personally for once
once X
Iran's on well I guess in the meantime
I will but
manually
I don't know how far back can you hear
that excellent
it's that annoying II I had to move it
out of my better
so I can also be you feet its
and week we can actually see how you
been doing over the course of the day
so we can see how many times you done
correct presence and
number time she bad bad process so today
you bill
10 times your past place the total
number
experiments is to her present correct
number twenty dispense
to an emergency press that button number
times the
buzzers boast and I can also see
the Chorley for your activity J
will you be my RBI
on
and so thats about you have any
any questions user ok ok this is all
okay software I've actually put all the
hardware to
a fun thing ever so it is all free
though work it
fix it mess with that build something
else
good
think you can bring
as if you have any questions Mike you up
front so
police comin ask your question thanks
that's very
users but the Raspberry Pi specifically
use use for use to
regular us xiiso
you certainly could insisted it sheep is
a hard
three dollars you could she's a big
alone you could run up a no Board
do any up you can run a web server and
people easily passed in
wonderful I don't wanna be when extra
the other question get back to squeak
design ok I'll
you really know me well
you really yummy you just needed right
text usage
keeping the pictures sec yes
it's not like dumping picturing onel
certainly there's like it's completely
mean I there's no there's no reason
really then two other show some
principles a hey I'm pushing this today
to bed
and yes you can get with a text file
into be probably
better easier more robust in a lot of
other stuff but I wanted
write some code that was actually a
little bit something that you could
build upon to do something slightly more
to rate things
I and that was my question to
Brett so tell us more about how
to put my uncle under excuse me had to
put my
go on to it he said it was hard overuse
it is actually a couple tutorials and it
was pretty straightforward you want to
start out with table or
jst heard and it will fail you will
not keep the state a long time or you
need to replicate it across something
else but no
on a day-to-day basis if you're
repeating once a day it seems really
robust
once it's running but it seems like when
the hi comes down it comes back up there
seems to be issues
until where we find the project
but so it's all up on it and so if you
should be on my blog here fairly quickly
but it's only getting
as a result
expire so we're still winning up my
friend used in mechanical engineering
we're still having problems with this
thing here and these are actually really
hard the food poppers
really hard to build 11 p.m. kicks
because they're
like kid tested or approved her you know
it you it does actually proprietary
Science Plan sugar pallets that they
normally feed rats and those
aside from the box being ten thousand
dollars those might as well be ten
thousand dollars for
sugar pellets us but getting that food
to move through its actually
you could use a lot harder than you
think it would be you when you're
running up a 3d printer
community stuff I'm but probably have
some shaping behavior here
cool project
one thing you might think about in some
rabbit
just to keep easy is IBM has an MQ TT
queuing system which is made raised
wasn't
is this muscle queuing system yeah
actually only
a shoes systems for doing hundreds
arrest papers definitely might prefer
for actually been using Ross a lot for
doing bigger real work project
and I i cant talk enough about how
awesome ross's ross's robot operating
system
if you guys have not play with it go
play with it cuz it is
Haas its rawson
any other questions you
period it's been