I'll I we had
her and she's here in stage and I'll
talk to us about how to turn your
computer into a server
peace will come
hi
the okay alright a high
I'm Karen I'm a freelance web developer
based in Mountain View Calif
hi I'm a sheepish I'm a security
engineer at event bright in San
Francisco
yeah but by people in the middle yeah
the this is turn your computer into the
server it's in introductory level talk
and we have three main goals for the
stalk
that first by the end of it you have a
basic understanding
love computer networking on you
believe that if you have a computer they
can access the Internet
you can run a server on it and you some
ideas how to do so
and family you have faith that you can
do this
and not get immediately hacked or have
you can get a break
or anything terribly awful bad happen so
30 parts the stock the first part
is about simple sharing sharing in
progress work or files from
your work computer and either
within a given network or across
networks and
part 2 will talk about home servers
which is a case where you want it to be
up basically all
time versus just one of connections and
the specific considerations associated
that use case
so but Medina scenario
your building your first web application
inlets a Django and you run
United tutorial you run the built-in web
server
command and the tutorial policing go to
this
local host corn 8,000 address in your
browser see do so
and you see your django application show
up
that's pretty exciting in fact you're so
excited
and I may or may not have done this
myself a
you quickly copy and paste the link
insanity remade to show off your work
I've course you quickly realize this
isn't going to work
local host that that only works on my
computer it's not going to be seen by
anybody else
so okay well you get clever
you like well I know the name of my
computer like and
so our place local host with my computer
that local in the URL
and that's going to work right well
not exactly and so your
roommates still can't see your django
application that you want to show off to
them
so to figure out why that didn't work
and how to fix it
we're gonna look a different tool for
basic local sharing
which is called simple issues P server
this is a model built and built-in comes
a pipe on
you have it on your computer if you
papon and the way the
use its is you go into a given directory
you run this command and files within a
directory will be served
by default template thousand you can
specify the port and
this is a really useful tool for doing
in sharing
fun and projects it smell CSS JavaScript
on
or basic file sharing and what's neat
about it
is it doesn't just work at local host
Hornets thousand
it works even at my computer that local
colony thousand
so this works but
the Jenga built-in server doesn't so
let's compare the two and figure out how
we can make
the Django built-in server act like this
simply
TP server so when we look at the log
message:
that we get when we run the simple HTTP
Server we get
serving HTTP at on
0 to 0 to 0 to 0 port a thousand
and I don't really know this 40 think
a but when I compare it to the Django
log message:
but I get there's a bunch of stuff and
it says it's serving at 127 dot the road
at 0 to 1
it doesn't have their daughter died 02 0
whatever that is
well you might try something other and
in be run server command instead of just
specifying the port
you might try putting the 40 thing in
front of it so it looks like this
and in the lot method you can see that
is no longer serving at 127
it serving at zeroed out there that
they're out at zero
cool so what to do that experiment
you ask your roommate to try again my
computer that local and
they see what you see they see your day
go out the kitchen that's pretty cool
it works but we still don't know why or
what
dur da dur da dur that 0 which employs
six saying
means though to explain we need to
discuss
a talk about a bit about how ports and
interfaces work in computer networking
you might already be familiar with ports
might've heard them
heard of them at least its easy to
conceptualize them
as these gateways a
a these entryways and your computer are
numbered
numbered 1 through over 60,000
and so they're not all John here
and different applications will listen
or buy into
different ports and so we know Django's
listening
to 40,000 and so it's listening for
requests to come in
a from outside the computer and sending
responses
moralist so that sort of our basic model
what ports are
the reality is actually a little bit
more complicated because you don't just
supports
you also have interfaces so really looks
more
something like this um these the what an
interface is
is a way that your computer get online
so here
this computer has three interfaces
there's wn2
which is your wireless card there's eth1
which is your internet connection
and then there's hello which is local
loopback
which is sort of a virtual interface you
can't actually connected from outside
it only works inside your computer and
so
each up these interfaces have their own
bankers ports
on you don't just have one port a
thousand you have in this case 3
you can see what interfaces your
computer has and some information about
them
if you run the command I F config on the
command line
on most you next the system's and I'll
give you some useful information about
your computer on so
we can see here that the reason why
with the default Django run server setup
your roommate wasn't able to see it is
by default only binds to port 8000
on the local loopback interface which
you're able to access via local host
but when your roommate rise their
connecting over the wifi
its checking a completely different port
8000 and nothing's listening there
were not able to connect what the 0 to 0
to 0 to 0
a shorthand means is bind to the sport
on all available interfaces and so
django does so
and for now you can connect
over local host and a roommate can
connect over WiFi and if we had people
connected on even if they could get
there too
pretty cool so
great we've accomplish our first or we
can show off her work
and show off how awesome your Django
programming skills art your roommate
or anyone else who happens to be on the
same network but
we've got a friends who don't live with
us who don't share wifi
a were elsewhere on the internet that we
also want to show off to you
and so we need different tools to be
able to communicate with them
am in order understand both
to understand how to do this we need the
first discuss IP addresses
a Internet Protocol addresses am
these are what are used for routing on
the Internet and there's two kinds
the first is private IP addresses which
exist within a given network
so if we imagine that this is your
network at home
um is your wifi router and there's you
and your roommate
and then the router standing between you
and the rest the Internet
private IP addresses only apply on the
left side with the
diagram between you and the router
on certain IP address blocks are
assigned to be private I'd
private addresses so if you see an
address starts with 19 2.1 6 8
or was her 172 dot some stuff
or 10 doubt stuff and that means you're
looking at a private address not a
public address
and you can find out what your
computer's private IP address
another is a number ways if configured
value for one
another way is using are simply CP
server that we're
doing for when you run it and you access
it over local host
when you look at the log message in the
terminal window you'll see one thing
you'll see it
a connection from 127 that the road out
there that what from local host
but when you connect over my computer at
local instead you'll see something else
the logs
you'll see 172 in this case that 27 that
the road at 14 and that is your private
IP address
on the network you're currently
connected to so
that's pretty cool and that means that
you can see roommates private IP address
to take an x
over the service you'll see a different
IP address belonging to your roommate
show up there an
yes lets private IP addresses thanks
karen I wanna talk a little bit about
public services so website like event
right we don't just want to be available
inside the office montana beach ball
from all over the world
for the only thing with the kinda
website you guys wanna work on also
and to make that happen you need to talk
up we need to talk about
public IP addresses which IP addresses
that will route
from anywhere on the internet so karen
mentioned that
IP addresses are what the Internet
routes messages based on
which means that if you type in
something like Google to comment your
browser
then your brother has to first look up
what the address is
other lot com so that it can send a
message to Google
have the web conversation to show you
the webpage an art show you what that
looks like
through a few her teens and I think that
Lynn route just gave a talk about DNS
this is going to be much shorter
dinners %ah but therefore you prolly one
look at hers
in the videos if you haven't so briefly
when you want to visit google.com your
brother sent a message to your home
router
and says hey what is the address for
Google com
your router may have it stored may have
a the answer
cached locally maybe look this up
recently
or maybe this is an address that is
based inside your home network
and so it sorta authoritative for the
answer if not
then it passes that request along to the
global DNS service one of the servers
might be Google's one is reversed my
belong to your ISP
eventually an answer comes back which
looks like this
and you rather than pass it along to you
so now your browser does what the
address israel %uh com
so they can then send a message there
but what if you just typed this IP
address into your address bar
will allow to cool here's URL with that
sup and it turns out if you the best yes
you get to go home page
this IP address just interchangeable for
that name
in terms of how the package get there
so for that's great %ah
this mean that you can route packets to
you computers based on names
and if you happen one look up a computer
based on his name you can use the
command-line tool called host
which you can query for some particular
name like Google com
and it will tell you what address car
sponsor that
so
alright
%uh so we've seen real web sites have
public IP addresses at least one
public IP address is standing up for any
website or web service
they are able to access over the wider
Internet but your computer
your laptop almost certainly doesn't
have a public IP address
and yet your computer still able to
communicate with the rest the Internet
it able to do so because a trick that
you're at it does
called network address translation
ornette a
and so the way this works going back to
this diagram here's our network
and a router is standing between the
machines on your local network
and the rest to the Internet an
important thing that you're at it needs
to do
is to keep track of who's traffickers
whose you don't want your router's
sending
the packets you requested to your
roommate or vice versa the way that
you're at it does this
is so let's look at a request you're
sending a packet to website somewhere on
the internet
books something like this there's among
other
meta-data Thursday to address and the
from address the to address
is the public IP address I'll the
website you trying to access
a ends in a port colon eighty which is
the default port for web services and
the from address
is your private IP address colon some
arbitrary port switch
computer picked out for this particular
TCP connection
the details that aren't important just
that
this particular connection has a
particular port on
so you some material at her rather
what's the packet
and takes the from address that you gave
it
and assigns it to a random
unused port number more less random a
and stores that in the net table
which is stored in your router so here
we were signed
the sport number four for 43 after does
this
it deface is your package a rewrite it
um removes the original from address and
instead
rates the routers public IP address
colon the sport
that it just a sign you after it takes
your
poor defaced packet sent along to the
rest the Internet
hopefully eventually you get a response
back
and course this response isn't obviously
sent to you it sent
to your router's public IP address and I
might have been a lot of requests
between when this was sent
and one you're at it gets the response
and so you're at it needs to figure out
where is this packet suppose to
ultimately go
does this by again looking in
the net table a based on the port number
and okay 4443 is here and corresponds
with this
private IP address a it rewrites the
packet again
to give it your private IP and sent it
along to you
and so this is happening each time
you're making requests
over the network and as far as you can
tell your seamlessly connecting with
Google
even though the packets are getting
changed back and forth by rather
so and that's pretty useful
on the good thing about it is it means
multiple devices can share one public IP
address
so if you don't have enough public IP
addresses you can still get
online which is pretty knees I like
being online be bad thing about it
is it makes it hard for people outside
your network to reach you
because you don't have a globally
accessible address you rather just like
I don't know where this goes you can
contact your router but you can't
contact
computers within the route the network
that the router
controls so I would still want to show
to the network
even though we have this difficulty we
need here on this issue and there's
several ways to do so
%uh the first one we're going to talk
about is SSH tunneling
on at this H is
eighty protocol you may have heard a bit
equipped to get graphic protocol that
does a lot of things
the thing that we're doing with it is
called remote port forwarding
and so in order to do this the first
thing you need
is access to a computer somewhere that
does have a public IP address
and as many ways to get access a you
might have
University account that has such access
or line 0 or Amazon ec2 account
or just a friend with the server who's
willing to give you SSH access
once you have this are you connect to
the remote machine pssh
this works like any other Internet
connection even if there happens to be
not in the middle
%uh the protocol also connects whatev
reported using for the connection
with the port their application is
running on the specified
so our application is running on twenty
thousand so
were making should pay attention to it
and similarly
we pick out reports that script being
unused on the other machine
in this case port 9,999
and connect to their as well and once
we've done this
then people anywhere on the internet ken
connect to the remote machines IP
address horse domain name it has one
and on the chosen port that that request
will get sent
through the SSH tunnel to your laptop
and group responses back we'll go back
the same way
be indentation on the command line that
does all this look something like this:
um that's our beans do for din of
traffic
St means date reports means use all
interfaces not just local loopback
and then the arguments we have first the
port on the remote machine that we want
to use
where staffers going to be accessible a
what interface port combination that we
want to be connecting on your local
machine
and finally the IP address or domain
name for the remote machine the you're
connecting to
are so great we've got this your L we
can send it to all over friends
and they're going to be able to access
an application that's running
on just your laptop even behind that
all you need to have this access
anywhere on the web
is money to pay for remote server or a
friend who's willing to give you SSH
access
so that works great if you have friends
money or SSH access
but i wanna tell you that my communique
even if you have none of those
on I do notice I'm not super on the wifi
a
we'll see about my demo okay so %ah
there are a couple of services on the
net that are willing to act as relays
for you in the way like an described
they are and rock and paid kite and rock
is designed to help you debug your
applications
anyone can set up whatever demand they
want start
and rock dot com and rock have a tunnel
client that they can you that you can
use
kinda like estate client we saw Inc and
example
paid kite is free for open source
developers like five dollars a month or
something
not for everyone else and there
they have a sort of freedom and privacy
bent but look at these anyway
our services that you can that we're
willing to broker a tunnel for you
you can borrow some demand from them and
I'll put your website online
and if I were online now i would tell
you all to go to this
URL then you have your computers open
and you are online and you go there
actually
you'll see a message from and rock that
says the tunnel is down
because the wifi sounds years right %ah
but I do have a Django app running on
this machine and i'm happy to show you
this
a low it is working ok great so you can
impact go to death
bizarrely okay share
whatever I go to it okay nevermind great
so we have this great angle at my
apologies for
my own stress our meilani
shimon ra and Tony a blow us away had
taken the tanker tutorial
added a few images and put in to give
repo I'm not running that here
the basic pulled up you can go in and
you the existing polls
you can wonder which is the most awesome
not to misuse teaching go
it did somebody break into admin nice
wirklich
of course they did right so in that case
I guess
lawls are better that any ideas and will
vote
so I'm glad you all agree but usually
crucially this website mobile talk about
security cynic
I crucially
refresh a not afraid to use I want
up anyway yeah lucien
a look here it is demonstrated that you
can connect to you this laptop running
right here
the website even though it says pie
conduct and rock dot com in the address
bar
is that a host on my laptop here and
%ah for a while I thought this seemed
think
yeah okay go yeah so anyway in the
nineties
%ah I read this fake news article by
fake person
in a pic MIT news magazine about the
coming and
up addresses on the internet %ah and I
thought this is a pretty funny thing
and this article hinges on that idea
that light fixtures will soon
have IP addresses yeah right but then
last year I went to a friend's apartment
and I found with the Phillip Hughes that
you combine for two hundred dollars
at the Apple Store their eighth grade
redid for a5
people seem to like them and they are
Internet address ball
light fixtures so it turns out that we
are really going to run
out if I P version for addresses there
aren't enough
addresses to go around for all the light
bulbs and all mobile phones in the world
in particular the least 6 billion mobile
phones currently deployed
and we don't have that many IP addresses
IP version 4 which is the current most
widely used version of the Internet
Protocol
gives you 32-bit for IP address: which
means that they can be at most
to 232 or about four billion addresses
fewer than the number mobile phones but
luckily also in the nineties
perhaps related to an article that i
read they invented a new version of the
Internet Protocol
IP version 6 and the addresses are so
long but they wanted on the screen
there are 128 bits long they
are there are more IQ version 6
addresses then there are protons
electrons neutrons
particles in the universe so hopefully
will crowd out
this time and %ah
this of course means that there's a next
generation transition that has to happen
now wept for pipe on people here
we're very familiar with the
next-generation transitions
that require backwards compatible
changes and asking everyone to you our
Changer app so that they work according
to the new standards
and IP version 6 have had at least as
much success as pat on three
so I you're a little over a year and a
half ago
fourteen years after the release a IP
version 6
a quarter of a percent all the traffic
to Google's web services were over IP
version 6
not that many %ah results guarantee no
okay but okay right I think that he pee
found that
recently Python 3 accounts for about 1
percent
are a year or so ago I covered in six
accounted for about 1 percent of
Internet traffic but
IP version 6 the doing even better now
were up to you
%ah a tenth a quarter of the Internet
but
%uh the nice thing is that this uptake
is increasing and
if you don't believe me I'll show you
this graph from Google
are you can look this up yourselves but
I'm not as making these up is a really
Google's numbers
so I'm not here just to tell you about
like you were in sixth
because I love it so very much I'm here
to tell you about it because
what it means for getting a computer
online what we've talked about with the
tunneling services
you have to borrow a port or hostname
from somebody from a friend on the
Internet
from and rock dot com assuming their
online and they do this complicated
complicated rewriting track but the way
the internet was supposed to work as you
just show up
on your computer and you get had an
address and then
whatever services you're running are
just available to the entire Internet
and since IP version 6 have so many
under says most
up the as those addresses our public
between the you can find your way
to getting a v6 address right now and
what else is on the verge in six network
can be directly without bother with any
tunnels and there are a few
services that let you do that without
asking for permission my favorite the
is one called me rindo weirdo and its
protocol call Terada or supported on
Windows and Linux systems I think
there's a Mac port
these let you even if you're behind some
network address translation box
sorta fight your way into getting a
virgin take address on your computer
and from that point forward any services
listening
on that version 6 virtual interface on
your computer are accessible globally
without you having to get specific
permission or
proxying for any particular service so
I'll take that the back to you so we've
covered a bunch of different ways
but you can share applications or files
on your laptop with people anywhere in
the world or within your network
on usually in use cases was just for a
limited time you want to get feedback on
something you made
or just one show off um so its part 10
the stock part 2
the stock is about the specific
considerations for a few actually want
to run a machine
at hosting something full time from home
so and always
up caveats server
so like computer ownership in general
Asus admitting
a home server is sometimes fun and
exciting a
sometimes things break sometimes things
crashed a
hopefully your server never looks like
this
the but there are some reasons why
maintaining a home server and having a
dedicated machine for the sort of thing
may be worth it for you so
one thing that you can do the home
servers home automation so maybe you got
a Raspberry Pi last year's icon and
you're excited about
turn your lights on and off or you have
sensors and you want to track your
temperature and humidity in your house
or any number of other things
and what bill to access that information
not just when you're already at home and
you can see that lights are on
but when you're elsewhere and so if
you're going to do that
having a machine that you can contact
from outside
your home all the time is really useful
on you've got this django application
and it doesn't be useful for you
and you want to run all the time simple
as that an
orders services that we often use posted
by other people
but you may want to host them yourself
for a variety of reasons
increase control increase privacy in the
current regulatory environment
it's a lot harder for emails gets nuked
if they're literally in your house
and and similarly you can run
I your own web services at home %uh so
your bookmarks your RSS
notes photos but music all sorts of
things
and live right ive examples of services
even poster self
they're open source for those sorts
applications and
the added benefit with those is not just
increase privacy in control
specifically you don't have to worry
about your favorite service getting
Carlos Lee shut down by some large tech
longer than just bought the startup but
does the thing that you love
on if you control yourself and host
yourself that's never going to happen a
must
your house will get spotted
a so that yet so there's some some
site Solus benefits to having home
servers and being able to do this
on and so sheesh is going to demonstrate
one service
that so %ah
if you have that web service at high
combat and rock dot com
you remember that it's only available
from I it's available via a tunnel
that means that it could go down if that
tunnel fails but i wanna talk with you
about
is hosting that in a way where your home
network
make sure that stays up consistently so
for this demo will view website at hi
com dot dot the end of story
and with the way to step it up on your
home router is what's called
home port forwarding so let's say that
this tango app is running on your laptop
on port 8,000 and you want to be
accessible globally on the Internet
by port eighty which is the normal
that's our report
to do that you would need to configure
something that looks a bit like this
you need to tell your home router
whenever packets arrive destined for
poor eighty
turn them over to my computer on port
8000 and would need to make this rule
somehow permanent
not just transitory while a connection
it made and a way to do this
is called port forwarding free router
and I'll show you what that looks like
in the assure that looks like when
packets both room
when they arrive they're destined to the
router on port 80 because no one on the
Internet
outside her home knows about your
internal address
the rather look that this port
forwarding rule and rewrites the packet
and send it off to you and then your
computer will respond
nationally through the router so
to configure something like that you
need a at you need to log into your
home wifi router and you'll find
interface that looks kinda like this
you'll see there's a bunch of options
here what's important is that the
external port is that
eighty the internal ports at eight
thousand and internal IP address
is set to the address your laptop inside
the network there's also the drop down
about TCP and maybe other things
for the purposes of this talk TCP is the
only right answer that
but for different services you much is
something else you can read about this
later
in order to people to reach your service
though they're going to need to know
what the address above your Radaris so
you need to know
what is my IP now if you just asked this
tool I F configure on your computer
ill show you your computer's internal IP
on your network if you actually Google
for this question
the Google servers will be happy to tell
you do that people will say
in the surface parties your public IP
addresses
whatever it is and if you want to get
that automatically
through some kind give API there are
services that let you do that to you
so this is great for letting people surf
to the routers IP address
and get routed by a router to your
Django server running inside a network
but if you want to give them some nice
to main like this
hi conduct and after Oregon address
then you need to register that somehow
so
there are these so-called dynamic DNS
services
for example ducked in ass this is the
logo by the way I'll be hatin support
questions for them in the answer them
really quickly
on their Google+ community and added new
features for us there happen to be free
but the cool thing about dynamic DNS
services in general
is that if your home routers IP address
changes for whatever reason let's say
you turn it off and on and as a result
you gonna sign in your address
these things make it really easy to
update your DNS name
with the new address
out so up that's all great for
letting people route to your server but
if they happen to do a lot with it if
they
send you are requesting you happen to
respond %ah
there might be some limitations and
they're probably some limitations that
is being inside the hike on network here
so all I can talk about that and yeah
so you can imagine with are Django polls
at
if the images on the app works
we don't resize them properly their full
size huge and
lots of people wanted to use our POS
application at once
then that could be kind of a drag and so
with the limitations associate with
running home server the first one of
course is banned with
on any traffic either requests to your
server or people applauding files to
your server if it's now position that
does that
will use up your home and with which
if two extremes I can interfere with
your regular
with anyone else on your network surfing
or using the Internet
normally an important thing to be
aware within that is others term called
buffer bloat
which is something especially bad with
Ben with that happened
if you're dealing with large files I
where the large file world
get privileged in its loading but like
regular tiny requests will just like
get backed up behind not be terrible
obsessed with googling
I'm sensible router a configuration can
make up for both these in partially
mitigate them another thing to be aware
is called is max connections so when
you're running a service
under computer on many services
can really take basically all the
connections you can throw at them
if you're hosting some static files with
Apache
it'll be fine the traffic is it where
you have to worry about well you have to
worry about more so is your home router
most home routers will not put up very
well with having hundreds of connections
per second coming in
pouring and sometimes even left them at
depending on the router
um what will happen is the net table
which we saw earlier in the diagrams
will fill up
and out when that happens then either
you can't just can't make any more
connections
or existing connections get dropped on
the floor neither which is very good
if you've ever had to restart your
router after someone on your network use
bit torrent
that the very similar phenomenon were
too many connections are just
making a router break am
your internet service provider may have
rules about where large do on your
network
on for example until relatively recently
Google fiber's Terms of Service will not
allow you to run home server
and so that's something to be aware
similarly some ISP's
filter certain ports before they even
get your house
on port 25 the default port for email
is blocks both incoming and outgoing by
many eyes peas
so if you want to host your own email
you're going to have to do some sort of
work around to get around that
and so that's just limitations things
that can go all wrong
or slow down your home internet are just
kind of a pain
but there's also security considerations
were someone
the faces you about ligation or breaks
into the database behind a web
application
and can thus do various things and so
I'm going to lead
event bright security engineer sheesh
attack about those
thanks although it almost seems like we
should have Luke talk about them
unfortunately I have the mic tho a there
are some risks that applied to any and
service weather is running on your home
computer
weather is running on the Internet in
the cloud rack in a data center
however are one of the most important
things you might care about your web app
is that it actually stay online it what
you don't want is for people to show up
to your web at
and a center seeing your beautiful
images they see a broken image icon
this is bite happen to you if your
website gets too popular
up for all sorts of reasons on
another problem that might occur is that
users might be able to break into each
other's information
so this could happen if users that bad
passwords
it could also happen if there's some
like was probably what we did by the way
%ah thanks a lot shimon inmate who set
up that demo
have a and it also might happen
if you fight if somebody find the
security bug in the code that you're
running
the something else have you ever which
is that most frameworks have settings
that you can set
to you make the app be running in a way
in a way that safe
for other people to access Django had a
debug equals
line that you can set to true or false
if you set it to true
then if any then if you tell that 20
Janko
or contributors will be like know how
could you do that because the
documentation has very clearly not to it
says to set it to false if you plead on
trust
are accessing the site the thing is that
if your running stuff at home there's
more stuff at risk
if somebody breaks into that service at
your house
hypothetically they can read all sorts
of havoc they could change your home
wifi router
so that when you go to wipe it is like
e-bay what you see
is all the images come back upside down
that it will get for this
I'll give you the week after that you
want Kathleen Q&A
but are given that there are
us a few considerations apply
specifically to running stuff at home
and they apply to the security of your
router and your computer in particular
so if you rather have the week admin
password
and somebody breaks into the web app or
other services you're running
they can then log in to your other
change your password
or reconfigure it they can also attack
other computers
and with a serious problem recently
where a bunch a homer
network attached storage like network
hardest boxes
have been broken into like tens or
hundreds of thousands of them
and we're all mining declines so
a their sisters risks about this
actually
they can also break into your computer
particular especially if your running
stuff
the running the web app on your computer
they could then install a keylogger and
record all your keystrokes
decade install mouth recorders and see
all the things you're clicking around
and so on
someone talk for a bit about how to
mitigate those in a few minutes we have
left
wanna most important things is to stay
up to date so
are ten years ago I was running a wiki
call TWiki
that was my personal website on Home
Server and
then a few days job well at one point
I discovered my server was being used to
send out spam
and this is because basically I haven't
upgraded my wiki there is a publicly
announce security vulnerability where
people could run whatever they want
by misusing the version control feature
not sitting and not staying up-to-date I
had to go clean up after that you're in
total mass
upgrade the second thing that the most
important to say
if take backups and backups our way to
recover from whatever crazy thing
happens to your server so
if you have a live replication setup
where any changes may hear automatically
synchronize our second hard disk
then when an attacker break senator lose
all your data that is Emilie
synchronized
your second hardest that's not a backup
you need a way to restore
in his whatever happens not
yeah not back tho there are some
particular ways to mitigate
other problems and the key is usually
separating concerned so
if you run your home server on your own
computer
then at least run inside a different
user account you can use the user's
group features so that
if they do break into that app they
can't go then look at your browsing
history
or modify your browser configuration to
give the attacker your Gmail password
for example which they could have a
running as your user account and they
had total control
another thing you can do is separated
two runs on a different machine for
example
we have a Raspberry Pi my apartment
thanks to my friend keith mcallister
which configure which I is responsible
for letting up a great ability is in the
living room
and that thing if somebody breaks into
it you can accessorize the after all
that thing can't attack %ah
my personal data that's not stored on
the Raspberry Pi
similarly you can isolate networks we've
talked a bit about public and private IP
addresses
there's another term you can look into
you call DMZ which is the way to have
a public service on your home network
where it can't reach the internal hosts
so then it wouldn't be able to reach
into your router even if the attacker
had broken and there's a lot more you
can learn about
web security in general the open web app
security project
has published list arrests call the top
10 list I recommend reading that
we can also talk talk more after that
after the stock
but having said all this order negative
stuff
I wanna say I wanna give you the picture
from the Chaos Computer congress
most the time your home server will be
fine doesn't want ads or at all about
people breaking in
I can avoid that if I upgraded but I
want to tell you one last story
about how things can go wrong and it is
where
a sophomore year in college received a
phone call from my mom
and he said pay dinner at home is
running really slowly
I said well I'm here in Baltimore you
out there in Rochester New York
how can I possibly help maybe the
neighbors are using the wifi lot maybe
the new network in town you need to
change
that wifi channel I don't know so I hung
up
and I want to be my email and I couldn't
I realize but you know is hosted in my
parents basement on Home Server
they might be onto something here and
when nothing else to do a district
website on myself Google
a new website do love the day with metal
products that so
i click to their happened click on the
Google Image Search tab
analysts are really familiar picture in
the top bro the images search
and this picture I realized for the
photo about a picture of the Mandelbrot
set
the my friend Jonathan had put on my
home server
on his personal hosting account there
for a high school product he made into
this class
so I click on that and lo and behold
really slow to load
so that I was going on there Ubuntu
random people really excited by Google
by Mandelbrot set and tried to load the
serb
server page in my parents basement
eventually allowed into that server
and I set up a redirect to that that
image got served not my parents basement
and everything handled the helpline this
is by and large one of the worst or as I
can tell you
so it's really there's not that much to
panic about especially if you do the
kind of separation we talked about
so that's all we have for you today I
hope that we left you with these
takeaways that you understand basic
networking now
that you know that if you're online you
can use tunnels are other mechanisms
to run a server and you understand the
basics on how to do so safely
so with that said we're happy to take
questions I will say that we have the
slides and also have the video
at this domain here I'm sorry donna
thanks
par top like 0
her there
I can governors hi karen is sheesh thank
you so much for your talk
I feel a lot more jazzed about running
stuff from my home
on I want to ask I'll whether you think
that
stand-alone appliances like freedom box
are things that people would wanna look
into right now are they do you happen to
know whether they're ready
or do you think that running something
from something like a Raspberry Pi
or or your own via tower laptop would be
the best way to go for stuff like
hosting hosting an email hosting and
photo stuff like that
so i cant yet so the question is about
%uh stand-alone boxes that's come
pre-configured with
home server software for example for the
box um
so I have no particular experience
running a bit about software but in
general
is kinda Raspberry Pi like machine that
runs
a Debian based operating system I think
that
at least right now it's good to
understand what's going on
and so I think that installing Debian on
some computer
and learning about log files is a pretty
Duyvil thing to do
and at that point mostly you are getting
that much by running
the zone 1 cats but then again I've been
running Debian since 2001
so you are my different opinions try
whatever you want I mean
yes so I'm excited about the PM box
project a lot and similar products like
it
a I think everyone should run stuff but
a I don't have that much experience with
what
the experience in running one is like at
this point a
and I do think it's important to know
how the freedom box like any other
machine you would read homeworks
so that's on my dick one other quick
addition is that
whether or not you're using some
standard appliance
upgrading matters an extremely large
amount
otherwise your commercially configured
home network appliance storage network
attached storage box will be mine back
lines
I was actually looking good
%um runnings up
and I was very route couple weeks ago
next system
Ross P&P which seems said
things didn't mention that for example
basically all routers p and equipped
you can just I think it is packing the
next
used talk to you water and to get the
external appeared
anything just from the applied and then
you can actually say
would
this total yes and it's completely
automated
soul would you recommend using that said
you know about you think it's a good
idea to go down yeah
said to repeat that there's a protocol
call UPnP
are universal plug and play much let's
applications inside your home network
configure the router without you logging
into the router's admin interface
and the question was is that great and
the answer is that is great
yeah we didn't mention it here be
cuz I've never used it basically I'm so
you sick looking around configuring
also you can like write a python script
to get stuff from it but it's not
integrated into
Django or anything else so you need to
be aware that stuff anyway
be are you can't you can be a shortcut
is
thanks for putting stop up to talk a
little bit more about the
units this morning freed or
and how does dan yes compare read
so I'm
Saint sure whatever a.m. yes so I guess
the distinction between as a shelling
and dynamic dns which may reading
super get in the talk is the idea
a like I do you just wanna send people
to a port
random port somewhere in time domain is
that good enough or a subdomain if it's
a service like
I am service like and rock
or would you rather have your own domain
name that you want
to get sent to forward to your home
server
and if you're setting that up you're
going to need a
you know be make sure that your domain
name is able to
stay in contact with your home IP and
since your router's IP address often
changes
um SonoSite only cheated once years and
have the jitters are a few weeks
depends on your eyes P dynamic dns
is necessary just to make sure that your
domain name is still pointing at the
right thing
and so that sorted in general what a
dynamic DNS server does
a service does and so ducked you know
it's also gives you the domain name
you could use your own domain name with
the service as well I believe you
fire name record yeah okay our
yet so that's where the distinction
where's the tunnel is
while you're gonna need a port number
Ford and it's gonna be on someone else's
domain
while us and just add one other thought
maybe two other quick parts duck DNS to
summarize
is to is just a free dynamic DNS service
and also I find that my SSH tunnels
sometimes go down when I'm not looking
and that's
why our router port forwarding is what I
would recommend instead of that if you
want to make sure it's set up
thank you so much for sometime