find its 1130 time to start the next
talk
I'd like to welcome Benjamin Peterson
gonna tell us all about garbage
collection and by Conor
thanks man thank you guys i'm happy to
be here
worker in the bigger room today I I
always try to read something into
where the pike on organizers put me in I
assume that they put me in the big room
so they can Paris me when no one shows
up but
you guys are proving them wrong mu them
wrong thank you so
what am I gonna cover in the stock well
main I like to talk about how
we actually in when garbage collection
in to
the main pipe on it went asians namely C
Python
and pipe I and in particular in the case
a pipe I
I'd like to address the issue
optimizations and
but sorghum patterns we see in Python
which lead to
I am the need for certain optimizations
and what how pipe I does that
and finally I'd like to spend a few
minutes talking about various
issues which with in the intersection of
language design and garbage collection
where garbage collection actually causes
us to have to think about the semantics
a python and how we want it to be
okay so where I'll start with some
importation basics
and and as I said I'm only gonna talk
about pipe I N C Python
and that's mostly because those are the
only two which
I have worked on and have knowledge on I
I do not want to
say anything bad about the IronPython
or a jacket on DC's but they inherit
them from their
language implementations and not written
specifically for Python
I'm like C Python and pipe I so
them most basic question ask is what we
mean by garbage collection
in any language and more specifically
pipeline well
will usually thing is that objects which
are no longer reachable by our program
will be the allocated in the resistance
they're using
I cleaned up so new objects can take
their place
up a somewhat subtle question is
when are we going to get our objects
cleanup and the Python language
reference which is sort of the standard
is a
very cagey about this it says object or
eventually be cleaned up or never
are so in theory you can make a python
importation which just called exit at
the end and
from the kernel cleaned up everything
for you but that probably would not
not not pass muster and where we really
like is that
objects are cleaned up up at some point
before we run out of memory are so
C Python venerable old reference I want
Asian
are private the primary or a primary
garbage collection
is reference counting and the idea is
very simple basically
be a lot we live the objects which are
reachable on your program
have account which says how many people
want them to still be alive
as how many people are expecting to be
able to use them
other objects that s and so when he
first create an object is
one 1p soco and one other optical we
reference and so have a reference count
and then that will go up and down as
other parts of the program
use it and finally when the objects
reaches a ref count is 0 we now can be
safely be allocated
so here's my diagram how that works
power
and we're gonna imagine that these
objects here are
pre-existing and during the course of
the program will allocate another object
called Arctic Sea
and sense it's a new our regular have
are recounted one
and then say if object be. now gets
a reference to objects see the wreck on
recu
will become too because it has to links
in the graph here
and then if are if another object is
allocated
and handed to you objects and are
object DD its a or objects see gets a
reference to
the Newark DE then once again our big
deal have
arrest got one now what happens when
objects CE are is no longer accessible
from
the live program well the links are
broken
and so each time a link is broken the
record as documented by one
and since there are now no longer anyway
X here
there are countless the OM I will
realize that the
object can be cleaned up and in the
process and its cleanup
your remove all the references that has
two RGB
and so R two-d_ you also become a dad
object and they can be reclaimed
are so if you ever look at the sea
Python source
it's littered with these macros pie in
craft and pied de craft
so here's an example and these are the
operations which actually
do reference counting in C Python II put
into a simplified example of how this
works
art so this is the code which sets
items in a West mister normal Python
West so this is the west with your site
is this is the index which your
bino you're saying and this is what
you're actually will be setting
and so you see which hit me with the
West takes a reference to
the be which is the object we're putting
into the less because the list is now
going on it
it this is the code which actually puts
the item at the index you expect
and then finally it documents the old
value which was holding in that
in that about index in the West are so
it can be cleaned up if because the list
is no longer references
01 subtlety in this piece a coded me
knows that we've
very carefully put the new item in the
west before we deallocate
are decorated the ref count up the old I
O and that's because if you
de commended the ref count oh the
all value before you had put the new
item in the list
it's possible that some Python code
could run which would
I touch the west and with it seein on it
initialize value at that place
are index in them the best
okay so reference counting is an
all-india
and it it works pretty well as the main
garbage collection in C++ Python but has
a major fly which is that if you have a
references return cycles reference they
will stay live for ever with peer
reference counting
and so what happens if going back to our
example
is that if you have an object here see
an object here D
and they both reference each other well
the number one's going into our big cr2
and because there's one coming from
being one coming from the older objects
and obadi has a ref conserve one and
even it now if we drop the link from the
pre-existing objects
so it's no longer referenced in our
program
then both it is obvious you still a POS
a ref count
because they still reference each other
even if they're not accessible from the
program
I so see python has a
separate guy risk by her cubs cyclically
see which
RD tax reference I goals and remove them
and so unlike reference County where you
immediately know once an object is
unreachable that you could be allocated
the server the cyclic GC
runs every once in a while to detect and
deallocate cycles
and this is where you're actually
invoking when you run GC collect
on C Python and the operational the
sickly DC is very simple basically it
looks for all cycles in the program and
then it de commence the internal
references are the cycles
so that's what's happened here if it's
in during the single garbage collection
the the internal references in cycles
are documented
and then if the objects in the cycles
region 0
then you know that it's a cycle which is
not reachable
because that references were only due to
internal cyclic once
so we're able to be allocated okay now
I'm gonna switch to T
what I consider the more interesting for
the Tigers pipeline
are so lemme briefly review the basics a
pipe I'm
so pipe I is written in a restricted
subset of Python call our Python
and BR Python can be translated to a
lower leg would right now that's
primarily see
and sensei interpreter is written in
Python
are it's actually has garbage collection
are python is garbage collected language
so I as the are python has been lowered
to see
garbage collection has to be added and
so what that means is that the
interpreter is actually abstracted away
from
be garbage collection implementation
unlike C Python which is
littered with artifacts abreast County
are so that means you can change the
garbage collection implementation
up at translation time which is the
lower in a bar Python
to see are so
as I said the pipe I do see is just
another low-level transformation
RB are Python object graph
and the garbage collection what Asian is
actually written in our pipeline itself
so it's you can you can go look at the
source code it's it's it's very strange
to see this
with our Python code which is on
actually
working with Ron memory want to
translate to see and also means it can
be tested in Python you can run on the
Python interpreter
and you'll get normal exceptions when is
not translated to see
on and so there been quite a lot of pipe
I garbage collection importations over
the years a
the current one is called many mark and
as well
I'll be discussing the basics up
so pipe I does not use reference
counting by default and so
uses ain't more traditional garbage
collections
scheme I guess you could say called
marken sweep are
but the idea is also very simple
basically start with objects machine or
alive in the garbage collection phase
and then you walk there references
all the way out and then you and while
you're doing that
yumm carefully marked them to say oh I
know this art is alive
and after doing that you move design
called the sweet phase where you walk
all the objects what you know about in
the program and if they're not marked
you know they can be doubt the allocated
and so this has no problem with
reference cycles because there's
no reference counting and you all to see
the cycle
as not reachable are so here's the
visualization now this
so again we have are newly allocated
objects here and work now on the market
bass who are suing that we know these
objects are live object A&B
and the garbage collector will traverses
links
LC objects see bill mark are receiving
knows it's alive
Anna next phase a garbage collection
sweeping
well lock all these are little see
object AB and C are marked
so we they are alive but
object the is not marked so we know it
began be doubt be allocated
up so what's really interesting is its
how we can use parts of
arm much things observations are the
Python language
usage patterns to you optimized garbage
collector want Asian
I so wanna the primary observations
I love Python and indeed most dynamic
languages is that
you are often allocating lhasa objects
which are soon to run away side put a
few examples of yourself
to traditionally you'll be alkenyl lotsa
intermediate float objects in the simple
average
which will be thrown away before they're
stored in a variable
and for example if you have a every time
you iterate over something in Python you
in a raid in iterator I think it's very
it's very transparent but you do
actually have two allocated internally
are and anytime you collin object on a
message you have to allocate
abound method which actually binds the
South
object to the method so you don't have
to pass self
and then another common pattern in
Python is I'll
long strings 'em above replacement so
like this this is some
courage I found in ginger to do HTML
scapin
and so it when these things create an
intermediate string object which is then
immediately not used after it
you move to the next replace com and so
in the
GC garbage collection community and this
goes by the
rather recover title high infant
mortality
I basically expert expressing the
the idea that you have many young
objects which up do not live very long
are so a contender in the dark metaphor
we
the opposition to use to help with this
is called the nursery
on and so the FBI deion nursery is that
you when every allocate a new object you
put in a small little bopper
and then you just garbage collect the
nursery very often
are much more than you collect the
entire object graph and
so months and if an offer to buy the
nursery collection
when you move it into and older
generation which is not garbage
collected so much under the assumption
that it will live longer than the things
which are garbage collected
in the nursery and so the same pretty
simple
but there's one side a point is that is
you actually have to be movin objects
around in memory
temple members and so that means is that
%uh pie pie has GC has the ability to
move object that is copy them to
different parts of the RAM
well also updating the internal
pointers to are which other objects
might have to that new object
and so thats Sperry very much so cases
the flexibility the pipe I model because
when we have the entire interpreter I'm
been translated see we can see
which objects will have internal
references to other objects so the
garbage collector can perfectly
are update internal references
another thing which pipe I try to
address is je C pas
are so basically in a traditional
garbage collector
and C Python cyclic our site when the
garbage collectors running your program
is not running
I just us the program so I can safely
walk to the object graph
are and so sometimes people have massive
servers
come but with a lot of objects allocated
and the
GC will stop the program for like have a
second which is bad
and but this becomes especially promote
what you're trying to do real tile
things like video processing
of course no one tried to do video
processing with Python before pipe I
came along and made it actually
reasonable to do that for computational
stuff with his
just in time compiler are but
now it's actually cut become a
possibility and so GC positive become
our problem
are so pie pie has something called in
and incremental garbage collector
and what that means is that instead of
doing homework sweet process
in in one go stopping the program to put
Lee
it can do AP marks what they can do a
small part of the marking process
and then let the program runs more and
then doing the next part of marking
process
as you can imagine that's not terribly
simple to do because
the you it's easier when you assume that
the the program has been stopped and you
will be mutating other objects
up but according to the pipe I blog post
where our men and
major implemented this it was actually
relatively painless to do
I'm Southwest go part time
and so this means that you can break
down the garbage collection time it's
just a few milliseconds wishin be
notable in real time processing kinda
applications
so in summary the attributes if someone
asks you know
what is great about the pipe I G C you
should tell them well
you can choose a kind of garbage
collector you want I'll
and it also has a as a nursery
to generate a generational garbage
collectors one which
I'm has the objects in different
categories based on how long have been
alive you can say it's incremental
and it's also integrated with the just
think I'm pyaar
so the last few minutes I like to spend
talking about some subtleties and
garbage collection semantics
specifically I'd like to talk about
under under Del
which I I think anybody has been in
Python for
a little while have bad experiences with
Dow
up and some the main problem with with
under under dell has led when arbiter
TLK to be a
of of computer fairly arbitrary point in
your in the program
and so on if you start running arbitrary
Python code in an arbitrary primary
program
stuff might not be initialized are you
might be in some
we are parting shot down
a so that's one per the unsafe miss
the other part is that if you have
finalize urs Witcher in a cycle then
it's hard to know
which one to deallocate first
because the final so in this example
the final either in our big see couldn't
the object see has a reference to
object the so it could tried own fetch
attributes
love RBD York our method on it up
and the same thing is true bob 2d and so
you don't know which one is safe to call
first
because they might be trying to use the
attributes of each other so it's it's a
tangled web
and so on the the solution to this and
see Python for a long time has been
to just not not run finalize urs which
are in
which are in cycles and was actually
means is that
objects cycles which were which contain
finalize we get moved to this
list in the garbage collection model
code: DC that garbage
and so it would essentially leak them
and it's clear you can like
use it for this listing DLK them safely
but a lot appeal that no other so if
they
someone had final I there's in cycles
then
there they were essentially be lost
up but this problem has been addressed
in C Python
3.4 was like a pet for 42 I'll talk
about on the second and
pie pie has always tried to do run the
final hours in a
reasonable order and reasonable in this
case means do
roughly do atop a logical sort the
object graph and
so you try it you try to run the ones
which have the least are dependencies
purse but at the end you pretty much
just had to pick an arbitrary finalize
our to run it because the garbage
collector does not know
which one is safe to run cell
specifically in on come on
okay specifically in pat 442 in C++
Python
this is the WorkCover C Python developer
knee and toe on patrol
I it proposed slowly Mon finest cyclic
garbage collector in C++ Python
n the way it works now is that you
detect all the cycles
in the program and then
you
you run finalizes on them and then you
see if the finalizes resurrect the
objects because that's also something
you can do and finalize our
and then if the
the objects continue to be daddy not
have themselves to
the alive part in the program then
you can safely clear them so this allows
cycles with finalizes to finally be
allocated and Ruben
an annoyance or serve cause I weeks in
C++ Python
programs ok
so coming coming to the end might aikman
me remind you both what what's I what
I'd like to cross is that
the garbage collection can be very
subtle and difficult OPIC
but also garbage collectors are awesome
and especially Popeyes so she's part
time
on and with that I will conclude my time
and if anyone would like to lineup for
questions
let me point you too some other sources
of information
on I've there's there's a big topic
and I have not covered all the many
things
which are interesting time out for
example I did not talk about we crafts
wreak references allow and you can
always
look at the Wikipedia article and or
are the sources I Z authoritative source
true alright
okay okay so
you got your nursery industry has all
the fresh objects that you making
and you keep intractable the point is
you making
into that nursery is there an explicit
way
to say making the nursery and a few
halfway through then go actually you
know what discuss nursery
I E suffer transactional memory has not
been looking into that
are so there's not a way to control this
with
a Python program are I
I'm not quite sure with how garbage
collection works and that's %uh for
transnational memory
its I I'm I've not been working on that
so you'd you'd have to ask Carmen
person who's been working on that abut I
do know that the garbage collector has
very deep integration
with suffer transactional memory
importation pipeline thanks for talking
I one thing's a I'm notices most lived
like more recent
developments and garbage collection all
assume that the garbage collection
processes
a synchronous so happened that some
arbitrary point in time after the are
Jack becomes collectible I'm is there
any
feeling in a pluggable part by by is
there any way to
implement a garbage collector they would
have liked more synchronous behavior
underscore search like the reference
count has reached zero
cleaning up now yeah so pie pie is
actually had a reference counting
garbage collection implementation
I just to show that you could do it it
was pretty inefficient
so it's certainly possible to do but I
think
the the common
the common feeling among most garbage
collection
researchers is that a synchronous
garbage collectors
allow for a lot more up our and
flexibility in in optimizing them so
it's it's certainly possible in Popeyes
model
but I I don't it's probably not
something you'd actually want to use
on hi
thanks for the talk i was just wondering
the
pipe a nursery sounds like the exact
same thing
as the job eat in space is there some
notable difference that a missing
on now the I'd I think the area so I
mean they
deep they differ in in small details but
up
a lot of the stuff was I mean a lot
everything that we've been implemented
in dynamically which is now is like in
Scheme enter birds in the eighties so
ok we're just dip II mean and this also
shared a lot of stuff with
arm modern JavaScript garbage collectors
like
to be aight and spider monkey also do
this kind so it's a
it's a very as I say as a very common
idea in the importation a dynamic
languages
okay and then also was taken to know
that someone miss this
is there to survive all spaces
Lake what the Java garbage collector has
for young generations to
word is played by do something else so
in the in their current
implantation there's they're sort of
to there's the nursery in and there's a
10-year generation arm
but there's are in one of the other
garbage collectors you can have more
generations
in fact in the sea the Sea Pines on
cyclic garbage collector has three
generations I think now
okay thanks hey
so on a building on the the previous
question
arm their art are a lot of languages
in the bigger family tree the Python
belongs to
all the way from small talks very sinker
nations to
self and he as well as JavaScript and
I was wondering if there are amongst the
many different generator
not senators are the many different GC's
bed i buy has
I've there any new research directions
for object-based languages that you have
been exploring
that nobody else has hit upon yet Hong
but see
I it I'm I have to admit something which
is it's been it's been awhile since I
worked intensely on the pipe I garbage
collector so
YouTube you might have to ask arm in arm
and there's another guy named Carl fruit
bowls about about that
I I can't think of anything at the time
I had sorry Norris
thank you very much I
are for both C Python and by how loaded
garbage collectors deal with our
fragmentation %ah yes I'll another son
C Python once the al Qaeda operatives
there forever
are so it its it's pretty much a
function of how good your
your heap al Qaeda is your your
underlying
a memory allocator well it because it
actually depends on the platform so see
python has its own
a memory allocation sorta
thing called of my like which
in theory should produce the
fragmentation be faster Python programs
but
up your kind of the kind of stuck where
you put the object
and you can write programs which cause a
lot of fragmentation high in pipe I
says you can move the object around 10
things you can do is kind of compact all
the objects into one part memory
up to in order to reduce fragmentation I
so
pipe I can certainly address that
go thanks
thank you for coming looks like that the
profession thanks everyone