please note:
doc is
at to infinity and
it did in by 10 to infinity and beyond I
was the key back doing does this
I still love it and just want to say one
few lines
about myself my name's but alas
I'm from India I'm out Federer
contributor
a fellow member in BSF and
I work as a community Gardiner in a
company called eucalyptus systems
I'm so
I should just thank them once because
the response on my travel and staying
and stuff
and I shirt and bike on also portrayed
sponsoring my
bike on picket to finance the late and
maybe against start the real talk no so
the stock is actually about hearing
all our experiences and
teams which worked and what didn't work
far-out online summer training
we started this training
back in 2000 8 its
on lane its are it runs on IRC
its runs for anyone who has the
comparatively new Linux distribution on
open mind to learn stuff and
basically whoever wants to become a
contributor so
if you see that name BDP Lugt
thats you can guess elude use Linux
users group
and DB is the place where I'm from dude
up will
the nearest down from my village and
wind its mint I started that lot back in
and during that time there was almost no
one
to pay less what exactly to do with this
thing called NX
other than clicking randomly and so
the goal of our whole lug was to learn
yourself
and peach others in Bengali Lake
chic or even Chicago me that the
transmission so
that's how we started doing or lug and
going ahead
but denby phone that there are many
enduring colleges
in that local 80 where we have so many
during college students
we're going to random companies to do
their summer training
where basically dead just being forty
months
summer amount of money learning nothing
at the end up the team is just they're
just getting a certificate
and they're trying to use that
certificate to get a better job
during college interviews in the final
year but
on most do you know knowledge Syrian the
so
destroy any started to actually have a
replacement for those kind of
I should say nonsense trainings where
people can only go only to beat seem
library management system yet after yet
and because
we already started doing a lot of free
software walk
as a contributor in different parts and
different projects
we talk that weekend actually feared the
whole King
as a summer training program so
from the very first year our goal was
always to
guarded the local people forced and then
the in a global event
so the initial idea was to go for of
lame campaign
as much as possible we started we
talking with the students who
we knew personally and then getting de
France contacts from their lake
in the same area audino other colleges
to ok India and
when I said quote India we started
getting into the part of mailing list
so that we announce it or mailing list
and
then it studied slowly started becoming
global effort
at the beginning it was only me
but I'll I'm going to name another
person here said the gunmen
he's not here but he is very well known
feder for us develop and mentor from
India
so he also teamed up with me to help out
the students
and we set up de ni si el parque Odom
thinks
to be done meet at any minimum req and
10 things we week think that we can get
out of this whole program
how things will go I and from there
Lake up him and he has a lot of people
are these tutorials online in this site
which you can just fine his name Google
you find those things
and then came the next tip because
on during those days I never heard the
word MOOC
as such and I know when you comin I only
know what the sites where we can go in
see some videos online videos to learn
about something
but which brings into this problem that
why we chose IRC as I what dude our
technology
we never had good band week when I spew
don't have
good banquet I'm right now the fastest
internet connection of my life
4mbps that is Lake and being a hundred
dollars for it
but I know most of the students in India
they don't have access to any
such internet now if they're lucky
daily Gate maybe 256 kbps if they are
in a big city there we get it read it is
this
of course but I S E was something which
was part of free software community I
thing from the very beginning
it walks it just works it's very less
man do it we can actually record the
stock because it's text
and weekend just keep the fights for the
later use
and I hope even in the time on nuclear
blasts and any other kind of catastrophe
IRC will be still there so that we can
contact with each other somehow
so regard okay we cry with IRC
and we did that offline and online
campaign in 2008
so first year we started out on
in students in doug has did you believe
buchanan
by the withdrawal we are calling it a
summer training we actually start on
most in the rainy season in India
Lake end of big government middle of
June
that start start timing so
out of 10 student I think I am the
training ran for three months
so a little bit more on the training is
that this is a addict
talk I mean dick on princess and I
should say between pic trainers and
students
so trainers will start talking in the
IRC channel and it will go on
deal many are some things like six hours
and d 2 a.m. in the night
for the student reduce a sense almost
every day night
other than weekends for first two months
and then
one month on are one and half month an
art project works
where we try to pose the same people
into afternoon
basis so out up in students regardless I
don't feel for students who stayed with
us
later they went in to defend other
projects
and that was the first year so we
started doing this year after year
2014 will be 78 for us
to last year
we started with AP students from
very different backgrounds when I
started these
the coolest injuring students but
I can give you an idea like what kind of
people we got our
not only from India from the side of the
world Lake North America
on after see it off Afghanistan Sri
Lanka
Obama this and
people came people talk with us many
people stayed
Lake out of eighty students you're
almost forty plus de ti that
three months training course they came
online almost every day
on time and gap between I mean
the Cape doing the stuff which was a
good
salt other than in years we had a me
this yen
was like being Masters in music and
wanted to learn by 10
and now as far as I know that he's
moving from Spain
to export and and on his music masters
degree he's
big he became our half but dayum Django
developer
we got there from Sudan I think we gotta
primary school English teacher who was
the food came by my school teacher
from there he moved into halftime apart
pain and
other part time as a sysadmin and bite
and developer
and fuse he said means from Germany who
became per game developers
just to move up the carrier and
regulating in college student
back an we had friends got it
we started this program based on our
friends we
try to talk with to them we try to talk
to their friends and get students into
this project
and we never part I would award which
I'm hearing
in the last few years a lot of time the
word is
every 30 I we never acted the part about
that
white from the very beginning we had
about 50 percent all men participation
save money last year out of eighty-plus
students we had almost 42 or 43
woman participating in this program we
never had a problem
where it was Lake pic too many boys
auditors Lake
are too many men centric program or
anything or did
it was all is almost in the same 11
at from the very beginning and we also
makes you know that
the message board it goes out in a
proper way
due to different colleges so after just
after the first year
when we got few people who are doing
good both
men and a woman we actually tried to put
them up
in the local community as local
superheroes
so they went to their colleges to their
friends and he had their own knowledge
and their life story that how they
started from the UN
they become something and which keep
bringing in more and more students
from bolt men and a woman like that
diverse city park
few times we thought they come and
because its online sessions
you know people speak many random things
sometimes the doctrine as and few of us
who do take lessons we become kinda ET
and be use lot of sarcasm maybe
but it go so well in both cases there is
no Lake
if you are a student you are just a
student
one more thing which worked really well
West
staying in touch so we are not a kind a
program where he just runs for three
months and it's over
instead those students become our
friends this day online
in the same place again and again year
after year
we mix week trip we try to guide
imploded college-level
and even in Dec 11 wind lake which
companies to join wear to work on
Lake what kinda project we can walk in
future
the differences actually beauty that
when when is someone new is coming in
they might take that
old XD it's a huge community I just want
to go and learn something
we want to break that part aren't we
want to make sure that they learnt that
dr. the community
the out part of this we if we have to
grow we have to grow old together
and this message
on list is if we make sure that people
are coming back
people are staying in touch and repeat
the same exercise
yet after year
a little bit on the course outline what
we teach
starting from communication bike lanes
Mill English guidelines for Desire C you
are mailing list how you should talk
whack went to talk from the air to
basics of Linux distributions dominoes
demands you have to learn source code
management system
a lot ups trimming dine goes into
documentation
why documentation is necessary making
sure everything
everyone loans about documents and fast
even before the start writing any code
and we try to push it too hard to that
it becomes the head
natural habit to write good
documentation and
we're getting kinda good result out
there
and the final part of the training is
actually taking those individual
students and making them a contributor
to some
upstream project it can be anything
i coming to the project a little bit
later
so whatever happened in the last few
years seven years
past six years the log said their in
that you are if you go you'll find that
last
this unlocks this thing helps too
to revisit though whatever we did before
you find many fancy funny things
on the consistence kinda questions
people ask
so you may want to just go and visited
later on
and in any kind of citizens we
always said that you should start from
the scratch
do not as the only that your students
are the people who are here
Dino this thing are detecting in
technology
they may be are coming from a complete
different word nothing to do with
technology
they just want to learn it so
the clock to progress based on that
speed up the snow is student
not on the people who can just learn
everything every day
so we try to piece that class based on
that
this brings in some a funny story is
Lake lessons learned even seen one way
late so during the command line tools
and training sparked
we try to teach people how to do the
basic
level up building c:\program celebrities
and what is believed to be an issue what
is make
on the basic things
and no one under says and we can really
say
install Fedora by default up but if you
are coming with Anna the distribution
today be another 12
will still help you we tell you what is
the exact command to use to
get things done so defile answer for
installing all our disaffected was the
only study City
everyone said it worked it worked yet
what and suddenly one student came up is
Lake
it's not working it's not working for
almost half an hour
make three or four of us were trying to
help him out
and after all the commands we actually
knew to figure out what's wrong with the
yom in that box
somebody actually of steam or by the way
which distribution you are in
well I mean going to and make
okay so how you got the young in the
first place
I said you people like telling everyone
to do YUM
so I D just did at getting star YUM
why can't you just apt-get install gcc
instead
but yep that's a part of the whole
process so we as human that the student
knows the difference between
back to use the arm already used the CC
out wrong adamson so did this we just
think that everyone knows nothing
and let's start from the scratch people
who can pick up fast don't pick up fast
but we is the program based on all
students
okay how to manage fifty-plus students
on as the channel
this is something was not I we
discovered we just reused
the process we each we have been fed our
project
so Peter project has this meeting rooms
Federer had been meeting figure I've
been meeting had been one
when we get many people at the same time
and by gays that person we speaking
domain are bus and we think year
he or she will be keep talking and other
people if they have any question do in
just died a clinician mark then the
moderate and the person who isn't here
in our case our trainers they would see
does exclamation marks and they will
allow people are asked people to speak
up and the students with end with that
yo mouf message
so that we know that he's done we can
say back
and along with eighty-plus student it
worked really well
there was never ever any problem where
make
following the roots but we had to mix
your dad the rule is being followed
strictly
if not we just saw back with gaps
to as I said let wheat when it comes to
burp
programming and bring stuff and I new
people coming up
a lot with this problem
in addition issues so don't try to solve
it dear
just teach them some beta radiators it
can be any edta can be just type in
notebook
that release all the New People's inland
is an issue
totally do not have that problem at all
sold reelect problems during the NECA
project is
we asked the students to solve problems
which are baiting yet dude im
instead the problems like any
mathematical quise or any other problems
which we think is good
to with the last few years we saw people
solving
are creating programs too late
downloading subtitles for the movies
they have
are one student actually an wrote that
cool
who scrap through all his movie
selection
getting all the meter data from IMDB and
so kissing in a nice
you right people are writing note-taking
applications
our system monitoring tool
compiling C++ programs from Windows to a
Linux box there are some areas
to some simple by conscripts stuff like
that two teams which are very near to
the students
and we believe that's the only way is to
students we love
the problem statement audited maybe just
some problem which is given by the
teacher
to talk but in this where do we find oh
this is something
can help me too on my friends too and
they can write it
and they can actually talk to the
students
other friend students
one big thing in our program superheroes
so for us the superheroes that they are
other
contributors were doing great things for
us for a long time
so we call this missile system says
guess since
our guest lectures where people from of
deemed
diplomat are any kind up often projects
come over and keep talks
most of the talks are on in general Lake
howdy started LA from zero knowledge to
where they are now direct talks on
see Creative Commons license
documentations licensing in general
last year nicole blood started that
talks
I'm his talk was the first Catholic
decision
this year hopefully many about that by
cannisters we come over and
gives isn't like this this actually
helps the students to
stain doctor to see that Dec person I
known that name
who wrote all these applications is
actually do. person
I can talk to him or her and I can ask
anything
so that gives them a much more
confidence so we try to sell them that
give them hope give them heroes
so that they can follow and they can
become better heal
we have a small home task and submission
system which is written in by 10
I'll I passed the link later on
so from all the strings what they found
people who are contributing to projects
like Federer Katie
OpenStreetMap people who are in
companies like a red hat Amazon
and Yahoo the new startups coming up and
all across the Indian IT service
companies
they got picked up baby faced which was
kinda followed going to actually get
this going to be just oppan
running
musically to that the things I think
wanted to talk about and
if you have pictures on doing the
questions I just want to take some
questions if they're
did a few students from the different
rating systems we just think in their
pictures
just before this bike on so that we can
just predicted there
we find like this guy he started as a
translator
it doesn't too fast but I'm and from
there I think he's doing a lot of
OpenStack nomination work I think he was
the second-highest coming during the
documentation
something that thing left few months
back so to
just like that we we do have are
sometimes questions if anybody's got one
arm
want can you expand the a
E all and y'all F
for cuts from I have a/c I'll
that's not a stalker actually just died
Bangla back its and baby you if
just so that we can understand the
message is over book messages over and
the second reason
and of something F on Lake
you can type I don't know that
indomethacin to fight
okay like that he said that you have
students come in with
problems that they want us all the you
you actually require that is part of it
are
X we tried to do that before with
educational efforts were you want people
come in with the project
not mine are actually no because not
everyone can come up with ideas
it will be Lake are the forty maybe five
or six we come up with their own I guess
rip artist up then we have some think
little bit similar kind of things
but we take it was them like what you
like next spent 15 defense 120 days and
fined 02
what kinda problems you have in your
daily life we try to talk a lot
where C get an ex its cuz we we had the
same problem not a not everybody's gonna
come up with an idea and I was always
kinda
a challenge yeah it's always a big
challenge
hi kinda good me
hi turned into that arm when you come up
for the challenge and they were coming
up the challenges
did you find a week with conceptual I
call the computer scientist and social
things they need to learn did you find
that
they were gone and miss some gap so that
all or the pollen said end up covering
all the gaps
I of course they're going to be some
gaps so during this isn't what we also
do is to pass them different book names
which meeting can give them some basic
idea say about opening systems
sale data structures what are these
things time to time
and we try to push them to other late
whatever be elected to be fine
which are useful things like that
because on leader maybe
I mean not everyone can actually learn
those things writing only solving
problems
but still relates problems is lead we
give them a chance to learn things
for example if you are writing a program
which and one game maybe
they can number guessing or something
would you want to give it be up free
next
so you have to learn about packaging
that how to pack is that thing so that
you can actually give it back ross
your friend so you have to do that and
learn something out of it
get up I actually Evelyn question one
other things it comes up
somewhat frequently is are people who
are kinda want to jump into
open source but don't miss reno what
project
to you dude you have advice that you can
give to the PPS doing your seems
yet how to go about that so what we do
is we just to try to keep a track of the
students how they're performing what are
the kind of things they like
because we not only talk about
programming and computer we talk I would
natural thing sold
I mean normal things what did we daily
life kind of thing start to become
friends to them
so that we can identify the points
liquid kind of things the lake do the
lake to use going on What Katie
would you like use gonna get easily May
12 men don't learn a little bit of sleep
last night
here at the feelings which can study
this if you have a problem
hear the people in our group who can
help you with the simplest most def
and from this lonely stepping up because
otherwise it's that like problem
identify that thing
because that's the question every time
it comes up so aseptic unknown if you
said his name
he has wanna bet a document called I you
want to do a project what should I do
now or something
so he actually explained it in that
completely that if you want to do a
project what are the steps
just follow it up there well if there's
no more questions
but something crucial thank you sky