sorry I welcome this afternoon session
I now we're gonna hear from their jack's
not be but helicopters
so so the total my talk is cheap
helicopters
in my living room I am my name's know
Jackson lovely on their jail on the
twitters
I the slides are up on my website NJL
.us
on so the whole point my talk the
purpose yes I I hope to know the
helicopters
I'm but I'm can talk about using up
papon
an Arduino together I'm I talk to people
about this a lot
and they say oh you're right pat you run
python on your tween oh and I don't know
that doesn't really work that way I just
try to
right as little on the road we know as
possible now my pocket offer
certainly take Python write a card we
knows where to put them together
with helicopters and do awesome things
I'm
this is all transparent attempt to get
%um doing awesome things
right I'm so are tweeners are the
gateway drug so
helicopters I'll talk about helicopters
our first
cuz they blow my mind that they work at
all and the fact they've been around
before like computer-controlled these
things
is insanity so I'm this is the Simon s
wanna 7g it's less than twenty dollars
on Amazon
you can click Buy It Now on Amazon
and I'll be waiting for you when you get
home this is where Pete this is a
helicopter
for less than twenty dollars that could
be waiting for you at home
okay so all talk about the details it
has lotsa features and I get a list of
all the features and some things don't
seem like features
but trust me when you're buying
helicopters for less than twenty dollars
some things are very definitely extra
features
okay so it goes up and down most of them
do that
it rotates left and right sick and
twisted left and right
it goes for him backwards that's
actually an awesome feature I have one
that only goes for words
um it has a blinking light I which
which sounds useless but trust me that's
pretty heady to I'm it has a USB charger
I am so you don't have to go dig around
for dozens of like these
you know AAA batteries also other stuff
I'm but the coolest feature
kahane the course features that is less
than twenty dollars in Amazon
on the second course feature is not in
for a protocol that controls it has been
reversed engineered
to somebody else has figured out what
this delightful little piece of hardware
does
and I'm has given you code that you can
use to control your helicopter
I have another version of this with
holes drilled in the back
with little wires running and so I could
try to figure out what was going on in
it
I'm now you don't need any that
somebody's reverse-engineered offer its
amazing
so helicopters helicopter is a fan
that is powerful enough to blow itself
into the air
right like like literally it is a fan
it blow straight down and it pushes
itself and potentially other things
up into the air um this 1i believe this
is a skyhook
I look up the specs it can pull up
twenty thousand pounds have stuff
not just itself 20,000 additional pounds
this is a fan that they can blow itself
and five or six SUV's into the air right
this is this is hysterical like the fact
these exist is just like
amazing so are nice little
Simon as 47 G twenty dollars buy it now
at Amazon
or you know from where you are but was
in 20 bucks earthly so this thing
has this concept up throttle so
you know how hard are you gonna push
down is a number from 0 to 127
I give you feeling here forty will spin
enough that
you might like go little out and bruise
your fingers sticking in there
I most have mine will hover in the upper
sixties lower 70's I think it depends on
just you know I mean it's less than 20
bucks so you know the build quality
varies a little bit
a battery lives very little bit there
lots going on there but so like
you know you're gonna hover in like
upper 60's or 70's generally
arm 127 is gonna augured into your
ceiling
I am so you know you kinda got the
throttle the play with once you get it
that downdraft I think I got a downdraft
here anyway so you get the throttle
0 to 127 makes a helicopter go up
if you turn it high enough Heights OH
I'm anybody remember conservation of
angular momentum
%ah haha okay I taught high school
physics and makes me really sad
on so I I guess I'll give you the
totally intuitive way to think about
this
so you're in mid-air and a helicopter
and you have a giant engine
and he starts spinning this rotor around
above your head
really fast what keeps you from spinning
in the opposite direction
Haxey I this is the second time in a
stock and I've given as
that's like a you know it's like to run
out there knows but say the tail rotor
and then some egos tell rotor yes
that thing on the back who I can do it
my point ever got that thing on the back
there
that actually blows sideways and keeps
the bottom the helicopter from spinning
right just like I considered hysterical
that these things work at all
I'm so this is the sign-in and
this is the first pictures in its kinda
cozy artist too big rotors on a top
actually spin in opposite directions
look at the shape the blades I think a
the top ones clockwise in the bar bottom
one is counterclockwise
and so they spin in opposite directions
and make cut they counteract each
other's angular momentum
and keep your helicopter kind of
pointing forwards right
so there's 8 little dial on the bottom
assists it's the trim
and it's basically trying to adjust if
there's little speed differences between
the top and the bottom
so you can adjust the trim manually to
find the exact center
or arm what I like to do because I have
complete control over this is i
effectively
jam one stick on Wearside an attribute
turn the trim on whether one side
and I can do turns sharper than I can
from actually using the control directly
which is pretty nifty
so I'm that idea this this like back and
forth
that ID attorneys called ewe if you
shake your head no
your yawning your head alright so ya is
this turn back and forth so did you keep
yourself flat picture rotating like a
lazy susan
that is yaw so ya goes from 0 to 127
trim goes from 0 to 127 and sixty-three
the middle
263 means pretty much go forward I guess
said
wasn't my box 63 means pretty much go
forward
arm 0 I think means right one price
Hermes left I remember their
their conscience I get 'em summer I'm
next up tool tailored missile thing it
does happen tailback there
it is AL is yet another fan but it is
pointed the wrong way
right like snot points I was like on a
real helicopter it's pointed up
this is for the with called pitch
pitches another kinda rotation 6 shake
your head
yes let's pitch but with the the
rotation at left his role which is this
way
and our helicopter does not to roll it's
been a 10 bucks for that
so pitch pitch is this nodding her head
yes
this is pitch and so if we if you think
about it if we're
if a blow to little fan way out and I'll
ever like that we're gonna took the
helicopter forwards
right and what happens when we took a
helicopter ford's the giant blade from
atop are now pointing forward to drag
the entire thing for words
right if we want to go backwards what we
do we blow the air
up we tilted back in the entire thing
was backwards
so this gives us enough control to be
able to move this thing in three
dimensions
right me go up and down we can turn it
we can go forward and backwards
right there's some other motions we
can't do but we get pretty close
so pitch also runs 0 to 127
pitch is it important to note that 63 is
of
because if your pitch is not set to of
you say all this at the pitch 20 that
means turn a little fan on in the back
as fast as you can go
in one direction or the other right so
it's important in general
I'm I have stuck my fingers into the
plate service
book at first on purpose to make sure
didn't hurt that much and then by
accident many many other times enough
you might get some bruises you might be
really mad
but so I so I'm the little preparing the
back there was fragile
and I'm I don't wanna like totally freak
out my dog
so I'm make sure when you re setting
stuff you wanna set the pitch back to 63
you want that the fail-safe
10 not have thing spinning on your toy
when you think it stopped thats had
important
on the infrared protocols really easy
there's four bytes one for each setting
I basically just flashes an infrared LED
on little 10 no second 10 microseconds
yet here we go ten microsecond pulses
and then there's positive to in the
polls as the sender is a once and stuff
arm it's actually very very
straightforward and like I said
something else wrote the code for us
so its cool actor helicopters are
awesome money set them aside I want to
talk about are tweeners
this is the eighty mega 320 a chip I'm
it hasn't a bit processor I it has I
think 15
digital input/output pins get some like
six arm
analog input/output pins you can use to
sing to turn like you can turn off the
electricity
and turn on the electricity or read in a
readout electricity on a bunch these
pins
from software it allows you to interact
with the real world very simply
I'm it has 32 kilobytes a flash
it has an awesome easy prompt some RAM
this is an entire computer I'm
not that much less powerful then the
Commodore 64 I started out on
I'm in a chip that you can buy for like
three bucks
I don't like my dad by 10 at them to get
them at three bucks a piece
but this is like this tiny cheap little
embedded controller that you can stick
anything and they are awesome and
amazing they're they're very very very
low
capability but they're so much better
than trying to figure out
electronics I like all that other stuff
to do it all by hand
they're amazing but the problem with
embedded development
is usually get to write the code in C
and the need to cross compile it and
then you this whole thing to upload it
and send it over
and is this enormous pain and he spent
like 700 dollars on the stupid
development kit
and it's just this frustrating messy
thing a group of people
Italy I have this open source hardware
the Arduino and the art we know to know
which is kinda like the main art we know
we're talking about that uses 80 mega
320 a chip that one is less than 30
bucks on Amazon I'm sorry is an Amazon
for everything but
I hit the button and it shows up on
so the its 30 bucks on Amazon and they
give you
this entire development environment that
you can use it to you
embedded development on so if you look
at it you can see this this blog right
here
that's the eighty mega chip that's it
right there that's most up what an
Arduino is an art we know is just
some support stuff for that chip a
top left corner there's a little red
reset button I have it set up so i hit
the reset button
the helicopter stops are right below it
that's a USB plug
and then down the bottom is a power plug
a river plug in the power kazakh a
runoff USB that's what it's doing right
now it's
lights are flashing its running of the
USB power I'm good
I'm super simple straightforward you
talked it over the USB
they have solved all the problems for
you except are matching up like cross
compile C
and then you have to do of the senate
cross they've written a
I T and I D E for you it's not
the most impressive feature rich ID it's
aimed at beginners
and you're writing in this weird kind of
see you can see little hints have some
ways written some javascript before this
as well
arm but it feels very see like and the
best feature is right up here we see
that little
a row you hit the arrow it compiles the
code it sends it over to the Arduino for
you
resets it and your coaches starts
running that's it
I'm so it's taken just massive amounts
of pain
and effort and unhappiness and it's made
into something that I can
hand to my 12 year old cousin and kind
of poke and prod him a little bit and
have been doing real stuff
so when people talk about embedded
development there's a hello world for
the embedded
world a deer well you can't see it cuz I
made it really dark
but yeah there's a type they're seeking
to declare types it feels like see
so we're gonna make i leda were gonna
say thirty most Arduino boards have
an LED on pay him $13 for you are ready
to as a buncha pins you can turn on/off
pin 13 already has an LED on the board
like I said mines working away furiously
and others couple magic function names
such as it's called
so when they are tweeners reset the
setup function gets called
just automatically and work on the spin
mode function
they were basically saying I want pin 13
to be output
this means I'm gonna take him 13 I'm
gonna turn it on and I'm gonna turn it
off
you can all sit input I'm gonna see if
there's electricity they're not but
we're gonna set pin 13 output
we don't have this loop Guadalupe is
gonna do
his is gonna write out to pin 13 says
pin 13
hi that means may collect electricity
come out of it that's what that means
soap in thirteen have electricity come
out a bit way to 1000 milliseconds
so wait a second 1013 go low
shut it off way two thousand of seconds
and that's it so this loop function will
be called
and then once it exits it'll be called
again so you just read a simple little
loop function you don't need to do an
infinite loop yourself
and so this will function is called over
and over again in this is the hello
world it blinks a light on
it turns off points light on it turns it
off
I'm and it's kind of awesome cuz you're
making stuff
in the real world blink I'll be honest
right so
there's a problem though I wanna write
Python I am
I don't like thinking and see I wanna
think in Python I want the real cost of
on real processors arm and so
this is the solution I am I heard a
laugh
so yes though those of us who've been
doing this for a while recognize a db9
port
I am which is how we always the plugin r
1200 baud modems
I am and sometimes three her by Monday
guess but so this is ace
this is what serial ports used to look
like this is a very very basic
extraction of talking to something
you basically have two wires I push
bites that you might push bits
you actually so but I can't read data
stream bites I send bites the you you
can send bites back to me
were the wonderful things about the
eighty mega chip it had is it has a
built-in serial port
and one other wonderful things about the
Arduino Uno
is id will turn that serial port into a
serial port that shows up
on your laptop so you can just talk over
the serial port yard we now
and have your art we no talk back to
your papon program
and all the sudden you're you're
communicating we started shipping
like on my god we've architecture anyway
I'm this is a little bit of a rewrite
above that a that hello world example
what's can we get the
LED 13 we're gonna goes blank line 13
I'm
with senator output but this time we're
adding a serial begin 9600 so we're
gonna listen at 9600 baud
arm don't worry about that means a in
the down here
we've got this serial event this gets
called every time things come in
over the cereal I'm in a serial liar
that we're just gonna read in a bite
if that bite 0
we turn it off if that bite is one
we turn it on right to these are the
exact same things you're doing before to
before we had to sleep in return is
infinite loop
now we're doing it but we're doing it
based on things that are coming in over
the serial I'd
reading in bytes we're turning the light
on and off
and then down here the loop just delays
it just leads for a second so it's not
in a
too fast spin simple enough right this
is very sorry for code
I'm so then what's the pipe on half look
like
pip install pie serial
and then you can import cereal and
create a serial object
I'm that's what a serial ports path
looks like in Linux or Mac
in Windows its you up to like com nine
or something
I'm sayin 9600 baud and then I have an
infinite loop
I write a bite which is one I sleep for
a second
I read by which is zero asleep for a
second so I have to Sri implemented that
hello world flashing
light paying except I've put half the
code
on the Arduino and I have moved when I'm
starting to think about the business
logic
I've slip that over into the pipeline
right
so now comes the fun part hardware
so I this is my attempt at doing a
schematic the
there are a million tutorials out there
about how to blink lights from yard we
now
I'm look at them occurs their stuff you
gonna do about making sure you're using
the right resistor and
you get a good online calculators and
put in details about your LED and stuff
but it's also report
arm for singing to you by Wendys you
feel like a real electronics hobbyist
this is called a breadboard and you can
plug wires into it
and I am like I said feel like a real
Electronix hobbyist I have like three
things plug into mine
but it feels so much more real um
you need wire this is this is this is
not as obvious as you think
you don't want to stop a lot a little
little wires inside you want the solid
core stuff
because then it easier to plug into the
art we know and the
as well as the breadboard I'm
you can buy resistors for like the one
you need in like a five pack for like
four dollars or something or you can
spend twelve dollars and they will
ship you a couple hundred resistors you
get all the fun of sorting through a try
to figure out what all those little
stripes mean
on which once again I'm just into this
to feel like an electronics hobbyist
a so I was all too that I'm gonna find
anyone the suckers
this is an infrared LED you can actually
see it blinking
which is pretty awkward arm but if you
look at your cell phone your cell phone
will pick it up and you can see it
blinking faintly in your cell phone
which is really nifty
um I bought this my local radio shack
I'm
if you still have a local radio shack
you can try that I am
otherwise I found a bunch on Amazon look
like they were good enough I've also
been thinking about cutting out
the ones that are in this cuz I have
enough for these controllers at this
point
I'm so this is the start of our code to
controlled helicopter I we're gonna set
up an array with
ya pitch throttle trim I'm a few in
paying attention you'll notice those are
the safe
values those are the stop moving values
which I want to release stress is a good
idea
arm when things initializing you're
dealing with things in the real world
in general you want things to be turned
off I'm just sayin
arm I actually did some work for friend
then he you
accidentally would flash everything on
and then turn it off as part of his
initialization
which was not really no support we
hooked up to like
relays and stuff that moved in then it
became a real big issue
so you wanna with stuff initializes
everything should be turned
of art so then in the set up we're gonna
say
the pin mode we're gonna say up we're
gonna be doing output the way I hope my
LED up bike
make it go high in order to turn off
whatever
on like that reason tutorials about
flashing LED's I'm
and then we do a serial begin 9600 by
once again we're gonna be
we're gonna be listening on serial port
I'm this is not exactly the most robust
coat but it
works arm I have a up slightly
longer production version is that
actually does like some check some stuff
but
whatever so if his there's four things
available
if we can grab for things out a serial
officer line
was just copy them into the commands
so that a rate that we just initialize
will copy those values in just
verbatim I'm and that's it
so that over here there's the send
packet thing which brings the LED's
I'm its like you blink 74 times to get
the helicopters attention and then you
wait
688 no seconds for one at like 415 all
second 30 or something
whatever it it flashes away this is good
stuff to write
in the Arduino code because it depends
on microsecond precision to do all that
and you bring the LED's in your turn a
time to sleep at the end of this
so you're you're breaking away and then
it says are you know i i wanna sleep for
you know
three hundred milliseconds or whatever
it does and so that in a loop
we send the command and we sleep until
the next time is set to commence again
and that's it that's that's I mean
there's you know there's like 2013 lines
in here but this is it
this is sufficient control helicopter
from their tween aside
was a python side look like well I we
have a helicopter object
I have a path I am this is me being lazy
and not wanting to hard code
I guess it's not lazy one heart Cody in
the TTY
USB 14.11 ever so I search for it I set
up a serial port
I V of pitch throttle and trim
attributes
and then I have a send function which
builds up a little message
writes the message out washes it and
then print it out to the strains I can
see it
that's it that is sufficient code to
control the helicopter from Python
cell I do at some belts and suspenders
I am because I you know I where both
belt and suspenders to keep my pants up
right
so I'm when I'm done with stuff that
moves I like to have as many things I
can hit
or press or freak out about to stop
stuff moving as I possibly can
I'm so in this case I just three times I
write out stop inflation sleep and 96
exit
and is hoping bomb out and stop sending
commands that so
wanna my thanks to mr. im in practice I
tend to hit the big red but more often
right so level 1 I think this is level 1
what is level 1 level one is
this is a 3d turtle that can take your
eye out
so this is a takeoff function we're
gonna set the ya pitch in
and tram of sixty three separate things
in the center we set the problem of
240 we send that and we sleep for five
seconds so we just said
put everything in neutral cracked the
throttle up a little bit sit there for
five seconds
the point in this is the helicopter
knees to sink up with the commands from
the infrared for a little bit
so your it'll be you'll be like that's
not working at all
Daniel for your finger will be there I
am so so this is thought this is time to
to whack your finger take your finger
out and then after supper 5 seconds
he said the problem ninety which is arm
climb
but don't hit the ceiling for me at
least I and he said that in any sleep
for 2nd circuit a little bit about
up and then you set the trial 68 this is
magic
I'm this was one of my helicopters I
don't think I actually another outlet
like two identical ones that look like
this are not but this one or the other
one
but for one of them 68 is the in still
air
kinda popper iraq so
he said that and I we now have a
function we can call
that basically causes a helicopter
takeoff so here's a final program
we create the helicopter object we talk
to take off we set the yada 0
so yeah I is this way so this means
basically take a hard
right I believe we set the pitch to 50
which is titled back slightly
we send thats are basically saying spin
backwards
for just the for a lil you know and for
a 10 seconds
and then we sail and which if you're a
member resets everything in crashes on
the program
okay so as can level one very basic
superfine your typing things that I
papon prompt and stuff is moving
arm and it's great so level two
this is what I do with everything are we
make web API so
from this is a complete flask ap I
believe
that provides a Web API and you can post
ya pitch throttling trim values to it I
am it reads them and from you know the
request and then it goes in set/sets
ESPN on helicopter in that sense it a
helicopter
and returns the helicopter what the
helicopters guys have been sector
I am so yeah that works
you now taken this toy helicopter and
you've made it available over the
Internet
I did this for the drumset want
something magical I am
alright so then level 3 this is my most
my Saturday mornings for the past
couple months I'm if you see the little
dot at actually me
finding LED I told to the blinking LED
was useful
finding the blinking LED with open CV
are some trying to track the helicopter
so I use open CV to fire a guy get the
video capture object at the tracker
is by the way the only need part my code
the code inside I'm
the code inside the trackers is pretty
disgusting
arm but so I try to handle its frame I
grab a sequence is a images of have
webcam
I tracked LED on the front and a
helicopter and then I'm trying to crack
for drift and hold it still
on there are much easier where his to
control helicopter make it hold still
by I wanted to play with open CV and P
ID loops and industrial control
technologies and stuff
I'm I've seen people do things like this
with a.m.
x-box connect and get much better result
much less effort
I'm but I but I'm having more fun I am
so
this calls of course for a live demo I
was actually told if I don't have a
helicopter flying over the audience
I failed so um will see what I can do
for you
I'm I also asked my like like I know a
couple people front row and Mike
get ready to catch this I so
of course I wrote a little Ajax thing
I am and i'ma see here
yeah come on ok great see I was up here
before and I was working fine
turn off again yes that that does make a
difference sometimes
sure
German however you
sana crank the crack at most the way
well II
and year
I so I
via the LED I got has a waco
30-degree angle so I have this car loan
I can fly an
and you all sorts of the edges account
that 1i safety features the aircraft is
it drops out the sky
when you're not saying it commands
anymore I'm so
world think so I really want to stress
about all this
is that its almost all just software I'm
you're making things move in the real
world but you're controlling of from
software
and the feeling you get the first time
you typed commands
at a command prompt and physical stuff
actually moves
is amazing I'm if you have kids you're
trying to get interested in programming
get them playing with an Arduino and
moving things as just it's just magical
like to giggle fits that happen
I'm you know one wonders if this
helicopter is like i said i bruised my
fingers
I'm but it's it's not that dangerous I'm
it now just noise my dog on but
point I'm trying to make is this is
software you can mess around with this
you can play with us you can do all
sorts of wonderful things
and you should do so are many should
help those around you do so
I and I've got wings on my blog in jail
but US we can buy all the stuff
and do it iraq thank you very much money
was a Jackson lovely
mejía on Twitter's what's up on in jail
.us
and time for questions one question
one question no questions
alright how ok a question question
II do II UN UN
on so salata magic values but then you
also showed that
you know you're using in computer vision
to controlled reference up
so whenever you build a new helicopter I
mean each jessica's cuts made it was
gonna have it so much
values yep have you tried to use
generation to basically set those values
they just left fly and then set the
values for that particular
that's what I've that's what I've been
trying to do but they are so I'm
like a little breeze will cause them to
to start going wild
so it's pretty hard I've been trying to
do a Pido perdon I mean you can like
machine learned about his for PI
the loop and I've been failing miserably
at that but having a wonderful time
I have Ubuntu scratches my computer
screen actually arm from
from trying to fly it between me and my
laptop and then things going horribly
awry
which has been fun and dude okay one
more
okay arm so we have way too many these
helicopters
my office and we also no such thing ap
and we also starting something like
thirty dollar quadcopter
YES on juneau protocol
weird I have I spent so much time
googling
and the river set so the question is
have other protocols in reverse
engineered
I'm Simon makes this whole like giant
Ranger these things
there's a bunch of other are
manufactured in China gorgeous churning
out clones and variations and
copies I'm I found at the reverse
engineering at this I found it on like
some message board
like two years ago from some guy who
lectured appointed hey look what I did
in like 10 way
so I V its what are these have been done
there's lotsa stuff out there
arm and I just not a comparable in size
or scope
so I just 11 diagnosed in reverse
engineered but if you go around as a
bunch other ones out there
i kno cuz I tried several them wondering
if they were the right ones for this
helicopter actually
some thank you you're welcome thank you
very much everybody