welcome everyone
and we've got a great speaker ahead of
us and
this is no I can't ritz with Python
packaging
as I cased alright welcome
I apologize for any one that saw this
was originally called
what's coming in by the packaging but
unfortunately or fortunately in the
roughly six months since I wrote the
proposal most the stuff that I was going
to say is coming soon is actually
happened
so this will be more of a a review of
the last 18 to 24 months
think it's a real estate to trade for
months
by the vaccine development but first a
little bit about me
on the infrastructure lead for the final
topper foundation where the organizers
up icon
by day I do server automation operations
work for balance payments
very involved the chef community and I
really like making things
also disclaimer this list is not in any
specific order not chronological number
importance it's just the order that I
could we've best presentation so don't
take this as an endorsement or
disparagement of any particular features
to getting started with a couple
org chart changes in Python community
the first major one
was the creation of the Python packaging
authority or pie PA
on this is now a group operating outside
the seat height on development team
although there is some overlap some
people were to spend both groups that's
handling most of the non-standard the
packaging
troll development in organizations such
things like pip setup tools virtual and
all that now lives under the pikey a
umbrella organization
second was the appointment love new
packaging DFL Nick cop-one
arm hope where pronounce that correctly
democrat for me
earlier but never sure these things
anyway he was appointed by kedo as the
packaging the DFL just means that he can
directly except perhaps related for
packaging
without the discussion moving on the
Python dev anyone's on Python dove
probably understand why this is a very
good thing
additionally rich Jones has taken back
the man to love PDF l4 the Python
package index itself
so he is back on the saddle for managing
anything where we need to break
compatibility we do try to file perhaps
and he's allowed to accept those
necessary on the actual features
I most you probably use the Python
package indexer pipes GI for short
either host your own packages or two
find libraries to use amid a lot of
improvements to that
biggest one in my mind is
a lot of TLS improvements we actually
use each
yes now arm and we support all the
latest goody is like
strips transport security say
automatically default %eh
yes trying to keep it much more secure I
we also offer perfect forward secrecy so
that
if keys are leaked how that ever
happened I no one can be crept past
record a traffic
on this one not actually
as recent as some this %uh for
mentioning but a lot of people don't
know exists
there is a chase on API of sorts for the
Python package index image that slash
chase on
tienda by their package for version URL
you'll get all the data of that page
NJ some format so if you have a reason
to need all the packaging information
you could ever possibly want
his real easy way to grab it I we now
have a
CDN powering are the paperback to tax
so its run by fast Lee who gloriously
sponsors it for us
they do a jew distributed caching system
based around varnish
with in automated static fallback so if
our servers
self-destruct we move to a the
Bandersnatch managed
static nearer in another data center
misled to vastly improve performance
for people that don't live outside the
US since the servers are no longer a
single box
somewhere in Oregon and just generally
improve stability
I because of the CDN
and combined with the fact that a lot of
the public mirrors were becoming
increasingly fragile
many of them were breaking or no longer
updating had to be kicked every couple
weeks are they fall under sink
with no deprecated the public near
network have you previously read article
couple Moss is wonderful post on
how to use mir's please disregard all of
that are my love to to take up in a very
glad that he wrote that
but no longer needed on we've removed
the DNS entries for them
and tip no longer ship support from
public near network and we have
deprecated in your authenticity ATI
that have been removed but I'd believe
it schedule removed in September
also topic amir's up 3-1 client has been
the workhorse for maintaining
local an internal mirrors for a very
long time it's now largely considered
deprecated in favor a vendor snatch
if you'd like to maintain a local here
in it certainly encourage it if you have
large-scale deployments or if you just
don't want to worry about us being down
even though fortunately that's now very
rare
Bandersnatch is definitely the tool use
a DEP TRAI is also somewhat recent
addition
its primary function is not nearing but
it can act as a
partial hearing tool sewers better
snatch large is used for keeping there
is a the entire
Python package index dope I heard FBI
can mirror only what you accessed
through it as a caching proxy
and finally warehouse so warehouse grew
out of the now-defunct Creteil project
so don't go to create I only more think
it's now being used by some other
company
but it is going to turn into I don't act
index 2.0
we have a demo site up at Warehouse top
I found at work
it currently supports package
installation
search and most of the TI's you cannot
yet upload packages to it
and I think user authentication is being
added very shortly
onto how do you actually get packages
from those servers
so again you might notice a pattern here
I think some the most important stuff is
around safety
possibly added in pip TLS verification
and we've deprecated external links and
dependency links
just means that you can now actually be
relatively certain that you'll be
downloading packages:
in a safe and verified matter
also pepper 453 landed when Python 2.4
shipped or is it landed a little earlier
but is now live
for those that don't know insure pip is
the module that we're shipping basically
meaning it is now part of the pipe on
standard library
are not quite actually lives in a
slightly different category but socially
speaking
if someone installs Python 3.4 on any
platform be it from the source tarballs
or in red hat or any other platform is
expected the PIP will be available
%uh this means we now can finally put
easy install to bed
this is a very very nice thing
no more easy and stop it
on two wheels so for those
that have played with them a little bit
you've probably seen their basally
simplified installation format
notably they don't require executing any
codes
the wheels grew out of the old setup
tools eg concept
instead of having a source distribution
file the pic downloads unpacked and run
setup i install which is what it does
now
that the the wheel format has things
effectively
in the floor mat they need to be when
they're installed on the system's a pic
unjust
on Packers a file in a very specific way
but you don't have to actually
run any codes do installs this means
that
ok this means that installs are
faster and much safer since you're not
executing arbitrary code from the
internet
turns out that's not always a good idea
downside wheels are definitely still
feel that development if you have pure
Python stuff they're wonderful you
should use them now
if you have see extensions or other
binary packages
you may want to look and play with them
a little bit before you
you going whole hog on Windows and OSX
because they have
very stable and long-term platform level
ADI's
it's relatively easy to know that if you
compile one channel work on another
that's not quite the case with 1x
unfortunately the wheel center doesn't
currently have any way to express the
complexity is when Xavi's I but we are
working on that
if you'd like to get started with wheel
today you can just pick install we'll
and instead of doing Estes store be just
as you can to be dis real
and finally on the getting side is a
tool called conduct this was written by
continuing analytics
relatively new entrant into the
installer field and maintain
made aimed mainly at scientific
environments
it can use a general-purpose installer
but there are some security concerns are
still working out so I wouldn't
necessarily recommend that much you need
its
a extra features which are largely based
around
scientific packages which need large
binary
barred binary installations things like
psychic learn UNFPA
live side by things like that where you
really don't wanna be compiling the
source largely
because of time and complexity
constraints if you're not doing
heavy number crunching scientific
analysis you may not need to be using
Honda
onto using packages so you've downloaded
them it has done some stuff depending on
the format
now you actually use packages so Vienna
is the evolution a virtual int it
shipped in Python 3.3
the script you call is slightly
different now Heidi Anderson a virtual
and but otherwise the internals
a are vastly cleaned up and the usage is
largely the same
distribute is gone a big thanks to PG
for
helping to emerge setup tools and the
community for distribute back together
like I said before they're both now
operating under the party a and have
resumed using the setup tools name
anywhere where you were installing
distribute any kind of Scripture
anything just replace it settles
and finally just utils to it did briefly
and up to the standard library
under the name packaging however it
ended up being removed because there are
some concerns when a plantation xanax no
longer under development
so if you were waiting for just a little
too sorry to disappoint them
and now making packages
so improvements the meta-data tip now
supports the idea pre-release is so if
you upload something
with dash alpha or dash beta people
understand that and will only install
them if
specifically requested by the end user
means that you can do pre-release
testing and release candidates and
same manner there's also kept for 26
creatively named
meta-data 2.0 this is my trying to take
all the meta-data that we should have
crammed into packages in weird places
over the years
put in one place but in Jason format
have standardized values
as far as applauding packages %uh so a
lot of people use Python setup.py upload
as their uploader
on there is a new project called twining
which is trying to pull all that update
lauder
upload logic out of dis utils the
measure this is we can update it
in a much faster way that we can
standard library we're not worried about
maintaining compatibility and things
like that the same way
twine I would highly recommend using it
now just utils for example does not
support
TLS verification uploads doesn't support
the upload a previously created
artifacts things like that
definitely check it out I'm probably
doing was offered a service even
mentioning it because it was shut down
due to non use
but I S H has been removed I'm sorry to
be four hundred people than ever used it
and finally the died up previously
called The Hitchhiker's Guide to
packaging now the Python packaging user
guide is available at package and %uh
Python org
it's basically an expanded version
everything I'm talking about here i
different checking out
and the few things that are still coming
soon like a mention meditated 2.0
is still under active discussion it sort
of the blocker right now for
most future efforts everyone's trying to
sort of centralize around getting meta
data 2.0
before we all go often use all the new
meta data in new and exciting ways
to other things that her right on the
cusp of being
discussed his estas 2.0 real 2.0
I'm like I said the wheel format has
some issues with binary compatibility
yes just format hasn't changed and what
twelve years now
things like that its it's about time for
those both to get our a once-over
especially in light of the new metadata
format
so if you're interested in pursuing
those discussions I will have
slides for you in a moment and also
coming soon like I mentioned warehouse
the hope is that sometime in the next
six months range that will be full
featured enough to
replace the existing project code base
at which point we will
just switch it from warehoused apartment
or it.i to 500 organ welcome our new
warehouse overlords
I do definitely recommend that if you
have anything that's doing a lot of
non-standard scripting or using a judge
directly
on I P I did you try them with the
warehouse top 100 or test site and
report any bugs
fine so when we do that switch over you
will not be suddenly surprise and broken
so what if you'd like to help us out so
like I mentioned the pikey a team has
taken over a lot of projects
they are sort of split though some stuff
is up and get help but notably pip
virtual and warehouse are all manage
into the pipe he ate organization on get
help
and setup tools heiii the old code base
and the wheel libraries and tooling are
under the pikey organization on
pickpocket
so if you're looking about these
projects just make sure you end up in
the repository
there's also an IRC channel on freenode
IRC
pound I T A a lot of the packaging
developers both from the pikey eighty
men from the standard the team even
though most
those are the same people hang out in
their so if you have any questions would
like to
learn more about how to help just jump
in there we also have the
venerable old issue till signaling
listed still going strong
it is definitely the primary
communication point for most packaging
discussions
there used to be another mailing list if
you were on it you got a notification
this catalog sega has been merged into
this detail saying that was the old
heiii specific mailing list so long live
digital sig
and finally sprints warehouse team a few
of them anyway
will be here and will be sprinting
during the pike on Sprint's on warehouse
if you'd like to join them
fine Richard Jones or any of the other
pipe CA folks and asked me how about
analytic lows with just a few shutouts a
first doll stuffed most you have never
heard
Donald stuffed and unfortunately wasn't
able to make up to Montreal
but I counted he has worked on at least
90 percent of the things that I
mentioned today
and basically runs Python packaging
makes all this happen
we all owe him a beer
and another shutout for nicaraguan a for
taking the way
love being the packaging BD FL on
shoulders I have certainly disagree with
in the past but he is the hero Gotham
needs
and finally our sponsors I just a quick
shout out to some response urs fastly
Rackspace dine
King Dom Pedro the DreamHost and
everyone else if I didn't get you into
my slide notes
without them we wouldn't be able to run
heiii or any of our other PSS services
so a big thank you to all of our
sponsors and thank you
and it has the questions
you could just go to Microcenter make
sure you step toward Mike could you
actually go back to Donald slide cuz
he's on our team. I wanted to get a
picture that to santo
thank you know as a
frequent power up library perpetrator I
wonder should I upload
Estes and wheels now yes you should
definitely still be uploading assests
will be
a long time before everyone's installers
are updated sport wheels
so legacy is legacy and there's no
downside uploading both something sports
we'll
will use real and life will be great and
otherwise you get status quo
could be worse I you mention that you're
going to be doing some improvements to
the lawn Xabi
tagging are can you give us any teasers
about what that might look like
is it going to be partly for 25 hours is
just in the air at this point
it's very much in the air there's a lot
of competing discussions about how best
to handle it
and I don't feel qualified to report on
those
in my preparations for pie thompson's
like I said above the organizers I've
been a little bit analyst for about two
weeks now
which is a long time these days which
trickle
that's that's a long time the world
packaging hi
do you know if there are any plans for
virtual improper
to become part of the standard library I
don't think so nor have I heard any
desire expressed on the part of the
march on proper authors
stuff ending up in the Central Library
drastically limits its ability to
to change and evolve over time so its it
is a mixed blessing
a virtual unfortunately was stable and
often did exactly one thing to do with
that was so it's not really big deal but
virtually rappers that myself growing
cell
not sure that would really be dust so I
just checked and evidence
still has incher disabled and 2.4
their three per package do you know if
there's plans to
reinstate that there's a fix Nikon but
so areas waving his hand
so so the I I kind of lost a little bit
the deal is that the end goal is that
if you install python 3.4 you get insure
paper is the way that we are supporting
that
for our sources traditions but the
the actual pet only specified that
people be available some
or distributors like Debbie and Red Hat
would prefer to not use interpret
because they want to continue
managed via their tooling so instead
most of them are changing the Python
virtual package to depend on the actual
fight on and on the pay package
so that they can continue the to like if
they have to do security releases or
certainly anyone that has the long-term
support releases can continue to use
their trolling for that
but you can still if you installed by
the way for and keep is not available
and working
it's about yet there is one thing with I
am
I don't know if it's been fixed but at
least when you called pay bien
it would fail because it couldn't find
incher there's an open Debian bug on
that
great thank you to questions
may be out at my ignorance with Kanda
but
a scientist at wills theoretically
should solve the problem of distributing
all that buying repeal trades so your ex
and
oh this is primarily for scientific
computing could you elaborate on these
will we need Kanda and what would be its
role these
distribution business I would certainly
love if Khan there was no longer
necessary book on the
does a lot more than just managing
haifong stuff
it's really designed to be are
installing work low tool for scientists
and number crunchers
but don't wanna know the details what
Python package even is
arledge wanna to push a couple buttons
and run something and they get
environments do their computing I would
certainly love it ends up being at that
point but like I said conder can also
install stuff it's not quite unrelated I
think
so I'm not sure that would really be in
scope
others definitely been talk at some
point francis conrad is a meditative
servers
we would love to eventually merge that
into warehouse so that it can be a
single ecosystem even if it's too
insular tools
and never got Mexican questions thank
what would you recommend to you
holes private packages to host private
packages and set up like pushing to pipe
I it's
de PI unequivocally it is the best tool
by leaps and bounds thanks thanks very
much
we have a little time for questions
going wants going to whites
okay kept on this time and
take now