good afternoon
our next talk is designing politically
PI's I aircrews
Eric works at Mozilla and by your
account right way too many bite on my
marriage
pre-game warm welcome
Wow thanks for packing and out in here
guys is a fantastic
up today we're going to take a look at
psychology and anthropology
and history of our own field and public
figure out how to write
more beautiful API's before we get
started I have a confession to make
which is that I am not a poet
unfortunately I know
but potent programmers we have a lot in
common
we both deal with very precisely
formulated language
and we both make up new terms backed
programmers do this
all the time whenever you name a
variable or coin new function
you're essentially making up a new piece
language if this invention have language
and the mental processes the go on with
that an akita rating excellent API's
it's vital that we create new language
with care
because the language you use influences
the thoughts that you can think
have ever had anyone to tell you should
colorless been go learn haskell it'll
change the way you think about
programming
yeah well there's something to that as
it turns out
there's a sold a psychological theory
called the superior work hypothesis
and how goes is the language that you
speak
determines in limits thought that you
can think and
soon as shaking her head there yes it
has gone out of fashion lately
but there was some evidence released
anecdote in its favor for a while
for example take the case a Ildefonso a
Mayan man who was born deaf
into a poor family and so they didn't
have a lot of resources to invest in
things like a
sign language training or lip reading
and so he was actually brought up
without language he didn't acquire
language until he was 27 years old
and during this early period of his life
he couldn't do math
with quantities beyond 10 for obvious
reasons
but now that he has language for and
he's received training he can do just
fine you can calculate with the best of
them
because he has the language for it now
for this strong sapir work hypothesis
which I'm still getting better looks
from someone about
has been disproved by counter example
when you can be connected to this is a
thought experiment
here we are in Montreal a bilingual City
and satisfying translations are possible
when I came into the airport I want to
grab a sandwich I got in late
I went to Subway the guy was making my
sandwich spoke French
I spoke English we used fresh words in
english words and
girls have language we use I would've
gotten the same sandwich out afterwards
pickens time write some
some pretty down-and-dirty philosophy
now you can translate that
that very precise German into English
and the
argument still make sensor at least say
much since they did for
but there's still a flavor to each
language right
who has an accused a colleague are you
reading job in Python knock it off
you're in Python a standard expire in 10
ml
bite on naturally makes you reach for
hash tables
functional languages make use of things
in terms of map unfold
JavaScript everything's a closure and
this is the week form
disappear work hard but we're fed up her
work hypothesis
which I dare you to say five times fast
and I think it does hold
but the language you use influences
a thought for you think now I'm getting
not thank you so
the balance at this influence have been
marked out experimentally
for example in English we don't have a
whole lot a good words
four colors in the red orange range now
if you show an English speaker bunch of
color swatches
they can certainly distinguish between
them visually but
if you can distract them with a card
game or something and bring them back
later
they won't be able to remember us what
you ask them to remember
if it didn't have a hand in a min their
language so it seems that having a
symbol for something a word for
something
makes it mentally later wat when you
draw simple like
red over budget details like well 632
617 animators wavelength
it acts like a mental abstraction you
can kick all the details out of your
head
and say that mental space for
higher-level pursuits like building
sentences with the word red abstracting
out symbols
is the root all human language
but it's also the route all software
engineering
now the pointer software engineering
what differentiates it from just hacking
around spaghetti code
is making supper intellectually
intelligible by finding good
abstractions
tough talk about API's in creating an
API
you make up your own symbols and their
meanings functions
variable names data structures and with
the names and semantics that you choose
you shape all future thought about that
system
remembered all the fun so couldn't get
above the number 10 until we had the
word sport
when you make a good API you give those
who come after you
including your future self those numbers
after 10
letting people think the thought that
they couldn't before
for example let's take a look at your
lip to versus requests
right so you're a live do is pretty
horrendous labor boasts it's hard to do
common things
part about it is because it has a
greater scope and is a shitty p but i
picking on it
requests a third party library have
become a rapid defacto standard
because introduces this brilliant new
symbol called the
HTTP request
and i think is even more brilliant
because apparently some people have
already heard of this abstraction and
had in their heads already
so one thing you can do is ask yourself
what a naive user
imagine my API should look like if there
are already existing symbols out there
just make them work that's easy one now
it's silly to try to turn good design
into a process that you can follow
or for real you can apply but I've got
hadn't taken a swing at anyway
there some requests code for comparison
so today I'm gonna give you
seven rules of thumb that you can use as
a checklist
he may not give you good design for free
but it will guide you along and it will
keep you from
up falling off all the worst clips
so the first principle is something not
to do
don't be an architecture astronaut my
first step in designing a new library
is actually two not designed a new
library
it's all well and good to try to do good
design the abstract
but design is basically imagination and
imagination
is little more than half part the sizing
and you know from history what happens
when you have part the size without
continually bring those high parties
back down to earth and testing them
against reality
you end up with alchemy rather than
chemistry right
it can be academic interesting it can be
visually impressive art sparks in bright
colors
but when it comes down to it it's just a
self-consistent certain
nonsense not a lot of practical value
that im gonna go love that led
so to bring our efforts back in Akkar
them in the realm of science
remember that the best libraries are
extracted not invented
what this means is he should have one
hopefully even to or as many as you can
Consuegra
applications that already do what your
library was going to do
and then you take the better than their
in common and you factor them up
into your library for example I wrote a
plugin called knows progressive
plugs into the popular test framework
knows and its purpose in life is to
display a progress bar
and fancy trace backs and just generally
make output easier to crock
now makes use a lot of terminals keep
codes for things like colors and bold
and positioning
and the code looks something like this
love terminal setup kinda intertwined
with the operative code lotsa
abbreviations for different betterment
purse strings
and there ought to I rock term capital
SGR 0 not very friendly thanks
are see the FAQ looking aside the
documentation to figure out what they
mean
every time I have to do some formatting
I would think
oil shares a decent abstraction around
this I would have to look at all the
time
and this is the magic point when you
have a real useful program with a
library struggling to get out
that you should come down from orbit and
start thinking about library design
in this case I ended up extracting the
terminal handling into lab recalled
blessings
and I want to use it as the first
example our extraction process
the first thing to do is dump everything
on the workbench
I what sort of things up a library to do
well want to print some texts for
mattered
any weapons and text may be at a
location like the bottom screen with a
progress bar is
and then snap back to what we were doing
up by the trace backs
what tools do we have well got
everything that's in a different
language
we've got functions with option a large
in positional arcs
we've got to decorators those are fun
context managers
and classes let you do inheritance but
we also have
common patterns the come from a culture
and from the thing at the library
encourages
again weeks after work sequences taken
for the brown iterators
and mappings then we shake the workbench
up
and we see if you can find some good
pairings between these things
what guys you in this consistency
you have the entire technical and
culture with the language
as well as the accumulated habits have
influential libraries and the programmer
community behind you
or designing website we think this way
people spend ninety percent other time I
other people sites
so yet put your logo on the upper left
to make it like your homepage
but Login link in the upper right call
your shopping cart shopping cart not
take up basket
make your links blue and so on now when
you're reading an API
you can use the same sort of thing users
spend ninety percent other time
calling other people's API's so if you
have to you can be weird and clever
but if you can stick with conventions
you get a lot of bonuses
first bought your conveyor spektr users
you're not some
outsider who's gonna come in to make
their code a massive clashing styles
bad case conventions and weird fact
rings how many times have you
encountered a job API masquerading as a
python one
thrown away in disgust second you'll get
learning speed and retention
if it's the same as everything else
there's less to learn in Leicester
member
as the brilliant thing about the early
mcintosh project
they had explicit written down Human
Interface Guidelines because
very soon after hiring the first
programmers they heard a whole buncha
technical writers
every program had the same commands
open/close quit copy/paste
and they all lived in the same menus and
had the same keyboard shortcuts
so in a very real sense when you learned
one program you had learned the mall
now API design is the same in so many
ways
as UI design and we can apply a lot of
the same principles
like the principal love least
astonishment so try to surprise the user
if you implement up some kinda mapping
type
and you have something that acts a lot
like a python mapping
you should call its gets get method get
should take
key and then default should call batch
universe
the arguments people pick it up faster
and remember it
better if you just plain old get plus
you get polymorphism
right I'm if you're consistent things
Hannah
how likely happen to you like I like a
substitute addict in
for my read us riding a mapping class
and use it to mock something's up my
tests or I can even
deploy small sites just using a big
ramírez in a dictionary is that have
talking over a socket and having a
set-up cost
so coming back to our terminal for
Manning example how we bang those tasks
against are justing language features
and conventions
well here quantity over quality rules
and to the same color of my views on
designing you are just get as many
alternatives out there on the workbench
as possible I call these my sketches
now for printing something at a location
there really only two choices
but for these are okay but second one
gives us the flexibility of putting
multiple statements inside
loops another calls out other functions
and then you could easily write printout
the first one in terms of the second one
to the second one is the winner here the
sketches for text formatting
we've got some square brackets in there
we've got some dots and some string
concatenation
couple function calls with keyword
arguments summer positional
required arguments now most of these
separate the printing from the
formatting
action to a good idea but to the first
one combine them together
I have a couple papers here there's this
one
it gives you a very familiar nested
function call syntax its composable
and frankly look a lot like HTML so poet
from ear to ear wide swath your audience
trouble is that didn't happen to be a
portable way up
turning off bold in terminals so that
was kinda out
now this I am
this just uses attributes and say that's
a great deal complexity went to score a
waste stayed to have any kind of
a big stable object for dragging around
remember if we turned on bold so that we
can meet the code later
now we just admit he met the exact
terminal codes as attributes are trial
class
now to support the nesting case
I should mention on notice that I'm
using this with Python's built-in
arm template formatting
syntax to buy being considerate language
features we get this for free without
ever on tumbling language which so many
terminal language
trouble for many libraries do
now support nest in case we have this
kinda mash it altogether syntax
red ball Orica said Red Bull Don white
now admittedly this is a bit novel but I
kept this example in the consistency
section because
I think it's really good to see that
these principles are all about
trade-offs
we can't just for all the knobs all the
way up to 11 or you just do that all the
time
and we would need to think about this at
all and I wouldn't be giving the stock
so if you're going to do something a
little bit weird at least be
self-consistent this mashed together
multi word syntax
is used for everything a6 formatting
foreground color background color it's
hard to get it wrong
you can put the for matters in any order
and it just works
and there's cashing for speed to not to
worry about using some favored
representation
to the user doesn't have to keep on
making a trip back to the docs
the internalize one slightly weird idea
and that carries them through all the
use cases
another released report example this is
jane goes RM syntax
got those double underscores right
nobody else does at
but this is used consistently throughout
the RM you learn at once
and you played everywhere
so when your belly when your consistency
watch out for these red flags
if you find yourself really referencing
your own documentation
or the source code library previously
written
as your building the stuff up I when I
call that tonight but the
argument in this order that order maybe
you should go back and I try to clarify
things
if you feel like you're inventing novel
syntax
make sure you stop and check yourself
you should judgment when you do novelty
make sure that it pays off
rather than just shows up
our thermal today's brevity how to make
common think short
in tokens I'm in but sometimes even in
terms of characters if it doesn't hurt
your inability to much
user excerpt from earlier and I will go
into I used to smash together syntax
little bit more
since formatting something and then
returning to plain text is the most
common operation
we try to make it shortest here's a
shortcut
these two lines are cooked you can
actually use this is a string like above
or you can just call it and it's cooked
but not everything has to be brief
this for example is a way to get down
and dirty and really control exactly
that bites that you're admitting
now most people don't need this they can
do the easier thing above but if you
wanna get down crazy in dirty
the slower thing lets you do it at the
cost of just being a little bit longer
the general principle is you should pay
for what you get
ask yourself these questions about
pretty you find yourself
cupping chunks of code from your
examples
it's probably too hard to type that
stuff
do you find yourself typing something
irrelevant saying I have to pass true
for this argument always true
why can't you just assume that well that
the default right there
another is to manifest is very long
argument lists on
you could be missing defaults maybe just
every complex data every better
encapsulated as a class they can
intention it once and then commented on
impossibility making your abstractions
composable means being able to reuse
them
in lots of different situations and put
them together in unforeseen ways
other million ways to say this of
flexibility loose coupling
small pieces loosely joined it all comes
down to the minimisation
assumptions other two ways you can go
about this
want the wrong let's go back to another
worker done by six
we could have a jammed together printing
and formatting on one go like this now
my friend Jeff lost put together a
really neat bulletin board system called
X 84
it's really old school it works over
telnet and it uses blessings
in a multi-process design I fog patches
got server process for most of the
action happens including the formatting
and then it doles out our two children
processes which
handle each socket each client
connection so
with the first line here there's no way
to past the output to the children
effect neither these first one personal
scores first one
because we assume that there's that
coupling that printing and formatting
would happen all in one go
now the wrong way to solve this a
beeline to at an option
say pass in a filehandle but now your
balls gotta
instantiate some file handler strongly
object even if you just want to keep
that string in memory
but makes the API more complicated
you've got a document that option
you gots to put a branch in your code
for it
and then you gotta write test the test
that branch
every time I think about adding an
option I look around for any other
escape route first
so a better way here is to break that
coupling at the assumption point
dividing into two orthogonal pieces
print
and format now because we've all the
composer ability rule of thumb and
blessings like this
Jeff was able to stick format strings
into memory really easily and pass them
off to a child processes
and despite the fact that he started X
84 10 years before but things even
existed
& imy a lot of architectural commitment
and decisions it was really easy
retrofit
because it minimizes assumptions are
made
so watch out for these red flags and
compose ability
classes with a lot state make me think
that there are multiple little classes
inside
just struggling to get out each serving
a single purpose
so other pylas text search connection
object library for talking to elastic
search for Python
and it needed a penalty box for elastic
church nodes that work responding
and wanna keep on trying these know that
they were responding a given five or ten
minutes to recover
now I was tempted at this directly to
the connection object
but I found out it was better back to
separate them
at a separate thing I can now use this
and other projects and this doesn't even
know
doesn't even assume it's for connections
all it happens to have any is
Buehrle's represent the nodes a
commitment from there it doesn't care
all it knows is you can be a bunch of
things you tell me which ones are dead
and alive
and I run a timer and give you wanna
random
another thing you have to watch out for
is deep inheritance hierarchies
people say in their right to the
composition is better than inheritance
and here's why they say that if you
inherit your object does get easy access
to the functionality the parents
that much is true but it also inherits
all the invariant baggage parent s it's
required
to maintain those in variance what
you've done now is just increase
the attack surface if you like the
amount of codesa tiptoe around
those in variance
the law of Demeter at the says if you do
choose to compose objects
no cheating so vlasic search contains
penalty box object US the church object
can call methods
on that penalty box but if not comment
heads
object inside the penalty box so the
covers the 1.1
it up be is fine it upbeat at sea is
less fine a lot be a C-dot
D is right out good if you decide you
reaching and everything like that you're
making assumptions all over the place
and there's no point putting up these
objects to begin with you might evolve
might want to solve dumped in one
namespace
marking and tests I above two minds
about market I think
if you hundreds of marking up too many
dependencies your code
you could estimate independence for
example how to test
this you have to reach into sis
and mark out maybe standard how to
minimum effort put back afterwards and
marking library maybe to help you do
that easily on the other hand this
doesn't require any market just compare
the returned string and bring about
printing
test will code is decoupled Co
and then finally bolt-on options look
out for those
another rule of thumb the helps with
reusability is plane data
sort of native data types
whenever possible your API should speak
with its callers using
simple built-in types Dixon in and
strings
not big hairy custom data structures
and the aim here which should be
sounding eerily familiar now is to
reduce
barriers to reuse what a barrier
all barriers the config parser class are
the Python standard lip
and is that excerpt of its API its
purpose in life history windows style
I and i files now unfortunately convict
parser is not just a parser that does
its job and translate for file into a
stringer
couple a dictionary is mister
dictionaries or whatever and get that
way
now it hangs around and you have to
write your entire program in terms
a bit API under but has option calls and
and get calls all over the place
but they're not idiomatic Python thinks
I get for example it's not your normal
get it section option
not key default at a little confusing
and you can imagine even has option
section option
we care about the whole thing as when s
the map you know
bracket section back adoption and away
you go
and later I if you want to make your
program more flexible and people &
Gamble configuration or something else
I you're still stuck to this API right
you have to put if senior Cody shiny to
configuration
we have to write your own abstraction
layer on top of this
so only pick on it a little bit more and
liar just a little bit about AP I'm
gonna say has a a read
command which it does it takes a single
file name: which actually doesn't
this might feel like a convenient since
configure often comes out files
actually its a bear a method should take
what it needs
in no more you need string
you need to file for any reason the
config files not 500 megabytes
can be seeking around in it there's no
reason it a filehandle
now if you want at the convenience back
that's fine you can a helper function
like file contents can be used in
combination with this
string taking method or you can now you
can go ahead and add a convenience
function also that does both parts
but make sure you also provide the core
method that takes the minimum thing it
needs
even when you have an inherently more
complicated data structure
cunt exposed as much of it as possible
has built-in interface
this little snippet from Beiber that I'm
working on called spider funk
and it does static analysis JavaScript
code
now I was ashamed to find
in my travels that I actually did a
doubly linked
tree to represent the abstract syntax
tree a
simply link wouldn't do it I could just
have nested lists
I need to be able to walk from the
analysts out to the other lists were up
the tree
so I had to make this node class and
it hurt my soul but there you have it
but the first thing I did was to break
back into the Python idiom by exposing
things as a had a built-in language
constructs in this case
a try transit up the tree as an iterator
now because I then expose this is
something that the language kinda gives
preference to
I could do pretty complicated things
with such a little one-liners like this
comprehension generator expressions
this fines with scope a penny a
javascript St node
by walking on up and taking the first
one that looks like a school be kinda
node so if you can't have pointed
everywhere
get back to it ASAP
I get a warning signs if users take your
output immediately change it to
something else
bucks at a given the something else if
conversely
you make them instantiate some massive
custom object
just to pass a tour Tina viewers well
maybe should just take those individual
things individually
unless you see them using lobbies in
bundles
and if you find yourself rewriting
things that the language already
provides in different terms
like convict parser had that get things
took a section in a key
where it's really just one key access
two key access
so I have this idea that you have my API
should spend most of their time in the
group
and I don't just mean performing well or
doing their work easily
I mean it in a more strictly physical
sets so
if you think a programming as walking
across a plane
and there's this groove on the plane
it's got it's a nice smooth path that
has kind of
Kirby side the 10 to keep you centered
in the groove
you can close your eyes and and walk
through it because even if the group is
curving it got these nice a gently
sloping sides
the push back into the center so
even if there's nothing keeping you from
stepping are the group in walking
somewhere else
the group was very attractive a new
users are drawn their first
here couple ideas on how to cut groove
in your API's
avoid nonsense representations
tough talk about I'll ask search briefly
again
there are two ways degree elastic search
you pass a big Jason blob very capable
but complicated
order to pass at this more limited but
tertiary string syntax
is no such thing as unless the church
choir that uses both formats at once
or neither format you have to choose one
now here's a pile after church used to
look like all charger optional
you could you have to pass in the string
style crews using the Q argument
and the Jason once using the body are
kept
of course this meant but nothing stopped
you from doing this
or even s both which are complete
nonsense
and I'd say shouldn't even be able to
get that far
you certainly should Nico near library
to reject this kind of silliness which
were used to need
the new pylas to church looks like this
we replace that mess with a single
required argument to which you can pass
either string
or adjacent dictionary you can't go
wrong because the interpreter won't let
you
it's much group you're now incidentally
this turns up another principle which is
to fail shallowly
in language is the commute respects this
is a very nice convenience
but if heaven forbid using language that
doesn't like a lot of JavaScript
implementations
this is absolutely vital and this is one
of the things that drives me nuts about
JavaScript design
job you know you have how'd under fines
and man's can pop out of things
squirreled away in data structures
only to appear 500 function calls later
and he spent all afternoon trying to
trace where these things came from
fail shallowly another way to provide
group is
REI
this is a possible balloon class but as
you can see you when you first construct
one it has
0 errant kneecap up a balloon has no air
right you might imagine sings and
documentation
that says before popping a balloon make
sure you fill it with care
now that's broken design a pop a balloon
clash should be pop ball all the time
full stop right these are shouldn't have
to head over the docs to figure out what
went wrong
so a better way here is to require
explicitness
which we know is a good thing reply
thanks to us
a better ways to take the initial full
amount to construction
users required to provide it gets air
they don't and so there's no wondering
later on why the balloon just went
squish when you picked it
REI eyes to more specific case love
don't have been variants that art
and a fine away providing cruises
through compelling examples
and these are the most over sorted group
the user knows that they're being
advised
is a screenshot from Mac paint 1.0 who's
actually seen this in the flesh on
original hardware
gotta lotta are people who love me and
here's great
health on the left menus from the top
and looks familiar to everybody in this
room
even those who didn't put their hand up
because Photoshop and Illustrator the
camp in Pixelmator picture pro in MS
Paint have been slavishly following this
pattern for the last thirty years
another great example is it had a
platformers right
this is original stuff on this hardware
outing but it done anything like this
before
but even today we're still jumping and
running to the right
set a good example people will happily
follow for ever
now a stir at my example code and really
liked the tactic fashion long outrageous
variable names inefficiency
for dehydrated efficiency tradeoff for
clarity
and i ended up having to stop doing that
because people were doing was they would
you take my code
example code in like paste into the
production systems
and that even leave the comments there
are the docs if they didn't apply
anymore
so I had I had actually dropped down and
realize that the
by users are dose I'll they will do
exactly what you tell them to do
and it's not that they're not that
they're not smart
they're just not interested in solving
that problem that you solved
they want to get in get the
functionality and get back to the
interesting problem that they're trying
to solve of
so be a good library status and give
good examples
previous yeah so look out for
representable States
that are nonsense should even be able to
state nonsense
look out for in variance that are to
bury it and
watch new users and see if they don't
know where to start
the up tech writers in the early
mcintosh project but often come back to
the programmers and say hey you know
this
suis totally confusing I'm having to
write all this documentation or to
explain it
bed design becomes obvious when you try
to document it
if you guys too hard to explain it's
probably too complicated
so let's go back and fix the design
incidentally this is why I like to write
the read me
first thing before writing any code
documentation driven design makes for
better UI
now we get to the walls
water to keep you from hurting yourself
or others
I just as in the physical metaphor
there's a continuum between groups and
walls
the more damage you can do with the
feature the higher the wall should be
the more barbed wire should happen to me
know the dogs in front of it should be
here's a horrible API with not enough
walls
anybody see what's wrong with this maybe
it's better you in the past
who hears wiped out a whole database
column because they forgot the WHERE
clause
at on money wasted in this room
so one way we could maybe fix that is to
require you to
say all when you mean all less
mathematically elegant
but think of all the money in time in
here would say since the advent of
sequel
general just not as the pretty common
thing to do right
trouble is to do it first trip type:
this switches seriously bad news
don't have returned by accident now
maybe we could require dash
F for the sort of thing I think actually
some shells a start doing this which is
fantastic
a very similar sort of thing happened in
pylas to church missile at the Delete
method used to look like
on pylas to church can delete a document
based on an ID
but one of its faults is if you don't
pass and ID it'll just we all the
documents
thank you very convenient I
and I D here if you notice is optional
I can certainly imagine pretty my and
print disease too soon are putting my ID
in there but I for got together arc so
it turns out to be a doctype not really
an ID
so we fix that and I here's how it looks
now
ID is mandatory pardon me
and a we introduced a separate to leave
all method for that weird case we will
delete all the documents
they can't possibly screw that up by
actor only screw up on purpose
the other thing to consider is how to
report errors said you have two choices
not to the time
and throwing exception is a lot better
than returning something because as we
all know from C
its way too easy to ignore return value
warning signs for shaved if you up back
to the docs again
if you're reading your docs in to see
the you're saying abram remember to
or make sure you do this on
maybe should make it so you don't have
to remember to or if it's a
make sure you do this before or make
sure you do this after consider context
managers
at a really great way in Python wrapping
things
second ask yourself what's the most
dangerous thing I can do
with my library and then make sure
they're barking dogs in front
you can't do that by accident
beware that most people won't
self-reports safety issues
a there's a stool culture blaming the
user that goes on in programming
we have to work to stop this out so
users are embarrassed to register to
admit they
made what they see as a mistake actually
designed mistake right
if you have an electrified doorknob it's
not you didn't go get asbestos Mitt
first a non-conductive met its that
should have an electrified or not what
you doing
32 actively watch out for users and
solicitor
solicit mistakes people mistakes people
made
those are my seven principles send
hereof compile them into a national
checklist
and if you bang your API's against the
Meijer designing them you should avoid
the most common pitfalls
but let me get met up for a second you
may have noticed there were no big black
lines between the some these principles
the kinda bleed into each other like
plane data helped compose ability and
brevity aids grittiness because you to
remember things
so began to wonder does any order arise
other relationships between these
and it turns out that it does
if you leave them all out and draw a
rose between them that indicate this one
contributes to that one
you see them kinda divide almost
perfectly into two clusters
the left cluster is a things the canopy
bade a quantitative definition
compactness groupings mister more for
human comprehension
well things on the right a more
calculable things you can imagine having
absolute impact on the number of lines
of code in the system
ignoring human comprehensibility if you
like
the left is Lingle and the right is
mathematical
now have often thought you can approach
computer science
from either of these directions is if
its language or its math
I mean like math in school I'm was okay
at it but I I didn't love it
up I still argue with people who say the
programming this actually map because
I'm a little thick
but both these things are necessary to
get anything to actually work
right so the spotlight spotlights the
thing that that
other programming languages have over
ordinary human languages
programs are alive they not only mean
things when people read them
but they actually do things when run
so very literally a program with
carefully chosen symbols
is poetry in motion
pretty neat thank you very much
mike is on
barrier Chur um your talk is good and
you should feel good
thank you I thank you valued
and I say I mean basically you agree
with my belief so we must not leap but
we must both be right
is be slowly cuz it echoes all over the
place okay
um I'm just a flatter you that's all arm
I I wanted to mention a couple of
additional resources
from people who came out of this talk
and said
wears more good arm in the book
making software what really works and
why we believe it
edited by Greg Wilson who's here and
Andy Orem
there's a chapter about API usability
man there's a chapter about what
different languages cause people to
think when trying to do the same
exercise with data structures they reach
for and stuff like that
case studies that be fascinating exactly
and
arm your design philosophy seems to
accord with
that proposed in RESTful web API's
the book my spouse wrote and how he made
a beautiful soup
the um which you know I sorta watched
him do
cell thank you very much I I agree with
all the ideas Thank You
you're quite welcome pick a similar iraq
thank you
I just want to know what's the EPI for
popping the pop a balloon
what is the API for popping a balloon
I suppose we have a pop method but it is
in Java you
construct a pin factory factor and then
apply it
took but but if it's apartment that the
more you end up with both
pop a balloon that you can't pop anymore
yes
that's represented by nonsense
%ah sorry echoes really bad here any
others
few
have to mark so many dependencies you
should have instabilities
what if instead
do you still believe in working well
a few a.m. so this is a whole separate
talkin testing
if you have to mark a little then you
have to mark a little
I sometimes are limited by our framework
and you can trip back to things how you
want to
there's also trade after mating testing
between it with an integration test want
to unit test in which do you value more
on myself I'm not making something super
complex right need those tests to
to prove things to prove my way up out
and to reach for integration tests first
just because they do test the whole
system
and their even though they won't tell me
specifically what
wrong if something breaks and the
integration tests are often
more couple been your tests and do
sparking so
you could bend that way if you wanted to
as to what the marking but
markings intrinsically evil with the
smell I don't like
things changed ok so
thank you top
thanks for coming get right up to the
mike
yeah so I am just what you think
from your lingo versus man dichotomy on
how you
name classes are Mon things as
real-world
ish verses more computer abstract answer
the truck
versus car yes
I like my code to read like it was
English prose
I and something up for doing lately is
incentive many my functions after burbs
you know sort whatever
I'll start naming them after now its so
you know
assorted for example there is a good
example the center library
so that I can just kinda Read Across and
say well this is the
sort of thing at the red thing and the
stacked thing
on the nice thing about that is
consistent with the purpose of making
functions and abstractions
at all which is to hide the details I
don't really care that it's doing a
quick story I just wanna sordid
the details may change later right so
you know his first name goes
don't put anything in the name that
isn't should become cared about the call
side
I'm
so I know there are a lot of other kind
really good
API design principles that I guess all a
bit more on the technical side like no
global stay
or or injector dependencies and things
like that you think those
necessarily follow from these principles
do you think they can have separate
Prince well that no global state thing
is a matter decoupling
if you have global state everywhere but
sharing in a couple at that point
I'm Peniche Witcher 2 pence injection
one on
dependency injection just the idea
castings in
instead a showing them behind-the-scene
again at the decoupling
think it is local state exactly I
decoupling has its
we caught tendrils and a lot of
different places you can see how it
connects to so many different things
call graph by the way thank you
my circles back on
I thought your point about the plastic
surgery PI with the
on with deletion was especially
interesting as I recall correctly
on the actual last text search REST API
does require you to explicitly say
all doesn't it didn't as a .9
the point something or other they made a
fix that 1.0 be a breaking change
on it was a really good breaking change
if they did I i believe the
the at least allow you to say oh now on
it do that with indexes I know I i found
that the a interesting example of how
you can
on sorta hang yourself by when when
translating
between as it were different languages
your
arm the looks like what happened was
that
an API that was safe on one side had
become unsafe by applying in other
languages principles to it
really I'm in this case we wrapped it
with a safer API because it was just too
great
version wherever you could simply
providing non and have a delete
everything
yeah um I'm not sure if the wrapping
introduced that I mean
the original recipe I was like that if
you type class you delete more kinda
like the RM
yes star thing yes and now that im now
that you mention it I do know that last
a church 1.0
has the same problem with indices if you
say to leave indexes
and say nothing to leave the mall really
yes bad news
and as a service center you can sectors
to not but that work which
I said it's the opposite the question is
trying to ask
the perils of completion in this case
translation adding safety
yes I and when you can
which brings up another interesting
question actually I mention breaking
changes like
do you think how do you think change
management and API's fits into this
framework is it like
on is it just is a mostly just a matter
of play
I mean I know there are some people who
are advocating the philosophy of never
break any
day but then there are some people who
are the
I like boys but I'm there but then
but or is it a matter of you have to you
you have to balance whether it's a
really important change purses /a
just a minor thing that like so let's
say you realize later
I have a better way to do something sure
by it's not necessarily a dangerous
thing like taking away
like requiring especially tall men it's
just a better way to do it
a breaking change on the less to break
into sure your compatibility is a is
actually
on my scripts lighter than quite make
the cut and compatibility
only basic philosophy is
you cemented burgeoning first ball if
you really gonna change something
up compatibility is a place where I can
be
prevailed upon to actually bought on an
argument
on now if I've design AP on a decoupled
way
like I was gonna this classic church API
that
to had a Bach index method but then it
set up taking a whole bunch of different
options I have a bunch helper procedures
which I could use to build a big data
structure
balking many documents and past that
into bach index
those things I could an obsolete
individually deprecate them and add new
ones
here use this one instead in past bach
index without changing bach index a
signature
that's one way to do it through
decoupling again refused a couple right
on the other things compatibility adds
another dimension to this
it puts us in four-dimensional space and
so then you start thinking about
coupling between time periods
and I haven't thought about but it would
make a great talk
so with the LASIK surgery sample of how
do you think about the trade off between
kinda having a more transparent layer
between
the library thing you're communicating
versus building up
your own API matches language or your
idea
how it should work and making a lot of
translations between
the service talking exactly
what's it like who i cant find
disaffection thought occurred well there
is
a there's what you say a very 121 API
hiding inside my last text search
and sees and request
I can look at them to track monitor is
actually there is that an API
inside my last text search papi the with
an expose publicly
echo both public but the one we advocate
is a little bit more aware gets rid of
the the dangerous things but some walls
up
and then on on top up I'll ask church
there even friendlier libraries like
elastic utils
that but you do kinda Django or I'm like
things under under filter
that kind of thing the way round it is
actually build March
exactly there's another scripts like
that I'd enough time for called fractal
us so they can API should be usable at
any little attraction to care for
some cases higher level be controlled on
starch care to
schorr
thank you X for skipping lunch