good afternoon everybody reading it
started with a Nextag collecting dues
kevin is gonna be talking about building
a high-throughput systems a pipeline
I say again my name is Kevin
I work for a company called tell apart
we build
a data platform for retailers I and we
deal with some
fairly hi high traffic rates low
latencies
on and we use Python to do pretty much
all it
so today I'm gonna talk about a project
called topper
which is a distributed event at big
Asian service
basically what does helps you in
straight your code by
putting calls to record events and then
those get aggregated into a central
location
where you can then freedom so for
example we can
record the the particular win price with
type: bid
and then period for for example the 10
minute sliding window in some
percentiles
so tough is built using Python
uses red is a back in store we have a a
cluster those instances
I make heavy use have G a vent and does
some optimizations using five on
arm and it does a fairly high in just
great uses
multiple over a hundred different
processors for the relatively
large-scale deployment so
instead of talking today about the the
architecture and how it's implemented
are we more useful to talk about summer
the lessons learned
I'm when trying to build large-scale
distributed systems
using Python so left number one
are is get your data model right so any
given problem has a number of different
ways you can solve it number different
ways you can model it
um and the one you go with really
limits or informs what your application
is capable of doing
and some very subtle differences in the
way the model program
can have massive impact on your ability
to perform later
and once you've committed to a model it
is
extremely important arts extremely
difficult to
go back and change it especially in a
distributed system where you have things
deployed all over the place and you have
protocols between different
components it's very hard to change so
at a high level
this is kind with the data model for
title looks like you have
a large room with an switcher generated
by clients both get aggregated
into the state objects arm 1 per tag
which is essentially them the metric and
the source on and those get stored in a
database
and then when you perform a query be
states but not that great a combined
into an aggregate
those different objects look like this
so in Aventis basically a tuba love be
the name the type the time and some
payload ominous
in this example other moving interval
counter the state is
I basically some bucket eyes counts in
totals
overture certain time range and those
states are stored as
compact efficient binary objects like
because there they go over the wire a
lot they
get edited very often severe extremely
efficient in terms of space
and mutability the aggregates
are responses to queries so they're the
friendly
chase on text that you'd wanna consumed
by now service
so when we can go
we can respond to queries go-between
state snag gets is
to convert each state into an aggregate
to simply representation
and then combine those together so
require that every counter type for
every metre type has
a way to combine was aggregates and the
seems like a reasonable thing to do
these aggregate object so much simpler
up there much simpler ski muscle bear be
easier to implement a way to combine
them
I'm however there's a problem with this
approach an aftershock you may have
picked up on it that you can't cash this
right if you were to you
cash the the projection aggregation
ahead of time
you'd be losing some other data like you
lose the temporal data
in that in that efficient state
representation
and so you can actually respond to
queries correctly
if you catch that had a time so the
solution is the change model
so that you provide a way are you choir
that there's a way to combine the
state's together
and by doing that you can actually catch
those on
those combinations ahead a time any
respond to queries almost instantly
and change model in this way has nothing
benefit
in that you can actually do pipelining
so instead of
having the requirement that all the
incoming events have to be
combined directly into the database
what's available you can actually
convert them into partial state and then
combines these together because you
already have
primitive so these examples are very
specific topper
but the the main takeaway is that on
the model the way that you treat data
the way flow data through a system
I'm could mean big differences in
performance even if its small
differences in the way you handle it
so that the small difference between I'm
projecting
and then combining versus the mining and
then projecting
means that queries can be responded to
in a matter of milliseconds as opposed
to a matter of minutes
so less number two a state is hard
maintaining consistent and durable state
is a very difficult problem it's one of
the most fundamental problems with
computer science
I'm and there are a lot of tools out
there that do this very well
and whenever possible you want to not
reinvent that we'll
you want to offload the state into
subsystems that
are designed to handle it which are
basically database systems
or offload your clients
missus be up basic architecture other
the top a back-end so in the center
there we have the
cluster apprentice instances that store
all the state in the system
its a hardon some service Army uses
master-slave replication use the
Sentinels for failover
does periodic snapshot ing on offsite
backups
that small component of the entire
system is
very well protected and uses a lot of
features a readiness to maintain that
consistent state the rest the system
which compose a these front and back
ends which run a number instances of the
public server process are completely
stateless next to the front and back in
from the exact same code
exact same image the only difference is
be traffic but they get sent
and because those are totally state was
the only actual state
the house is whatever's in there working
memory whatever prop request they're
working on now
um and those requests are always stored
somewhere else while they're being
processed
big because at that this is very
resistant
to failure so if any other fun and go
down in the back and go down
it doesn't matter traffic I'll just get
simply rerouted somewhere else
it also means we can very easily scale
up and down
based on the the current load so if we
need to handle spike we can double the
number %uh service doesn't matter
I'm or if at the middle in the middle of
the night you know when there's not a
lot of traffic
we can shut down half the cost and we
actually do code pushes in this way
so we have a little script that one
machine boots up it down was leaves cone
starts running at
to do a push just upload the latest
bundle shut down the entire cluster
started back up and it starts up with
the new code
Solis number three this is a an
interesting pattern
about that back that comes about when
when using agreements and generators
ob the they work extremely well together
especially
in processing pipelines data
so this this pattern that occurs
allotment have a code his concept
a sickness iterator so basically what it
is is you have this object
which acts like an iterator with a
generator it has an input queue
I love a objects that its
processing from a a source iterator and
as number up
agreements that are acting as workers
and I'll pick you that
is exposed as be as the open at the
iterator
and the trick is that the internal cues
are perfect size
so that when you try to put something
into a fork you are removed from an
empty one
that current agreement will block arm
and the one remix block what they do is
they switch to another one immediately
so you can actually cheney's into a long
series
love processors that will
basically jump around to wherever in the
chain
currently requires processing and you
can because I've the
the wage if it works you can actually
hide some fairly complicated network
work inside these these work agreements
I'm and when you get the network a
digital John somewhere else
so you can do real time processing on a
stream of data
I without having to explicitly you to do
four batches
or you synchronization between different
points in a chain kinda happens
automatically
so what left thing wanna talk about are
is
the so this is specific to see Python
arm
and I'm assuming a Linux system um it
does suffer from
memory fragmentation I an extra couple
really great parks
earlier today about memory management in
Python I'll
and I will be all that going to nearly
as much detail I think it bears
repeating here
so fragmentation is when a process
keepers in a fictional used that is be I
operating system will report a
much larger in number in terms the
amount member used then
the a garbage collector well member both
be right
and the reason for this is that you end
up with lots of chunks memory which are
not not optimally usable fragmentation
happens bustle sees you start with the
keep it looks like this
it's perfectly allocated your
application continues to
execute I'll and as prime the execution
you're you're free up some blocks of
memory
some blocks will be allocated and at
some point you'll want to
allocating object love this yellow sites
here
and that object is smaller than the
total amount of remembering
but because objects have to be
contiguous memory there's no one place
to put it
so you have to what ends up happening is
that the interpreter will have to go
back to the operating system
I'm request more keep and put it at the
end
so the ways to fight fragmentation
you want to avoid large numbers of small
objects
and because small objects tend to get
placed wherever there is space for them
in the heap
arm and thats mostly true to some
optimizations that the interpreter
lecture do for
for very common objects like to people's
lists
but generally small objects will get
placed arbitrarily threat the heap
and then when your quest that generated
them completes
until get collected from arbitrary place
he pee in the potty a little spaces in
this gets much worse if you're dealing
with a combination of
a few large objects in many small %ah
just because then there's
never a good place to put those few
large objects in the always having to
keep growing he
so another way to pay pregnant Asians to
minimizing flight data
so less number used means less memory
fragmented and generators like I
mentioned earlier are
a really great use for this I N
of a good piece of advice in general is
whenever possible reference
don't copy
so we use another technique in Tyler on
we will actually use iPhone
which for those not familiar sight on is
a kinda hybrid C Python language Rican
switch between the two
obviously line the line abt we use I
kinda
to go down to the sea level and you
manual memory allocation on a particular
type of object
on and we been hand those objects of the
GC and let handle it normally
so so you have this requests coming in
this is a an HP quest with from Jason
data
what you would normally do is decoder
and it would
generate a lot since little strings in
little reference objects in the go
wherever confinement
someplace for them keep I what we do
instead
is that we decoded insight phone arm and
then we allocate
pagesize wats up memory that point back
to
out Rangers up text in that original
blog
data and their first pass that seems a
little efficient because
you could be allocating an entire 4k
page just hold a couple pointers
I'm but the the main takeaway is that
by putting pieces a memory that are
related next which other you end up when
you end up finishing that request and
free memory
you get large continued ting contiguous
blocks memory
that are freed all at once and large
walks are more useful for storing
more incoming data and there is also
much higher chance to look at released
back to the operating system
more thing wanna talk about is the
concept of ratcheting
and that's kinda a pathological case a
fragmentation
caused by the fact that he passed to be
contiguous I'm in a little Astrix I
contiguous because that's not
a hundred percent true on it depends on
be platform in the allocator using and
some alligators are worse than others
but for pipe on Linux using standard out
here this is mostly true
so so you have this heap that's fairly
efficiently allocated
I and you get a request that requires
you to al Qaeda really big chunk a
memory see it's really big
is a text store so goes the operating
system
request a whole bunch a heap and put it
in there and everything's fine
so you prosecute continue processing
your request and at some point some
background process
the runs and allocate some small object
and decide the place it right at the end
to the
your quest completes it collects that
big :love: data
but that little object was al Qaeda in
the background sticks around
and because they're that one little
object right at the end of the heap
it can shrink so you end up in a
situation we have this really terrible
memory usage
and you can't create the operating
system because at one point the object
and this is is the basic limitation up
the way see pythons implemented
I'm it can't move objects around in
memory
monster allocated um
see a E basic leaders be
there's no way to move it see catching
the
so some ways to fight this um
so avoid persons objects o'clock it's a
really common offenders here
um they especially in connection pools
so when you're applications under its
highest load
that typically when it's using the most
memory and when there's most
the most pressure on the connection pool
if the pool is implemented poorly
it'll actually allocates a new socket at
that point
it could stick it near the end they keep
and if it does that
that object will never die you'll never
be able to keep down
so you want to avoid person objects as
much as possible everything should have
a lifetime
a cash is another good example here I'm
everything in a cash
should have a finite lifetime you should
always try to clear out your
anything cash anything that has to be
persistent
should be created when the application
starts up so soon as possible before you
start crossing a data
and by doing that you'll get pretty much
all other objects
fairly compactly down near the bottom of
the heap on C don't get this
issue we have long-lived objects near
the top
and obviously let's the avoid letting
the keep growing first place
on again less memory means less
fragmented memory means less
ratchet memory
soil at all the blessings I had for
today arm
the code for toppers upon get help if
anybody's interested and I B
happy to answer any questions
got any questions there's the like in
the middle here
so I wasn't able to make it to the
earlier talks I'm garbage collection
birch you're talking about this
fragmentation problem
see pipeline is the same true II
are you were good question I'm
a its not it whites fragmentation is
always an issue in dynamic languages
on but pipe I is able to move things
around in memory
I'm so we can do carry on a compaction
and you don't get nearly as bad
performance
relook at nearly as bad fragmentation a
ratcheting hi
our thanks for the talk um we found done
a little bit a benchmarking we've G
event intensive concurrency
and in a very artificial
condoms Saints like much benchmarks I'm
we ran into
like a CPU package issues so much CPU
that was the first thing ran into did
you seem like you doing
lot concurrent requests we I G what was
that
I guess the fisting you ran into stop
denying
more concurrently how did you get around
out so
are bottleneck was actually network i/o
arm and for those can use cases the
event is great because
it me designed specifically for
switching contacts on
I O I'm personally I found that the
event is pretty good for any work
although that's not CPU bound
arm if you are CPU bound though it's
actually it has a lot of problems
because
it uses a non preemptive model so you
end up
you can actually end up in a in a state
where one green light will hog the CPU
for a long time and that actually
prevent anything else would happen
including
responding to requests um so G event is
yep rate for network found not great for
CPU downloads thanks
well another questions that 12
thank you for for listening to talk