how everyone
I welcome to my talk on making our
leasing and selling an anti-gay made in
Python
thank you to Pike on for having meant to
say bonjour
I've murdered from the very first word
but I am at
I'm very excited to be here I'm dodgy
bill on
most important web sites on the internet
you can get my contact details from any
of the major security leaks in the last
five years
you know hardly NSA all the Sony
PlayStation credit card leak
today I'm going to talk about
my game design aims I'm going to use pie
the day my engine to make a point and
click adventure game
very small angst a lot to get through
I'm going to about releasing a game in
publicizing it
I thought I'd start by introducing my
games am i
mainline is my ex-wife in space tyrant
and I'm working on a second one cause
came from pleasure planet
mice were gonna space tyrant as a
two-day point-and-click adventure
allelic a certain tell-tale inspirations
a day of the tentacle Space Quest and
Sam and Max
back to the future that's really the
science-fiction adventure
said inspirations were Star Trek The
Next Generation
Doctor Who and space 1999 and any of you
have seen that show in like it please
come in talking about it because I've
never met anybody else that has
you know he loves that show as much as I
did the screenshots by the way to give
you an idea of what it looks like
a big a famed and if you haven't figured
out by now
now's the time and inspirations
Priscilla Queen of the desert and
strained a culture and that's caused a
bit of coke bottle
sometimes overseas workers strand a
culture is quite camp in kitch
comparatively year and it was released
in December 2012 is digital download an
innate you play
as Captain Tai Chi Minh ok brought out
over time and to face invasion fleet
led by your ex boyfriend its non
pornographic
it's a serious attempt at a commercial
game and it's been paying the rent 7
very lucky
so that was the who where
what and when the why I made it is
because growing up there was a lack of
same-sex love interest in the science
fiction I loved
about the quests I got was in one other
foundation books
where I think I nation s where the main
character goes down to this: icy planet
ship gets impounded and to get it out
has to sleep with the minister of
security and she's a beautiful woman
but asimov is a pains to point out how
manly she is
and yes there wasn't much I had growing
up
so I picked a point and click adventure
game because a gay thing applies a gay
story and point-and-click gianna is
great for narrative
and its event-driven not time driven to
people played at their own pace
and I thought that would be a good idea
because my in my mind
the target audience were gay man who may
be once every five years players elder
our civilization
and I picked didn't Disney style
graphics up because
you know a lot of people are afraid of
computer games and they're afraid of gay
content and I thought by making at
non-threatening and fun
it would lend itself to comedy but it
also maximize its chance for success
up before we go any further and break
game sign down into its components
I'd like to say that I think in my
opinion game design
Croft and you want all the components
working together
all the time see what the artistic side
and the technical side and the business
side
always to be meshed together working all
the time see conscious to the art
and then come up with a game encounters
make a game and go how do I sell this
you know it every step of the process
you've got to ask is this artistic
is this technical but technically
competent you know can I sell this car
market
up so I'm gonna keep coming back to that
idea that it's
its whole process rather than just one
individual things will get up I think I
did a couple of minutes
but I just thought I'd point I disorder
mention that the actual card
is just a small part of the overall
process of making and selling a game so
what should
indie game developers aim for when
they're making a game I think
first whole day should aim to make
entertaining games now when I first made
the slide
I had fun bus as an indie developer
compared to you largest years you have
some advantages and see have some
disadvantages
out one advantage you have is that at a
conceptual stage
you get a be you get to think outside
the box and you know I really push the
boundaries it
so you need to make a fun game you know
your a
horror game doesn't need to be fun or
sad game doesn't need to be fun
but at some level they all need to be
entertaining so how do you make a game
entertaining
well we talk about gameplay and that
sometimes a nebulous concept
up but if you play or make games long
enough you sometimes can detect that
they had a bit of a beat
and they say has developed by your
charger that beat
not you games also have high points and
low points anti-one to maximize
the high points and minimize the low
points the number and the duration of
them
and you want to do it as soon as
possible cuz lady getting the process
the higher ed
and hard it is to remove that the dull
spots and I speak from personal
experience because in my ex-boyfriend
the space tyrant about half an hour into
the game there's a is really dead spot
we have to walk between
a castle in a field about three times
and every time I watch someone play the
game
they get to that point and its death to
it's too sterile I feel bad about it but
I'll
a so how can you make a game play
entertaining well a simple way is reward
for effort
safety kill swamp rats you get five gold
coins
but he kill the Queen at the spa brats
you give them five thousand gold coins
I made a cut saying thats a basic
example
if you wanna get even a living will take
about you can consider your game play in
terms of push and pull factors
so what's pushing a play through the
game and was pulling him through the
game
for example the push factor could be a
wall of fire that slowly advancing
through the level
an example a pull factor could be
something as simple as an open door in
the distance
because people always tend to like to
see what over the horizon
another way you can streamline game and
make it more entertaining is to focus on
making your controls an interface as
polished as possible
an example from Mikes way from the space
tyrant was that
there's an inventory system so and when
you clicked on its keeping in mind the
artistic side had this beautiful
animation
where the inventory swerved up and then
sweep down
and 12 testis came to mean goes it feels
like a bit of a drag to use the
inventory and I like it when there's an
inventory puzzle
entire place so that lovely animation
with just a simple pop pop pop down
and instantly the game felt snappier and
lighter and faster
and so you've just really got to kind of
in our focus on the game play to make an
insane game
something else I think game makers need
to focus on is quality
are you gay must be polished a
and how you achieve that well but free
and that's easier said than done
you wanna make a complete game say I
want half finished levels are dead ends
or anything like that
and you also wants the menu 3 polished
and that sounds like something that's
not so important
but it's really that kind of polished
that crossing the t's and dotting the
i's
that elevator game from an amateur game
to professional game and a professional
game is something that you can sell
and the other thing I think we need to
focus on as part of quality is making
the game good-looking
I know in the open source movement we
sometimes struggle with the estate
excite a software
bus you know if you make you can make a
great game but it doesn't look good no
one not very few people wanna players
a so don't bother coming to the party if
you're not prepared to put in the
resources to make your game
good-looking and I think finally
what game developer should focus on when
they make the game
is making an interesting game and it
must be interesting to other people
and that ties into the marketing
published decided making a game
and we often think of those as dirty
words but they really just tools for
putting the game in front of people who
find it interesting
and dietary process when you put in
front of people who have no interest at
all because enya scamming another time
at one thing to consider when making
interesting game is there's a difference
between making something people want
versus what they will want and Kathryn
Kennedy I'll come out the canadian
example
a lot of people want zombie games so if
you're Canadian developer maybe you make
Canadians on the game and
bring us two games are fun to the
Canadian game at they may gravitate
towards the Canadians on the game
instead the generics on the game
a whether that and that's because you
may something they will want
not necessary something they want but
whether that is profitable for you is
the business decision you have to make
so Klein adultery test to my game is
entertaining
well I mention the dead spot about half
an hour and that'll an experience for me
the point n click genre is a mixed bag
has a reputation for being a bit slow
and you've just got up kinda mitigate
that sometimes I
work to that by making a comedy if you
can afford explosions and things like
that put in a joke people often
remembered just as much
there's a tip system to help you when
you get stock you can't get help from
the system and I'll tell you where to go
that's really important in a
point-and-click hi it can be frustrating
and FPS
to have your %ah spawn location camp by
sniper but that's nothing compared to
the frustration have
not being able to put the fish in the
bucket which so often in point and click
adventure games
yes a is a quality well I thought I was
a complete package with a few rough
edges
and is an interesting well it has been
quite compelling fit for gay men the
target audience and it was quite
compelling for the press
have two sides coming up on that so it
let's make a game
using my engine al Qaeda too small on to
the first step is to
rights your own adventure in this
example will to see that really can't I
go into the foyer
as a guard at the door there's a steady
drip from a small crack in a dime
you i'd in the crack because the flood
the God leaves his post up at the crack
so the doors on got it then you go
inside and destroy them sing
so already should be asking yourself is
entertaining is this quality is an
interesting can I sell it to you
baking at every level but for the
purposes today affecting
so my engine the basics if I V to is
simplicity
to use it constant feedback to the
designer so they know what's happening
and
unit runs like a tank because it's going
on all its computers an adventure games
can really be made using bait six basic
sort of
fun interactions like looking at
something interacting something using
an item on another item saying things
going places
and doing things with by Vita I really
tried to bring a stage play mentality
it's the process always think I've
inner hothouse directors with a ever
make a computer game version of the art
house film
and so they go into the room with the
developers in the developers would say
well the first thing you need to do
is load up your background resource know
those people would just turn around and
walk out of the room
but if you're strapped up into the sort
of stage by idea
conceptually it's a lot easier to deal
with and you know we
getting I and when you go to a stage
play
mentality it lapse overlaps very well
for two tester in mentality
you think ever play as something that's
written first and then you acted
where is a test driven you write the
test specimen you feel on the card
in fact and private or cards that so
much so that
a space tyrant was written using tester
and development
sir let's look at some examples
at this is you can people read their
phone to write
the night that's less good alright so
we can see here the simplest game is
just a black screen doesn't do anything
so we'll move on to more elaborate
example at you import your
your classes the heavy in track scripts
sir you click on the lake it says hello
world it's late to become a god goes
hold his go there
because they're then we have out some
scaffolding where we build us a net
assets a week
traders say no the background week right
after we first
idle action you know we do the same for
the leak into the main player
Demi add them to the same set the camera
and we got
I look at the code I roll my eyes a bit
that will give it a go
right so you can see here that's it
slowed up are saying
and at Actis to the sane including a
lake and 58 is done
a bit of magic already works detected
that the lake was an animation insert
animating force but there's nothing much
you can do because
you know we can really say we didn't
like it. much
sir let sector the next step if you're
willing to use
the smart layout that Piper private aka
news
you know you act as a directory fonts
and everything in our directory to
replace all the scaffolding
with a smile attraction so you have to
use it but I highly recommend
so we check out amoral our script well
at some ways
would expand at a lake script so that
when you click on a lake
it will crack it'll get bigger the
gobble spot at
walk over there and in the game state
changes so they can move around
on all that scaffolding been replaced by
this one call to smile I'd
and we've added a little extra button:
to the menu to stick it make it a little
bit nice on exiting
sorry run at and see what happens
where you get a loading screen for
example but here we have
now skirt once again click on Lake
cracks
gets bigger got spots at
he walks AR plugs at and now
you're free to walk around
bit of this rank as the revelation and
because there are multiple actions for
the
the that act out their path planning
algorithm kicks in and you can play
around
and keeping in mind the constant
feedback thing other show you a little
feature of the engine is there's an in
game it up
said designers can just make the changes
and instantly see
what's happening telex that so that's
a basic game adventure game made a party
to now mission daily at that is test
driven development
and that's a very useful feature
especially with a point click adventure
game
which is very narrative based so we go
back to that script we looked at
that we just ran and scroll down to the
bottom out description of the game that
we very rarely I
has been broken down into a series of
steps in a start in the foyer
started the fire you track to the lake
center and
eccentric cetera and we sing the courage
that but as a second-half to the game
that there is a code for where you go in
Thai side the dime
destroy them saying and that's missing
so when you do run the test run a the
game runs perfectly in till
it confines the second sane and its
tasks are areas and that's when you can
tell the game us guard rails
so it's quite useful never got but
its are useful for that once you've
embedded that
walks her into the card you do get
access to a lot of other things not just
test you can also generates
a human-readable walk sorry from the
game automatically
which is very useful for point click
adventure game tonight a feature
is also useful to help system you can
track where someone is in the game by if
have tripped
the next step in the walk sorry but
there is one mea culpa with this that
happen to me why I was based aren't on
its cover just before release
is that when those tests or completes
you can guarantee that someone can play
the game from start to finish
if and only if they play it perfectly if
at any point they deviate from the
walkthrough
a that's when you can get a raise and
that's actually turned out to be the
source of much problems
to the preferred by Vita water is you
write a game-breaking step-by-step to
stir
directions build the set snack to say hi
routes or something like that
and then I need and you actually fill
out the game scripts
something else I think is a sign a
quality nazar
overlook game design is accessibility I
other place that people don't have
accessibility issues software has
accessibility issues
is a really great website called the
game Accessibility Guidelines
has about three dozen suggestions on how
you can make a game more accessible
simple things like making sure there are
subtitles all the way up to
making sure you can skip the cognitively
challenging puzzles
I've had a background in web design
e-commerce and I think a lot of
suggestions we actually also apply to a
website
something else i think is a sign of
quality and is very underutilized the
nominees including the sauce with your
game
on its a selling point with a segment of
the community it assists with
accessibility because people can
customize the experience there are needs
it make gives the game a longer life as
it can be ported to platforms that don't
exist yet
uses continue bug fixes which is always
lovely and also to myself open
ecosystem that we all you know I really
love and support
as its good points just reiterate that
the game code is only a small part
but the overall process of making and
selling again
cuts out the tools I use for making
gains I use Google Drive
Google drive whatever it's called outlet
to the design space art was made using
Python 2.7 pie game my next game
is using Python 3.4 and maybe piglet I'm
expanding at the moment
I I've been trying to write Python 3
compatible card for couple view service
which has been quite easy
you guys really genius when they first
announced by from three because they had
brackets
to bike converted prints from a
statement to have met a function and
what attracted me to tighten in the
first place is how simple Prince hello
world was
and I feel like a loser great retrograde
step but having used it for
exclusively for three to six months now
there's Israel al against by from three
so you have made the switch yet
his another vote for me free to do so
eyes get help
soco deposit review not using american
depositary the peace of mind brings is
amazing
project management a stellar to calm
which is a web service
where you have cots Petoskey not much
better than email
but most importantly you have Irish for
tasks which is very important when
you're planning a large project
the game scripts which is a small pot
packaging have a slide on that
for the website I is a something like
Amazon Web Services is quite good
and further online sales I use a service
could be Antimicrob
them so packaging on Python a binary for
sale
you know I think by design that made it
difficult for their highways around it
on Windows he can use game to exceed up
I to compile it and I set bundle it up
pie to ap are and create mg on Mac to
crater
distributed disc image and on lanix I
have a source archives and a little
install scripts that installs the
dependencies
like pie and that system-wide a debate
whether it was okay to install thing
system on someone system but
a the steam Linux client does the same
thing and I thought itself can get away
if thats
I our getaway the turkey so go down to
one can fix Krypton 3
build scripts so it's alright talk right
something that you really should
consider when you're making a game is
having some method for updating it or at
least
letting people know it as an update you
never launched 110 perfectly so
make sure you know I you've got some
method for letting people nine
%uh your website in a trailer is so
important to our people leave it to the
end but from day one you should be
planning a trial and maybe even your
website
%ah you know at least initially your
trailer will sell more copies of your
game any game will
sorry really deserves a lot of time and
effort
and ask the same questions you ask if
you gain your is this entertaining is
this quality
is it interesting you're treated like
the first part of your game
se ve made a fun game maker fun website
if you made a horror
game make our website you wanna sell
your aim at their
lots of ways to do it in PC world you
are sold direct
there's BMT my current humble store I
use BNT my car
no problem sir it's pretty good and
thing is switching to how most or mostly
because the sale widgets
is on the same page as as the game and
where's BNT micro takes you to a special
page
and I feel that that may affect
conversion rates and you won every sale
you can get
some they can do his team up with other
indie developers and
come up with a bundle where you put your
six games together and
then people pay what they want to sounds
big cat counter-intuitive but is being
quite profitable for people involved
they're also at stores for PC games
three main ones a desire a good road
games and steam but I
of the 3i anyone really matters and
that's tame a
about 90 percent people sales come out
the same so should focus on getting on
that really
and something else turned out in two
games is that they have a long tail so
when we think a blockbuster games and
blockbuster films
they often if they fail on the first day
that I make money on the first weekend
people say the failed
but with any games it takes a while from
a typical a through the internet
and in case it might work in space
tyrant he really took six months for
sales to start to pick up
and have been quite consistent sense
something that happens
when you finally released a game is a
thing called the death the of where you
have no control over how people actually
receive a game
and you can try our hardest to make an
entertaining game but if someone's head
a bad mood you know bad morning or you
know their parents were killed by clowns
when I sit down trivia clown game del
give it a bad review
a but you just gotta kinda blanche role
that Atletico because it's nothing
personal
things that you should be ready for
feedback from users and how you gonna
deal that journalists
review copies always have some on hand
and also try and get ready copies at
reviewers at least two weeks before you
launch
because a lot of viewers like to have
their review up on day one
so it's fresh for everyone involved
because you get reviews
quite the good ones and land from the
bad ones in all the really really bad
ones
a hero swagga something I like to do you
just send a copy of the game someone
that's inspired you are more often than
not
essential to thank you night and then
you got a little connection to someone
you like
not something I'd never heard of until I
lost a game
is this this the sort of John Irving
entertainments Coldplay there so let's
play
where people play the game online on
YouTube but which
for their followers to watch and II
gotta be blindsided lies on my way to
convention last year
and decide hopping on the plane I got a
little media let from Google
that some fella but uploaded a place
throughout the game
and by the time I got off the plane an
hour and a half later forty thousand
people have viewed it
and watching its it was it
did my head in a bit because he was
playing it as an authority because he
knew he was straight and he was an
interesting day games but its repeated
interest a bit
answer she was in playing its how I
envisioned it being played
but United there is a right way to play
a game
and it's not nice to give players a
community politics is something you
gotta be careful of I am
I put space tyrant up on Steam
greenlight
sustain green light is this process
where everyone on Steam get a yes or no
vote
asserts an ultimatum are 60 a game like
space tyrant which is
in a targeted for pipes and population
it was never going to fare well
but the economics of it a tu la should
not because we get on Steam it's very
very good thing
but one thing's life-size ready for it
to be sort on down
but what did surprise me was that when
you
insert a game into an ongoing community
it becomes a proxy for conversations
they've been having for a long time so
one thinks the steam greenlight people
always talk about is what
make steam different to other gaming web
sites and the usual game as a proxy for
that
that I mean anything by it read it as
well %uh just now be careful as to get
away
request from head attention to media is
something
used should focus on like the Indy game
Press is very very crowded
there's hundreds against race day I
think that's fair to say that
but there's a lot of other press but is
very few games come along so I was very
lucky in that I had the gay press
to pick up on a gay game cuz it's not
many of them and then once it gets into
the search and gentle media's excess
ability me is a great one too
once it's out there a kind of goes
sideways into the gaming press
so that's a really great way to get
coverage and once you start getting
coverage
you get their party advocacy and if you
can get other people who don't know
talking about your game
that really really make should life a
lot easier
see all get feedback he is you know a
lot of feedback I got
I'd don't know how much time I got left
but may be the last ones just indicative
of the whole thing really
I sware dis is made up it's cherry trees
to be made up but I like it and I
is a whole lotta fun as a gay guy does
the game i won his play all my life
thank you brian of course you get
negative feedback
well I got negative feedback
fan of the spelling Obama but it is what
it is
and united just after awhile it just
becomes noise in a way
a so with the press its
importantly he came into use 7 beds some
stories in it for the press to pick up
on so I
made sure I had you know a gay story to
tell
to the gay press and a strain story to
tell to the
to restrain Press and gaming story to
tell the gaming press even on you know
gaming press probably
work gonna be a hard sell %ah and that
worked out quite well but one thing I
did learn about dealing with the press
special the gaming press
is this are rare is that I only game is
interested in games
to getting non-gay miss to talk about
your game is very very hot
and I miscalculated a bit in at my
when I made the game I made it to people
who don't really play games very often
it turns out they really play games very
often at the people to play games
a game it's so if you're going to make a
game make it for
game it's Anna yes something else I like
the hard way
eyes that Jowell
potential price point very important %ah
you know
don't undersell you work but when you're
planning your work unite do the size
put in effort to let you know a price
point and I S
the loss thing that I i Lance the hard
way
was the great ideas become guys come
pouring ideas games
are a marathon not a snot sprints answer
something that seems like a great
moments
you have a libel moment on you can be
with that idea for her eighteen months
to years
so you really wanna battle tested early
on Anna T
has seven well I'm making another game
the air schedule pleasure planet
Anna and as i doing in the future survey
will wrap it up there
if you wanna know more about it feel
free to come up and ask in the slides
online
yeah ok out some sorta there
so if anyone would like a task question
there's a microphone right here in front
so
we gotta 23 minutes left
so that's on out there I'm and villagers
shock
I was wondering did you all into like
art and urself
and what tools to use but Sir I have an
artist in San Diego
of El Cajon Phillips and he's quite a
famous k oddest
he worked for DC and %ah comics in the
nines Salisbury
very lucky in fact probably on the
greatest days of my life is when he said
yes cuz I spent years going
her his out style it really suits
discovered game and one data source
you know about Askim n he said yes so
kinda made it work really but I do some
animation a cause he's campaigning scape
now X so
I'm very interested in the actually just
think making the bike you mentioned to
you plan to use
3 next time already have plans
make the make the bank because
by to accent 3 the
the painter by 3 what doesn't sorry but
doesn't work by 2x
doesn't work with my 3 our that's why
I'm switching everything got
which is another graphics library book
I mean by to accept that all right right
right
yeah hopefully we'll put it there we're
looking into that
okay yeah thanks there
on and this is traditional business plan
you have for this game
that is you sell it on Steam or his
ideas
you talk about free to play or other
micro micro
payment system well United
I did have a thing about the price
points Tom basically I I looked at it
as a project that is like a gay film or
a gay novels so it's a boutique product
for boutique audience and initially
I never thought that its competitors
while the computer games I thought its
competitors
where no box sets having a clear as far
call
and Amistad more open book and so that
was really the mentality of it
service I like free play and name
like a cheaper version on the iPhone or
Android I'm not particularly interested
in going up because it's such a small
markets so you've got a kind of I really
want to try and keep the price went up a
little bit
you thanks for the talk it's great but I
finally got to see
um so you're up stories
kind of unique contacted directly do you
have any advice
for people creating and how they might
go about finding posts
well sorry I actually two artists I have
the character out in the background
artist
and I got the background out a ser
deviantART and
you know I its action underutilized
resource and think
they know what they've got a really he
just garner this thousands have
artist mostly hobbyists but this I
professional about it
just fine art style that you like and
send them if your email sorry it took
I think four or five guys to find a
background artist to was interested
I went through a couple so they want the
fest at a spot
in a for the budget for indie game
developers things like they've got a
really great
pay pay them night they're they're very
cheap
now now thank you very much