this year we had the privilege of having
a third Hall speakers be women and that
the special thanks to just McKellar and
her average
which is fantastic
so once again if you enjoy talk please
let them now so they know
they did something wonderful to and
tomorrow
im um I'd also like to thank the path
and softer foundation
um the PSF axes basically financial
backer for this entire conference
so basically they're on the hook if
anything goes wrong I
which obviously having a sold-out crowd
three years in a row once again this
year
is seems like it's on a big deal
references when the recession hit
the PSF was the one they had to cover
expenses and stuff and this off as
planned
two three four years in advance so stuff
does happen so you want the PSF for
been landed take the financial risk of
keeping this conference going
um also I think the sponsors
arm if you don't know how expensive it
is to run a conference
is very expensive I the hobby is
consequences does not come close to
covering expenses and it's thanks to
sponsors
both to the part that such permission
and sponsors here at the conference the
help keep the price low enough
so that students and hobbyists and
people who can get an employee
employer Dec to pay for them to come to
you will have to make this an affordable
conference compared to other companies
out there
and a special thanks to Justin all there
were areas
for Guinness 110 sponsors this year to
help make this conference possible
as SEO says:
some
this year we had a frame fantastic
amount of financial aid to help get
people here who can afford to come on
their own
%uh the PSF alone donated eighty
thousand dollars
to help fun people for tickets flights
hotels it after
arm I think the pie ladies who raised
forty thousand dollars to help get
people to come
and also thinks the pike on Australia
who also raised on their own three
thousand five hundred dollars
up so thank you to all them
and making sure we can have as many
people who can calm as possible regards
to their financial needs
so I'm gonna cover what's already
happened
a not to make you jealous but so that
hopefully all you have not been here
before will know when you when you miss
the next year
which I hope will be all you coming back
can know you can come for early on and
actually enjoy the conference the
morning you will this year
prompted start there's actually a group
love
Prime Minister's coming out from the
Triangle area on tobacco pipe on Rails
where they basically rented out a train
car from Toronto test too much out yes
but I other nonspecific it up
I'm and the message just to train
together
on Thursday and it is all talked and
hung out oMG my wife and I took the
train was a fantastic experience the
runs one Lincoln Terrace gorgeous
are so few coming from the trainer or
honestly want to fly to Toronto
which is not hard and then take the
train with them next year would highly
recommend it
I am we had tutorials
all at once and Thursday there were 36
the alarm
attended by eight hundred pick some
people in
1,446 seats I receive very successful
year
hearts agree with the learned some
things and also the support the tutorial
speakers because
they're able to attend the conference
build-up I was asked if you did attend a
tutorial
please fill out the survey form for the
two trolls you attended
is uses the back for the tutorial
speakers for them to help improve their
farm Charles and such and it's very
invaluable Sopris dollars out but we had
the language some in
basically the loss on the court Obama
team get together every wednesday before
the conference
sit around and argue a
various things come up is one of the few
times there were wrecks are allowed to
sit down pat
as people face to face and discuss
things and have things out get updates
that
don't spam large trading stuff in very
productive as always and was meant as a
guide to do that
there's also an education summit
yesterday workers educators and
stakeholders were able to get together
attorney hope advanced Python and
education world
france is the huge push up the UK and
you simply raspberry PIs to help our
students learn in such small part about
something that's
going on today and tomorrow but that
doesn't really with sponsor chops the
past ones and there they were basically
sponsors had a chance to come in
and actually give you tutorial I know
how kinda sounds it sounds like it's
just a big pitch but I as the fuel to
the topic for actually useful on how to
actually use tools
how to use Python a unique way that
someone's also said you're so is a good
way to actually if you're here for
tutorials
to kinda feel time between them or if
you're only here for one to have the
next day
access something to do it without having
to pay for anything and make sure your
time to do through time
we also the opening reception yesterday
thief I went for sponsoring a proud I
had a good time and obviously you
the two free drink tickets helped a
was great also see all the sponsored up
there and who's using Python which is
growing every year and continues to
amaze me so that's what happened
so once again if you missed it come back
next year you can
do all that use of a comp up but here's
what you got looking for two today
Saturday and Sunday
for small we have a hundred talks this
year
across five tracks plus the keynotes
which i think is absolutely fantastic
I i believe i was told there are about
600 submissions
so as you can tell by that number there
was a huge amount competition this year
to try to get talks in
so I expect this will be a fantastic
conference once again
I do have some last-minute changes to
you
the schedule to announce armed in
Lindsay's talk today at Every Phone
30 cream bombe proved importers has of
course been cancelled
are and there has been a replacement
avatar could be
and have today Peter finds talk free
softer free people
has been substituted with advanced
methods for creating decorators by
Graham dump them
no those are the only changes in the
schedule at this point
I am
well we all get to sit around and talk
about Python and such throughout are the
next three days
we actually are looking up to have BT
kids here conference
are beauty Monty Python as we pay them
high game
this is something that started up icon
out in San Francisco
up man him and it was such a thing or
miss the sex
successor imagery body back this year
it's sold out and I don't know if you've
ever put your head in this room from the
past two years but if you haven't had
spent SEC's Kinsler makers
these are people blue kids angry under
the age of 18 you have never learned how
to program
city in there just wide-eyed like we all
once weren't going
wow look at what I can do and it's
fantastic to see
it sold out in Fort Lee so you brought
your kids I'm sorry
but you can sign up early hopefully next
year in catechism
they're going to be lightning talks this
year as usual if you don't let me talk
is basically
its up five-minute talk it's really fast
we get to the point
and the commuter lot of fun good luck
people do them on the spot
are this year though actually train a
kind of different thing where half the
talks were previously pitched
except in and other have gone with you
sign up arm the will be at the beginning
and end of each day except for the big
game today so it'll start the
and the today product and then every
morning before the conference starts
and every evening when the conference
and still be settling talks
I highly recommend attending they're
always on a fun there's always at least
several fantastic many talks that are
different person
we have open spaces every day during the
conference if you don't know the open
spaces
you can't kinda think it was a
self-organized aspect to the conference
you can basically
reserve a room for at least half an hour
and you can you there
present something you can get together
with like minded people have a
discussion
it's completely up to you there's a
board bleed Emerson
are they can go sign up for room and
just newsroom for whatever you need to
to everyone I'm
with the first this year we actually
have child care for those you traveling
with children
rides every day this year I I suspect if
the reception is good will bring it back
so hopefully if you didn't bring your
family this year because
to ensure what to have their own you
brought with you to you while you're
here geeking out
that's fine about picture make sure to
bring them cuz watcher care to help make
sure the tinkerer
while you're doing your thing
I we have what's been kinda dub the
sixth track
I was physics for Montreal I every day
at eleven o'clock upset registration
there's a two yr to is we show you
around this wonderful city
I i believe there's a sign up on a vent
brace
I am by I don't know about you but
I from the city amazing and is
everywhere trying to sign up for if you
have the time
in your schedule to actually do this has
been run by the local
Montreal Python group so they know what
they're talking about their locals
I see hope a up we have the unique your
culture perot
basically there's the national
taxi international now because we've
included Canada where
there were five times this year we're
basically startups came
and pitched ideas to various people and
try to use a
I want to kinda Pike on please give me a
free booze for day
I give me give us two free passes and
we'd love to a temp icon
as a startup so these were the winners
are those competitions
on Friday in a bar inbox ap ML Class 10
scores
abstract rankin procured health I have a
booth
today and the sponsors
room I on Saturday check I wrote in D
transferred out on a roach and you
partly missed I diana will have their
booze on summer
so if you wanna see some other
up-and-coming start-ups that were
selected please
check both Friday and Saturday
there's going to be a pike on dinner for
the first time this year
are two dinners in fact one hurts my
brain inroads in 1/2 has been a great
Brockman
I basically you this is a appreciably
their tickets still available so she
wants to go basically
with pre-booked space in some
restaurants where these two
preliminaries group basically be hosting
a dinner and having discussions quizzes
and astronomy is we have a good time
we're all those connected get to know
each other
as a community outside the conference
and a relaxing environment where we can
actually just
have a chat
there's going to be a 5k charity run
tomorrow morning at 7am
I believe the mood the path is gonna be
along the water in Old Montreal
on please come if you're at all runner
or jogger or even just wanna walk it
are all proceeds from the sturdy one
will go to Electronic Frontier
Foundation
so please come
us became series that will be charity
auction tomorrow night
at beating thirty-year 6:30 I am 70 Mb
all proceeds from this auction will go
to pile it is very sponsors in Group A
don't need various things I believe last
year the largest spa
auction item was an original piece of
artwork from wreck it Ralph
so there's some pretty cool stuff on
there is
a cover charge the board are some big
deal
are we have square readers to take
credit cards getting pre-pay for that
arm once again all purses good politics
there will be a jobs fair for those
interested
up over 60 bon sirs hearst about taking
part
and this officer in its gonna happen
Sunday from 10 to you
1300 or 1 o'clock I am so if you're
in the market good place to go and talk
to the various over 60 companies looking
for people
and while that's going on I if you're
dying or for some reason are looking for
work
which is fine about this in a poster
session from the exact same amount of
time
I interview academia know exactly what
this is if not
basically people comin make a poster to
basically present things are working on
i've seen things all day from working
with open date in government
all the way up to people do in
bioinformatics with part time so the
topics vary greatly as agreed have a
conversation cuz the
poster presenter is standing there and
you just have a nice talk about what
they've been working on and give them
supporter
get information from them and what
they're doing
I on Sunday there's gonna be a pilot is
lunch open to anyone
who identifies as a woman in room 516 at
one o'clock
I it was so popular last year it was
completely oversold
so the really expanded its so hopefully
we'll have his basis is this year
so tell me feel free to come
up suffer carpentry is actually after
the conference on Monday and Tuesday
for those you don't know subcompact
carpentry
is run with Mozilla and basically
eternity its
scientists and engineers in such people
who are not naturally programmers
is a big how to use technology and how
to program Tom
it's not totally geared towards exactly
scientists over insist they're gonna
have courses on
are I for numeric analysis they have
other courses because we can't because
I'm for scientists P check it out there
are tickets available
and it is open to anyone is not
restricted at all to just the conference
so feel free to have anyone who happens
to be in the area have come with you to
potentially attend
press office is on the website
up lastly in terms of events there are
going to be sprints
I Monday through Thursday I am
I personally view this france is almost
the highlight p.m. hallway track at this
conference
on I like to see I learned how to
program thanks to Python
am part that's because I hope I've
gotten to 10 the sprints
I'm basically projects com
and using the leaders in the projects
have people come join them and they show
them the ropes
uke they'll explain here's how you
commit here's how you can get you the
project
and you learn times these people who
runs from the top notch products in this
and in this community and know all the
ins and outs have their project how to
do things well in Python
and is an extremely wonderful learning
experience and once again is another
great way to socialize and meet people
because
everyone's relaxin want or need to
another talk you sittin there hanging
out
and just coding and I perceive and a
fantastic
arm can attend this year do invite I'd
do highly highly recommend you try to
find time next year
I'm its I just cancel enough it's just
fantastic
I'm lastly just because the somewhat
unique to our conference although I
believe is expanding throughout the
conference I'll cover throats of we do
have a code of conduct
basically just beaten
basically just be professional
respectful on kinds are you can read the
full version on the website I believe so
sir covers gun
I was when I wanna feel welcome in this
penthouse community
I'm some that's why we have them and I
believe I have
a few minutes to just opine I
yeah I know I hear some you grozny local
guy was in a sec %ah
I love this community I've been lucky
enough to be apart this community
since 2002 and that was back should win
that as before the first I can honestly
in 2003 NPC
and I think we had 300 350
people I was easy it's gone a little bit
I
this attack on people so are you do use
profanities pearl
how
but back then look going good the
committee was smaller but the Aussie
felt the same it was an extremely
welcoming
friendly constructive
group for people core always willing to
let people come in
help them out and let them enjoy
programming
and Quino and Barry we're sorry and
computers and for Drake
all those early people have done a
fantastic job starting a wonderful
community
that all of us have come together and
worked around to make sure it's continue
to move forward
now an address you so
but I like to think about is I came for
the language by stayed for the community
so I want to personally think olive you
for making this such a wonderful place
to be and such a wonderful group of
people to be around
so thank you the
now some and embarrass myself too much
with an
I'd like to introduce our first keynote
speaker
I John Perry Barlow was actually a
lyricist for the grateful dead:
I E the cofounder the Electronic
Frontier Foundation
and he is also a fellow at the Merc man
Law Center at
are Harvard Law and I like to welcome
John up to police
present