right hi everybody I I'd like to
introduce Nathan your color who's going
to talk about
in death valley Debbe thank you
um my name is Nathan I'm a principal
engineer Adam m bright
and Dom today I'd like to talk to you
about PBM
this talk is all about how to find and
remove bugs from your software
if you're interested in adding bugs
there are other talks available
so now is the time to arm
perhaps check those out arm
not the NMR fella blunders
are they were arm so
attributable euros up first
arm just to hope once again
there okay um summary showing a bunch of
examples above using PDB a couple
different contexts and I a dozen be back
during run through the might be hard
I hope that a hundred I think I tried to
adjust the font appropriately
but you can follow along on present to
Tron if you arm if you so desire
so we're here to talk about PB the
Python debugger
and I hope that by the end of this talk
I will convince you that
PDB is better than using prints for
debugging that PT
well on you know there are the
tried-and-true stables
and a there's a reason you know take
some
energy to break out those that you'll
know how to use PDB to explore a running
program
and that you love be convinced that PDB
is a useful tool to understand
so that you can extend it to behave in a
way that's most useful for you
so what's rethinks can you actually do
with PDB
a you can look around running code this
is an example
a program that will talk about later to
be a little calculator
the course and in this case have been
prime just looking at what a valuable
variable is
but more interestingly than this you can
also look around pythons code
so if I wanted to know what OS top path
not join does when I actually call it
I can stop pop I found execution inside
this function
and I can do this without editing files
inside of my
I system Python and I can in this case
discover that it's actually kinda module
called POSIX path
which who knew I got a return to the
scene of a crime
if I have a piece of code like this that
create a server
and when I actually a call to it raises
exception because the address already in
use
I can actually use PDB to jump back
into the program ac for the exceptions
re: occurred and inspect the stay as it
was
when the program died so is all things
real talk about
everybody Prince everybody uses print as
a tried-and-true
debugging mechanism but PBS better PB
let you explore CNN program or a dead
one
it was repeatedly run your program so
you can debug it actually
get into a flow debugging as you work
with the PC software
and it lets you build the tools you need
to extend it so that is appropriate for
your particular use cases
let's start with some a little bit I've
PDB 101
and twirl a little bit a groundwork so
we're all on the same page around
how to use PDB the most common way to be
in the PDB
is with such grace so set race is a
function the tells Python
stop immediately when you get here you
can see with the green arrow on the arm
left him partially coated my little for
the Nazi program the green arrow
pointing to my
my set raceline and when I actually run
they're on the right hand side
you'll see that Python stops before use
the print statement and that
agree the PDB prompt and let me know
it's about
to do this next line so from here
there's a few really basic commands
those 10 cover briefly so that we
so we all know about them and can
understand the difference I can say next
if I wanna text you the entire neck
statement so in this case you'll see
that
um oh yeah people tweet at me
to a buzz on my watch so that'll be fun
arm
a you can see if I did next here
um it's going to XQ that entire print
statement for me so
it's going to call filled with Sis RB
it's going to put it out to see the 8
their below next 20 print the dash dash
return which means I reached the end of
a block
and there's gonna wait for the next
command so next excuse the current line
and any calls my have to make this isn't
a
contrast to stop if I do this again and
just one step
step also excuse the cut line but stops
as soon as it possibly can
so this kid inside adaptive function
and at this point now I can actually
continue to stop
or next and walk to that when I've
figured out
wanting to know one Roddick derail the
program there's the continuum and COMT
very commonly named but this leaves the
debugger and let you can too and it is
actually the back
execute a program so the those are for
love
when I'm working with more junior
engineers those are the three commands
that
we do first and we like give a master
because they're gonna for the base is
almost everything else we look up
so there's next step continue and
issue present a real repeat the previous
command except if its list in which case
we'll talk about that
so the PTB prompt can look a little
foreign
I what point out its its books forum
because it's meant for Speed
once you understand how to use it and
you understand what the commands are
you can operate very very quickly and
you can vary easily understand what's
going on your program
so you can always ask for help arm but
he's commands
a except the undocumented ones of course
and arm and get into some context
so with look at how to enter PDB
directly at a particular point
but more useful in my experience is
actually executing code under PCB's
control
and soldiers were gonna do for the rest
to the presentation is look at how this
works and then dive into some more
um ways you can extend PDB for your
particular users
PDB like a lot a Python modules can be
excused as a script
so the Python basham PTB and then what
you're actually going to run
this is gonna stop your program before
it does anything so in this case you can
see a sub that should not shut up I
mine one it at the module level and it's
getting ready to import sys
so it's done nothing at this point you
can use this even for running Django
under PDB
so that you can do your gender run
server and set a breakpoint which will
talk about
or do some other sort of introspection
love love lower levels
other web app arm before the program
starts
you can also do this there's all these
run and run call functions
um I don't use a whole lot less I may be
working in interactive
prompt your trying to understand a piece
of code little better
but this was you i think is pretty clear
the run with quotes
basically execs a little bit of code and
run call takes a callable into arguments
excuse under PDB and again it stops
immediately
it sort of interesting that you do arm
run with the
quoted a code that
it stops inside of string1 module
as opposed to the actual thing because
it hasn't actually him exact yet
so if we in one or two hundred and PB
control and a PB immediately
we now have the necessary understanding
to back to debug under PB and help us
our fix
somebody software I should point out
that the software's
this little program is in the hub repo
with the slides so
so I wrote a program small program but
of course does a postfix notation
calculator
over HTTP as one is want to do arm
I think we're gonna roll it out as part
of our payment system event bright
by Tom it's very important to the
support post expectation
it so you can do things like 21 plus and
get back three
you can do 210 starring at twenty up
to ten plus two star is naturally 24
um unfortunately up up
I'm not that good at writing calculators
so
it's not a great with unexpected input
so if I have something is not an integer
for example
it blows up with a valuer so if I wanna
X if I wanted to bug this program is in
PB the first up is simply to run it
under PDB
you'll notice that it again it stops
before does anything
its key rate import the whiskey server
and I say continue COMT
it all tell me that it's ready to serve
on poor 8,000
and now I can actually use curl to make
my requests and started for you I was
going on
keep in mind we haven't put in a set
race in here we're just running
under PB so we run under PB and UX you
curled
it's going to again give you trace back
because bug still exists
but then it's going to tell you that
there's uncaught exception and into
what's called the postmortem debugger
and this is one of my favorite PDB
features it's one of the most useful in
my opinion because
this is what led to jump back in time
to arm 22 where your program died
I believe this is the core argue does
Time Machine
so you see here with the exception
occurred
is now telling us that is in the push
method in PF calcd up I'll Mon 28
and it's getting ready to from call
int value or operator I say getting
ready to call but its it meets already
been called write the program is already
died
but this is where happened so this is
the state I want actually inspect
to figure out um what went wrong my
program
and i cant theres as much mental used to
serve start inspecting stay looking
around
I can print the value or something I can
look at arms with the arms to man
which tells me a exactly what the
arguments were too
to the current function or method these
are um
blue really useful dispersed but can
understand in the lay of the land
also important because right now all I
really know is a line 28 has this
int a value operator and this could
potentially be code that
somebody else's or a third-party module
so I can do list
and list by default Prince five lines
above and below the current line so you
get a little bit
context really use PDB and
I think you should are it behooves you
to read the list documentation because
its has some subtle behavior about what
happens when you run list repeatedly
it incentive repeating the exact command
and show you those lines
it starts to show you more more code
which can if not
aware of it it can be a little
disorienting um
and always want to %uh show for Python 3
Python 3.2 a added the long list command
lol
this is pretty great on a look inside
you got the normal list
which shows the five lines above and
below
on the right hand side have long list
long list is delightful it only shows
you the current method or function
that's being executed
so you can see it actually gives me this
information that but about the
conditional on about love
the declaration I'm have missing in the
in the Python to version
and also omits the def result from the
and
was just kinda close up a display makes
so one more thing to ignore
as I'm looking at arm trying to feel its
programs during
in the sake fringe in the interest of
completion leaders there is a pretty
print as well
great um
this does raise the issue in question I
look at this pretty print slide how
would I do division with my a shitty be
calculator
I don't know um so
that's great you can see what the that
these values are
but a lot of times you'll have a
hypothesis about what's going on you
me think oh yeah I think that I think
this values actually
should be you know there should be
some other expression used or you know
you want to something out in the context
to be running code
so PB provides the bangor exclamation
point command
and them is it was an aside to explain
why this is important because I this is
a miscarriage love people
if I have a function called added the
stakes three numbers and adds them
and i wanna stop inside here because
addition is hard
and i wanna inspect what's going on
so I saw Penelope B and now I wanna see
what B-plus see on its own is
if I put that into PB it's going to give
me this rather confusing message that
plus C is not a function or is not on
the system path
arm let's sort of weird I was expecting
that
what's going on here is that the PDB
prompt
is a lot like pythons rubble prompt just
not a smart
so when you have something that starts
with Stef with the same letters
as a PB command getting to the commands
in this case the things we're trying to
set a breakpoint
at the function name plus see which or
not
if you do bang people's see you get the
actual results you expect
highly encourage everyone to get in the
habit of using the bank operator when
you're
workers had a PB if nothing else
because if you're a very bold name
something like context
with the first four letters match be
continue command
you won't accidentally blow away your
entire debugging session and continuing
the program
when really all you wanted to see was
that context
and again Python 3.2 is better are three
is better there's interact command which
drops you right into an interactive
shell so you don't have to remember that
so how do we action navigate the program
though how so we've come alt we've been
looking at the state where an error
occurred or so a break point
um the there's almost certainly going to
be a desire
tis to see how we got into this mess and
how we
how we got to the to the state that
we're in an hour what the calls were up
to you here so if we have it will
consider another are
bug in my calculator which I
I you the VP of Engineering is here and
i'm talking about these bugs my software
so
I hope that um hopis he's forgetful
around
performers resign but um
easier 523 plus five I've got this extra
operandi my into my postfix notation
and its gonna raise a syntax error
turnabout expression for much for my
particular calculator
among into PB so again I'm gonna drop
into the prompt right away
um and I can use the where command to
figure out
just what the Cossack yes and I wasn't
like actually a middle much allies
in the hopes for making this like summer
readable um
but the important thing to note here is
that the free first line is the first
call your program made
to get here and the last one on the
bottom of the slide here
is the actual point where the error
occurred so this is just like a
traceback stack trace
a that shows you how you got to this
particular point
and you can go up and down the stock so
if you
use the up the company name up command
yellow
wind up at the previous call and you can
action spectra look at the frame their
and you go down and any other commands
my issue
are gonna be actually actually um
execute in that context so
this movie so you can see how this let
you start to build up
they are suite of tools for use in and
then apply them a different point in
your program
to really understand what's going on how
are you out maybe your code interface
with other party coder with a framework
some like that
so I want one quick note about
post-mortem to bug in which is what
we've been using a lot of here
where we jump back in time to this
exceptional were occurred
when we run lemme um under the PDP
module
were running with postmortem debugger
and our server starts with these
I love you know threes three statements
we make the server
we present status message and we surfer
ever
the postmortem debugger effectively does
this it effectively wraps that code in a
try except
a barracks up so catches everything
imports PDB
and then calls P beat-up post-mortem so
this looks an awful lot like AR
uS actress call read import PTV copy to
be set race
but its it significantly different I
wanna show you what show you how
arm and I also want to note water here
the you can use this in your own
software if you have some sort of
exception handler
and you actually have the exception to
pull from likes this target last acts
AXA extn is um
you catch a pass that in the PDB and
have a jump to a particular point as
opposed to just
a bear exception so if we view such
racist that a post-mortem
we're not gonna get all we want some
will hit wall curl to get into the
debugger
and if you'll notice the point we stop
inside a PB is actually the set trace
call not were the exception occurred so
this point
that call to out how to the calculator
has already been made
has failed it has raise an exception and
all the context is gone
so the post-war letters is Islam
is pretty honking great
so moving on to break points this is a
more started i've a little bit deeper
into PB
on break points
are a way to set stop point in your code
without actually edited it
which i think is pretty great especially
are doing with system library or a
framework
so here's an example where on the left
hand side in a slider seen
the some code from our our posts are
cock their application
this is the actual risk yet whiskey up
portion of it on the right hand side
you're seen the shell
interaction I love running under PTB
and now incentives type in COMT to
continuous news entropy be
I'm gonna tell I wanna break at PF calcd
RRP an app
so review set a breakpoint you can be
either a callable
or it can be at a particular line
number: arm
in in a in a file and this file can be
located
any in any directory that on the Python
path
you'll see that told that Pb tells you
the break point number one was Sat
tell you what line was set at and now we
go ahead and continue
so seven break-point is really simple um
it's a file online
or some function more product return to
that last parameter the condition in a
little while
so what is it a break point if we
use curl to make a another request
you can see that is gonna stop right
inside I love that RPN out function that
we've talked about before
even Chris the hike after class before
tries to process the
the arm input with him you inspect the
state of things like in Marin path info
I and then we can go ahead and continue
in let Iran or you may we actually want
to
look up in on the stock for some reason
just a little bit I've additional
commission a break points I'm when you
issue the Britpop brakeman by itself
without any promoters
I'll tell you what list all the break
points for you and tell you have been
triggered
arm the number of times triggered
is usually not all that interesting to
me he had there have been times I've
used briefly commands
incorrectly and I realize I only realize
it because
the the count getting commended but um I
think I'll
washable and AnnaLynne a little bit
%uh when you're running under PDB in the
post-war debugger the other thing that's
interesting is
if you press Control see or is a program
stops
is gonna automatically restart it for
you and all these break points remain
intact
so this is pretty handy at if you're
working on a program
and %ah you're making a few changes
in the Coen in your your code based on a
break inside the frame or the calls it
to actually step into an aspect was
going on you can make your edits
control see restart the program you
break points are intact and you're ready
to go again
um so P be a pretty good job love
managing
of managing this information for you so
you can
really focus on debugging your program
there are few arm additional commands
around breakpoints to enable them to
disable them
not a particular interest in
so what about that condition clause some
in the break in when he comes same break
points this assortment wrist in um
there are times when you a if you're
buying a web application for example
arm you might wanna only you know what
your problem
you no problem occurs on posts but you
don't wanna break
at every request because there's a whole
lotta gets before you
actually are able to push the button and
up
and get the post so YouTube reply
conditioned to do that sort of give us
our behavior
the replay condition is a python
expression that's going to be evaluated
in the context to the breakpoint and the
breakpoint only going to fire
if it evaluates to something true team
so in this case
I I'm gonna check if environment quest
method
is not equal to get as Gus tell me that
a break point
and I tiebreak it all let me know yep
I've set a breakpoint for you and I'm
only gonna stop
if this condition is true so
be when you actually go to run your
program you want to do something like
this
a lot entitlement program running on the
right hand side I'm gonna show
some girl calls if I did million or
request
two times three I'll simply see that
outputs
the it returns the interest 6 and
outputs the long line
I do to post reporters same thing but I
do a post with coral
is a sheer drop me into PT be right
there and now I can see the the request
method is post at this point
so report additions are really um
they make putting breakpoint very low
levels
are palatable mitnick a possible if your
own user django application to put
inside of the lowest level
our request handling arm it because if
you know if you have an idea what you're
looking for
you can bring you still very narrowly
target those breaks
to talk to her and her PDB how to look
around a program
how to go up and down the stock how to
set breakpoints
the final thing I wanna talk about arms
afternoon
is how you extend PDB and some
so the and there's a couple different
ways a
you go about this on
the and the first to these is aliases
wyman debugging a program I used or a
lot
I'll if an object but i wanna look at
I'll ill with Django for example using a
member right
i'm looking a model I know that there's
a way legalistic
all the local fields not model but I can
never for life me actually remember what
I method is
could ever call it my day-to-day work I
only seem to call it when I'm
is the writing some more primer coat or
when debugging something
so I use this Dr alias to from
shorthand pretty print door some
something and the shows he is the
someone's going to get
Rep replaced any up with the first are
you at the passengers alias
sold where does not look as if I just do
a print on self I'm gonna get a rep
wrote this class right
but I use dr. self it's actually going
to pretty print out
all the members of this class for me so
so this is sorrel showing a few couple
things re house on a list that you can
pass parameters to them
and arm that this is an example to me
that I use a lot
that probably doesn't belong inside of a
the stock behavior
but I can put into interim my bag of
tricks
um I didn't know why uses are will LOC
for locals
arm I've got the love are absurdres
whatever in PB bust
by default but know what would knowing
what the state is a special on going up
in on the stock
is is particularly useful Elise
oh and this is what middle doll does
show a local cues
is this can also refer other a-listers
arm so how predict alias I had a list
that two pt
was imminent know here is that my PD
alias doesn't specify percent one
all those arguments get passed on
automatically for me so
I'll you I mention that the the PDB
interpreter is old
it's simplistic in hand how approaches
parson and
sousa find a match it's going to go
ahead and pass on the remainder anything
22 that echoed in and of course
your aliases can also call aliases
YouTube you can do you start composing
things
so missus this was a cookies are a
little use for a while when I was
are more lot of sir classic Django views
that arm I wanted to look at what you
know if I request in context what are
the cookies on that request
did the way that you can um extended PDB
without actually headed in the sources
breakpoint commands
so these are commands that can be
executed
when a break point is hit and they're
actually hear it
just as if you were typed them at the PB
prompt um
those you give us some of the commands
that can be the water twenty or
I'll recommend you want basically
anything except I
next door step or continue and and as
the other one
and the reason you can use next step
continue it could be modify
where the car frame is it would be
ambiguous if you are you know what where
the next commander decks
what it would mean at that point so
example how this works is arm if I'm
with you my calculator program again
I just wanna see some
what the stock looks like a as as a
process as the input
I can do this for the breakpoint
commands so the first thing I do is
actually set my break point
and I know that line 21 is where its I
would have a pimple to the source
and I know it's where I wanna start
looking at things
and then I tell it commands one so that
one
is the breakpoint number that we got
back from break
you can see the prompt changes from PDB
to calm at this point now I'm entering
commands are gonna be executed
when this breakpoint shirts so in this
case I want to do
a couple things I wanna pretty print the
state which is the stock
and i wanna preprint what then what the
next value or operator coming in is
and then I'm gonna continue as I
continue
drop you back to the PB prompt I can
continue again to action star serving my
program
so when I run this what happens is I
make a call request and it goes to a
bunch of steps for me
basically is gonna continues to hit his
break point three times
in the process of process the one
request but is never actually gonna stop
executing
because the last commander told it was
continue so this is an example where
I've now effectively used a break point
which normally stops execution
to simply give me a little bit of
context about what's going on
so that I can play with my program a
little bit and understand it better
um and and go back and look at it
is also a you know it you knows does
still say it does still
point out PF calcd up I 21 to tell me
where it's breakin
there's also a silent command you can
give it to completely suppress that so
that all you see is this log information
are my views this bomb a few times
when been debating something in is again
inside a framework inside a python
um where I wanted to know what was going
on when I seen some code
but I did actually wanna stop because I
it was hit a whole lot
and I just wanted to grab a bunch of
State or on
because I was doing a much more
operations on on a program
the some customization we talked about
are interesting
but vay require that you actually type
in these commands rightly you type in an
alias antibodies breakpoint commands
and PTV actually provides a speedy BRC
file
and this is actually one what you want
to create for yourself or for your team
if you're gonna have his commands that
you share took sort of tool PDB for your
particular project or
organization this can be look at your
home directory or
or the current directory and if they
both exist is gonna actually the home
version first and then the current
directory and these commiserate are
basically entered
exactly as if they were entered entered
at PB's prompt
so you could imagine um using this
225 much a-listers defined break points
you commonly use and then
disable them so they're they're waiting
waiting for you when you drop in the PDB
in need them
um and and at all that sort of thing
and you gotta be that put comment on it
so that its are clear
its pretty powerful actually this is an
example I found
some the somebody smarter than me
figured out which is how to implement
stopwatch
and next watch and what this does is it
adds to commence to PB
the basically say continue execution
until this very bored I'm watching
changes
arm there's some really interesting
stuff going on here
and for people who one actually doctors
were diving the PB's
you know the actual controls a bit the
the religion thing to me here's the
command Q
cm dq kisses mission is pushing more
command into the queue
I as part of as part of execution alias
from so there's
lessened the sack overflowing in the AM
slides that
you can go on with the entire discussion
about it but those pretty interesting
that this is
some behavior that's pretty nice to have
inside your debugger
that you can very easily add to with the
PBR see
BB also arm to me um
is acceptable by other tools um but not
to talk about it in depth but as well
mention that there's
budget wasn't on public PB over
WebSockets
PB on in a sure curses interface
there's a I P be the dads tab completion
all these are built on the same core and
if your gonna start museum every we
talked about works
in these tools as well arm so these my
really want check out
if your knee max user and I hope you are
um
there's Python mode includes a nickel
PDB track
which his arms are the most amazing
thing ever wear it will actually
I'll follow you as usual if you want to
be inside the max
and why would he of course um
it will open files as you hit them so
that a
you always have the floor buffer right
next to you
Sappi be let you explore your program
however Christie about that
you can stop inside of code you can only
edit and
BB is extensible you can actually make
it fit your particular needs
um and your particular project with some
very simple commands
arm and I hope the y'all
walkway I'm here understanding that PDB
is a
is a great we'll have a little bag thank
you
I think we have a few minutes for
questions the farm maybe has them
there's a mic on
other side
thank you for the dark and your home at
my question is
related to when you have a break point
into his
loop a hand is this group is
really fast and every time you
it continue you good you go back at some
point like
you know that you have a million
iteration all big member
right and you want to quit and you
create and then you get back to the same
point in you breathe again and
good book and then you look for the
the ID to kill it in right for the
there's a couple different
commands we'll talk about end up the
that would be useful a bigger kit
particulars case
there's a week if you are done looking
at a particular function you just want
to get out of it
there's a return command there will be
one until the current
context um returns um
and so that with that would know if you
if you a break points at
though you have to some you could either
chart the return
which will return for the current
context and there's until we fall run
until a particular line is hit
but if you have a break points at than
what you really need to do is
arm disable it or tell it to ignore so
there was a slight like
452 replica mens if you know that is
going to have another 10,000 iterations
but you might say ignore to
forces by .2 5,000 as girl in 15
thousand times in a little break for you
so there's a couple drops you can depend
on how to set it up
but return until and then ignore disable
are probably give us a look at
thanks us who
when you're with when you're working on
a project I
you did mention the the BRC right and
said the
the breakpoints command their arm that
is
AC its desirable to said the the break
points there
arm but is there a way to said
the breakpoints in the source itself
maybe
and only trigger them if a certain flag
is called
I I saw that you can import PDB so I'm
guessing that year I do that
arm and my second question follow-up to
that
is arm would you use PTV to
test and and an instance on a staging
server and maybe
pipe though results at the calls to I
don't know
syslog or whatever so with respect your
first question about
um I magnin as you clarify commercial
segment so maybe stay there
are with respect to the first question
about
arm about condition about dismissed by
the break point inside at the source
and only triggering a in certain
conditions
at that point is really no different
than using such a race
so something the you might do is you
know if
some fly is true then PDB does a trace
and the centrists was gone actually drop
into
into PDB yeah I was mostly
interested in up for example I want to
run
my program and I'm only interested in
the post-mortem
so it's like okay run this do I have to
go in and
type continue I C um
you don't have to so some you could
the so basically you just need a use the
post-mortem call
at a top love and a top or bottom
handler so
you can imagine writing Django
middleware for example the prior has a
that has a Heather exception handler on
it that
imports PDB incalls PDB DUP post-mortem
arm with the exception information from
from sister I get lost
the xy um you
good imagine the island soap years ago
had a post-mortem debugging mode as well
that basically the same thing so
all you really do without points have a
top-level exception handler
and then you won't have to and calls PB
a post-mortem
and then you will have to arm type
continue in the program
was read your second question around um
running this on
staging and piping it to syslog I'm not
too sure
a creamy PB is really an interactive
tool you could conceivably arm
you conceivably is how a break point has
some commands that print is something
out
um I'm not sure how useful it actually
is there are there goes standard air
so if you can read rushed into their
that just sort of peoples gather
thats a great momentum thank you talk
and don't really have a question but on
I D one point out that if the your nine
Python user you can use test PDB
in if you get an exception I'm hi sonya
dropped right into it
a call so that if is out if using iPod
on from
interpreter is just a dash PB it'll drop
in the PDB
exactly in that applies to the notebook
as well ok cool
return 0 thanks one of the really nice
features a
DDB is being out to attach to a program
and started packing yet when its only
run
was one of those remote ones can do
something like that
so um RTB sort of does that
we desire to be before two arm basically
listen ot have another process wasn't or
socket
and then let you attaches something are
have another thread that was not a
socket let you attach
that way there's actually a project that
was on I
came across a complete so-called higher
inge
that does GB style attachment so is pyar
ING
allied include here cuz doesn't actually
use PDB it uses stone
sort of command syntax but that might be
something that you will look at as well
I have an hour compared GB question
their way to get like a display
like GB such a considers alt I'll
expression or variables as I step
through code
um so the question is around whether you
can see our display that shows the
resulting special as the comps
as its happening right select Display
you right
um the closest I be able to get
is basically the breakpoint commands
which continues so
is it they're dumb I think PUD be
is this curses version yet it's a and
it's really great yeah and then that has
the sort of dumb display you're talking
about
before your stock PDB um
the there's not really a place to show
that very aware that might be outputted
on a soul one-timer debugger that
unsupported an understatement
and no interest in phnom so he's 70 on
Thames to tipper
I'm it in her post not post mortem which
is why I think over
do but right and that works just by
recording the entire session altman's
event is
behind then I'm when you done dude stop
the programming in reply last month
which works like enough times to be
useful the book
I'm it I i guess i havent talked through
the help enough
like a zero is our way to the the thing
as a quick way to take that into
it's been a big don't think there's a
quick way to hack it in but it will be
pretty interesting to try
arm if you just wanted to record the
commands
and then play them back your you
probably
be able to justify some class in PB
but it's going to be pretty limited in
terms of the
the two cases well as national work
because if you had any other interaction
with the program
you're gonna have to re you're gonna
have to manually do that retraction
as well so from
it's a that's a quality I musher are you
how you about it most easily
right I'd like to thank Nathan for vet
has to talk and later he knows a break
down stairs
thank you very much