okay
good afternoon hike on hope you enjoyed
your luncheon at the poster session
there
and the job fair I am just a couple
announcements before we get started here
and I just like to remind all the
auction winners to pick up their
winnings
if you want an item the auction last
night please go down to the registration
desk
right now to pick it up they'll be
closing soon and secondly
I like to mention the sprints after the
conference and it will be holding
developments prints
Spencer great chance to get your first
patch accepted to you favor library
and meet the authors and get introduced
to open source contribution
so stick around after the closing
messages for an introduction to the
sprints
or just show up here on Monday and if
you want to lead a sprint
please prepare a two minute description
to get people excited about spending on
the project
okay assessed humanism
okay it is now twenty seconds okay and
to get people excited about spending on
the project
you have to present that after the
lightning talks okay
I am so next up we have crater schemes
and he's gonna be telling us about
PostgreSQL almonds
for humans take a two-week break thanks
to everyone
so I'm cursing I work at hurricane Iran
product for a couple teams for data team
a transfer record high stress
I languages team I am I basically have
the job doing whatever the engineers
don't want to be a
is where describe it I to really quickly
a to sort of sound some quick in Chama
spikes
and drugs talk it's gonna be a little
bit of a shotgun approach Metro kinda
lotta
but there is information that you on a
lot to get through so it'll kind of be a
little bit desperate
at times on for some shameless plugs II
curator I
non-islamic help us first weekly on
eastern end user app developer and his a
stress hopefully it has useful content
I I'd like a good bet pass-first guy is
kinda
a guide for I'm you know getting started
up to you
some and I think all things and
prosperous I if you're on a map
Mac use post rest ap don't use
back porch a homebrew on a GRT got it
great keep using it but I if you run
into problems with it which you well
I get past estaba try and then our
Erica we ran a lot of stress so I
usually when I i cant quite he talks and
usually when I talk about you know high
stress on my screen I put up a slide
I that looks kinda like this on this is
all the awesome features and pasta
recipe don't know about something aside
google it every single thing here he's
probably know about news
I'll have the ability to use it sometime
arm
to make this easy for for Twitter I
this is a quote by a coworker and
basically post press is becoming more
and more
data platform that is just a relational
database on this full text search there
she is.
and there's about everything you could
want to do in there I
and it's really becoming a much more
flexible haha wrong so kinda getting in
till a bit more
that the meat I'll when you think about
database workloads are sketchy wasters
I allow penalty p IOM
cell ltp is essentially webapps om
that's you know web application Shango
flask I
small writes and reads transactional
workloads I am
allowed is business reporting be I
larger ports over a lot of data
on you're looking at I am pp type
solutions here
and I essentially not gonna talk about
any %uh this really in the talk
I'm so sure looking at this I you need
to get kinda
advice I'm and warehousing stuff have
been shot afterwards
but hopefully most the people in this
room are by that developers
my sister has said the case for most
people developing webapps
okay costs alright I can't thank God
I am on set up and configure I'm not
gonna spend a whole lot I'm here since
you only have to do it once
other shorter than is a John
Amazon I use her ok Ill Oregon check out
this talk last year I think from
icon on said mining and analyzing a cop
it is pasta ski on its not your day job
by Christoph Hess it's a great talk
basically there's about 30 convicts you
need to set up once
what you do it you're done I am so I
start there
and essentially don't worry about it on
because Amazon
it's short of virtualized infrastructure
atop a virtualized infrastructure on top
shelf
more virtualization on it a little
different
if you're on any other cloud I'm a lot
of them are a good bit different you get
a little more predictability and
and disconnect anything I'm the best bet
is to stress going to get a job
so you're saying how much you can take
their I'm a little different
I'll basically you up and running and if
you're on real hardware
I high-performance PostgreSQL despite a
little
all now is based on as Chris 9.0 on but
if you guy
SSD's fusion-io I'm really kinda any
real hardware
at this is still really applicable i
think is being upgraded for updated for
9.3
but I essentially this is aryanna Starr
on and they're going to the slides as
well
so I anytime I i coming weekend i'm new
database
a first thing I do is like take the
thirty thousand but you have
how's this doing on there's any more
hardware
is it just screwed on how how that are
we doing
I and the number one thing that anywhere
that care about
is that the cash so post-crescent really
good at keeping frequently accessed data
in memory
I I know you think any better at
catching your data and has Creswell
you want on go ahead and try it's really
getting this
I'm so all essentially a name for a
pretty high like 99 percent cash ratio
administering de nada memory
99 percent at a time one person
attending desk arm
to get that year and the super simple
query
and its gonna give you something that
looks like this I am
basically don't cry try to memorize the
clear you figure out what it's doing its
crazy and help us press stuff some the
columns actually don't make sense
combats gonna give you know the cache
hit ratio
on and like I said 99 percent or higher
is what you're aiming for
on if you don't have that you probably
wanna throw more memory in the box
on that's the easiest way to search
going to database
so index hit is another one and how
often are using indexes for not so
this is definitely important for web
applications if you're talking about be
I
and reporting applications it's less
common I
but what I wanna see is you know heavy
index usage on thing sir
trend X on frequently
so that crazy me something like this and
from here I can actually start digging
in and saying
I where we're going to add in Texas
and %uh some rough guidelines so cache
hit ratio
I'm 99 percent or higher as soon as you
drop below 90
9 percent don't like 95 you're gonna see
performance significantly tank
and ex-head ratio a greater than 95
percent
I actually have a tweet somewhere in my
history that aladdin and exxon every
column and every table in your database
I'll an encourager be could definitely
do it on
if you're using a table that said I've
got a table and backers again said there
never using index
I start acting like it should be pretty
straight forward on higher using the
table
I if it's really small table and you can
get away without it
so I love really handy shortcut how he
will hear use like a pasar see here
MRC how the people here use a PC carsey
I'm actually impressed that theres like
10 hands in the room I'm so peace Eagle
RC is awesome
it does and it's the same thing right
and you can set a lotta commands
at the really nice thing is that you
cannot set in short cuts here so I can
name Clarisse
so I can have that cash head query saved
and just ran cacheid
on any database I can act on its gonna
run a query for me answer really handy
for free call use queries across
different systems are working with
so a better a quick detour on how data
is retrieved
I'm hopefully this is really boring and
101 by if it's not
I think it's a good baseline for every
one and a half
so on when iraq in your database in your
training data from it
really basically attack on come down to
consume data want to waste
on a sequential scans all the data
simply sitting on desk
and if you have a query select star
where this condition is true it's gonna
start generating on desk
on and looking for data that meets at
condition
and the only way it's gonna stop on
scanning that he was why it's
you got a lot on so she got a limit of
one its gonna find the first row
and tell me second ish an reading desk
is obviously slow
are in contrast is an index right so
here to add really done down version a
b-tree index
whereas can now based on this initial
value I'm gonna go to you
but the setting records anarchy
traversing down to have this record
on indexes House press nine to four
always had to help desk
so post retire the covers is a really
giant and only lock
I just keeps writing data writing their
writing do you know when you to lead a
date actually writes data
so N and exit in memory may not know the
date has been removed
so it always has had escalating index
and post crest
by +91 up and there's something an index
only scant that
if he can use it it's great it's kind of
magic white doesn't doesn't
I am there's not created by Shirley tell
a shooting when it should be using wired
doesn't buy it must that I can use it
well
I know that's not super helpful but here
on ninety nine three get some
performance gains there
so roth somewhere sequential scans okay
they're not always bad they're good for
like report any better
carry-over atomic data on
and expands web applications this is
where you should mostly see
I index can't be in use on its famous
coming quarters in your app
isolation expect
so how do you understand specific query
performance
and given a really basic wary I what we
can do is put in explaining from it
on post dress for every query its Ryan
has a
a query plan and putting a smile show
you what the query planes going to be
and how long it thinks it's going to
take I mean you're gonna get this
kinda cryptic output the Super Street
Ford and anyone the first time a look at
it
I it's really not too bad so there's
three values right there
on the startup time which is how long it
takes to start that process
I'm the max I'm it thinks it's going to
take and how many roses thinks it's
going to return
on running explain analyze
you're going to get what it thinks it's
going to do which is great out there
about any actual time
and so want the real thing you wanna
look at there is that Max hyman each
step
a whereas taking it on a time
dumbing ahead have a rough guidelines I
love queries and web applications
on aiming for pagers hi simon Le Santana
Moss I guess kinda nice
are coming for you should be in less
than 10 milliseconds I really am for
round one I can always get below one
millisecond
I can usually get to I have
wine .5 Chennai seconds pretty
consistently on any
for a run I mean more rare queries less
happened in a sec
to coming back here on it you gotta pay
that's slow
I you can basically run me explain on to
explain allies
I would actually executes the query as
well and see how long it takes
and say okay this is crap let's a
let's start optimizing on basically
pretty straight forward I had
filter on salary understand that an
index on salary
I wanna see this hot from using a
scandal scandal Return Index can now
and Mike Hightower expect
so this is great if I have us at page
that I want optimizing queries
I'm some people start there but for a
lot of people it's like
hey how do I look at my database an
aggregate say I wanted to start
optimizing queries at Pt stats cement is
probably the least
are most underused physically told
directly and prosperous
so what it doesn't is normalized every
single query
against your database to where I got you
know I Cox question right there
on its like Iran and at that with were
in a legal strike in iraq and I just
walked out I get her a few
on for that parameter and when this is
gonna do
I'll when you turn on your database by
just running for an extension piece
estimate
Harcourt every single Korean its rhyme
I'm the average time it takes
and how many times it's run I'm so I can
run something like this now
which will give me the total number of
time a craze been running into some the
average number time
and the query itself
so from here I can say what are the most
expensive queries in aggregate on my
system and won't work I optimize
so coming back to this knowing I can get
to it and he's probably down to 10
seconds
I can say I i cant get two orders of
magnitude back on a second one and get a
lot of time back to my system pretty
spread quickly
so our index is high-stress has quite a
few
on if you're like me I when you when you
read the docs
the general reaction is this
on the docks to help out on and explain
kinda what they are under the covers but
not when you use them
I really done down versions b-tree when
you say create index
this is what you get this is usually
what you want usually don't have to
think too much about it
on if you're doing anything interesting
I like pushy I asked for full text
search
or something more unique data types like
hora you may want to resellers
so I generalize inverted index as I
Genentech's
I wrought on it he got multiple values
in a single column this is what you want
so its shore I had eventually J sign
I a race out of time to put this on
their
and some cases just to be a little
better but I wouldn't worry too much
about it
I jest ruffle a tom is full text search
for shapes
so if you're doing GIS stuff I'm going
to be using a lot I just
Nexus aspin three others
I can and as for similarity
SPGs I've had this explain to me about
50 times by a lot of us press people
on it all I know is is good for phone
numbers so
I yeah on if you have a straightforward
explanation I would love to hear
I'm vodka on cell
almost all these index has come out as a
group led the Huskers community i
I'm here for stress the russians I am
their job at a professor's over and
University of moscow want a professor
astrophysics and attacks on house place
for fun
on the come up with crazy ideas for
indexes and optimizations
and I but I believe is one that
up-and-coming
it's a space partition Chen and X I
and because they're Russian they they
thought we had Jan and we needed by K
and their
this is the working name I hope it
doesn't make it in this this I don't
know
when that battle I
yeah so morning Texas I'll spit and he's
pretty quickly on you also have a
condition on factual a nexus
on conditional hopefully is pretty
straightforward I'm selecting star from
places
on and I say I only want big cities rain
and maybe that's a a common thing in my
application
a good example is this is where current
address is true rate if you got history
where everyone's leading the only care
about the recent one mostly
on UK index on that and pretty
straightforward seniors can add the
condition on the index
just like you would in a query I'm so he
got out on a date at the only 1i index
of it
for I efficiency I have news for teasing
also functional in Texas so you can
index on a function
I'm so in this case I got sunday sunday
to
I am daytime a stress is marginally
useful right now
on yet to write about two functions to
make it useful
I'm but I can basically say give me this
at
key back population and i wanna find her
populations greater than
10,000 so I can actually add an index on
that function so I
any function impulse Press any
user-defined function you can and exxon
I am one important thing about
functional in Texas
and hopefully a sound a little weird
counter-intuitive candidate in the first
if the same and putting the function
returns the same output
I you want to meet up on it so basically
if you have random things happening in
the function
are you wanna meet upon and post-test
rhesus differently and knows that has
always been a return the same result
given the same input
and does very very different things for
her performance
ISO condition on functional I hopefully
no surprise here you can combine DC
can say in how the output in this
function is created in some time
to another thing a create index
concurrently if you're running any
production
%uh system this is probably what you
wanna be using I'm here and create
indexes gonna hold the lock on a table
of rewriting that index
i'm concerned. other databases this is
the only choice you have
I post-crescent least gives you another
option where create indexing currently
is going to build this index up in the
background
I'll I say there's a whole lot that's
only half true at all to lock for
a couple of milliseconds so for a couple
of milliseconds you can write here David
database I but it's pretty trivial
I it's gonna be slower by it's just not
working
factory now production on everyone's
happier
I'm is anyone here using a store and
past press
okay thing on hazing Jason
okay a few hands I am eight stores are
some people should use it if you're
unfamiliar with it
are here have a quick run through after
eight stories a key-value store inside
your database
outside just another datatype I you
enable it by running for an extension a
store
and then you have this a store data type
down here
on I usually get some flack for congress
data but I think it's fair catch train
and AM turning in there is a keen eye
store
an be can do things like this
psych answered you know I genders male
status California here
I can answer all sorts in your keys I
can die
search filter on those just like you
expect I'm just like any other key to
the store
I J sin God and suppose kress and
9 who I believe and 93 it became a
little more useful
I am it's still marginally useful on J
sin is really just
validation on text today and there's no
big optimizations around it just
validates the Texas Dallas
on there are some functions for helping
was searching on it now
that came in 93 I but overall it have a
marginal use
on if you're using EES I eight stores
kinda the way I have go today
I'm index has worked with its own Jan
just index you can just at age in index
at Sky index every key every value I
insider database
there's a talk at fosston this year
research for performance have
I post best first Mongo DB I am
it actually hold up compares pretty well
arm in some cases it's faster
some cases lowers in some cases the
grandest and some cases smaller but it's
really comparable overall
I it's not a full document star though
which is what a lot of people I
I'm such a sign you know what's that on
it is a for Jason documents are in
Cyprus Press
I but functional indexes are you have to
do to get good performance there unless
you're just showing and i cant pulling
it out
I'm so have fun with that I miss him a
lot of working at performance
I press nine fours around the corner and
Jason be just committed
I'm so Jason B is binary representation
and chase on desk
and that this is actually crowd poration
with a lot of people with Engine Yard
Roku PD experts and the russians of
course
and they were involved in something
crazy I
said this is what was aged or two
with Chase on top of it which indexes
work so kinda the best serve all worlds
finely tuned to buttress
I believe the plan is just to bina data
type
so our connection pooling on is another
big area
on if you're on Django 1.5 or earlier
please tell me you're using a connection
polar
I'm Django 1.6 II got persistent
connections and the ability to have a
polar
and makes life a lot better on if you're
running a database with SSL you should
expect a connection on Jinger 15
to be around thirty to forty seconds I
30 to 40 milliseconds for just getting a
connection you've got maybe you want to
second query
are no sanctuary but you're spending 30
times had actually just getting the
texture database
I see clout to me is already pretty good
here on but in short you can I got a
couple options about the application
framework handling this for you
question has gotten a lot better I'm in
recent releases see clock me does as
well
i'm anne also got the nationalist an
on-demand so even with
a connection to learn your framework on
you may
matsu run II server-side application
side
on caterpillar I am post rest as well
up to a hundred China connections and
then after that you need to consider
another option
on the POS press Options there's really
two IPD bouncer and petty pol
I won't go into details over might
encourage these at PG bouncer I don't
know that anchors the city for
it takes such as you're doing a whole
lot of things okay
and PD bouncer does one thing really
well which is connectable
are so when it comes to scaling
as I mentioned the easiest way a bus
killing when you need more memory
is scale-up I'll but as a certain point
that's not possible for databases
IMC can also scale that out on post
dress when you have a replica any such
an increase to it
it to keep that cast completely separate
so it's gonna have all the same data
but its cash much in memory is going to
be different so you can do things like
sending
guy you now read-only queries for
certain model arch one database as gonna
keep all that data in memory
so you can start to feel out pretty
easily that way without a heavy shorting
architecture I to set that up you know I
have some kinda replication
I her cue we make it easy with followers
I a lot of service providers try
different things there
and injuring yourself there's several
options
some these have been around for a really
long time and their summaries in one so
posh Prescott
a a synchronous I replication around
I forget it either 90 or 91 I'm it's got
a lot more useful
on its okay to set up on your own
without any help
and the skilled too tall to hear the
bottom I make a lot easier so while you
something we'd open source
on it runs powers all her record
databases
on for foreign policy stuff I barman is
something out a second quadrant
I Bali is high time it's basically just
the
at Sprint report Itasca to get a lot of
utilities to make this easier
I backups so there's two types the
backups
I and post rest most people and I think
about backups they only think about
logical backups
so this is what happens when he ran
keyed up on your database and this is
what most people think I'm as backups
I'm a charitable its portable a Thai
people start with
I the other is a %uh as a backup
or also known as a base backup on if you
set up replication
you had to do this at some point this is
kinda what powers act I'm just the
physical by time desk
this is not crash cross-platform across
architecture dependent
I am it it up promise to be it may be is
some people have said it is so much that
it isn't
don't rely on this it will break at some
point that's pretty much a guarantee
a little bit a comparison between this
here I logical backups are
by good for you know moving something
from
your production environment on locally I
miss you guys had developing on a Mac
person
running on Ubuntu on get for portability
I but has led on the database when he
fired this of it's going to have a lot
on your database
impact performance I it works early on
but it stops working at a certain point
especially if your database has slowed
so if you're in now serving traffic I am
it'll have an impact there at South
working at a certain point
I generally the community search
encourage
once you're a big database image
strictly to physical backups
I'm there's a little more initial setup
I but there's limits and no load on the
system
and it scales I essentially everyone its
large-scale
eyes you so kind of a
really quick recap I am a lap
is a whole other talk I am when you're
looking at all applications Desai
the scale is really important I'm so
you're looking at
as a seasoned fusion-io the hardware on
the order on desk is
helpful important and PD reorg is crazy
thing outta NTT that reordered
bites and Esquire sitting there in your
your databases live in production
works really well as long as you don't
do anything wrong and possibly wipe all
your data
part to that are being examined for
contributed back to progress but it's a
it's a
ways to go to make that safe and then
there's a lot I am pp solutions on top
stress I a lot of data warehousing
project start our
as press I so there's post respite in
there i think im
if you look at redshift it even a a long
long long ago post grass
at some point though it they started to
be a pretty far from that
on and then for the bulk and SRTP
webapps I mention about commuting is in
cash
on and that you have to get high cash
rate optimize your overall query love
with peace at statements
on check your indexes and then you know
when cash ox at room or at it
it really is an easy way to start the
day these problems I wouldn't be overly
wasteful
I but scaling up more memory and it
definitely helps if you're low on cash
thanks and I'll take a few questions
a great
messed up thanks i was just wondering if
you could talk a little about
the whether Herold who uses the vacuum
statement
backing analyze yes lol
we're we have a heart attack him on all
databases
I we don't mean a leak bigger too much
on backing used to be horrible
high-stress
now it's just bad I
it's actually gotten a lot better iraq
has pretty good how much you have a
database with
super super high load I so are attacking
should keep up
on if you look it up on our actual
speedy action as if you search for that
on her IQ
I there's a i command line plugin that
charge a lot for researchers like cash
index hit there's also one for bloat I'm
in looking at Dannys
lotus has away at the need to Chiang I a
vacuum or not
I tightest going still Eclair Yorkshire
on her ok you look at
your pediatrician and saying out his
plan hi
and there's a blunt actor on usually I'd
say something about 5 10 X
as well and okay backing is not doing
its job package weekend thank you
a
thanks for the talk I'm you talked a lot
about optimizing the database for heavy
reload do you have any advice for either
what performance metrics to look at her
how to optimize database for heavy right
loan yet so heavy right low and it's
rare to see
on heading right load on you can do a
variety of things
I'm depends on how much you care about
your data on you can run us kress
I with unlock tables which I consider my
god mode
where basically your data center right
really fast but may or may not stay
there
I every index
has been a slow that down I mean it's
the biggest thing is over Houston Texas
I'm you can get away a lot of that on a
heavy retiree but just because you don't
need high throughput
I there's on market indexes
om there's a variety of us question
thanks i'd might look it up
that talk has crashed killing it on your
day job on it gets a little more down to
ask
makes I don't think there's anything
super high cap to developer level
other than don't overuse index is really
when Tyrell
I'm sorry didn't hear you mention
analyze and I've had some pretty big
surprise at some point with some
database that were not analyzed in their
return some harsh
quieres so is is is still there needed
with the latest version of that was his
crew
yes OR so around analyze the thing
years you need to run after doing a big
ball club I
once if you're kinda running a fraction
much citing you know you're not doing a
lot of bach loads
on and off resort type things then
you're fine
%ah allies I is actually really
important do at a level closer to that
post rest knows to lay out your data
I but on the production side night she
wearing because us press is constantly
monitoring and watching this
I so yeah it's it's definitely something
to consider if you're
like doing ETL processes are with allied
data
I but for average production site I
wouldn't worry about it after really
depends I
his case thank you you mentioned it
very wide open in just a few weeks ago
some other work that's being done
for pluggable storage day portable
storage engines in there
potentially column their stores and
stuff like that you elaborate a little
bit on the future that and purrs Chris
over the next few releases
so the up talkable storage engine is
definitely speculative
on these people wanted to feel they
don't think me tank or on
there was a car store release has
appointed a rapper by cited state a
last week which is really awesome I'll
I think we're gonna see a lot FTW
support on this
and anti-morsi more up I also read
engine I know some companies I can talk
about that has an interest in it
I so there's some potential for it but I
think we're definitely looking at least
I year and a half probably
two-and-a-half years before we have
I a completely Michael storage where
some really interested in
NH torso when you say keep value store
I actually think about memcache reddish
but if you have a 99 percent
cash hit rate and your cash is in memory
it seems like this could be a really
cool way to not have to spend up like a
man cash a reticence in send you
everything in post press
so is that can if the kollek how you see
people actually using each door is this
kind of like where that's going on my
totally of I mean it definitely can I
don't think that's the
top I'm or use case I think it's more
that schema less flexibility
I am so like for us we use it in
whenever a huge production systems at
I'm to check on every database every 30
seconds I me answer all sorts of things
and every week you wanna say hey we want
to measure something new
SN running a migration adding some
columns in may be throwing away a month
later
we just added to our HR I and start
observing at data and it's already index
we can see if it's useful and so we can
I every factor it out
but generally we just leave it there
just because it works performant
I may get a slight asking less
flexibility I'm
there's a lot of stuff for a user
account I may eventually wanna track
I that I can just throw in there I'm
are a nominee email and password but I
mainly I had no idea what else I wanna
track for user
I'm you can get some other functionality
at a
they would use a red predator in cash I
might start there I
I don't like go to too far with it
I I can I could use cases feature fact
right on
you need to rule out future fights for
everything on a feature or me just have
a bucket a future flaxen what some
insight into
I and a lot of people will look at our
restaurant cash sometimes there
I so it depends I would start with a
store
and then as you outgrow it what you will
on
register and cast be helpful there okay
that's all we have time for
thank you Greg when
in