right now it is my pleasure to welcome
augie
fackler and Nathaniel meant to stop
close
I give them a warm round of applause hi
hi good afternoon thank you for coming
this is my friend augie he is a
contributor to mercurial and various
pipe on libraries
this is my friend Daniel he's the tech
leader my lunch the summer cold weather
application that also runs cool coat in
and has contributed to pilot how many
view task your software
good good how many %uh view task your
software from the perspective other
users
so if you're writing a web app you have
to ask the driver browser
okay now how many have you document your
software in terms of stating
what people can actually explicitly
depend on about your behavior
men's good now how many have you have
had an angry mob come after you because
you made some change your software
it didn't change in a year guarantees in
all it s kept passing but they were
still angry because something had
changed
okay we've we've all been there and
we've all had that problem and we want
to expand on these topics today
to give you some better tools to have a
better conversation
when that situation comes up and what
we're going to be talking about
is behavior or envelopes for software
now these are gonna be like a physical
and below matter
metaphor it's not going to be like
putting network packets in some
larger envelope we are thinking in terms
of
flight envelope spur aircraft so this is
the flight envelope
love a F 104 a Starfighter airplane
this particular a envelope talks about
the behavior the aircraft big
as relates between its airspeed and its
altitude and there's some extra
information here I G forces that's kinda
hard to understand
but the if you're above those curved
lines
in still inside the white space on the
chart your plane flies when you're
having a pretty good time after below
those curved lines your plane isn't
going fast enough to fly
and if you're in the Reds base your plan
is falling apart
now I found this compelling because it's
a very simple matter for
right it tough it takes oliver given you
know
space in along certain dimensions and it
divides it into
what is allowed and what's not allowed
and I wanted to know can we do this for
software
can for software systems we find a
mansions along which
some you serve the software is allowed
and some his disallowed
you know whether it looks like this we
don't quite know what the dimensions are
you up but
but can we talk about our software this
way in terms of envelopes
and so we think that we can and in fact
we have some examples
the math package in Python has the
square root function
and it actually has a very well defined
set of inputs
rate you can give it any number that's
greater than or equal to 0
and anything less than zero is invalid
and give you a valuer
another level obstruction if you spot a
video game
you know the the webstore the box will
have some descriptions are
what the requirements for your system
are great how much RAM you have to have
CPU speed you need to take things like
that one of my favorites
runs and four gigs around by Hassli
close by when brother cuz I only have
four gigs because otherwise
the performance is really terrible
kilometer the bottom and unacceptable
performance there
another example is an HTTP Server
America bunch of different ways we can
look at http for servers
they're a bunch of different things we
can call HTTP servers
so here's Python class rhyanne
and it's a pipe bomb object and it's an
HTTP Server
and it has an input any input must be of
type
HTTP request and if we pass a string
that is unwarranted use up the system
the system is not specify that way
so if we look at this system's behavior
all input there is
in the space of all possible pipe on
values
there's an allowance for objects of type
HTTP request and everything else is
disallowed
at another level abstraction HP server
is a service you're talking to
over the network so you connect to it
you send us some sequence of bytes
if not a valid input it works if it's on
forbidden him from a beer
just sending it random garbage it will
tell you that you sent to dinner
that might look something like this with
the plane in this case the is every
possible sequence and by its
and the red dots are sort of a a word
crude representation of things that are
going to be invalid
now sometimes when we talk about an HTTP
Server
we're talking about something like this
and even though it's a physical says
some
it's still supports the notion of
disallowed input
right this is a disallowed input for the
server right
some joker decided to hook a cat5e
Ethernet cable up to a wall socket
and call that the ether killer so you
can let the magic smoke out if you
return a cardinal stop working
but we can still talk about the systems
in part in the same terms
right from -1 the positive one vaults is
supported in part
and everything else is disallowed we've
drawn it in two dimensions here
but because there were eight wires and
the ethernet cable it's actually kinda
van Oct 20
hypercube now we both have some on a
background in physics where the things
we do in physics a lot
is sorta look at a system from both
sides and try and apply similar
principles
so we're gonna go through the looking
glass and start talking about the
outputs Kamloops am a lot of time
thinking about
inputs to a system so when we talk about
the outputs of a system and output
envelopes
we're not talking about systems that
have deterministic evaluations right
this is
a system that always evaluates to the
exact same value in fact that's what the
utility of this expression is
and here's another one if this didn't
always produce exactly the same value
it wouldn't be nearly as useful to us
but here's a system but
doesn't produce exactly the same value
every time
but it doesn't produce any arbitrary
value either make its gonna give you a
value between 0&1
but input the promises actual it'll give
you some random value that's the whole
point
there are others more complicated
systems that have definitions kinda like
this as well this is a software package
we discovered reading the star
that is a database which will give you
less accurate results the quicker you
want a result so one of the inputs you
give to the system his how fast you need
a response
and it'll give you less accurate data
the last time you give it but it still
guarantees some value
systems for operate in the presence have
adversary all contact
I'm such as those that are proprietary
in some way or something like games that
are dealing with cheaters
who often have inexact specified system
behaviors right because they don't want
to give too much away
they simply want to specify the bare
minimum that they possibly can
and leave room for a lot of different
implementation details
so we've talked about input envelopes
and similarly there are output envelopes
and we're gonna described now that a
system's behavior or envelope
is the sum of those things and any other
incidental behaviors in between like
side effects
and so this is kind of like a worm hole
through multiple dimensions but
there some input domain with I am with
dimensions of its own
and a system will translate into another
universe
into some output domain with some other
dimensions
so now we define what animal it is we
want to say that you should be stating
your system's behavior envelope
preferably the only communication that
your client should need to be able to
make use if your system
should be this description love what
behaviors are guaranteed cannot
guarantee you're probably already doing
some part of this right
you specify valid inputs you specify the
Rangers outputs
maybe you talk about what parts of your
system are thread-safe
now when you specify your envelope it
guarantees that you will have thought
about it
which will put you hadn't shoulders
above many of your colleagues and peers
who haven't done that
so we see three tools that are the most
readily accessible for defining these
envelopes
the first one is a type system that's a
job for example has a stronger type
system to imagine
many you've encountered I there's
machine check constraints for it that
the tests
in that documentation and the
documentation itself is also very
important as are some things you just
can't fit in a type system
so digging deeper into type systems
here's the same function
in two different languages right we have
pie pan on top
and we have passed on the bottom in pipe
on the function exists
but there's no type rich information
about it we can't
query up for what its types are it
doesn't it doesn't communicate with its
types are
the Haskell version house a type
annotation along with it
and scripts and machine assistance can
come along and
and can say to programmers using a
conseguir hey you've made a mistake here
you've made a TypeError here
also new users about function can come
along
and they can look at it and without
reading a prose a a word of prose
documentation
they can see okay this is a system in
which inputs and outputs are related
a certain way and in particular they can
see that
the input type up the first argument to
the function
must match the component type up the
second argument to the function
and so its behavioral in part kind of
looks like this
infinitely far along the dimensions are
the first and second arguments to the
function but only valid along the line
at which the component typeof the second
argument matches that
the input type up the first argument now
tests generally look something like
this:
and the tests are valuable because
they're sort of these fans come straight
the
the the type system trees others nice
broad continuous
boundary for you the tests are sort of
suggestive a boundary
will come back to it later but these
tests you know they're useful
but they're not a salir you might wanna
sure somebody else so you might also
write tests that look more like this
right so when we're saying you should
use task to define your envelope
this is a very easy task for you to tell
a client about
for you to use as part of your
specification and then documentation
let's use or to fill in the gaps where
you don't have other tools rate very few
tech type systems
let you annotate whether or not
something is thread-safe ugh I'm
probably doing haskell because their
type system Middle Eastern complete
but you can't do that use fully enjoy
our price:
so these systems are not don't just
stand in isolation very complimentary
and that reminds us of our child's right
so
this reminds us a defining space another
way which is
when we were kids like we go over to the
aunts house you know you'd wanna go out
in the giant backyard to play
and the grown-ups would want to keep an
eye on us and they tell us things like
okay you know I want to be able to see
you when you play is so
don't cross that line into the woods and
stay between the two trees on either
side
and this is carries because its defining
a space using a combination of
continuous lines
and distinct points along some other
dimension
this is kinda the way that type systems
and test specifications play together
the type systems draw continuous
contours through some space
and separate out all values of one type
from all values have another type
whereas test conditions specify specific
points with specific values have
individual
point %uh individual types but you can
still use them in combination
to define some region up some space so
coming back to softer here's a different
HTP sir and so taking
a request object that's already done a
whole bunch of work this takes a string
in
intake and emits a string out and so
from the type systems perspective that
the input looks kinda like this
in the space of all possible objects
there's this ellipse
with that will assert represents all
strings that can come in
now we can start writing tests that no
Britain that we've reject things they
were invalid and then add in more fence
posts that are basically things that are
valid and you can sort of see this
boundary within
the domain of strings that some strings
are valid and some art but it's not
described in this nice
concrete way where there's a hard and
fast line
so when you've received guidance that
says you should author your test
conditions near the boundaries of what
your software supports
the reason for that is that your tasks
are in part
defining the boundaries up what your
software system supports
and then documentation and types work
together very well
to the so this is a screenshot of some
javadoc just because it presents better
than
and some the other documentation systems
but you notice is a buncha types in the
slide
that the programmer didn't put their
entire front I heard
generated documentation you'll still see
like the names of the funk the
function arguments as as their specified
in the code these things play together
very well
to how many have you have ever read
software that contains less
written software that contains less
alright
this is a legal disclaimer Betfair's
legally there is no reason for you to
believe that this software is any good
for anything
but when we write software hand and
specifically when we want to persuade
clients or customers to use for softer
we'd like them to believe that our
software accomplishes some goal
we'd like them to to see that our
software works
and the way that we can do that the best
way to do that is with a demonstration
of it with a real live
exercise of code that comes from Taz
tass are real live exercises code
so this is another argument saying you
should ship your tests
as part of the definition up your
software and you should not just have
tests that are
you know unit St their budget codes can
implement read
if it makes sense if it's part of what
your clients should really be reading is
pretty documentation
you should have in your documentation
machine checked examples that people can
read from
and understand how your system operates
in a in a more fluid way that they can
trust because of course
that itself is machine checked and
verified to start work
so where we are is your system has an
input envelope
and an output envelope that comprises
its behavioral envelope
and we're saying you should use that
types tass
and documentation to specify that now
are some envelopes better than others
yes in particular
we feel the smallest envelope you can
use fully provide to your users
it or you know library users end-users
is the best one great that the fewest
promises you can make today
but still have a useful package is is
what you should be aiming for
and fewer promises makes everyone
happier because
I am fewer promises
make everyone happier because fruit
fewer promises reserves
future growth on if your system is going
to be long-lived and if your system is
not going to break backwards
compatibility
then your envelope must never recede and
so if your envelope start small
you're reserving space to grow if your
envelope starts a large
you're gonna have a lot of promises to
keep as time goes by
so we've got some examples love
envelopes that have sort of been
ill-defined great that there's at least
is an envelope to find but we're not
happy with it
and so the first 1 I'm going to pick on
his HD peel them I
issues actually a pretty decent HTP
library if you're doing the normal
HTTPS things you're not going to have
any problems
other than the API being a little bit
wacky but Mike
my beef with HTTP Live is right in the
doc string for the model has this
enormous state machine actually bleeds
of the end of the slide in its not
important that you can see the whole
state machine it's important that it's
there
and that after that state machine in the
documentation has this wonderful sense
which states that I'm not going to
enforce the state machine even though
it's what I assert that I'm going to go
through
so that if you're a sophisticated clan
you can abuse my internal implementation
details to do something clever like
implement request pipelining
now that sounds awesome but it's
actually terrible because it means you
can't go in and fix defects
in the implementation HTTP Live because
you've documented all this internal
behavior as part of the things that your
clients can depend on
and in fact there are things that I
would try and fix in HD feel that just
park feasible because I've the document
documented internal behavior now we've
talked about
envelopes for systems that are directly
call a ball
such as functions it turns out that
classes have envelopes as well
and in particular the input and below
per class is
the Sat Nav functionality that is
available to call on that class
Java's object a class as an example
love I a place where the input and elope
was gotten wrong
they were deciding what is the Sat above
methods
that should be callable on all Java
objects
and they mistakenly made it too wide and
they included these two methods
in that's at and it turns out that these
were specified in such a way
that they couldn't always fulfill their
goals and they wound up being useless
and meaning less than their
worked on the language and no one really
uses them at all anymore
for for concrete example finalizes like
Dunderdale in Python
break it's the thing that gets run when
your object has been cleaned up by the
garbage collector
the promise that the semantics for the
garbage collector such that you have no
guarantee your object will ever actually
be cleaned up
and as such there's no guarantee that
your final EIS will ever run
and so if you have some expensive
resource you thought you wanted to clean
up
you can't depend on this to actually do
it so
we have some positive examples things
that actually make us happy as well
we're not just cranky today I I really
admire what was done with the original
HTTP protocol
I'm had started off with these 15
response codes that you see here
and F-fifteen response codes is in the
numerator at finite set
and most at the time that we have an
enumerated fine i sat we say
okay I'm gonna number them zero through
14 and I'm done
but what was done with the original
protocol here was
they broke it up they spread across
arrange a thousand integers
and the use the hundreds digit to
communicate the general class
have the response code so 200 as
everything's good
300 as I'm sending you over there 400 is
you made a mistake and 500 is
I made a mistake this left a lot of room
for future growth
that they reserved and in particular in
the original protocol specification
be reserved what you should do when you
get a response that you don't understand
now the other positive example is the
futures package in Python 3 which has a
backport Tupac fun too
and what the future is you haven't
played fly very it's a way to schedule
some piece of work to be performed in
the future in the passage this
executor class at which whilst run it
when resources are available however
it's configured
and when you actually need the result to
that future you can block on its you can
fire off a bunch requests in parallel or
something and then block on the moment
the app
what's great about this is the
definition of an executor is
sufficiently narrow that eighty
it already ships with two
implementations that basically have the
same guarantees
the process pool executor requires that
your arguments be pick a lable
but other than that the function
identically and it's possible to
envision something that would you say
stack was as micro threads instead of a
heavyweight efforts
no one of the things that happens when
you start talking about envelopes is
that you find that their
necessarily different than the code that
they constrain
so how many have you think that this
statement is thread-safe
how many have you think that this
statement is not thread-safe
statement is thread-safe
if mikey is already present in the
dictionary
okay so it happens in the implementation
details
that this is thread safe but the reason
this comes up is because we had a a
discussion internally that led to
a a lot of frustration because some
people are saying oh this is thread-safe
I've read the source code and other
people that red
the language specification and said
there's no guarantee that actually has
to be thread-safe
so we're asserting that source code is
not the best documentation
that the best documentation is the
definition of the emblem the things you
can actually depend on
so when you're first starting the
program I everything's exact
everything's precise and programming
starts to feel like wiring
a circuit together your your assembling
some aggregate behavior
that will be precise and deterministic
out of precise and deterministic some
parts
but when you there engineering with
envelopes it feels a lot more like
plumbing
in an aggregate flow system great things
kinda fit together loosely
they don't always fit precisely the way
you expect them to
that sort of thing so to summarize you
should be providing
the smallest possible but very well
defined and elope and you should try
your very best only rely on the stated
envelope others provide
thank you
questions yes on the road
other thanks that was a was a great talk
to them
a lot more programs I'm as well make one
comment
and monitor us lies about us on
one thing we've done it was the project
that has helped us use tests
as a up one thing that we've done it was
the project that has helped us define
tests as part of an envelope is to
ban test doc strings that begin test
that
or ensure that or I the word correctly
particularly is not allowed in tests
everything is just a declarative
statement about what that system does
in a particular sis job situation York
context or
certain inputs so for example not test
that
a certain page displays correctly but
say are when the group page of the
website
as requested our a 202 area code is our
a $200 status code is returned and the
title is displayed
or something much more specific and
forcing everyone to think about that is
actually made our tests much more
specific and and also separate so
because if you have the one test which
is test that loads correctly every time
you
add you expand that envelope of
correctness
that has just gets bigger and bigger and
more sperm yes
yes I agree and I like the fact that we
don't talk about correctness when we
talk about defining handle apps
it's up to you to define what's correct
or what supported for your system
and to communicate back through types
through Taz and through documentation
and not to worry about necessarily like
some
abstract our objective or universal
notion of correctness there's just the
correctness up whether a system behaves
as you wish it to behave
or if it doesn't behave as you wish it
to behave I
let's go to the side so first well
thanks s
really great %uh I'm wondering if you've
looked into
whether there exists a anything or if
it's feasible for such a thing to exist
that actually would
define this and Lopez a thing rather
than 80
loosely associate collection dioxin
tests and types
sir some other language out there that
does that
could I don't do that I
I think it would be a very challenging
given how loose the type system in
Python tends to be
a back I imagine there's a research
language out there that somebody is
is either working on our has has done
that that tries this but I i'm not from
a refund I'm not remotely familiar with
anything and the challenge
feels large given that we're talking
about the summer
I love what type systems can do what
dynamic constraints as exercise by
Toscan du
and what's done in documentation because
its doesn't fit into the other two
systems so so I just it feels like a
huge problem
arm 5 wondering what for tools do you
currently use to try and do that in your
job right now
so a my sisters little peculiar cuz I
work I'm version control software
so I am most have my stuff that the
you actually are aware exists is inside
mercurial and materials
test suite actually is for this the I
guess you call it literate programming
right it looks like
a interactive shell transcript and then
its
split up by the test runner and executed
I that's certainly worth looking at
for higher level functions I try to use
doctor asked
I'm I haven't written anything
complicated enough I've top a need to
reach for spanks but I've heard that
it's pretty good
I in Python I use
pile end for static analysis which is
the closest to a type system with which
I use
I unit AST and a few other testing
frameworks not as much
for testing and I also have lent
check my documentation to make sure that
argument descriptions are present return
value descriptions are present because
in a lot of code that I've seen
especially old co that I've taken over
I and had to maintain going forward the
I the inconsistencies in the behavioral
envelope are the problems in the
behavioral envelope
sneak by when the doc strings
up the code are absent or missing pieces
and so I find that here because I'm my
own best friend I'm I'm
eager to forgive myself most and and I'm
a poor credit card myself
if I can outsource their criticism to an
automated system which will then tell
you
hey you're under specified in this way
it helps me prevent mice
it it helps prevent me from poor fooling
myself
I'm which is a perennial problem of mine
I'm back on the left so you mentioned it
taking over project inheriting projects
that are
well-defined they don't have a good on
blood do you have a
any other recommendations on taking
where a situation where the source
essentially is the envelope then
getting to a place where to better
define in doc strings and wanna
yeah it's a slow incremental process
that's very painful
come in my experience I don't know if
you have anything better than that say
I I know over huge system a Google that
was taken over that was under specified
and the first thing the lead engineer
dead on it was
define a test suite for a and they went
forward and over the course of several
months as this test suite expanded
they would make changes to the code and
that would break someone and that
someone would complain and they would
say okay
we're glad you're here we're glad your
vocal where sorry your crying out for
our blood but we're gonna take your use
case and build it in the
to sweet so that this doesn't happen
again
I'm your when you think about using
assert statements
to make envelopes more explicit I use a
certain statements for that all the time
as some people don't like them as well
heard I guided her on whether
assert is the right tool or raising an
explicit exceptions to retool
a but I i yeah I agree there
they're fine modulo my overall
philosophy on a certain statements
which is they scare me because they can
be turned off and yeah
contacts Yap
thanks I I
unfortunately I still have to write a
lot of c plus plus code
and that we comment using ducks GM okay
and what are the things that
I really like about docs jim is that you
they're actually some directives for
documenting preconditions and post
conditions which seems to me like if
it's really close he would
what you're trying to to to express a
dime
as far as I know Python documentation
tools don't
provide anything for that I use things
all the time and I i havent seen that
there
any comments on that at I I don't happen
to know and I
at the the documentation tools I come
across in Python I I've never seen as a
feature
com I didn't know about the featured
oxygen it sounds great day that wouldn't
mind having
a and something like that by phone so so
thinking about it for a moment
I'll say that perhaps something about
the lack of a formal system for that has
done
to the style in which I coded is that it
has pressured me and I've moved to this
new practice
I love ensuring at bat I
the type system is the type system
itself sat at
insures the satisfaction of my
preconditions so for example
instead of taking an argument of type
string as we saw on one of those HTTP
root server
a examples I where the strain could
parse as in a shitty be request or it
might not
I favor more creation up objects I
such as the one that the HTTP server
that token
HTTP request object so that by the time
the server is invoked you already know
that the precondition for its invocation
has been mad
by the typeof the object passed to it
and that plays nicely with a whole lot
of other things such as loose coupling
and
and minimal specification and so forth
so I would say
look and see if if you can go in that
direction
one more adjuster actually follow for
the last question we actually do have a
facility in context live
and the with statement built into Python
now that
effectively can enforce in a pre and
post conditions as
in variance and I can't say that
honestly that I've
used a lot for that purpose her it
it is actually rather elegant way to
express am
you know in variance that you expect up
you know around a
a function call around another block
code okay and you're saying that's in
the standard library contact with
Marshall
yeah just the with statement and I'll
are but you know it easy
to build context with the context lime
to
I'm on the right side again the I just
wanted to mention %uh numbed by
ahead about 45 years ago a huge
improvement
documentation but they did was a
to introduce a number I documentation
standoff
that explicitly a word quiet that you
have to specify the inputs but I
Dr and what but the weed on solid
including ordered types
and a turn on by doc
package is automatically convert them to
know this information to swing stock
commendation so this was a huge
improvement in getting standardize
documentation most after sandy feature
by 10 site-based acts okay I'm
and for but the second one okay
thank you thank you and thank you all
for coming