like to do sustern Travis re talking
about you coded character encoding this
morning
help icon
I'm Travis this is Esther we're very
excited to be with you this morning
a drunk last night that we can figure
out how to get the slides up some
feeling really good about Pike on so far
I after I've worked at cars that come
new cars dot com
together for the last couple years papon
shop icon sponsor
users a pyramid Esther still at the
great team at cars dot com
I'm with another Los Angeles Python shop
ship dot com
so I want to introduce you to Cody code
is experiencing pain
experienced the frustration and
confusion so wise Cody experience to me
things
well he's dealing with the heart bleed
blog on his website but on top of that
he's trying to write software
that deals with character encoding and
unique code and if you are anything like
aster myself for Cody it brings about
these emotions
when you're trying to write software
that deals with character encoding and
in may result in that the legendary
double table flip
cell we're hoping this talk will help to
alleviate some about pain for you
speaking a flipping tables
we have a confession to make we chose
the title over talk now just because
it is art is silly and fun but because
we were evil as the pike our program
committee found out when our talk title
crashed PIRC thought that they use when
they
review proposals we really drove home
the point that
this is a topic that's very relevant to
anyone who's ever had to deal with texts
character encoding in your code
which is all of us at some point in our
careers before continuing
I have to mention that we're not going
to talk about Python 3 in our talk
we do want to cover the fundamentals
love tax
characters character encoding unique
code and streams
so that you can understand at a
fundamental level how those things work
and that will make it easier for you to
understand the differences between the
way Python 3
and Python to handle text and character
encoding
but we just don't have time to talk
about this today we're gonna start up
with the fundamentals
an amana mention I met Batchelder give a
fantastic talk by Con 2012
on the fundamental view record in
character encoding help tester and I
understand it a lot
so I recommend go check back talk out
the video as soon as you can if you
haven't seen it
we're gonna try and build on that and I
take your little further
so fundamentals humans use tax
to communicate right we use written
language we use characters
the computer speak bites computers on a
fundamental level
just deal with binary so how do we deal
with that will be as programmers
need to translate are written taxed into
binary
we use something called character
encoding you guys know this right
we take a character like the lower case
Latin a and we just map it
to some binary representation we assign
it some bets
this is the ASCII encoding for the lower
case a
cell there's a bunch a different
character encodings out there
they're all unique they do things
differently they do try to agree and
have some compatibility
for like your basic a disease that
that's represented in ASCII
but because their unique encoding they
differ
a character like the Euro symbol is
represented with different binary
representations in these various
encodings and the result that bat
is that the same binary sequence may
represent
two different characters depending on
what encoding you are using
and this is because of a lot of pain
what think about all the characters that
we like to use in our written
communication
but don't lie under sorry don't but
don't fall under the standard it is
easier
9 range to ASCII presents us we like to
use
mathematical symbols punctuation marks
and even
unico snowmen and of course there are
other languages in English that have
their own scripts
some other have dozens or even hundreds
of characters that also need to be
encoded
so unique code was away to standardize a
way that we can encode
any character that anyone might ever
want to encode the unico does this
is by providing a universally recognized
mapping
between a character any Unicode code
point
this is a universally recognized
identifiers for character
its denoted by a capital you in a plus
sign followed by a unique exodus more
value
assigned uniquely to that character what
you should know
is that unico does not provide aid
binary mapping for a character
code points are purely an abstraction
layer its limited a character itself
its wholly separate from any binary
representation
it's purely a description for a
character
of course ultimately computers you need
bites to deal with taxi
transmitted and store it so what we need
is a way to map
between a unique code code point for
every character
to that binary representation so what we
need is a unique 02 where
encoding unico transformation format are
you tee eff
which there are several but the one that
you should use wherever you can
is utf8 for many reasons it's become the
defacto standard used across
the Internet is by email clients
internet browsers
and operating systems so Esther just
explain unit code in utf8 right
these are highly related terms but I
just wanna drive home the point
they are unique ideas and you should
just blindly use those terms
interchangeably unit code
is code points unique identifiers that
are universally known and accepted for
characters
you tee eff a UT F-sixteen these are
binary encodings
for those code points to just keep those
separate in your mind
so sorry I'm I
let's talk layers and abstraction let's
put this all in a little bit a context
right
on a high level I'm gonna use the
computer my
could have stopped working I on
high-level you deal with
the display layer right you show
characters on the screen
you print them I best I life characters
called the glyph
you render it using font rendering
exciter a below that
you have the tax Slayer abstraction this
deals with the elements are written in
languages
this is what we as humans deal with
right this is what you need coating code
point tries to address it gives unique
ID's to those characters
but ultimately computers big bites we
need to start transmit them
so we need something like utf8 to
represented in binary
those are the layers are gonna have to
deal with how does Python deal with this
law specifically to seven cuz three is
different right a should go learn about
that if you can use three
but Python 27 gives you the string type
the sister type
this is a byte string it's a sequence a
bite
that represent tax and what that implies
is there's a specific
character encoding there there's no such
thing as like plain text bite
there's always a character encoding you
need to know it Python also gives you
the unico type
this deals with cold points this deals
with that tax abstraction layer
so even though python has an internal
representation when you're dealing with
the Unicode object you is the programmer
don't need to worry
about been coding this is characters
this is unique code code points
you really need to translate between
your bike you bite strengthen your
unique coating by spur so how do you do
that
of you have some bites need tournament
the unit code
that's the decode operation your
decoding your encoded bites into unit
code
going the other direction you've got a
unique code object you want to encoded
into bites you can store transmit well
it's the encode function right be in
cooperation up for beginners sometimes
keeping the straight and the directions
as a little tricky I came up with this
name on it device
I using my had I just misspelled the
function name za five bites I B code
them at five unico to you in code them
I don't that's helpful for you but i
thought id throw it out there
for the fundamental thing that you need
to know about a byte string is that it
contains no information it have itself
about how each sequence of bytes what
should be decoded back into
the character you have to be told fire
some sort of external declaration
what encoding was used to store that
text as a byte string
so you might find this in a document
header an ATP header
or other file meta-data or even a code
commenter email from a coworker telling
you
when encoding was used the point is if
you don't know what encoding was used on
a given byte string
you can't figure it out just by looking
at the string you have to be told
when encoding was used or else you can
be sure that your decoding properly back
into the original text
so knowing these fundamentals what can
we as Python developers due to write
applications to handle
our text properly but what they're a
simple application that we're gonna
build right here
let's say that we have this year see
files are datasource and it contains a
bunch of car reviews cover
car website we're gonna write a simple
python application to do some processing
overtaxed
and store in a texan oppose Chris
database so that ultimately we can
render in a browser
on a website like new cars are calm
let's take a look at our source file the
city file you can see is created using
Microsoft Excel
and the person who sent us this file
says he used a really old version of
Windows
and so we're gonna say that this was
windows for 52 encoded RCP 12:52 encoded
our application is very simple we're
just gonna look for instance is that the
word Montreal without any accents
and we're gonna replace it with the word
Montreal it's properly spelled with the
accent over the E
when we store our text data in our
database
we want to use put posters and we're
gonna use utf8
as the encoding that we want to
converter text into by strings attached
because it's a best practice the reason
for this being that
we know that we can handle any character
that comes across from Mercer stated
your application
if we use a targeting coating that is
unico to wear
taking a closer look at an example
review you can see we have
the target word that we're going to
replace with their application I also
want to point out a couple characters
here though
these don't lie inside that a tizzy 029
ASCII range
and so if we were ever to use an
encoding other than are searching
coating of CP 12:52
then we might end up with 8 the risk I
have coming up with a different bites
your representation for these characters
I'm just doing a little foreshadowing
here so let's write some code
skin walking through this line by line
this is our application
we're gonna start off by the Clarion the
in codeine our source code
on the guy should be doing this there's
a number of reasons why but basically
you're telling
potential your text editor but more
importantly the Python interpreter
the bites that are to follow should be
interpreted as being
such encoded and so we're using utf8 for
our encoding
gonna open the file we're gonna iterate
over it line by line
and we're gonna do some very simple CSB
processing
we're just gonna split on the comma and
then we're going to do
some simple text processing we're gonna
call dot replace
on our review taxed we're gonna search
for the Montreal spot without the accent
and we're gonna replace it with the
properly accented version Montreal
and ultimately we're gonna store that in
a database using this simple database
API that we have at our disposal
let's run this code and see what happens
so OK the code ran our date is in the
database
but this is what we're seeing we're
looking at our utf8 encoded Postgres
database and were seen
this not what we're hoping for right
you've got the question mark law singers
in there
something didn't go all right Montreal
did get properly replace so we're happy
about that but we gotta figure out
what's the deal with the Los Angeles so
let's take back into our code and try to
figure it out
we're dealing with tax treaty with
character encoding we're dealing with
byte strings
so I piloted all the byte strings here
and when we have a byte string we know
there's an encoding
what encoding do these bites trains use
well
let's figure it out got are straining
literals
we use the quotes we create a string
type in Python
the string literals are utf8 encoded
why's that while we declare our source
code to be
utf8 encoded and so therefore we also
wrote
bites into that file that were you tee
eff 8
byte strings and Python interprets our
string literals as low as utf8 byte
strings
now we're redeem CP 12:52 data
out of this CSV file so the data that
we're really now
the variables that were signing those
bites trains
RCP 12:52 encoded bite strings that
leaves us with one byte string we
haven't talked about converted review
what character encoding is converted
review well
we're creating converted review and
we're creating it with this operation
we're taking a CP 12:52 byte string
were telling Python dot replace and
we're handing dot replace
utf8 encoded bite strings
Python will happily do that for us
because Python doesn't know about these
encodings pythons just looking at bytes
in this case
so Python created a nice mixed encoding
mass for us really we created it by just
telling Python to do what I time does
and then restored that in our database
so visually
here's what happened right CP 12:52
source data
coming out of our file we tell pipe on
top replace
here is utf8 byte string Python happily
operates on those bites for us and gives
us a byte string that contains some
sleepy 12:52 bites
some utf8 bytes now when we load bat in
our database
client the database client
is looking for utf8 bite has it the utf8
database from the disconnect to it using
utf8
when utf8 database sees BCP 12:52 curly
quotes
and Euro symbol it just throws it hands
up in size those are bite I don't
recognize I can interpret them as utf8
thus the question mark lawson's
to a travis has just illustrated is best
practice one that we recommend
know you're in coatings there's no such
thing as a plain text string
on a computer the only way to store text
on a computer issue encoded into bytes
and you have to know what encoding
you're using the Turner Tech Center
bites
fourth fix our application we know we
want to avoid mixing up in coatings the
way we just did
we should probably be dealing with
Unicode characters so that we're doing
purely on the level
love the text so let's take those row
text objects that we pull from our file
their bites rings what's called decode
on them to turn them into Unicode
objects
then we could split them into to get our
other dating review
text as you code objects as well and
we're also going to replace
the byte string literals in our
application with unico literals
so now we're dealing with you the code
at every level in our application
we should be good to go Ono acceptance
or not
so you've probably seen this error
message many times have you
what is the word ask you doing in that
area message we never declared anything
to be ask your application
let's take a look at the road a cause
the exception inner
intercut so we can't decode on this road
text byte string
but we forgot something we forgot to
tell Python
when according to use when decoding that
bites ring into Unicode object
soap I thought to have some problematic
default behavior
it tries to be helpful and it seems that
you want to use your system's default
encoding
which in most cases is going to be
asking and so
when it encounters have curly quotes
ASCII is going to blow up in
your application is going to fail we've
actually done
is a lesson best practice known as you
could whack a mole
which I'm sure many viewers play we've
played it plenty of times
and it's exacerbated by Python two's
problematic default behavior
the fix is pretty simple you just have
to explicitly d
a declared the encoding that you want to
use in our case this a CP 12:52
are searching coating and so now that
we've declared the encoding
Python can correctly turned that unico
to that biting uptick
into Unicode object also want to point
out that
in the final I never application we
answered our data we now have three
Unicode objects that we wanna stay that
we're sending over to our database
depending on the database that you use
in the features it has are the API that
you
you have at your disposal this may or
may not be a problem
in our case we want to explicitly
encoders you could object
into byte strings and of course we're
going to declare the encoding
that we want to use which is utf8
so whatsoever any application one more
time
and finally we get what we're looking
for everything looks good
so this is best practice number to Astor
just walk you through it
called the unit code sandwich and it's
not quite as delicious as it sounds but
it does make your life nice
so what's take a look at that right you
could sandwiches just this
unit decode from bites early in your
application as soon as you're reading
bites out of eyler
are getting them across the wire decode
them any Unicode then in your
application layer
you can deal with Unicode you can deal
with characters and not have to worry
about character encoding
and then you're gonna in code back into
bite slave in your application before
persisting are transmitting that data
so again what about look like in our
application well esther
decoded from CP 12:52 as she was reading
bites out in the file
and then she encoded into our target
utf8 encoding
immediately before persisting those
bites in the database
and what that allowed is everywhere in
the middle we had delicious blue Unicode
ice cream filling
I'm we didn't have to worry about
character encodings our application
this really does make your life nice if
your application will allow you to use
this pattern
but their best practice at we want to
recommend is for you to write good tests
against your code to make sure that
it is handling text properly you want to
test the ranges
in boundaries are the encoding that
you're using if you're
application is supposed to handle unico
text then be sure that you're using test
strings that contain more than just the
it is easier tonight ask your age there
are fair to text generators online
you can use to generate some crazy unico
characters that you can put
in your tests you also want to test your
interfaces against both Python unico
girls
and byte string literals you may be
using libraries in your application that
do their own unique 02 string
conversions and they may or may not do
it correctly
you can't be sure unless you write tests
so if you have something that expecting
a code
they rode a bike string and see what it
does and if it expects bites throated a
Unicode string is
and see what happens you wanna make sure
that your texts isn't causing problems
as it makes its way through your
application
you also want to test for the handling
of incorrectly coded text if you have
code that expect ASCII
try throwing it some utf8 encoded text
and see and see what happens
maybe you want to raising a right away
so that you know that you have a problem
in your source data that's changed
in Cali authorities complain whatever or
maybe what your application a chug along
without breaking
whatever you do make sure that you're
writing a proper tests for this
so just to recap those best practices
for you always know you're in coatings
cuz there's no such thing as plain tax
right if you have bites
their encoded you need to know when
encoding was used
then wherever you can use the unique
codes and much so that you can deal with
tax with you know Cody your application
layer and you don't have to worry about
encodings
and then finally test your code I hope
this is the best practice you all see
the value n
in Python in general but when you're
talking about texting character encoding
these blogs are sneaky right because
your application is we're keen
and then all the sudden you encounter a
character that comes across Denmark AP
Iran a file
and your application blows up are so
test your text related code
so we know our best practices were using
them
our world is great we're doing the right
thing but ultimately
your system is gonna and Iraq with
outside systems outside external beta
and someone else's system is gonna cause
you pain
so what does that look like what can you
do about it couple quick examples
what happens when you get a file bat is
using
on incorrect encoding or decoding that's
different than what was declared so
example at
we have our application its processing
RCP 12:52 day to day after day month
after month year after year
were happy were enjoying life and then
one day
utf8 shows up and we all know about it
right this was still declared CP 12:52
by at the water cooler conversation with
the coworker two years ago when he told
us he was gonna email SEP 12 52
but one day we get utf8 and we're on our
program
and new killer table flap it blows up
and we're not happy I so how do you deal
with that as well
this is pretty simple one right there's
human interaction
you can go talk to people you can use
your words you can ask am
I what happened what happened to CP
12:52 white agate utf8 did you get a new
program what's going on
on but maybe he left the company or
maybe you're not on speaking terms or
maybe he's up in management more talked
about character encoding anymore
and in that case you're gonna have to
guess and you can just blindly yes you
can say
ASCII utf8 let's try and find out
but that's not a great way to write
quality software so
you can get intelligently by using a
library like chart at no charge that is
just gonna look at your bites
and give you statistical probability on
those bites mean back it was encoded in
a certain encoding so you know this is
ninety percent chance this is utf8
but ultimately that is a gas based on
probability
maybe someone invents a new character
encoding in-charge
that doesn't know about it yet or
something like that just understand it's
a gas
and then again if you wrote your tasks
you already know how your application is
going to fail in this case
and presumably you wrote it in a way
where you are going to have to flip
tables when you encounter utf8 data
another problem that you might encounter
is what if you receive data from an
application developer who didn't watch
our talk
they played a little too much you could
whack a mole so they give you the
strings in your
in in your source data they're all mixed
up they contain garbage characters miss
encoded miss decoded characters mixing
coatings
or just escape characters there's a word
for this
it's called mochi parquet and it's a
real pain affects because first of all
you don't know
what that developer did to give you this
mix-up string and how they missing
coated in
mixed up those in coatings in it in
their tax much less
how are you supposed to know what the
original characters were supposed to be
to use one example that we've
encountered this year is supposed to be
the name
have a car dealer and it you can tell
it's not quite correct
how did you get this way we're gonna
play a little unique ok yes I hear
we're gonna in code that unico 3 into
a byte string using are known in calling
a few feet of 52
and we're gonna end up with this biting
sequence so you can see here each
character
up above is matte color maps to the byte
string representation a bit below
we did some extensive research on the
sequence of bytes
and we found that in a different
encoding those three characters
the street bites actually represent a
single character
using utf8 so just to clear clarify
you have this bites ring with those
three characters those bike thanks
sequences that if you decode using utf8
will actually give you
a much more reasonable looking name for
an auto dealer
to recap somebody had a smart apostrophe
basically that day encoded using utf8
into the following
bytes and then somebody else or maybe
even the same person
miss decoded it using the wrong encoding
and gave us
the three garbage characters so this is
how much you back key is born
and there are a couple ways to fix it
actually one thing you can't do
is to change the encoding that you're
using TTF 8 because you know that your
the rest of your source data is CP 2 of
52 so what you could do is maybe keep
track
have known troublesome byte sequences
like the ones that we have here
and just can't keep track of them into a
manual replacement
with the biting reputation that's
correct in CP 12:52 for that character
if you do this so your list is only
gonna grow along your application runs
and
a huge pain to maintain likely for you
there's a library called Python ftfy
fixes text for you
and it fixes muddy backing so it has its
own conversion tables and uses
heuristics to process tax
and try to clean up any Mota packy
strings that you have
all you have to do is pass it that much
you back aid you could object
run fixed text on it an offer you back
its best guess for what
cleaned up more correction should be
it's not a perfect labor is still under
active development but it really good we
use it in our production code it saved
us
a great deal of time so one more issue
and that's where you need to store data
using a target in codeine
that can handle the characters in your
source in coding
so what do I mean by that let's say yes
some source data
thats utf8 rights coming in from Twitter
or something and they're snowmen and
their people like to write about snowman
and you're told you need to store this
data in a CP 12:52 database name it my
sequel
and that target database is out of your
control you can change the encoding your
told you need to store the state NCP
12:52
wall the problem is CP 12:52 you can't
handle snowman
I short up some kinda crazy hack which
its not advised so
at the application level what are your
options well
the default behavior when you see a
snowman
or another character and you encode it
into an encoding that can handle that
character
is this strict behavior and what Python
does
using the strict behavior is it just
raises stack trace right it airs out to
you could use this
and write some fancy code that fires up
an email and says hey we found snowman
in the source data we can handle this
fix your source data
or whatever but that's not super
flexible so pipe and a few other options
you have other options and you know
any any character encoding process seen
so one option is to ignore
those characters right processing your
data moving it to CP 12:52
you say when I see a snowman move along
everything's great here
you know just ignored the problem is
then your target data
is miss seen those characters and you
might end up with some really funky
looking output data
arm so I a slightly more graceful way to
handle it
is to replace those characters with the
circuit character
just a placeholder so you processing
your text you see snowman
he say I can't do snowman in CP 12:52
but I'm a drop a marker here so the
person who comes after me recognizes
there was a character there
that couldn't be properly encoded using
the target in coding
it's important with both and ignore or
replace operation
to know that these are lost the
operations thats RBS
by on if you may be able to upgrade your
database utf8 in the future then maybe
it's worth keeping the source data
around
so that you can properly encoded in the
future
for that we've server at a time and come
to the universe talk
we hope that we've covered the basics
well enough for you to do more research
but also to make your life a little
easier even now
wanna thank other fine people for
helping us with our talk
and I I don't know how to refer
questions but we do have our site up
online right now
sometimes gonna blow through these you
can look them up yourself and do some
further reading
by our side her up and feel free to
contact us through these channels if you
have any questions
thank you very much
-10 for like one question
okay
okay here you
yep I country so Python 3
kinda flipped everything upside down a
little bit and reverses the rolls right
and we don't have enough time to give
you any kind of actual grasp on that
on again adds 2002 2012 talk actually
deals with a pretty well and explains
that
there some other talks go to a pipe
video I'm and look for the unico talks
and it will give you a good
understanding a
Python 3 good yep
by order marks right so
summing Cody means I UT F-sixteen
for example I will drop by by at the
very beginning evolve attacks to tell
tell you I big endian little and the end
and so
I I don't actually I can't go super into
detail on that right now again there's
some other talks that do get into the
details on it and frankly I've avoided
encodings where that was an issue but
I'm not used to be a real big issue in
kinda UT F-sixteen was
the you know de facto you know coding
coding so you know what's nice about
utf8 is that it doesn't require that by
tournament because
a uses it just because an intense the
the from future import
unit code literals I'll we haven't
actually used that
arm I think had yeah I better not a
better not speak gotta turn I've read
about it a little bit but
RR the stuff we've been doing recently
has been not required to
sup great thank you