a lower-body
welcome to the last session in the
automation
ops team to track I'm
very happy to introduce to you Peter
Baumgartner is gonna talk about salt
salt stack
and the way
all right thank you thank everybody for
coming
and so yeah this is getting started with
salt
the like you said I'm Peter Baumgartner
ponder for a company called Lincoln
whoop
we do lots of web application
development and pipe and so we end up
setting up a lot of servers
to do that we use all the just to get a
idea who's here
some how many people in our interviews
shopper puppet in the past
for configuration management while ca
the
fabric views fabric okay
and is able to hear you salt okay
the this is a a pretty introductory
the talk so if you
you saw quite a bit you may find a
boring or repetitive but
yeah any thought dives in a an audience
okay good
noted it on their own oh wait I see a
hand
%uh now okay what I screwed something up
a minha okay so
I let's get third one assault stack
South sac
this is from their web sites all sector
livers a dynamic infrastructure
communication bus
use for orchestration remote execution
configuration management and much more
on so kinda some buzz word bingo they're
and
a lot of things going on so so let's
break it down on
salts act is configuration management
other configuration management tools you
may have heard a
CF engine was one of the early ones
there's shop and pop it like many have
you
views answerable is out there as well
another
pipe an option so before configuration
management
we would set up a server with setup and
attacks on the server and we'd
configure internet access on the
internet stock comp file on
then we want to make a change to engine
x-com and we back it up
and then we would do it again and again
and I'm we just need to stop doing that
yeah so I am after configuration
management it looks like this
configuration management lets you have a
single set up files
that tell you exactly what your server
is doing how is configured
when people make changes you get nice
log so you can put in version control on
all these nice things to you you
basically version control your servers
itself documenting when somebody wants
to know if the servers doing they can
review
your configuration management system and
see that its
as easy to set up one server as it is a
hundred servers so
repeatable and reusable Thompson except
salt fact is remote execution
remote execution is kinda the
territorial fabric
capistrano funk basically the ability to
run one or more commands
against one or more remote systems this
is
sorta vow to the scopa watch of
unpopular
designed to do some examples a
one you want to use remote execution
deploying your code
running all all the things necessary to
do a deploy
running one of scripts during critical
packet updates so
open SSL harpley issue is a great
example
when you might wanna run a specific
command one time against many systems
a n you can use the process to
monitoring as well so
you know checked the load on the server
every five minutes
or the startup servers and report back
so
that's what salt stock is are a subset
at least
and will cover today on why would you
want to salt stock
big thing for me I'm a Python developer
typically work build website and Django
so
salt sex written in Python it's
configured with the animal
which is a a dead simple kinda
configuration language
and it uses ginger to you as a
templating engine so
coming from to the Django world Jan 22
template for very familiar to me
it's all familiar tools easy for me to
hack on in contrast
tools like shopping puppet use their own
custom DSL
there sir based off Ruby on that wasn't
very comfortable for me so
those are things I liked about Sol
another thing I like
it's got really good documentation if
you want to print it out on their
website at: over 800 pages
they're insanely response that their
their IRC room is always poor people
if you file an issue and get help don't
be surprised to get a response the same
day
on and and finally it it's backed by a
for-profit organization so
there's people with a vested interest in
making sure salt is
cutting-edge state-of-the-art and works
they're not gonna go away your deposit
with their day job and disappear
so all things I liked about it so
thats that's why you might wanna juice
salt sack about
for some reason maybe why you might not
wanna to salt stock
a here here serves the the common things
I hear
a about why people don't like Saul on
at the young project it moves fast
they're they're constantly building new
features
that might be scary its long as they can
to maintain stability
on that's that's a plus in my book there
there making it better without breaking
old stuff
and in my general experience over the
last
probably couple years now that's the
case
a and it doesn't use ssh as a tramper
transport and communication mechanism
between servers
so the as the sages tried-and-true
people trust that
and that's great a lot of things salt
needs to do it does over kinda been
always on communication bus between
servers
as a CH really on doesn't work as well
for that
and doesn't scale to level they want to
scale there
you know talking thousands of servers
managed by by one master that has some
messages part in our first status right
now
but you don't want to use that and
production
I'm so let's dive in and actually start
learning about Sol
so the first thing we need to do is take
a cab vocabulary lesson
on the state gov can adopt in general is
is terrible with ok area where there is
no kinda widely accepted
terminology for the stuff so shop has
sniping recipes and cookbooks and puppet
has
terminus and meta parameters handsome
boys play books and inventories
on salt might be the worst offender here
there's
lotsa terminology unita learn so
to get started there's the master this
is the server that kinda managers
everything
a you know authenticating other servers
States pillars we'll get into that in a
second
there's a minyan a million connects to
the master
typically you have one master server and
many minions you can have
0 master servers minutes can manage
themselves
and there's lots of other configurations
but in general a minyan at the server
controlled by the master
there's a state Minnesota State so the
state is a declarative representation up
system state
basically how you want your minion to be
configured so
when you stack up all the states that's
that the configuration of your system
there is a grain a grain is a static
piece of information
about your minion you're basically
you're your server your configuring
this is things that but don't change
regularly
things like how much RAM is in the box
how many CPU that has
what OS it's running her
there's pillars pillars are herb is the
camping amid
as variables so bizarre things that you
might want to change between
different appointments maybe you have a
a development server that runs
a one branch your code and production
server that runs another
use pillars to manage this ports pile
powers
things like that that change between
your system
so kinda putting it all together on
we've got our our big master server here
it's got a set up alerts on a an
assertive States
that mastered connects to one or many
minions in each million brings its own
set up Green's whether
okay next up is the top file the top
file matches states and pillars
to minions so in your master you
probably have configuration for lots of
different systems may be a database
server may be an application server
the top files what says the specific
states go to the specific servers are
basically pulled out a subset
and matches those and finally
there's high state high state is that
subset States
that belong to you a specific minion
so adding to our diagram we now have
pillars and states those kinda filter
through a top
file on the minion hand it's grains to
the
to the master that are cash their some
magic happens at all smashes together
and your configuration lives on your
minion
its it's really not to magical it's just
Python
but just getting started with salt so it
mattered for now
okay so let's really get started on
insulation
the really easy there's binaries
available for most distributions
you can pip install it if you wanna the
bleeding edge
or if you wanted hack on it in part on
yourself
there is a script available at bootstrap
got salt stock .org
it probably does what you want which is
to
reach out to you repose that salt
managers and
install binaries from there you did
usually don't wanna install from your
operating systems repose because
their probably old and mica said the
project minutes past
so what's the this is an example with
Ubuntu
a I'm gonna go ahead and let's say we've
installed the
South package archive their pee PA to
get the master running I would run
apt-get install salt master we can also
run it master list which are shown in a
second
next up we're gonna set up a minyan so
apt-get install salt minion
and then we need to tell that minion
where
its master lives so but a fall it's
gonna look for server called salt
so we can drop the the IP address in
your hosts file
alternatively some there's this
configuration file
at at sea slash salt slash mass births
are such minion
and you can put in whatever hostname
their your master lives on
so a when that when you do that the
minions going to reach out to the master
and say hey
here's my the authentication key let me
a
access you know over on the state's the
Masters gonna say I don't recognize you
I've never seen the server for and put
it into a set of pending servers that
have now
authenticated with the master we can go
to the master now
salt pesky dash a has except and except
the this many in connecting you can also
list although
the keys waiting and you can verify them
with their fingerprints to make sure
that actually is the server you think it
is
an but will discuss short circuit that
for now and go ahead and accept that
so a let's writer for state
on missus this is probably the simplest
eight we can run
it lives in slash SRB slash salt
that's kinda salts default directory for
all its
States and it's called my state dot as a
last-start
SOS is the file extension that's all
users
on package dot installed is the state
we're gonna call and we're gonna call it
for and relax here so what this is going
to do is install in Jax
on our system so that the state file
next we need to create the top piled
atop piles that thing that matters
States
to minions so that also lives in
five serves much salt it's called topped
out as a last Sat though is called
topped out at the last
a yeah it and this is the environment
base here
we're not going to deal with
environments today so just we're always
going to use base
my server is the name of the server were
expecting to connect
and my state is the file name: love
the State recruit her my state that I
sell us
so this does whenever my server texan
send it might stay
an hour gonna high state so a few
different ways to do this
because assault has a kinda annoys on
communication bus
we can push it down from the master
looks like salt
the name of the server you wanna push to
and state that high state
that's the model we want to run
we can put from the minion so that's
salt ash call
state that high stay and then you can
actually run master list so if we didn't
have a master server
and the those files we created were
living on the minion
we could just run with this dash dash
local flag
and that is going to portrait of the
local filesystem
next up you're going to get a wall taxed
that's gonna do all sorts of stuff like
to install and relax on your system
its gonna install these packages that
engine X depends on to run
and it's going to tell you at the very
end
wait out the bottom here you get this
green line 1 succeeded nets are we ran
one state
it succeeded success we've done it
so just review again created its
safe I'll we created a top pile and we
told the minion
to check in and get it I stay and we
kinda ran through the bottom section
about
picture so at a really basic state
example
let's do something a little more advance
a
chairman to create a user on the system
you can kind of think it states like
Python functions
they take they can take keyword
arguments so
user to present as the state we're gonna
call the name in the state is P
so that's going to create a user copy on
my system
I'm gonna give it a a shell and a home
directory and all that good stuff
I can stack state up so
hereof gonna use it up present state at
the top
and below I'm gonna said an SSH
key for myself on it so as a state of
dot present as my second state
and I'm gonna run it for the user p and
a
I've got sourcing require so those kinda
probably require a little explanation so
on
in that has slashed SRV slash salt
directory
you can basically sir files out at that
and push those down your minions
so in this example I would have a file
called pitot pub
that would have my public key in it and
I would put it and slash serve slash
salt
and that could push it right down for
that user
as a accept a key on and then I have
this requires him in here
that that says that the associate of
requires that
the user state named p which are defined
right above
it needs to run for this to run the
the requires art totally necessary
anymore on
salt runs state's top to bottom so
I can be pretty guarantee that the user
to present is gonna run before the SSH
of dot president but this makes that
relationship explicit
and when you have when you're debugging
are you have airs
on that's really nice so rather than
having all your heirs kinda pile up and
having to sift through to figure out
what cause
what problem my my if my first state
fails
my second one is gonna say a state I
depend on
prerequisite failed and I didn't run so
it makes it really easy to find the root
cause a problem so
even the required isn't totally
necessary recommended just keep things
explicit
we like that pic on it
on here's another example the state get
out latest as the state I'm calling
checking out a get repo from get her I A
can get better
revision Anna place the directory on to
land on my filesystem Intel it but
the package no get needs to be installed
in order to run this
I can also run arbitrary command so
command outrun
is is another state I can call in this
example I've gotta
they've got a Django site now I want to
thank the database so
bypass and the name I told where to run
and
I need to make sure my my softwares is
on the server as well
so and tons ways you can kinda makes
these up
and set up your servers there's over 50
built in states
date they do pretty much everything you
need to do its it's very rare that you
need to
build your own state or module to
to set up a server so for Python people
pippin virtual number there you can
manage databases database users
you can bring services up and down you
can put files on your server
you can add crime jobs or you can write
your own it's just papon
so a next up is pillars so if you
remember
pillars are basically variables and in
this whole system
made available for part one or more
minions
so let's create our first pillar are
pillars live in Flash
a service last pillar that's the default
location just like slash
SRV slash salt as the default location
for states
you can change those but if you put in
there everything just works
so we're gonna create a pillar called
might say and
it's got this value in it key value
branch
develop so just like
on our States we're gonna create a top
I'll
serve pillar topped out a SOLAS the
the base environment and then we put the
server that it applies to you
and the name up the pillar so
again week we called it my site doesn't
need to be
the same name as their state i'd it's
just an example so
my site as a last will match that
on you can get fancy with top files to
you
so so this is home you know some some
kinda comments up you'll see
star will match anything so if you have
a default you maybe want to
put all your users your company that
they can log into the server so you
could put that into their and I will
match all the servers
on you can use clubbing so obviously
start out something in
match you know maybe all your app
servers or something like that
you can match on grains so I can say a
thus
this applies to all my Ubuntu servers if
maybe you've got some
Ubuntu and Windows stuff in your
infrastructure you can use reg X
regular expression regular expressions
Mike and/or
compound statement so you can get really
fancy with this
this applies to you pillar top filed it
also applies to state top filed
it also applies to the way we ran it
from the command line so
we just show an example when we did high
state of
up a single server but you can match
multiple servers with one command so
a will take let's go back and take a
here's our pillar we created my say
branch develop and
we're gonna apply that to a state so his
example we've got our application
and we wanna a pyre develop branch to
one server and our production branch to
another server
we can use a pillar to modifier state so
we can
you reuse the same state and when those
on all those things merge the right
thing happens on the right
server minion a
it's ginger so you can use some papon
constructs inside here
so in this example I'm gonna check the
my site
dictionary which is what it ends up
being and if branch
exists in there I'll use that value or
not
I'm gonna use the value master as the
fall
so you can do all sorts of crazy stuff
with ginger inside these
if you want to
you can use grains and pillars you can
use them in states you can use them in
files
a this is what using a green looks like
so
in this example I'm a setup a pillar in
I'm gonna for the pillar name red is max
memory
and there's 'em a grain called man total
that's all the memory in my system in
megabytes
and I'm gonna say use happen that memory
for the Spiller rose max memory so if I
had
512 megabytes in the system this is
gonna
output 256 Mb
now I could write a state and in my
state I
to I'm gonna some I read this dot com
file
and I'm gonna tell it that it is agenda
template
there's other template language is
available if you want to and I tell
where the sources
thus also lives in that slash SRV slash
salt directory
read a stock car that gingers the name
of the file and a Passover Seder
defaults those are basically variables
that are going to get used when this
file gets rendered out to
the server so that templates gonna look
like this
its not going to work as we britain at
but when it gets dumped onto
with the minyan the votes gonna run that
max memory variable is going to be
replaced
with the value redefined in our
killer here so you can get
really dynamic with a view cam apply the
stuff really anywhere in the system
inside pillars in tight state inside
files
yeah so so that is kinda the the basics
assault a and setting up a server
there are it's like the tiniest little
subset what
thought can do but thats getting started
with salt on
other things that are interesting in
salt aerosol cloud
so-called lets you bring up and down
cloud servers and a.w.s or Rackspace or
line odor digital oceana cut although
providers all the popular providers are
in there so really awesome
for on you maybe wanna test you can test
your configurations
you know spin up a server run it
you know do a continuous integration and
Jenkins make sure
it's configured properly and you can
access your web site and tear it all
down when you're done and pay for
five minutes of usage a you can build
custom modules so
modules are and the things that back
like
commando run that we saw our get out
latest you can do those in Python
so I've written some custom modules that
will
probe for status on uncertain system so
check my engine axe status how many
active connections does it have
probe and memcached status and push that
somewhere
the scheduler is pretty great its
like Ron but probably easier to use I
think
and so you can schedule a certain task
to run and
also configure what happens to the
output up that so
this works really well for unlike system
honoring
I can say you checked the load on the
system and San
send that info to graphite when I'm done
there's custom renders so when I showed
you today is is %um all
and ginger but you can use other things
you can actually configured in pure
Python
just just writing partial Python you can
it has its own pipeline DSL if you
thought but the S l's and
shopping reviewer up in public where a
good idea on
and maco has custom returners so
when we ran the the state's the first
time if returned to the console in
dispute all that textile
week instead could configure it to you
returned to
an email address so whenever anybody
runs high state I wanna
you get an email to ops address to know
on you can return to graphite you can
return
to century you can return to thirst log
so lots of different ways you can kinda
handle the output
a you're SOL commands and then
finally the reactor this is something
that i think is kinda unique to
saw it's got this always on
communication bus between all your
servers
and anything anytime salt is doing
something in your system
it's firing offense over that
communication bus you can
basically plug into it and listen to
those amounts and react to them
and do other things so you could say
every time I run a high state I want to
notify
New Relic that a new deploy happened
you know mark that in my history so I
can see that my grass
you can do that in %um all directly or
you can actually write Python scripts
custom Python scripts that will listened
and
do stuff based on what's happening over
that bus
a few tips and tricks
1 the DePaul output as you saw it is
really for both
I like to go into the minion
configuration file in Chains output mode
to mixed
that will show all your success
statements as just one single line
anything that fails you get the full
output on so it easier fine
problems on to ginger too is a
seriously powerful template language
don't go crazy with it
a.m. like I said what are the benefits
love configuration management is that
you can look at the configuration files
and understand what's happening and
understand what your servers are doing
if you go crazy with logic all over your
templates earlier configuration files
on you're not going to be able to reason
what they're doing
very easily in and you don't want to
have to debug
when you're dealing with important
things like your servers
the update often the
do release is pretty quickly in review
the change log it's not often that they
have backwards compatibility stuff
but I'm usually reviewing the change log
for kinda what do you call a few
features I can use that make the system
better for me
and then finally as far as testing
before you deploy bigger and darker
are great tools here you can actually
run your full so the salt States
in the bigger machine on your on your
desktop or laptop
you can run in da kar so kinda make sure
to sanity checks before you push those
out production
there's actually a project called salty
vagrant which will
help with that as well
so a that I have thank you very much for
coming
and I'm here for questions and I've got
a booth with
a company like a loop at the booth 615
down in the expo hall so if you don't
catch me here
feel free to stop by there and I love to
talk about the stuff for
thank you
it's hard to see the mic from here on
yes we have a question hi the to see you
were applying for a lot of customers
on and you didn't really want them to
see
the contents a your salt configuration
files
because those contains a intellectual
property
my show them how could you obfuscate
those on those hosts
when the customers say don't have route
but they do have user access they can
ssh in stuff like that haha
on well all
you could set up the you you can set up
multiple masters
a which might be an option so maybe you
have a master for
each a customer on the
the the I don't know the default
permissions the cash
the that that we're all the state files
are get cash but I don't
if I remember correctly its it's not
going to push
all your state files down to the minion
just the ones that applied to that
minion
and it may be possible that they didn't
have root you could make them so they
weren't readable
the by by that user cool thanks up
the problem had with us all TV current
now on when I tried actually used for
testing is that vagrant isn't happy
assigning specific network addresses
yes when you spin at multiple vagrants
yes on which means they can't find the
salt server
is there some kind an easy fix for that
a
okay so why when I views that I've just
done it for single server sir single
set up server setup so I haven't had an
issue with that finding
the the salt server because I'm
basically pushing
the state's down in running at Mass true
master was basically a
other other states gone to that bigger
box on on
spin up as far as running
yeah I'm I'm not sure how you would do a
multi set up
there's some interesting stuff
the there's a something called salt mine
which lets
millions talk to minions I think so
maybe it's possible that you could kind
of query for where the master is
dynamically and
set something up the
yeah not I'm not quite sure but yet like
I said most most the time doing it for a
single box
and it works were just Masroor set up
but
not sure how you dynamically do that
otherwise ok
oca so your other what's the name of the
product bossman eight er
host man eight er okay so yet maybe
there's possibility to
inject info on your hosts file and make
that work
I
I have a question I know that salt
implemented its own crypto
could you please going to the reasons
behind that
and wide is a good thing her and I is
I'm not a assault developer I work with
salt
I am a I I
you think that's the holdover I think
their pretty aware that
maybe there are better options there
on and just haven't gotten to it a
I think on if
if if you're very concerned about the
crypto there are other options
you can them you know basically firewall
stuff
you can make sure your minions can only
talk to
you know the master over that poor and
maybe just
trusted as you know encryption on so
yeah I I think
the the only reason that is in there now
there's a there's a
long-running issue and get home about
their crypto implementation
they're kinda two issues what that one
is its
it's using an to crypto which is
sorta slowly dying in the Python world
and so they can't I think stop by
country compatible
requires compiling so it's not your
Python on
and then the other one is you know are
there more
secure way is a doing it so
I think it's a known issue it just
is probably a a development bandwidth
issue at this point
there there's I know they're looking at
keys are back that Google has there's
another
project called NaCl that
has a little more about it crypto stuff
so you know I don't know exactly why but
I would say it's mostly like to see
her
have the number questions thank you very
much better
serb icon is a conference that relies on
volunteers and sponsors for keeping the
and and she lo and so we really wanna
thank
this particular sponsor go meet him in
the booth and say how much you love them
and volunteers as well somebody asked me
like how did you get this job
like the one I do this a way of signing
up
before the conference starts as anybody
can do this kinda job we all volunteered
in a
I don't get paid for this is on and the
third one is this a break right now
in room 220 dei so see you later
by