welcome just an Abrams
self-talk computer programmer is going
to share with us computer science for
the soft top forever
thanks very much hello everyone
a as as he said and Justin Abrams and i
wanna talk about
computer science force of top
programmers a little bit about me
on I am a director product jeering at a
company called Quick left
we do you consulting and also in a
product that I work on
constantly which is a project management
app we're hiring security
talk about that let me know I'm also the
author in motor
which is a tool that will take static
analysis
stuff like violent or JS and and pipe
that in to get her code review comments
and you can find me online under the
name just neighbors
am so
an overview this talk I am we're going
to talk about Big O notation
and how I learned about it what it is
how do you do it
and then some wisdom and resources
around
so too star of
I am I work for a design agency in New
York City
a several years ago and this was my
first
career job that where I was really
working on things that were important
and they're important to think to people
and it was a product that mattered
and before that I work for a newspaper
and
the the things that we did were
very quick to start they had a limited
shelf life
and then they can have trailed off and
no one really it didn't really matter
anymore
as examples that might be like and so
was reading an article about aids and in
various counties and they wanna
visualizations a bill that and then the
article publishers and three weeks later
no one has ever know it's gonna visit
that site anymore and
so I did some work for a
ticket seller and the sole Broadway
tickets
am and I might my responsibilities were
to gonna build the entire thing from an
architectural same point and I did the
schema design
and and the to getting example of what
a seen at a model looks like you can see
here
you have a module and it this model has
dependencies
on other modules and and they're very
clearly define relationships
and and then here was our data model and
there was a an erroneous requirement
laid out which is
that everything had to be related to
everything I am
which is a unfortunate because we didn't
just have three objects in a data model
we had a lot of objects in a data model
and
and any unfortunate thing about this is
that it was really slow when it came
time to launch
and and this kinda represented wanted
biggest feelings I've had in my career
and it and it boiled down to not
questioning the requirements given
and not really understanding the
implications of what I was doing
a corker mine igor and
came to at the project
after it was it deemed a very slow and
he said
and he he was like all of course this is
slow you doing in place once elects
now is like ol that some bad what is in
place once lets
and and so this is what in plus one
select SAR
and we're going to get a list love posts
for this website and number in a loop
through those and then fix them for that
from the database
and so we make a single query to get
some post ID's and then
for each one of those we we make another
sequel harry didn't get the rest to the
information
and this kind of this happens due to
have abusing jingle foreign guy jerk
foreign keys
and by it this was kinda my first
introduction into this like in plus Y
and kind of syntax that I'd never really
heard before
and said he questions which is
how did I not know this had a missed
this thing how did igor know about him
plus one selection I had never heard and
was one selects
and then how can I make sure this never
happens again and
like I it it was very and interesting
because
it identified a gap in my knowledge and
and
so I guess that begs the question i've
white is big in addition will be to
notation describes limiting behavior
as a function tends toward infinity
using simply functions
which means absolutely no one nothing to
anyone unless you already know
everything about
the connotation a so begin at Asian is
how programmers talk about
how the two pieces of code relate
II in terms of performance
and and this this was really important
when I
went to my interview with Google and so
in prepping for this interview there was
a study was I had
and needed to know data structures and
algorithms and system design in Java
stuff and concurrency stuff
and you know this that be does not on
this list
these are the big no items and no one
no Institute done in your view and says
here's a function was the connotation a
dysfunction
and its kind of assumed knowledge
for these topics and this is kind of how
you
express your knowledge in those topics
and
and so it's it's probably worth talking
about a
brief overview of data structures and
algorithms a data structure is how you
structure your data
and it is kinda how you organize things
and
NN kinda and oversimplification would be
if Python didn't give you lists and sets
and dictionaries and it only gave you
object how would you build lists and
sets and all that other stuff
am that how is is data structures
an and algorithms are a step-by-step
procedure for doing nothing
and so a
and algorithm for making a peanut butter
and jelly sandwich would be
arrest just the recipe it's the
instruction set up how you do it
and and after them is also one of those
words that makes you sound super fancy
to people who don't know that
it just means recipe and so
let's talk about to go notation this is
kinda but begun addition looks like
and there is an ok function it is a big
O
and it has a few
I think they can go inside princes and
so that had to go that there are are
with one
which is how you be this a loved one I
am
at which is called constant I'm a over
login is logarithmic
with and is linear open squares
quadratic
and 00 in factorial spec toria and and
there more than this these are the main
ones that you're most likely to see
I'm probably not going to talk about or
than factorial because it's
a little you see it but it's not super
easy to graph and have a few grass in
here that
make things make sense and if you're
your math class
a was a little long ago look it has been
for me you might
not quite remember what these things
look like and so
this is a graph have and
the various up complexities which is and
what you talk
runtime: complexities which is can how
we talk about big
things and so in squared is the line in
blue
that goes up really quickly and a within
his red
and kinda increases in a flatline to
happen to the right
and the Green Line that you can see just
above the
Orange Line is login and it doesn't
its its a group faster than an
constant time which is the other line
but not by a lot and certainly not by as
fast as everything else does
so the axis and axes being bald here our
time is the y-axis how long something
takes
and the X axis is
at the number I've items input into the
function so
if you had at five items and you gave it
to a function that was
11 squared which is the blue line
you know you can have track this up and
you can see that it's at maybe 35
units a time however we want to meet
measure time but if you're the pass it
to the same function
on the and on the orange it would be one
unit
because is a constant amount of time no
matter how many items you have
and so it's kinda go through
and some examples a these time
complexities
and this is and over one function
it is pitching something from a list
from from a an array by index
and and the reason this is constant time
is because it doesn't matter if the
index into the array is 5
items big the item is are the array is
five times bigger or if it's five
hundred items day
it takes the same amount of time and in
this this makes little sense when you
have a kinda conceptual understanding
how arrays work
which is that they're all memory assets
into
at sun block of memory so to say and
and going from you know block 18 to
block twenty is no
different it's just the same it's the
same physical operation in Chi
and over then
is I am Kenneth canonically
a for loop for loops mean its north and
then
and or that that instruction is or then
we're in is the sizeof
the thing you're looking over and so
this is a function that
checks whether something is contained in
and unordered list
and so we look over the list if the
thing we're looking for
is the thing that we were we have found
in this current
iteration of the loop your turn true
otherwise return false
so you might be asking I see the for
loop and
who is second there's other stuff going
on in their function besides just a for
loop
what happened all that are not coming in
and
so let's its gonna break down this
function and
as I said a the for loop means it's an
all
in operation we're in is the size a the
lst variable
and checking whether an injury is
people to the item we're looking for is
constant I'm
you can kinda think this says comparing
two numbers that's the the simplest
version
and detecting whether one is able to to
you
should be the same speed as checking
whether one is able to 2000
nasa it's not dependent on the size
above the thing you're getting
and and then the return true is
is a constant thing
doesn't matter what your turn it's the
same sixty and
so that gives us a within times over
one-plus old one
right so we add up all those those
things and
so the question an expression is why
don't we just say
old n times over one plus 01
and and the answer is that that's really
people to say Anna mine hurts to say all
that functions within ten to one puzzle
on
a and and for a better
answer we have to go back to at kinda
the formal definition
and any and if I would translate that
into non Matty terms
what that means is that if we plot our
function I
we can also apply another function which
is n which is some constant that we make
up
times the Big O have the function and
and all values to the right
have that function and
we should should be under and so we have
two lines
and and those lines should never cross
going for the right after a certain
point and I'll kinda break this down
I am so the question is how we plot to
go
okay so we have bigger love 11 times
love one possible one
and we're gonna plot something and
so over then always means X in our
graphing
and that's because it increases over
time
and we want to see how this function
changes
its the amount of time it takes changes
over time
an so we
substitute X 40 then and
over one is a constant its constant
times he could pick any constant
I picked 59 because they make progress
easier
and so now we have the to plot
X times five plus nine which looks a bit
like that
just a straight line going to the right
and so if we were to
if this is truly a with n an
or at then we should be able to multiply
or event I'm some constant
and and this blue line should stay under
the new line I am and so here is
applauding and with the concept n so
what this is online flooding
10x and you can see the blue line is
never going to cross that red-line
after about 3 a
so we can say that this function is 00
then
for all values greater than three and
so this that's how we know that 11 is
correct
at so you might be curious at what and
counterexamples to this are
and so let's ask the question is this: a
loved one
I of 1 means are constant I'm right
and concert I means that we should be
able to plot
some constant number to seize the same
regardless I love the x value
and we're here x is equal to 15% to
applying that
the line 5815 and and you can see that
the blue line
is in fact above this redline
am and and because it that the and
we know this is not a constant I'm
function
okay and so the next question is is it
the next higher
complexity level is it 11 squared
and and you can see here for values
greater than 7
that blue line is never going to cross
this red line cuz that red-line shit up
very quickly
and and services applying Eq squares the
red line
and you can see the yeah I actually for
for
values greater than 6 this will never
cross
and so it is true that this
X times five plus nine is in accordance
weird operation
it just also happens to be an with in
operation
and so that's to say that it is
it is true to say that something he is
a higher degree of complexity it's just
not the best answer
and so that would be like saying the
number 10 is greater than 5
yes but it's also greater than seven and
nine it doesn't make any
one less true but and kinda gives you
a you really want the the lower blows
number
that you can that you can choose their
and
so Big O is an approximation up
algorithmic complexity
which is which is to say that and Big O
is and how you
approximate how complex something is how
much how much time or how many
operations that will take and
so to get back to the code we still have
the same code as before
but both the list is empty and is the
if the list is empty then we're gonna
returns for ever gonna return false
immediately
and but bigger notation deals with the
worst-case performance at something
and even if it's empty we want to know
how bad it could be
if it had 10 items in it and and
there are other Big O flavors for you
know
that don't deal with the best at the
worst-case an
but we're not gonna cover that has its
it's not really brought up as often
in in cap act please
on okay so transitioning into or login
and this is logarithmic time and a good
where he's going to the same that things
before
I we're gonna find something analysts
been said that being in unsorted list
we're going to sort the list
and that allows for more efficient
lookup for the sort of that
unless kinda discuss why as we have this
list of 10 integers
and we want to see if the number four is
in how my research works
is we choose a center point in our list
and then say
is for equal to 6% will know fours not
able to six
so because this is sorted we can rule
out everything added in an index higher
than
the index six was an I so we can say
that
you know everything because in six is
not gonna have for it because it's all
sorted
and so we split again and
and we see is is for equal to three no
it's not
and so that leaves us two numbers and
and we take a sporty before and it is
asl at this is logarithmic because
for every iteration this sample size we
have to operate on
is a fraction of the size if that makes
sense
and okay so the next one of these is
over then squared
and this will make at ice
I'll a list have payers in
from an from a list and so
this is a EE nested for loop and these
the Big O
this is the big over that so as I said
for loops are or then and and
generating list is will call that of
wine and and returning
one independent well and
the once we at all these up and Kenneth
in algebra terms we get over one-plus oh
then times or than
times over one-plus or one which is
again insane
and so let's break this down a little
bit I am
so we can read let's rearrange this this
plus
this plus love wanna move that to the
end and makes things a little
easier and then we'll plug in some
numbers like we did before
we Rosa and become axes and Constance
become numbers that we
decide arbitrarily and
and that went once we simplify this at
this reduces to
exc weird plus 29 okay so
now let's play X cleared plus 29 it
looks kinda like this
I am so if this is true we all within
squared
we should be able to apply some constant
times in squared
and this function will never cross it so
he replied in 10 times
X squared I'm and you'll notice that the
blue line will never cross those red
line
a for values greater than three so this
does in fact Valley
that and this is an or then squared
function and
so there there are few gots is when it
comes to you to
tracking the Big O or something
and and a big one is that the
baidoa function might not matter if you
happen old in squared operation and
and yours the the size the list that
you're going to past something
is 5 items and 5 squared is 25
rate so you're gonna do 25 operations
am the computers are pretty fast
and 25 operations are basically instant
and
and so for really small sample sizes and
this is
not as it can it can just not matter
like your computer may be fast enough
that you can just ignore the field
and another gotcha is that be
theoretical speed have something is
different than the actual speed or
something
and and as we said that constancy it is
to pick a number
when you're wrapping and the reality is
that those numbers may be really large
and so you might have a constant that
always takes
200,000 operations to do something but
it doesn't matter how big the list is
just always 600,000 operations an
and on so you could have
constant I'm operations that are slower
than your
an yours all within squared operations
because as we said
innocence as five you have 25 operations
its dramatically less than 200,000 so
this these numbers in practicality
might not pan out and the other thing is
that this is probably not gonna make
your app faster
and a lot of the the performance
bottlenecks that come in in
most applications are kinda tied to you
input/output operations so like speaking
to a database ready to a file system
those things will will often dwarf the
the speed have I've any particular
operation
and one exception to this is kinda CPU
bounce off
and and changing which data structures
and algorithms
her user is Palin make that difference
which is kinda where ago and and while
this is not going to make your apt
faster
is going to make your learning easier
and it's going to make
especially as you get into data
structures and algorithms and then that
aspect
and and it's also going to make your
code review criticisms more articulate
so you can say that this is this is bad
code and this is bad code because this
is an
oh that's weird operation and you can
instead use and/or an operation which is
better
and so let's look at some
resources and that you can look at for
continuing and this is the algorithm
design manual
by Skeena and he is a fantastic book am
is the first quarter up the book
is a and overview Big O
from more mathematical perspective am
data structures and algorithms and the
last
three quarters at the book are so you
have this problem
you want to sort allister integers well
here are some ways you can do that
these are the rent on complexities of
them add ol
are your numbers all less than a hundred
maybe you want to use this other other
than instead which is a little faster if
you have that one special case
this is a really great book and I I
recommend everyone
take a look there is a Corsair course
and run by Stanford called algorithms
design analysis
and they go over a lot of this graphing
things and
and how to I had care how to do that
and and its it said a good course
it has a lotta I'm
it has a lot of math stuff in there so
when I was going through this course I
also had to kinda
read up on the math so it's a little
slower and
but it's still a really great resource
I'm also in the process of reading a
book called computer science for
software programmers
and so that might be a
views it's not released yet but if you
message me i'm happy to you let you know
when it's
went to be available so you might be
asking however Michael differently now
the answer is that knowing they go
doesn't mean he radioed any differently
and because let's face it were mostly
colours in here if you need to know it
to rate your code better
you probably already know by now and but
that the thing that is this is useful
for is it the baseline knowledge for
data structures and algorithms
and data structures and algorithms will
make greater differently
and also this is a communication tool
similar to design patterns which
you informally use but don't know what
you're using you don't know what to call
them it's a vocabulary that you can use
to you make your life easier in
communication with other programmers
better
so taken a recap Big O is useful in
communicating about the complexity of
your code
II is big just basic algorithm
at basic arithmetic and algebra and
it's used in talking about algorithms
and data structures
and it's not as hard as it originally
sounds and
so thanks I'm Justin and if you want to
hear more about this book I'm reading
or no tap or quick left email me to be
fine at this conference and I'd love to
talk to you
thank you
okay so
Allen to your second question for
switches how different is
and login compared to you and or login
and see if you remember the graph from
the beginning which
let's go back there and in log n
is in times login so
n is this red line going up into the
right login is this green line that
barely increases about constant
and so it's a little slower than
its as the that difference between in
and in login is the difference between
this constant I'm Orange Line
and the login you rate so its
it's actually end times login it's
almost an but not quite
too little slower than that and in the
first question was how
how do you know what numbers up again
okay so the question is how do you know
whether to add or multiply
in in these items so
this and the 0 the first over one
operation here
if entries able to items is done once
every time in for the for loop so
it happens and be one-time
times the number items in the list so
you think I know if view everything that
happens inside the for loop
as being in parentheses and saying like
this number
the size at this for loop times the
number the waivers happening inside
and then again if we can advanced up to
the in squared operation we have this
and this for loop with inside is another
for loop
so we have this and times in times one
because the four I to enlist we do
one concert I'm operation for each item
in list
rain and then we multiplied that by the
numbers in the first list
a so that's how you know where than with
an immersion
I had
yes so that the beginning and the things
that are just some one searches
the quality operator itself is another
algorithm so that could have
not 01 operation time
if it's a string for example I P O M or
like the whatever thats Prince
your your energy example I think I saw
one but for other
object item may not be yes that is true
thank you
I i think is probably worth mentioning
man
I'm by no means an expert in Big O
notation this is kind of
practical Big O there there's a lot of
the intricacies and people who
really no big oh well from a theoretical
perspective might have some quibbles
about how
I presented it but the this is enough to
pass a
Google interview and enough to be able
to speak
about it in a way that makes you not
seem crazy
so hopefully that colors this little
that
better what's your other favorite tool
for actually evaluating Steve
function I am IRC
is my favorite tool and asking people I
think this is this
let's talk about it because it's II
eight don't
know who love a tool that will just spit
out the answer
and so it's a lot of looking at this and
saying
and okay so peerless equals new array
that's our new list what happens when we
built a list well we probably allocates
memory in that memory reallocate is
prolly the same size the matter what we
do so
I'll are just call it the constant a
at and thence you you ask someone else
and and I'll tell you
it really boils down to you having a
a really solid understanding of what the
heck your kids doing until it when
you're building an array what is
actually happening
and the knowledge and data structures
and algorithms
help you because they will tell you oh
you're doing
Insur into and array well inserts into
array have a worst-case performance
with whatever and then you say oh well
I'm gonna happen generate look up in
this data structures documentation
what is the unit Asian let's give just
another runner plus thank you very much