good afternoon everyone thank you so
much
this is the last session I what does
give yourselves a round of applause you
made it
I hope you guys had a fantastic time
this has been a great conference
um just a final note I do wanna push
this sprints one last time as you may
well know this is not the last day
a bike on their arse developments Prince
happening
tomorrow onwards and this is
the best time to work with the world's
best Python programmers the world's best
minds in the
you know like in this city you have the
advantage of working on high-profile
projects like mercurial and type I
in pyramid and all sorts of other
products including getting help for your
own products um at the and the lightning
talks which I highly encourage that you
go to
I you will be able to pitch for 20
seconds whatever products that you want
to have help with please go there
pitcher project but any kind a product
that you wanted to have advice on
even if it's a little hobby thing go and
pitch it
show up to the sprints all our if you
get really excited about someone else
project please go and contributes the
best way
to get started in open source now
it's my pleasure to introduce call Meyer
who I'll when he's not hacking on
pipeline
plays a mean Ultimate Frisbee and he's
gonna be talking about setting your code
free releasing in maintaining
and open source i dont live ripley's a
big round of path
thank you
i'm carl myer I work for our bird we
build web applications in Dubai time
code consultation and review
so if you want to hire a second let me
know are we talking about
releasing in maintaining your first open
source Python library
the premise of this talk is that you
have code
writing that code is outside the scope
of this particular talk
we presume you haven't already we're
presuming also
that you want me to use your code and a
particular means is the open stall
there's
other methods of getting your code to
users web application deployment
or creating gooey installers or
operating system packages
those methods of getting code users are
also outside the scope of the stock
will be discussing pip install and the
other premises that you want me to
contribute to your code
and presumably you want to be able to
accept my contributions without breaking
your software or losing your sanity
so you look up some documentation on the
internet about how to do this for the
Python project
and you may find
more than one source of information and
documentation and more than one relevant
project
and it might be a little confusing
finding your way through and navigating
the the various advice and documentation
when you're doing something for the
first time
too many choices can kill your
motivation to finish it
so this talk the idea is to present to
set a rails
for releasing in maintaining your first
open source Python project
it's not the only way to do it there are
many choices that you could make
this is one set of choices that can work
so will be long and opinions here short
on traces
the ideas from zero toss them in 20
minutes
some of the awesome that wall have after
20 minutes are over
includes public HTML documentation
with responsive theme that automatically
updates when you push the repo
I'm tests that automatically run every
time you push the repository
a pip install working and a project
that's welcoming to new contributors
and if you've done this before if you're
already the owner of a python open
source project
hopefully I'll still pick up a new
trigger to you the road map for this
presentation includes talking about a
project structure
choosing a license where to host your
code
your documentation testing in continuous
integration
packaging your code so people can
install it
and setting up a community around your
project that's welcoming deter new
contributors
here's a bare-bones project structure
for a hypothetical project
have named a hypothetical project
high-flyer which I was shocked to
discover is not yet registered on the
paper and packaging decks
so consider this the 0 day for that a
who we'll see who's the first to
register and build something under that
name
while the docs directory with inner out
a repository directory for a
documentation will live
well have a top-level python package
containing all your Python code
that's marked with every stirred under
in net dot pi file and probably some
other
Python modules what a test directory
where a test live
a license file manifest dot in we'll
talk about a little later
a read me and a set up top I which is
what makes a package installed by other
users
the first decision you have to make you
for going to release some code is open
source is what license to release it
under
obligatory disclaimer am NOT a lawyer
know what's on the slide as legal advice
but your license is the conditions under
which I'm a user code
if you don't have a license the default
is all rights reserved
so the fact that you've pushed your code
to get herb does not mean I can use it
if it doesn't have an open source
license then a
you have not given me any conditions
under which I'm allowed to use your code
if you aren't sure what license to use I
recommend starting with BSD your MIT
license
the XOR a less restrictive open source
licenses essentially all you ask from
your users
is that if they modifier redistribute or
code they preserve
your name attached to it so you keep
your credit for writing the code
and they preserve the license under
which you've released the code that you
wrote
so if you're interested in having people
use our software
almost anyone can use our software under
those conditions
other reasonable alternatives if you
know why you need them
included the GPL or LGPL the Apache
License are the Mozilla Public License
the GP on particulars a bit more
restrictive it requires
a anyone redistributing or modifying
your code to resolve their contributions
under the same license
if you're concerned about freeloaders
you may think about that
it will probably mean that some people
choose not to use our software so that's
the tradeoff
don't use any other licenses decides
these
ago the goal the license is to it
clarify for someone else the terms under
which they can use their software and
reduce their concern that they'll be
getting into legal trouble by using our
software
if you use a less well-known license
you're simply giving potential users
have your software
a reason to question whether it's safe
to use
you don't want someone considering using
your code to feel like they have to go
ask their legal department
whether it's safe to do so so you avoid
that by using a well known in common
license and you hope to avoid license
plate proliferation
quick at it most other advice on the
slide comes from a lightning talk to
Jacob Kaplan Moss gave a Django Connie
you 2010
if you find my slides online laters this
is a link to that lighting talking you
can view
see that advice in a little more depth
so here's a sample of how we apply a
licensed or corrode we simply put in the
license to txt file
or in some cases some people call the
file copying
the tax title license you want to use
this is the to cause BSD license what
are the ones I
recommended as a a good choice
we got a lot of items to get through the
stalks a think for some other mercury
very short and sweet as one of them
you should know Serco don't get hurt
because that's where the people are
documentation is another one that
certain sweet
i like reading code I read a lot of code
I will happily Rieger code to find a bug
to find out what I'm doing wrong to fix
a bug
or just a better understand what your
library does
but if I have to read your code in order
to even start using it to figure out the
very first Apple have what I need to
call in what order to make it do a thing
then I'm probably going to decide that
it's easier just to rate myself
or use a competing library for the same
purpose
fortunately how to write your docs and
how to host them are also very easy
choices these days
you should write your docs using Sphinx
which is the tool the Pythons on docs
are written in
and you should host a doc said read the
docs
to get started with things will pip
install it
change into the docs directory run the
Sphinx quick start to all
which I just ask you a series of
questions for your first time most
likely the default answered every one of
those questions will serve just fine
once you've answered all those questions
you have a number files in your docs
directory in one of them will be indexed
rst
and you can just jump right and in
Dexter St and start writing
documentation
spring stocks are written in the
restructured text format
if you haven't written restructure text
before it's very easy to get started
with
we have underlined headers you can have
different layers have headers with
different
underline characters we have in line
formatting bold
we can have code liberals in line and we
can have code example just introduced
with the double cone
and this code example automatically the
syntax highlighted
as Python code
even if you write exactly this much
documentation for your package
it's already miles ahead a package
without any documentation
I can look at this and I already
understand to be the most basic thing
with your package
this is what I need to do and this this
would take five minutes to rate
so then run make HTML to generate an
HTML version for documentation
and after we've done that spinks gives
us this and ice
table of contents based on our header
structure
we see all our syntax highlighting their
inner cord example
say just get html files so anyone host
is publicly and for that we use read the
docs
so we go to read the docs .org give read
the docs a few pieces of information and
name for package
in the repository URL and then we head
over to get herb
and activate the redox web book from the
long list get a Web Works
and push or project and will have
documentation built
posted publicly read the docs .org using
their theme which is mobile responsive
there's you can build not multiple
versions have your docs it'll
automatically build one for various tags
are branches in your code base
and gives you a virgin switcher for
people to choose which version they want
to read
if your code is changing over time and
you don't have automated tests for it
or all secure a staff over time the
likelihood
attack code being broken approaches one
having tests is important for any code
but for open source code it can be
especially important
here's into the a a problem that open
source libraries often have is the
dependency matrix problem
if we have five versions a python we
want to support
and five versions have a dependency say
Django in this case the for writing a
project that depends on Django
now we have 25 different boxes here
that represent environments that we
ideally should be testing if we really
mean to support all these versions of
all these dependencies
if you aren't actually creating 25
virtual ends and running your tests
under any one of those environments
then your claim to support all those
environments is purely theoretical
and over time it's almost certainly not
true
fortunately there's a tool to help with
this problem
the talks to with one command talks will
create a whole bunch a virtual ans all
the ones we need for all the environment
in your test inside
and will run your test in all those
environments
here's an example the very simple talk
setup you
placer talks configuration in the talks
that I and II file
in the repository you give it list if
the environments
in which you want to run your tests this
is a very simple talks that I and II
we're just running our tests under
Python 2.7 Python 3 out for another pipe
I
regionally I had only the first year
then Alex Gaynor
looked over my shoulder and saw my
slides men tied me up and wouldn't let
me go on to lay out a pipe I
then we also define the dependencies for
for testing our project so in this case
will say we want to install pie test
and then the commands the need to be run
to test our project in this case will
just run pilot test
you can stick anything in here that you
can run a shell prompt and talks will
decide whether your test pastor failed
simply based on the return code so you
can
use any kind of testing framework can
imagine with talks
you can of course do much more complex
things talks can handle the form
a matrix of dependencies and Python
versions that we saw in the previous
matrix
I'm showing a very simple example here
if you wanna see are the more complex
things you can check the documentation I
be happy to show you some
real-life examples after the talk
when we run talks it creates a packages
up our project it creates a virtual end
for Python 2.7 in this case it installs
are dependencies
installer project into the virtual and
runs our tests
seriously the output from pie test
running our tests 3 three test passed
and then you'll see exactly the same
output for Python 3.4 and again for pie
pie
and then at the end it informs us that
our test passed on all three
environments
and gives a smiley face
so you have talk set up that's great
with one command you can run tests and
verify the support all the environments
you claim to you
so you get a poor request from someone
so you open your terminal
you add the source of the poor request
as a get remote you fetch that branch
the source branch for the poor request
and then you run talks
just a lot nicer than having to run your
test 25 times that poor quest but
they're still bitter
boilerplate work in there you have to do
to review a poor request
went to be nice if when you first look
at a poor request your project
you already knew whether the test passed
or failed
this used to be a hard thing to do to
set up today fortunately it's easy
thanks to a number services
wanna talk about today is Travis CI dork
because it's the one I've used
droned I oh i think is another service
that does similar things
there may be others Travis CI will
provide continuous integration for free
for public data projects
to use its very easy go to traverse the
I dot org
log in with your YouTube account using a
lot it will give you a list of all your
public get
data repositories and you simply quickly
on button for any of them that you want
to run your tests on Travis the I dot
org
and it will automatically set up the web
or can't get hard for those projects
second thing we have to do is tell
Travis how to run our tests we do this
via Travis diagram of Iona repository
it this there's a similar purpose to the
talks that I and I we tell Travis that
it's a Python project
we want to run our tests under these
three Python versions
we need these install commands run
before the tests are run
and this is the script for running our
tests I dot test
there are tools to automatically convert
talks that I and II to a travesty I am
on vice versa
one is called pan CI you can also
districts you can use to it
make you sadder talks environments
within your traversed I am or
for my projects I tend to just maintain
them both in parallel they don't change
that often it's not hard to do
and simpler so once you've done that
you'll get something like this from
Travis every time he pushed the
repository
it'll summarize whether the bill passed
or failed and show you teach
environmental you specified
whether that environment pastor failed
and every time send someone sends a poor
request to your get have
repository get help or even show you
about the poor request Travis will run
your tests using the app or request code
and get help I'll tell you whether the
test pastor failed so the first moment
you look at APO request
you already know whether bro protests
so you also want someone to be able to
tap install your thing
the key to that is the setup I file
will just look at a sample set up top I
go through some other
the key elements in it
in this setup I we're gonna you setup
tools
which is a third-party project it's not
part a python standard library
in practice almost everyone has it if
you're concerned about people being able
to pip install your code
paper lies on setup tools see you can
assume that your users will have set up
tools already
in that scenario we have a remade rst
file
which we wrote person very basic
documentation may be linking to our for
documentation
and I get help or displayed on the front
page for project on github
an the Python package index has a
similar longdescription where you could
have restructured text format it
description of your project
so it's nice to reuse the read me we've
already written as our long description
on the package index
so we can do that and set up I just by
opening the read me
and ass assigning its contents or long
description
we call the setup function when you
execute supped up I the setup function
will magically do some things based on
whatever command line arguments he gave
every pass to set up I a variety of
meta-data about our package
so the name in the package the version
a short description are long description
the author's name the author's e-mail:
URL homepage for the project the
rest of Python packages in the projects
in this case we just have one top level
package
I fly install requires a story can
specify dependencies and other packages
in this case will say world we depend on
the six package which is
tools for supporting pipe onto and
Python 3 in a single code base
and then lastly trove classifiers these
allow you provide extra meditate about
your package which automated tools can
use to collect statistics on
on the package index or make decisions
about
about your to do things about your your
software these are not
used by Pepe so specifying your Python
version support here won't affect what
pic will or won't install
but it can still be useful for knowing
how many packages
a on on packaging tech support by phone
three for instance if you
provide the versions the support here
and your license here
also is it just providing information to
your users in a structured way
another file we need for packaging is
manifest dot and
when Python when you're supped up I
build the source distribution is your
package it will include all your Python
code automatically
and if there's any non Python files you
want to include we need to specify them
in our manifesto did
so in this case will include our authors
file change log get the license file
are manifest Rd NR read me and I will
include all the documentation so anyone
who downloads the source distribution
for the package index
also has access to the documentation and
source form
once we have those two files can prepare
to release to the package index
before we release what Hagar releasing
get up
well pusher takes to get her but doesn't
happen by default
and then we'll create a source
distribution Estes stands for source
distribution is just basically a tarball
have your code in some associated files
you can create that with Python set up I
fastest there's also a new we all format
which encourage you to look into it a
binary format so if your cur if your
package has compiled extensions
using the Wii or format will make it
much easier for people to install
if it's a pure Python package in its
your first time it a party simpler just
to stick with Estes that's the most
common form and storks very well for
pure Python packages
once you have your St Ste you can
actually install it directly with Pepe
set up I will place the S test inside
the dist
subdirectory and pick can install
directly from that terrible
and that way you know you can test to
make sure that your packaging works
correctly with your package installs and
you can import it and use it
before you actually uploaded to the
package index
now Python set up top I it does have a
command for uploading code
uploading your Estes to the package
index unfortunately it works
over a plate plane a an uninterrupted
connection
so it actually passes your package index
credentials uninterrupted
surrounded in using that we use a third
party package called twine which can
securely upload
your project to the package index open
stall twine
and then we just ate wine upload and
pointed at our table
arrest ist and uploaded to the package
index
before you can do this step you need to
have already gone to the Python package
index web page
created an account and claimed your
package name on the package index and
then you can use twenty upload
to upload your %uh version of your
project
once we've done that we should be able
to Pippin stop I fly in our packet wants
to offer back in index
for the last i'ma talk about are first
come for more information about
packaging there's a lot more that could
be covered
packaging apartment at Oregon's
documentation their dire si channel pipe
EA on freenode
where there's people hanging out will be
glad to help you with your packaging
problems
and there's a dispute all signify that
our mailing list
last to talk a little bit about building
a community around your project
people join communities because they
make their lives better to building a
community around your project is all
about finding ways to make your users
and contributors lives better
a lot of that has to do with valuing
their time so talk about some ways to
value the time in your users and
contributors
one way to value users time is to
communicate clearly about changes
to your software that will affect them
semantic versioning
is a technique to use your version
numbers to communicate information to
your users about changes in your
software
the idea is that if you ever version
number like X dot wide-eyed Z
your increment acts
anytime you make breaking changes to
your API
so someone knows that if the upgrade
from version 1.0 died 02 version 2.0
they're likely to need to update their
code to use your softer differently
because he made breaking changes:
your increment why for future changes
that are backwards compatible
enduring increments easy for releases
that include only bug fixes
cember .org has more information on
semantic versioning
another part a value your users time
when someone sees the you've made
backers incompatible changes
the change log is where they can look to
find out what those changes are
and what kinda things don't need
updating their code system integration
in tells users about the magnitude in
the typeof changes in a release
and the change law gives them details
change log
is not just a something you can generate
automatically from your commit log
it should pull out user interesting
changes and summarize the many user
friendly way
here's an example of how I structure
change log using restructure text
so wat you can value your contributors
time and save yourself time
is by having a contributing document
here's a
some things you might want to include in
your contributing document will call it
contributing at rst in the router
repository
you can include things like how to get
setup for development
how we contributor can run the tests for
your project
but they should include a bug reporter
poor request
what coding standards or test coverage
standards are other requirements you
have for contributing to your code base
that they should know about Advance
and my side effect if you have a
top-level filing a report called
contributing dot something
get have will find it an automatic we
provide a link to it prominently
on top of the new poor requester the new
issue form
so contributors will be guided to your
contributing guidelines before they
contribute
so I'm all excited to fix a bug I found
in your project
i download it I follow your contributing
guidelines I get all set up for
development I install the dependencies a
more excited to run the tests so that I
can have a clean slate to work from a
tram not breaking anything with my
change
and four tests fail and my motivation to
contribute your project
is gone so one very important thing you
can do is keep your test passing
another way to value contributors time
in contribution is to give quick
feedback
when you get bug reports reporter quests
you may not have time to deal with the
right away or thankfully through the
future requester
how to fix the bug but you can very
easily have a one line response on the
issue report request saying
have time to look at this now I really
appreciate the contribution I'll look at
next week or in a month or
maybe in three years or whatever the
truth is
but you can give immediate feedback for
contributions
and when people pitch in you can give
them props you can do that in a commit
message
you can do that in your change log you
can do that in an author's file that
lists all your contributors
you can do that with tweets you can all
kinds of ways you can give people props
and give them credit for their work
but that motivate people to contribute
even beyond that if you have helpful
contributors who have submitted a couple
good poor requests
you can be very quick to give them
commit access with dove distributed
version control commit access is it is
technically important as it used to be
but it's still a market confidence that
store social signal that you trust
someone
to handle your project correctly and
forgiving commit access to someone
will motivate greater involvement from
them and
chances are someday you're gonna be
tired maintaining this project you're
gonna move on to other things
you can have other things to manage your
time so giving commit access
to someone is preparing someone to
possibly take over the project from you
in the future when you're done with it
the very last thing but definitely not
least
anytime you get a bike or a poor
requesting your software
even if it's irritating or it's phrased
in a aggressive way or someone hasn't
done their homework and read the
contributing document or whatever it
might be
it still represents someone who took the
time to did
to to take the initiative to make a
contribution to your project because
they wanted to be better
because they cared about it to represent
someone who cares about your project due
to time and energy
to try to make it better and regardless
of what other issues you may have with
their contribution
you can always thank them for taking
their time and energy
for every one person that you
communicate with directly in a public
way via an issuer pork Western get other
there's or mailing list dryers your
whatever there maybe ten or twenty or
fifty or a hundred other people
who will see that interaction either now
or in the future
and based on what they see in an
interaction may make a decision about
whether it's worth their time to
interact with you and contribute your
project
there is nothing to be lost by being
nice to everyone who contributes to your
project
so go forth and release code
agree have about
four minutes for questions thank you
very much for nice summary of
many good things you could do to your
project and few comments
I don't know why give people did but you
don't want to tack on the
tag and and attack you want to use
annotated or sin tax
because if you ski describe command
which is really useful to define where
you are
in this actually he threw development
those will not be used
so use those with this am you can
provide even message was discredited
right there in the common line
then for from for licenses I i'm sorry
I've missed that part but
I asked around if you're using
third-party code in your code
it would be great if you come up with
description of what code
have used for this to cooperate with his
license license and self
without Cup right doesn't matter so it
needs to be a bundle of cooperate in the
license
also be careful about looking at the
third party modules which have more
restricted licenses if you use to peel
code
and your project is a meteor bees the
effectively at runtime
is GPL so those guys in the next room
who compile their code write and deliver
it that will build Ridge appealed code
you would need to provide your sources
well not in these both the words
important since we do it open source
anyway laurie
and if you do semantic versioning that
thats awesome
and but if you want to verify somebody's
else version
you could use these two deals lose
version and strict version to do proper
comparison
not like breaking to topple and then
compared some other ways because that
might fail badly
if you use development persons other
projects thank you again
great that's was a great addition thank
you from via
I originally included ash s in the get a
gym and then you should definitely sign
your dick
tags if you have a a pgp setup
also if you have pgp synergy PG setup
you should also use dash dash signer
dasher signer twine upload
and that will sign your fastest file on
the package index
I remove those who don't work people who
don't have GPG set up
but if your gonna be releasing software
as pie with your time to
get a GPG key set up and make sure sign
those things I thank you very much
our thank you's a great talk common lot
information
arm how do you feel about using get have
is a source of are requesting people
hoping a project in the sunset you have
an idea of where you want the project to
be
and you have a certain level skill and
you kinda got it to get started but you
need assistance to you
see that is bad way to get started her
arm using did have to get contributors
how exactly I'm in the sense that you
you're you're not at the level that you
need you need you need assistance in
your project but you have some sort of
working coli collect the boilerplate a
bit in a sense it's me died
you would like other people to help
contribute to your project doesn't hurt
to try
I mean usually my experience is that you
get contributors because you've got
something useful that helps them
and then they need something else you to
do something else and so they're
motivated to
to edit add to it so if you you put
something up or get out that's more
her more an idea than an actual working
code I think in most cases there
probably won't be that successful but
if it's something that a lot of people
really wants doesn't hurt
thanks hi
haves as a ring if your advice for
maintaining does manifest on
files like I've broken libraries the
EU's
internally because I've made code
changes in forgot to update
the man sign in part include so
their tools are there are tools that I
use to help maintain manifest started
there may be some other than I don't
know if yeah that is a problem
it's a good reason to to test your Estes
be before you upload them the package
index another thing I should try mention
is that
a when they had enough time to include
in the slides is what to do if you have
made a bad release
you do you upload a release to the
package index that doesn't work
and the answer is you should not remove
or change that release want to talk on
the package index
you should consider there for good you
just upload a new release with the
pumped micro version number and move on
yep
I have one more question last question
thank you for the talk and I know
its still alive stops and its at least
it's a lot like last last year must
complicated for now but do you feel that
what extent do you think that service
that can be automated
in the future perhaps to make it much
more forgetting
packages it's already a lot more
automated than it was a few years ago I
mean a few years ago for a given the
stock we wouldn't have had read the docs
when about Travis the eye and so there's
a very important steps
a here's where it would have been a way
harder a couple years ago so
yeah I presume that that I hope that
things will continue to get easier
particularly on the on the packaging
side of things is definitely movement in
that area
so we'll see yeah I know
I'll be in the hallway if anybody wants
to talk more about but things are you
about them