hello everybody %uh I'm here to present
lights the flame will be speaking about
upgrading your web development will
change please welcome him
within plus well
lol thank you so welcome to my
a Brit your web development to chain
that time give so
as usual and what about me so I'm doing
a full well at full stack web
development
I mostly lead project and teams that
and still learning a lot everyday
probably
as love you so what this talk is about
in fact this stock is about more ID's
and patterns
it's about combining two it's also about
working with people's a
people on project it's not about
let's see strong opinions because I'm
not there over
a punitive guy it's not about to
cookbook recipies do and it's not
in-depth technical
examples and I'm open to everything so
if you want to discuss anything about
what I'm talking today after
I'll be a happy to talk with neru so
the talk was planned under the best
practices
and patterns so let's just talk a bit
about that
and dogmatism is never a good thing
I think being like close to
order ID's is not a good idea in itself
and
I try to not be dogmatic about what I
just said that
but I think is the right way to be open
to others
and it should always at this significant
benefit so it means that why would you
do something
and it gives you less after so it mean
you'd need at minimum a significant
benefit an
to stick to what really makes a
difference so why would you
they used tool because all the hype
let's say
and rewrite everything in indiana you
get the same results so you should be
careful
about what you should to to to use then
the ideal the TOC is bays about problem
I tried to sold across the years and
its many bays on how to tie up
multiple in development project so for
sure when you have just one project to
install and everything it's easy
at some point you you'll need to
separate and
in some company that could be like a
separate in that case will be more
like the front in stock with the back in
stock but you could can start like
sharing components like for web forms
there that obeys or anything you want to
reuse across project and then
the idea is to have night and
environment where you can
develop dole's multiple projects at the
same time so
to tie up multiple environments and
tools and to make some development teams
because at some point when your project
grew
a lot more people involved and probably
more teen
could be a remote teams to so you need
to find a way to mix up
all those thing togethers in the same
way so my point of view is to the
separation of concerns
so for sure for each of us concerns
could be different
could be different like Ace like I said
after adapt to conduct so depending on
the context so
it's a also be used known tools
and that's good to create your own staff
but at some point to get stock
with what you're doing so try to use it
to
already existed and that people are
beyond those tools so if you need help
or anything
and try to add that to context that
means that the
debt wondering to rule them all is not
a good way to think about things so it's
not because you
developed a way of doing things that way
will be good for everything you'll be
doing
beat sometimes people like
concept and ID's and tools and make
everything fits
in those patterns I think people are
more important than tools
so we should find a way to make the most
out of people
so what will people
people do if if I die if you die it
means if
I create a lot of thing that I like em i
alone
ed at to work with so if
at some point and no longer part of the
project people will get stock with what
what I've done in the lab to rewrite
everything so when
you mad at something you should be
careful about what you use
and be sure you do thing in the way
people will be able to continue
and work on top of what you've done
so what's the typical workflow for
project
I'm it is is be the thing I don't want
to too much in detailee just like to
understand I do
the the steps so normally you loud like
a server provisioning and set up
you land that web application
development and your lab
the deployment phase
so 42 provisioning and development and
deployment
you need somewhere to run her
application
on so it could be your own machine could
be the developer machine
could be dedicated ard where it could be
any other the awesome man i cum laude
thing we had like line 0 the Rackspace
their work you
an the it could be
the setup manually by someone
or with an orchestration the to like and
symbols I'll stack
doctor in majors it could be provided in
any way
but we should not care
where'd the application will run yes
for deployment that when you develop it
should be your it should not be your
concern
so the should call you
in their process of building there and
there's
their their setup and their deployment
environment
so they should provide you all the tools
like and that a basin
cashing systemic up in all that up so a
developer could
install I love dad by himself with this
system package if you want to be you
want to you like a virtual machine or
anything
we should not care when we organized the
weed
at environment is done so
the at environment that and should be
self-contained as much as possible so
if it still self-contained and
its eventually it will be able to be
around
on multiple platforms environment and
that will provide
a better test than and robbers kobe's
so to bring bad the bagged a concept Bob
up people is I I still think in the team
and tools are not more important than
people so
you won't asked like you're a developer
to use at Vienna because you have
developed a
develop it a lot are there a super
awesome
make ru and then you you want everyone
to use the same setup menu
and Malta the developers use assist and
the
tweak do the way they want to have their
own stop on it
and their database and everything so I
think York
ap environment should not tell them how
to use their own
their own computer and their own we can
do in doing things
and if you want to get the most
out-of-date and you should let them
word in a way there effective so
there with that and development
actually is mostly front-end and
back-end work so
when you back and mostly you're doing
for us
by 10 we're using web frameworks like
pyramid jangle
Laska and we use it 10 template engines
like may call
and ginger to Kenya leon's or ramen
I'll all other libraries and for front
and
the use like HTML CSS JavaScript to use
frameworks to like
angle our backbone the use preprocessor
like a
less sasser copy script a lot of stuff
day they're used to so
both abdulah their own expertise in
tools and network flow so
in some corners the overlaps a some
others
the they are like complimentary just as
an example
and if we look at package management so
under pi don't weir's do so we can do
easy install
or people style packages are a package
with
its own version and for front and they
can do the same
like but were installed jQuery or jQuery
a specific version and in fires like
in require requirement doc the txt or a
set up I we can specify
all the required libraries with their
own version and with the bobber file
edges and finally we can do the same
thing for and then
the front end so what is my were it
simply package manager for to win
actually the problem the problem is a
where is the line the
at the the front end developer will need
like two
to to nope I town and
add is own dependency in item code:
so at some point it make no sense to add
the front end developer
relying on the back and stop so let's
look a bit
and with asset management so
we can use on the back inside and
with assets in that is a great tools
where you can
the final it's a bundles with those
bundles
you can t find a lot of different fires
you can apply filters to let's say
unified and
cash busting everything and like the
output file
let C pac the GS and then within the
application
or within the template you can refer
Rance and the file
and any tried to the the right to your
own everything so for
back in user it's awesome because it
ease a lot
up things but they have the same or
something similar in the front and world
so
they have their own tools to let's say
min if I
and packages and and then
if you look at adults small snippet so
it loads
and and module granted GS min source:
map and then it register at Ascot and
the task is defined in the country
so you would say they're there's no way
in the back in like to refer Rennes does
your own everything
but that's a bit the point because at
some point to
and you you'll reach sorry
so just to get background like you said
is a task runner
effort to missions so it it's a tool for
them
to help them like to to do a lot
other things we normally do on the back
and sign but
for them and then and sorry
okay and I was referring to how we were
for rent
things in there like the application so
in the front signed the
the front at downside the also need away
other including important reply you're a
library's
what we do on the back and sign but at
some point
the need that too because the
application becomes more and more
complicated
so they need a way to load dependencies
to so
if you look at this simple then
snippet you'll see that you can define a
path for jQuery
for specific library and Dan in their
own code
they can let's say and at Chick worry
and make it avaliable as the dollar
strain
inside that module so why would you want
from tend to rely
a net back and dependency why you'd be
would you want them to know about the
pipe down
so you'll reach appoint
up separation where when the application
is an eye bridge applications so a lot
of stuff is done
on the front end or it's a single page
application
so in that case your bank back and
becomes like
just an API so it won't make sense
to have does front-end developer relying
on
all the stuff you can do on the back end
so
you'll benefit from split into multiple
projects so multiple project could be
per team copper concern for so
in that case it means probably back in
stock
and front and stuff so let's say we had
a single page app
so we can add like the back and in a
github repo
the package and the same for the front
end but what we want to use
is to use dole's project under dissing
global
ap or project environment and share a
common set of tools and patterns
so this is where build-out entered the
game
so bill doubted these the
its application centric so ET's the
essentially
and deployment other application
environment and make
that original repeatable process
so build out that he uses extendable
configuration files
so simple like I nighttime it uses
extensions
entity uses received so if you look at
the simple at build-out config file
and you'll see like did at the build-out
part to work I use the extension mister
the blubber
it's an extension like to he's the the
development are
multiple in development projects we can
I like multiple repo
under at the same at a given environment
it extends
a configuration files a on get up don
beyer
Bowl ashrita was kind enough to create
that they're simple the config files
that wraps and like ground and our calm
and
inside your application environment and
then you see I have different parts like
the years eggs and power modules bar
modules in the ritz from day
you men come to your Asian and then
under the flap
this is where I out my multiple
application
so my cap one in my at to and so on
and under D years I am I use a receipt
sorry
I use piracy p to create a directory so
let's say
var directory for temperate see
things on the format application and
then
the source my at one in my apt to
where to get them from and in the egg
part I after receipt be like to in style
like my apt 1 in my apt to that will
abdel
their dependency and I can add other
dependencies just like for the project
so
if I want like to say to add actin like
dat
client trap monetary for my application
instead of defining that into my setup
not by:
project it would be a better place to
to have that in the ap environment
configuration
so the idea is to provide
a development project that builds the
application environment so you add
a new project and you don't care about
my apt one in my apt to
and do a gift at Cologne and Ed and do
the people in everything so it's
the application environment will take
care up building
everything so basically what you get is
is that so you have a grand final for
different tasks
so we'll probably have to make final
I'll tell you that the
more about after you out like the
bootstrap that PI what
P wife I'll that that used to bootstrap
the build-up environment
so the byword for the Bauer dependencies
your javascript dependencies
and the build-out configuration probably
and the TC directories for your
application
configuration and the package judges and
it's for the node
module package management
to install its a grant and power and
other
required libraries then to set up the
project
allowed like to clone that the
environment project
then see the rapper do every trial and
the
and then round bootstrap bootstrap will
boo troubled out and then around build
out and build out we'll take care
against ollie everything you need for
your application
then you're done so people can start
working on your project
white make sense it's because I don't
think you need to provide a full stack
environment with
all the server components under virtual
machine
or an image or anything yet 4 developing
an application for deployment yes but
for
for development it's a bit different I
think so
it will look a bit like that so once you
and start the application you get
all the same fines plus other ones like
that the bean
dead include done by the virtual and and
the ex done by then
build-out configuration and you get done
or more jewels and the components
for by our and that no modules
then and another temp simple way to
to rap das comments and in in the easier
way
would be to use let's say to make file
just around those comp come and
under and a common API so from in people
don't care like to to know about it I
can't comment and probably put it back
in people
don't care about knowing the front
uncommon so you can probably create like
a makefile
where your app how we prayed the virtual
and
how you bootstrapper build-out how your
own build-out
and add a comment: set-top that runs all
those common
so indie and let's say your front end
developer to get started the project
will just how I like to clone your
project and then see the app and
make setup everything will be done and
then you could add other common like
make run that happened that will do like
it P survey
your your a knife i in and around the
web server
and when you separate project so let's
say you have
the front and total these stand-alone
so ground provide
a small web server for them to develop
so there's no need for Dan to Ron
your heightened code to test and
organize their thing
but at some point it would be important
like to run the back and
or anything so both project can coexist
under the same at environment so in fact
the goal is to isolate application
environment
it's too organize projects in this
flexible way
and give more power to users anti so
many questions perhaps
anyone has a question
and his microphone over there for asking
questions on
I guess no questions so on
thank you very much up the time we're
not getting there is a question
I was gonna ask you afterwards but
guessing that's good for everybody here
on buildup is pretty cool but what
happens when you have
repositories that depend upon other
repositories which themselves have their
own set ups
which are arbitrarily complex you're
probably would like to some module I
would get up
you needed a to get some modules are not
get some Marshall some
I've been burned by up on water twice
already ok arm
actual separate git repositories that
your core project if you
split something out into multiple get
repost transport some reason
and I that Model A and model be our
separate get repose
yet and how would you use build-out
actually check all that stuff out and
set up both
environments and partly because they
have overlapping requirements but not
completely overlapping requirements
well then I mean for
multiple project under the same and
application environment would probably
means you need
you need the same set so if you develop
like tree different module
who believe need the same virtual and
and everything so it's not different
let's say
it's not multiple literal and inside the
same application environments Chris but
you need the same requirements for all
those modules
but at least mister developer as an
extension lets you have comments 2
to all dole's then check out and
everything
under Dan the application environment
but it won't create different virtual
and for does different projects
actually that's actually good that's
exactly what I would want to duplicate
thank you okay
that's given make plays hand then
20 you way