okay
jackets on who and the mikes on
only have net
Jackson here that lovely Jackson
on stage and he's going to talk to us
about she mining peaceful back
I run how ya doing
so my name I talk is enough machine
learning to make Hacker News readable
again
yes that's a little snarky I'm sorry on
so what I want to talk about sort uva
focuses I'm
Russian introduce myself to tonight and
plug in my partner
which
I it's just me oh by the way the slider
up on my website in jail but US
arm I'm the jail on the twitters things
I can email me and jail in jail that US
two I don't know ask me questions or
yell at me or whatever
so what I do here is a simple achievable
project something that is machine
learning related by think
all this RK per beloved which is a
personalized filter for Hacker News
taking Hacker News inserting articles
into what are called rack
and not track and then you read the not
track
and you feel much better about the world
in general
I'm so the whole point my talk is
I can machine learning and you can too
%uh machine learning
bike has this crazy name it. feels like
artificial intelligence like the machine
is learning man
and that's a lot of intimidation there
is a wanna science involved there's a
lot of terminology
you spent a lot of time googling you
spend a lot of time reading Wikipedia
articles and
survey over easy stuff but the essence a
machine learning
is actually start approach Engineering
Center pro tools you can use
I'm machine learning is just applying
statistics the big piles of data
that's really all it is so we gave this
wonderful name
when you get down to it your building
statistical models
a bunch input data and you're using it
to understand that they do better
or to make predictions are to better or
two sort of go further with the data
so yeah this terminology but we're gonna
I'm gonna give you a bunch of it and
then try to such a list
so here's sort of the workflow when you
doing machine learning you have to get
the data
which usually not as easy as you think
need to engineer the data
which means that need to take this Messi
real world stuff that you
scraped off the Weber got outta some
database in turn into nice on umpire
arrays with a well-written you know with
well-formed values
and then you need to train and two in
the model this is the science part that
training tuning the model
but in at other people but libraries you
can just use their libraries is great
and then applying the mall to new data
once again you just use libraries
you talk to folks who do this for a
living we have doctor to spend a lot of
time working machine learning
they spend all their time getting the
date in engineering the data
they burn a lot of CPU cycles but not a
lot of time training in tuning models
and then you know just applying it is is
very straightforward
so I'll be talking mostly about psych it
learn
on the documentation for psych it learn
is fantastic I
a couple pippin stalls away from having
a fully functioning awesome machine
learning library sitting on your machine
I heart spars install installing I'm and
song side pipe
so you've got a tutorial user guides API
docs in this flow chart
this flow chart is one of the coolest
things ever so
the hard part with machine learning is
there's too much terminology there are
too many things you can do you
there too many options there are people
say oh you support vector machines for
everything in the probably right
burden who knows like maybe you're
trying to something else so what this
does
this chart gives you some steps you can
go through to figure out what you wanna
start googling
alright it's a it's really head straight
for you say
II goodwill less than fifty samples ok
nevermind
right and so you can step your way
through this flow chart try to figure
out what you'd
pry into your data and you can start
figuring out what part to psych it
learned you need to research more
I would you need to find a couple papers
on on that what's good papers the coming
to be in overview the field without
bogging you down too much and we don't
understand the math go blah blah blah
keep reading
my my advice so something that we hear a
lot about a machine learning and I think
it's worth talking about bringing up in
just making people aware of
is concept to supervise versus
unsupervised
the supervised learning is when you have
input data
and then there's some output value so
for me
this was the input data was a buncha
stuff I scraped off a hacker news
insights that link to Hacker News
now as the input data and output was is
this crap or not
right so a bullion value true or false
threw something on a read
false something I wish didn't exist
right and so
thats classification that supervised
learning where you go and you have a
buncha labels in
output values and you try to turn input
data
into those labels are output values
thats supervised learning
unsupervised learning is more about
understanding your data that would be
I have mmm you know
thousands a packer news articles can I E
visualize them somehow
can I group them by subjects and I don't
know how many subjects there are but
Mike
fine subjects in Group them just kinda
unsupervised
sort of trying to understand the data
will be better are water power to it one
interesting bits there
I'm but I'm gonna set that a cyclist
talk in a pretty much we talk about
supervised learning
there are water really accessible books
on the topic I'm national language
processing with Python programming
collective intelligence the O'Reilly
books
aren't directly dealing with the topic
this hawk
but they do a really good job getting
you thinking about dealing with big
powers have text
as data which is a kind like a little
bit over thing to stretch your mind
to say you know what its tax but I can
turn into numbers and how do I go about
trying to numbers
the books from packed up buildings human
existence the papon in learning socket
learn
are both really good books that step you
through step by step but it ended kinda
walk you through a little bit contrived
example psalm and kimchi a
hide you from local to the real world so
not but as a side by the socket learn
thing and some patterns and stuff you
can see over and over again as you're
reading psych it learn code
and things look out for be aware of so
first things first they love them some
parallel arrays
I'm X is the input so in my case this is
an array of dictionaries
with lots of random junk from Hacker
News why
is the value you're trying to get out so
X is the input data
in my case why would be a bully and true
I wanna read it
false I don't first thing you want to do
with machine learning
and this is this is one of those hard
hard-won things that the
community is finally come to you is you
want to set aside
what's called the validation set you're
trying to train the computer to notice
patterns in to pick up on things on data
it has never seen before
right so it would be trivial to write
something which
saved all the input does it saw exactly
and then spit out the output values
again when it saw the same input values
it would look like it was perfect
it's a hit book I put it in a contrite
out Borchard curious about what you
wanna learn about
is new weird different interesting stuff
your machine hasn't seen it all
so what the idea validation said is is
you take about 25 percent your data
any serious I totally you know how to
touch it you know I'd like to look at it
at the very and you're done with
everything and use the validation set
to figure out if you did a good enough
job earn
for me I mark them on the database and
then when I was pulling in messing with
the data
my validation set didn't show up at all
and finally the end I is the
validation set to figure out how good my
results were
so how do you work what do you do you
you're gonna build pipelines
two sequences are things that operate on
data you're gonna optimize parameters
you're gonna be tweaking how these
things are operating on a date
pipeline just a sequence of operations
that's all it is
on they are this amazing wonderful thing
that allows you to
I'm put together a bunch of potentially
really complex steps
and then optimize this entire series a
complex steps
to get the best possible results so what
I have right here
universe and how it incurred up I'm just
importing the pipeline
I'm getting a this text package and a
linear support vector classifier
I'm so I create the pipeline I just give
each one of them a name
and basically this will take input blobs
have text in turn them into nice
numerical number I raise
in this will attempt to learn from that
input.text
missus you know very straightforward and
thats an almost complete
reasonable way first step to understand
some tax them to make some predictions
about text
really need but there's these things
called hyper parameters
so there are amazing amounts wonderful
Twi couple little
bits have math going on inside all these
these
gigantic statistical methods and
if you look you like oh there's this
thing called see Nick I wanna said to
some power
to when whatever you google that you
figured out you get some vague idea
what's going on
and then use these things called up well
they got a couple different kinds a
way to do this but the grid searches
amazing so you basically say
there are I don't know for different
values for see that seem reasonable
as two different guys for the loss
function I wanna try to different values
for the n-gram thing
and then the grid search I set the
number jobs -1 which means use
all my CPU's I put for both sequels to
which means print a lot of stuff the
output so that I feel like things are
happening
on and then I look at eight stop in all
of my all my CP is are pegged red
I'm the fans go on ages
crunches I actually had one that took
four hours cuz I was doing
multiple pipelines in parallel in just
testing all are trying to find the best
one
see just tryout all these possible
combinations in it finds out which one
is best at predicting your data for you
it does cross-validation always I think
for you behind the scenes
but you just try a buncha values it
tries all the values it right all the
combinations
and will spit out an object to the end
that is the most effective and efficient
and and accurate
I trained model very straightforward
that fit function is something you can
see a lot of
the three functions a particular
interesting I'm
transform unfit are both ones you might
have to write yourself and predict
is where be awesome statistics people
have done the magic for you
that's that's where the the sciences in
predicts and fits
so this is the transform are hashing the
treasury's we saw a little bit earlier
to turn
blobs have text into nice or raise
so all this one does though I through in
two parts by import this
and it turns it into a sparse matrix
floats with ten-story
elements are just takes this text is
read text and actually
for each column is a word not precisely
because enough each column is a word
each row
is a some input.text and we'll set those
values based on a simple text
really really handy way to turn text
into
something you can operate on it it was
numbers I'm the next step is
fit so this is this is where the magic
happens
I think that's that's the line so I'm
right here you say hey here's a bunch
input data and here's what the results
should be for that
right result should be that with the
output data should be is this why
it matches up the X&Y does a lot of math
and statistics
and it figures out what the value you
know it it figures out what it needs to
store internally or a bill to make
predictions in the future
predictions in the futures is predicting
you pass an array of things to make
predictions on
it spits out an array of gases
basically based report so
that's kinda it like that's that's the
real essence service there's
what server engineering though the real
world messy scary
I you gotta get the data right I'm how'd
you get the data
question Alexa now so I got a is
something that
scrapes the front two pages the Hacker
News every 45 minutes
personnel XML I pull out the links I
crawl the links if I haven't seen them
before
and I just basically go through and try
to grab all the data possible that I can
from
from Hacker News so I have this raw data
but what I need to know
is a need to know what's good and what's
not good I'm so I wrote myself a web app
I Mike the classified reckon on track
you can see the big red buttons for bad
the cacophony slide
on and so the course about six weeks I
think
I classified a five thousand articles
and found about 20 percent of them were
things I was going to read
I it was it was pretty epic for a while
there
I am I i came up with lotsa tricks to
make this faster so I controlled F
for quien I am or NSA
a or San Francisco or a bunch of other
things in
and just try to get rid of world news
and
business hacks and I'm stuff I salaried
and so i win and this is all my opinion
I'm so anyway I go through when I click
bad bad bad bad bad
on this bring the pain buttonwood show
me site after site an iframe with big
buttons at the top for good and bad
so there was a period there where I read
everything that made the front two pages
a packer news
almost I'm so yeah this was that
this was the hard part right this was
actually the hardest most involve part
entire thing was getting this data
that I could then feed into my models so
what they did I have had
the the title that was made with I had a
title for changed
I had the URL who similar it what was
there
arm how would smacks rank was how many
boats Academy comment
time a day and most importantly in most
painfully arrived at
whether I found to be directly or not so
we turn this message data into
normalized happy healthy fine
numb hi-res I'm there's a lot of
techniques for turning
words into numbers and I kinda wanna
give a
brief overview some items that you've
seen them once again you know what a
Google
up first up backwards so we have no the
phrase time flies like an arrow fruit
flies like bananas
arm and this is an incredibly
grammatically correct a grammatically
complicated in deep freights right like
flies
is a verb in one and its ones'
Island simply on at this is this is hard
for human being to fully parts right
I'm so forget grammar who needs it
we're gonna treat these words if they
were just a bag-of-words and say oh
flies like time in a row for bananas
good they're on their maybe some some
techniques account I'm summits bullying
you say whether the word is they're not
arm and also implicitly this doesn't
mention pat Quinn
I'm so pick 10 so we just can't
counterparts they're treated like
tobacco words
in just totally ignore this grammar
stuff grammer's hard
so if you wanna hinted the grammar
though there's this thing called n-grams
because talk about 10 grams immune grams
by grams and try grams and I don't know
what
would be quite grams are enough people
say four grams so so you just get
chunks words and you think these chunks
of words as if they were themselves
words
so instead of time flies being two words
you think it is
time flies you think a flies like and
you
look at just pairs of words are groups
of three or four however much input data
you have and how much memory you're
willing to burn
and he's kinda start building this
higher level understanding
love a bit that includes just that
little him to the grammar
does it is consequent normalization so
there's you sometimes hear stemming
limit is Asian
I'm and stemming is generally a hack
unlimited station is looking up in a
dictionary
I'm this is a really interesting thing
so there's this
thing called the snowball stammer and in
NLT K which is the national language
toolkit has lotsa fun things to play
with texting
and he grabbed a stammer and feed it
just
english-language taxed it tries to
normalize it so
does it really matter if you safe wiser
fly later flying
your anyone about other couple different
parts of speech it doesn't really matter
they're all kinda the same thing
so when he fly he like to fly up on
early flight searches
normalizes the words so that it kinda
hides a little bit have
10 scissor PLO roe versus singular he
does a great job
and finally there's this concept called
%uh stop words out
up final one its cuz I'll stop words in
the idea would stop words is
their words which are just useless they
don't give you any information about
what's actually going on
if you know that in our that a a article
the 20 from Hacker News
uses the word la but doesn't give you
any additional information
right who cares alright its it's just
its for the fluff that we use in normal
English grammar to glue stuff together
there's a set up stop words for English
that are included in Psych it learn
and I'm you can just send an option on a
bunch different things to
ignore stop words which can be you know
pretty pretty big boost
I'm this is this is the last thing here
term frequency inverse document
frequency so the idea is
if you have a word like bitcoins
in bitcoins shows up twelve times in
this article
wears on average it only shows up one in
every four articles
this article is clearly verily strongly
about pat Quinn has much more big point
in it
than any other article so let's give the
word
idk wine a little bit of a boost
and you let's give the word becoming a
little bit of a boost here
are told to kind have you know
get rid of it so other stuff here about
engineering features
so this is some some code I i've
actually used in my
my temps here so we can pull a relevant
tax
there's something called readability and
readability are
LX a male is a python re implementation
this browser plugin
tries to get rid of all the junk around
the outside a web page
so recommended links that you know a
menu at the top
ads also have other stuff that don't
directly relate to the main content to
the article
try to pull them all out with your
sticks and so with really believe that's
now
I take it I grab that summary
I parse the thing with LX email again I
try to pull out all the text and then I
returned the text
so I'm cleaning out all the HTML tags
and cleaning out everything I'm trying
to get
just two what is the relevant actual
real text
for this particular from for this
particular
each email page right
because a roll-your-own features so I
had a theory that I liked long-form
content
so what this does is our right here in
the transform function
it takes array of text and
just count how long each one is ever
turns their back as a nice two
dimensional array
and so you free texting you get back out
numbers between I don't know 0 and
probably tens of thousands
I'm all these things want the numbers to
be like centered on 0
and usually like standard deviation to
either side 12 -1
and the standard scale earthing which is
outta the box
takes these written random crazy link
numbers in centers than 10
and makes them a nice little even
distribution around zero
so I could any have this additional
feature that I created from scratch
where I kinda inferred something from
that source material
that wasn't immediately obvious in it
like
I'm you can also combine features with
this thing called feature Union
and basically what this does is this
takes art to
numb high res and kinda concatenate
someone sticks right next to each other
so that you can feed in multiple signals
am sticking together with this feature
Union
and you also notice I stuck this link
pipeline in as if it were
yet another thing so I I have like
pipeline since I pipelines as I
pipelines
I'm to sort of massage together
different features that then get exposed
all the way up
but my data starts his dictionary so i'm
just points out among the database
because I'm lazy
and this little thing here's a
transformer
that will poll values out over
dictionary and return those values
the way I use this as I get this idea
that maybe host names are relevant
right there are places that seem to pose
good content as places that post awful
content
and that should be a signal that might
should go into this machine learning
that right
so what I do is I arm use URL parse the
whole out the hostname for URL
and then I just returned that and then I
build a pipeline
once again about the pipeline so I feed
this in the raw manga results from my
database
extracts the URL from that and turns it
into an array of strings I then
extracted the hostname
from that URL and I pass it through this
defect arises thing
which then turns it into a nice
numerical number iraq which is pretty
much always the goal is to turn into
this nice little numb pirate
so what is the actual application look
like how you actually use the stuff to
do new protections you do this
I'm sorry Alex a anyway I'm
say savior save your input data so you
can recreate it later
I know if production systems which can
not be upgraded
on penalty of death because there's some
pickle from like
seven years ago that we can recreate and
like don't touch it
right so anyway keeper sample keepers or
status you can recreate it
but you just take that thing you pick
like mine is I think it's like
Jeezy up to the pickle at that the
predictions is like five mags and I've
got a chance will script that pulls it
down from s3 in frozen in the right
place
on the news passenger input data in the
same format that it got
the input data when your training it and
it magically works
I'm so I built this thing and
is a bunch different colors a mosam have
to do with what date I can grab
but read basically mean stuff it things
I shouldn't read
in green is stuff I think it should read
and I put up at each end up in jail that
US and I
like this morning when I hope I promise
to return cash in on for that
Soho pleated that right and if you have
all this data
right so you can build a staff to sort
stuff but he had anything to us both
things
so much unsupervised learning I'm can
you look at it
and figure out other other interesting
things I can do here or there other
is there tight cluster it like I said
can I find clusters
arm maybe could predict articles course
I
which would then be really interesting
combine with something that watching RSS
feed
and maybe are submitted I'm just saying
I am
and the real point I talked the thing i
really wanna stresses that machine
learning
is becoming engineering this is starting
to move out the Rangers
science where nobody really understands
what it does and you have to read a
million articles
and get a doctor in the stuff in to be
able to actually apply to the real world
there are libras out there that you can
use that you can start to understand the
properties up
you know twenty years ago if you want to
use a red-black tree pretty much had to
read it yourself
right and now we just accept that these
fancy things are in libraries and I
think machine learning is going the same
way
these are gonna be awesome statistical
techniques you need to know about
characteristics of
but they're gonna be libraries they are
in library thing you just go use 'em so
go use a min do interesting things I'm
thank you
she
thank you for talking to me a valid for
Q&A four minutes for Q&A
we have any questions we we don't have
the Mac power
a go-ahead II seige talk about smoking
area in
that when I was getting data that I look
at a search engine
are yet no that was
that was older that I i've I did this I
did this
I'm I think it is a couple months before
the new search engine
I'm yes I look at that I i you know
frankly I just need to grab to
essentially static web pages every five
minutes
arm I wasn't really interested in doing
in dept mining the data
there was enough scary danger in it
dangerousness
in crawling random URL's of a pattern is
applying them a database to keep me
occupied
your questions yes over there could
yeah if we could try to get line for the
mic is working now
yeah awesome I feel like I should just
had to shut your question running
airline
so
so he's whining about my accuracy with
the features I picked I found a fancy I
got
the worst my accuracy got I it's around
ninety percent accurate
and all the failures except for one I
cuz I i look to each one cuz I was going
on
so it's ninety percent accurate which
I'm proud of because anybody can get
eighty percent
are campus but it's not over that
accurate in all the failures are things
that
things I shouldn't read that a marked as
I would read
and I went back and looked at them and
they were usually things where
I said oh I would like to read the first
article about the NSA
I'm and then the rest to them I was like
new
are no I'm done now so a lot of my
failures were things I
marked as readable and then change my
mind your questions
I get we do have a mic we should
probably be lining up for
right lap ride some way back there
yes so on
so basically you do something called
cross for validation where you
i holed out a portion of your data as if
it's you know
cross-validation in you train the other
80 percent and then you see how it's
good
is a particular 20 percent and so you
try bunch a different methods
and you try and i actually built this
thing that put like many pipelines in
parallel
and then optimized everyone in these
pipelines and then pick the best
pipeline and spit out what that was for
me and then retrieve the data so that my
pickle was only
25 megabytes rock instead of like 500
megabytes rock
so you can you can you just
try out all the options like this all
the switches and you just flipped all
the switches
and you have to keep your foot all the
switches for you and next thing you know
you know your laptop is very very hot
and you have something that can
predictive hacker news articles a
crapper not
amazing yes question so cute rain as you
use
your countries use it yeah I just this
whole thing about
you know feedback loops and I'm taking a
model and updating the model
on there's lots love complicated stuff
there that I'm happy to say is sorted
starts being out of my realm love real
understanding but I do have some stuff
in place where I go through every once
in a while
and I will flag a bunch articles as this
one is bad this one is good
and I will use the fact that it's
already been sorted for me too kindly
help me go through them faster
I'm there are techniques for like you
know
updating your model and stuff but
frankly I'm scared them
yes said the yep
would be the minimum number actually so
I did five thousand articles what would
be the minimum number of articles we'll
do this sort of thing
art that's a good question arm you know
if you look at the National flow chart
is owed you at least 50 things okay then
you can start doing stuff
but the real sort of weird thing that
the way this works is you want your
number samples
and see what kind of the number rose to
beam
to be much more then the number of
columns
I think we're done you want the number
for us both to be more than the number
of columns
and so if your gonna be feeding in text
which
by nature having all these different
words gonna have been many different
columns
you can you need to have a lot of
perot's right
so 5,000 may not be enough
but again who knows maybe 1000 work
and anybody else alright thank you very
much everyone really preach