good morning everybody I'm our first
argument
is developing flask extensions by Rachel
Sanders
she's over it LinkedIn is an organizer
pilot season 7 disco so please give a
warm welcome
a body I want to apologize in advance
for my voice I have caught the confluent
like a couple days early
so I will try my best not to sneeze and
ethanol love you but other
thank you for giving warnings out there
we go %uh anyway welcome thank you so
much for coming
welcome to developing last extensions um
before we get started a little bit about
me I am a pie ladies in this coordinator
organizer and powder and what about
doing that I'm an engineer and technical
lead at LinkedIn
and at LinkedIn I code in Python all day
every day and that's because LinkedIn's
internal stack
is iPod I thought and flaps that to be
specific
this so this talk came into something I
did it work for my team I needed to
write an extension for them
and I really struggled with getting
something reasonable together because
there's not a lot of documentation up
there on reading extension and doing
this kind of work
so it turns out that flask is designed
to be expanded and
actually I think very very
straightforward and so
that's my goal at this talk for you all
the walk out of here thinking that
extension development is just is
straightforward and easy as I think it
is
ok soloing talk about a
we're gonna do it really really quick
introduction a for
those of you who haven't worked with
laughter aren't familiar with it
I promise it'll be very quick it'll be
like two minutes long
and we'll talk about what it means to
extend flask over to spend most of the
talk
on a case study on this extension that I
wrote cell
and we'll talk about how it works and
the implementation a bit it's a very
simple extension
it was like a hundred like the cone I've
connected down to quite a bit
so what we see that very basic extension
we're gonna talk about
where you can go from there for
nontrivial examples for non you know
I kind of think so will go through a
case study in other a
extensions that are good to learn from I
think and buy me when the questions
okay so I thought of a number of ways to
do an introduction to this
and the best way I could come up with
with just to show you a working-class
complication
this is a working-class complication
if you pick install flask and run this
in a file
what you'll get is adept server running
on port 5000 that
with you load local host 5,000 in your
browser
what you get is the word hello Cindy
hyping it there
and okay so if you're coming from like
the Django or rails world
you look at this and go that's great
nice
hello world function okay with the rest
a bit
where's where's my database where are my
forms where's my admin interface and
left doesn't have any of the it is a
micro framework
and this is pretty much what you get you
get
route you get controllers its ships with
the temple dealing with ginger
and has some session cookie stuff but
what you see in the slightest pretty
much what you get
and actually on purpose because the idea
a flask is to build a good foundation
for all applications
everything else is up to you or
extensions missus Armin
who is the creator a flask laugh
is at heart toolkit use it to build HTTP
things and the core library is purposely
kept very small and focus to be
good at doing that and that means that
most the stuff you need at the
day-to-day application developer
is all in the extension go system so
learning how to read extensions is a key
part
a learning how to write flask ok
so let's talk about what it means to
extend lasso
this is the same hello san dimas hi
application
and the slide what really but what
requiring
after min ago but if you look at like 3
that Apple's law school it actually
doing a whole lot
so it may use a a method on a call route
to map the route URL
to that hello function and I don't know
if you've ever had to do anything I
programming which
I had to do back in my battle pearl days
but those three lines of code art
a lighting over a hi love magic or doing
inbound routing at we have some string
that we're somehow
translating into I can ATT be
responsible for the lot of stuff going
on there
and in the last one we're actually
taking off an entire dev
test server so the takeaway is ap
is at the heart a flat but app magic app
update with him in a college
is that is where all the functionally
what flask is
so it is the core and when we talk about
extending flask
what we're really talking about is
changing that ap object and modifying it
like I said flask is designed to be
extended and you can change the ap
object
in like lots of ways you can say pay
when a request comes in let me have it
first so that I can look at it
send mail response by what to or
after the application is done looking at
it let me have it before goes out the
door so I can do
at cookies I can rewrite the response
whatever I'm I can also give my end user
developers
more resources I can point apt to wear
other things are like
I can't tell it where other filters
aren't things I can extend ginger for
them
I can programmatically adding routes
blueprints
with her last way up organizing code
at our assets and things like that I'm
I can wrap the app in middleware and i
cant even local pageant we will see an
example that lead in the talk
okay that is also super super super
dinner so
look at a real real example here I'm
okay so I'm a team lead for a small
kinda internal workflow we believe kinda
cool cooking
and we wanted to move to continue with
integration weird playing every two
weeks we want to play every day or every
other day
so knowing if the bad wrong idea the
main site the mailing confided you all
the news have had this for days and it's
like
we are internal and we are sort of in
our own a little bit and
we girlfriends we all try to make sure
all work in the same direction but
sometimes
by looking to go out this way the other
2012 the company or any other way
we try to be consistent but sometimes
were we're a little bit different so it
felt like I'm talking about a
twelve-person company is head over 5,000
wanna at like so
it up anyway so we needed a way when you
move to continues in Gration
we needed a way to be able to commit and
deploy code that was not ready for users
to see
so up I wrote an extension to do that I
Road extension to turn parts of the app
are of
based on configuration I did not make up
the idiom it's called feature flagging
therefore last feature flags
so the actual extension that you can get
on pie PI
and Gallatin get home a is about a
hundred lines of code
and I could not fit that applied so
instead I have shrunk it down to about
and 15 baby will f wines and I've done
that by
cutting out all the functionality all
the air handling all the paranoia and
anything I would want an actual
production library so
don't judge a book by its heavily edited
Reader's Digest version
now anyway okay so
what do I do with our talk about you
with extension from the end user's point
of view
so if you were to download the fitness
expansion and use it
let's talk about how that would work
first and then we'll go into the
implementation details of it
quick services are all friendly hello
sandy was high application
I've cut out the demo test server for
space reason
okay so extensions are just modules
like models like anything else so you
import them import
last ext features like as future left
give you this little
indirection thing so the name and
extension actually of
underscore Peter flag but I think this
is the support a way of doing it
and I'm importing it alias to feature
because I can't say the other
so I take that and then I instantiate an
object called
feature flag and I feed at that magic ap
object
so from the end user's point of view
this is all they have to do to configure
this
that it and now they can start using it
okay the second thing I wanna have if
the module level
function called is active it has one
argument
which is the string that the name in the
future features are just rings
and it supposed to return true the
pictures on or
Paul the features of so you run this
if feature is active icon well pack
enough
below seventeen hi if you run this what
you actually get a hello sandy with high
because
I haven't actually find any pictures yet
sup
let's talk about how we would do that so
in vanilla flask there's really only one
place
to store configuration like that and
it's called
in the ap dot config on that magic ap
objectors
a property called big which is mostly
like a dictionary
and its stores config key names and
values
so we're gonna call are configured up
feature flags
and itself will be a dictionary so the
names of our
the name of the key he's are going to be
the name for the feature
and the valuable be bullying true the
features on
also the features of so this is how you
would turn a feature on
app.config feature flags will feature
true I run this I will get hello i cud
okay so this is great for the pipeline
like that the app developers like me but
I want my pride and
developers in my web dev to be able to
use this in the general area as well
and to do that I'm gonna use a and thing
a ginger called
template test and this is what a
template test looks like
if Pike on is active feature hi Pike on
else
hello sending hi active feature
is the name on the template s and it
it's like a function
it will get hike on as an argument and
it's a poster turn true
the features on or false future law
basically identical to the is active
thing we just it
over to put on our our project manager
had for a second writes back
there's only really three things are
gonna do one for us for the future
flights in the config
restore be Jim the rest have agenda
template s called
actor feature and a lot of ocean called
is active so I switched left to
the order left you for a reason to think
ok
look at going back in season actual code
here a fair warning there the giant wala
ko coming up
I no giant wall coating hard to read for
those are you back in the cheap seats
but
I will do my best to talk through it and
but if you have a laptop
feel free to open it to be at least last
giant wall ok
code which is the link to a gist about
everything I'm not talk about
so and if you have that feel free to
open it and look at pics the cattle fed
up
10 up so badly left I all code
after neighbors regret
ok so I remember lee said that
flat extensions are involves a changing
that app object
so we need a callable extensions are
just call ables
they can be functions they can be object
in practice there almost always object
because they're all always like to be
also ours is going to be an object to
this is class
feature flag and hear from object
so like all objects and had a double
underscored method and a Wii
allow the user to pass that magic up ap
object to a
but if you notice we're actually making
optional
and the and do something kinda weird
we're going to
if we get ap pass to us we're really
gonna pass the buck
over to another method called it ap
which is
not optional ap okay so what why are we
doing this
this is to support something called
application factories
which is a really really common laugh
idiom I will use it what did you do
number
things us with the function or something
that generate that ap object for you
up the reason why I'm splitting these
two things is I want my expansion to be
able to be instantiated
one without having that ap active yet
a application factors are used for
things like testing so we may have many
APs being generated
and I want to be able to feed them to
that extent without having to create
destroy
every single time so armen actually the
crater floor
actually suggests this is how you
structure your that's not why one show
it to you
so inlet is all in your pension level
and sensation
and in it ap is all the changes you're
making to the ap
utmost extensions of see out in the wild
are structured like this
but that's why one show it to you okay
it's look actually writes all real code
and not wanna play
%uh the first thing you want to do what
store are features in the conflict
so I said the Configure mostly a
dictionary and hear the case worth not
so that's that app.config set default
because we're all professional
developers in with that thing
default or out so are default for our
feature clyde is going to be just an
empty dictionary
so that's already or so if you remember
a couple flight back
I sorta barely did ap configure feature
flags
iconic was true and i cant usually do
that in Python
I to let you make a key in a subkey
without throwing a key air
think and so that's why I could do that
is because I set a default
here effort to make our lives easier
we're gonna write a method
called Inc in Fig which takes one
argument which is the feature name:
okay so if you you noticed I'm not
actually story in the app
anywhere in extension there is no
self-taught Apple ap
and that is on purpose I want the fifth
engine to not
know how that fade within I want the app
to contain all the state all the things
like this so
up after the application factor that
other things like that
so yeah so I am but to in order to get I
need to get the app break they need
to getting that can fit a and so
I'm gonna use an ATM a flash flood saves
me here
by having something called current ap
up her after the global when an
applicant cation kinda livor
if the request is live of the last steps
her apt to be whatever magic ap object
is currently running and currently
controlling that request so
that's how I can get to it here so here
I miss a Apple
with her abductor Fig features like to
look for my
in Fig the theater features there that
is overturn a billion
and if it's not waterfalls
okay what dot in a temple test
just to remind you what that looks like
like this if hike on
is active feature hi Pike on else hello
sandy with high
so it turns out we can add a template s2
ginger in
aren't just last in one line of code
there's a whole
API for flask in this is one at the
hopes that it has
it looks like this appetite ad template
test
has two arguments one is a function
reference we wanted to call so we'll
callin configure I the release tension
at a much later will have to invest but
whatever it's fine for now Inc big and
be named the second one is the name what
we want to use an agenda where
so active feature %uh okay
so I did this I committed it and all I
love my Travis CI build went red
and I was like huh weird
so I look at the API lol up
a right weird I can't wait to meet your
problem here
yeah a noon burdened and I was running
version 8
this is something I want to talk about
eg application developers you deal with
one
version a flask Extension developers you
deal with as many as you care to support
and so you'll be doing this a lot a
plaque was under rapid development and
has
and dot can specifically rewrote love
you got adding a lot of nice things to
do this kind of stuff so it it's great
what you have to be really careful so
what I end up having to do is actually
do with has adderall
up and check for that API call
and cuz that's the standard going
forward I want to use that going forward
but if it's not there then I need to
fall back to editing
basically dictionaries directly I will
say that trap CIA is amazing for stuff
like this
and if you're curious you can look at
the gate hub offer Mike privacy i cant
bigan
and see how I did it I can test every
version up I thought I support
every version of last I support and it
all works great
ok able to done the last one is the is
active module level function
so just remind you what that looks like
if feature
is active hi Kat okay so
this is gonna be a little confusing II
hope it was clear
what I'm doing is not as important as
how I'm doing it P
be a little example many you with a
little bit contrived but
I wanted to show you part of this whole
thing so
I see things like ok this is the module
level function
it is not extension object we created
earlier
if you notice online five-week throw it
away basically
it doesn't have the model function is
active hadn't no idea where that is
how to get to it but I need it to be
able to call it
in config method so you might look this
lingo
wanna wanna see in like pass it to the
the inactive function or something at
just rose
I mean it it work here but like if I had
multiple files
I have a sec importing things like its
circular important gross
up so but why do have I can get to the
current
up we RTC something in there already
so the short version as we can save
ourselves in the current
in the app so all that wasn't clear at
all
this is the takeaway part so this is
what I want to show you
flask at the special registry for
expects tension it call
app that expansion be key is the name
here
attention and you can store anything you
like it here
in this case I miss the store myself I'm
so go along with the ride for the app
you might say well women I thought we
didn't wanna hope those two up together
right
I don't let's say the ap with be
extension because I want the extension
to be able to run any app again
yet you know makefield you can she wants
and run it
but the app is the heart we are ready
modify or are you doing things to it so
it's okayed for
for the extension arrival all the app
but that's what we're gonna do
and that means writing that modulo
function is super easy
actually while I would have split here
and to just for readability
a the sources feature clutter
I look in the current app that's why the
the global I can get to it
i lookin its extension registry for our
stuff
and that's myself was just sitting there
like all the income big
like anything else so all we do
all right we're done we have for
thinking they can big
we have a template test and we have that
is active culture
I some right what did we learn we
learned
use in it app because application
factors
we learn how to set config the fall we
learned about calling
flask books with that ad template test
and we also learned that dot 10 in the
trap and we have to be careful about
what
you know what things are available and
we also learn how to use the stench
registry
to get to work session later okay
so I hope you're all saying how old to
develop its so easy so straightforward
great I why I never done this before and
then
wait a minute my use cases way less
trivial
I have the database I have other stuff I
need to do
cell so there's not a lot documentation
on this out there
I wanna show you sorta sampler
extensions that I think are good
and that are going to want to learn from
and came from
the first one i wanna talk about
developed of debug toolbar
it's a great example a highly complex
extension I was really written by
Michael been telling Jim I hope I have
his name right
and it's currently maintain my map good
who I work with at LinkedIn
it is a port love the Django debug
toolbar so
in your flask ap what you'll get at the
sidebar with a whole bunch of candles to
it
it shows you HT to be a her that her
active
I what temple surrendered variables are
powerful templates
and I'll show you Squaw Peak Way reason
is from logging and things like that
%uh it's a little hard to read but and
I'm this is that
screenshot of %uh get help basically so
I'll any I've given you know other
context
but I think this is actually pretty
readable I think if you look at the
flight later but
it to the top line says in it apt with
using that same split as we are the
sauce with in it ap
and in the first two lines are iterating
for some things in it
setting app.config set default with just
setting the app default
a check a couple configs for paranoid
purposes and then the middle says
debug toolbar load panels ap actually
happen the app to stop extension so
it can do or configuration and the rest
is just calling template just calling a
hoax
app before request call me whenever
starts at after quest
call this method will nap ends when
there were questions
%uh cared a request for the lot the the
one over there ap
this Patrick with actually monkey
patching the dispatcher request
to be able to Tim to view that it is
handle that you and do other things like
that lucky monkey patching itself that
and the last two lines are just adding a
you all routes
and blueprint so we can do CSS and
JavaScript and things like that
so other great extensions up blast
ceaser a is a CSRF protection library
and so it's a great one to look at if
you're doing request processing
are handling cookies that does things
like that I love it does a lot of her
stuff
left admin of love admin is kinda
Belcourt
the flaps gathered django admin
interface
immigrate to seek a welcoming has
blueprint a static file for the lot of
things like that
another one could want to look at it had
no I think a slightly different
approach so using sick walkman of debug
toolbar so you can kind of compare and
contrast between the two
and then finally after class classy with
I love I love this extension
add class-based you so I you can have an
object with a
get posts put delete methods
that will map those HTTP methods
directly to those things you can create
an API really really easily
and its pretty fantastic for that
%uh okay with that I am I'm done so
thank you so much for watching you need
who I'll reach me I am I am here to
thank you so much
idk of what alright I we have five
minutes for questions %uh
anybody would like to pick my brain up
to the microphone and I will try to
remember turkey your question
what I've been told par-5
and you also want to thank you
can you give me a sense over within
within LinkedIn how much do you use
extensions
versus blueprints for your own code
rather things that are increased
externally
it really depends a so my
I'll my team is very workflow have a so
we have a very very big and very work
winner
I V kinda things we used blueprint
extensively
and we use we build our own mentioned
extensively I'm
have a couple that we've dined in terms
and
the other thing so flask is Python a
general use for tooling and trolled
I'm in architecture and other stuff like
that as well collapse so
mostly blueprint the proper use more we
do have a few extensions like that
I pried open source on the ones we have
so it's her depend on you skate you have
such a wide
Rangers thought that's why we use flask
weaknesses it so flexible
that answer question okay I can't think
too much