good afternoon everyone welcome back
after lunch
as the first the afternoon sessions
we're gonna be listening to any girl
giving us a talk about doing RESTful web
services with flask
thank you
thank you for coming up
so before I start case you
but no me it's a little bit of
background information myself
but two years ago I E R Rob my blog
engine in flask from scratch and then
up in these two years I
her a few articles on it a flask
you may have heard about dr. make a
tutorial
or maybe did did for so
articles make the ice I wrote up
I have a a bunch of extensions also for
flask
on December 5 that I amount most proud
of
so feel free to check them out and a
last but not least I wrote be alright
people
on flask which up it's going to be in
bookstores
reason so
up another preliminary slide up
all the stuff that i'm gonna show today
exists
in it get her project it'll
working code that runs up bookmark
that address and a after after the talk
if you're interested you
welcome to play with the API domina
percent here
up they are a very detailed instructions
in the relief I'll
so even if you are a beginner you should
be able to run this
now
for week for the those of you that
have no idea what flask s this is the
only begin to slide I have
up this is basically 279
hello world from the flask official
documentation
up the first two lines create an
application
the bottom two lines run it the middle
stuff
it's where important things go on and
its BC theres
pursue decorated function up at the
route tells flask that the French the
follows
is the handler for their root URL that
you can see
progressive slash so
flask knows that when a client requests
the root URL it needs to call this
function and and then a collects
the return value of the function and
sense that to the client if the response
and if you understand this I think you
understand most a foot flask is
because it doesn't have much more than
this okay
if you run this as a script on
are you on your server then you connect
with a web browser and you will see for
the world you're a
your browser window that said so OK
so let's start with the good stuff up
Press late the ice so
I'm gonna show the few basic
up API methods and how I implement them
on not that they say how I
implement them it's not the only way
flask it's all about freedom and choice
so anything you don't like about how I
do things you should improve it
and let me know so I learned to up
so okay for this example
I'm I have a up system that keeps track
of students in classes and students
register two classes
so that that's not something that i'm
gonna up politically know the examples
so I have a
up around that gets the list to students
this is a GET request
might URL slashed you can slash
I want to hear to end in slash this is
optional but I
want to look like a folder because it
returns collection
so
how implement this let let's look at it
the 19
in this function from the right up for
to follow I
topped my database and and for this I'm
using flasks equal alchemy
again that's my preference you can use
whatever you want
but using Flash sequel Oconee I get all
my students
and then hi I for each student
I get I asked the student to give me its
URL
so that I ends up being a list of URL's
I put that in a dictionary with key name
URL's
and then that pictionary gets Jason a
fight this is it
a flask helper function that converts
a dictionary to Jason for my as a string
and then that's a response
that's what the client gets list a few
rounds
so the client knows only a few top-level
URL see knows how to get the list of
students
outlook get the list of our classes and
so on but
it doesn't know much more than that but
now are
the client asked for the list students
and now
it's got few new URL studied in know
about before
so single student can be a pain
with now with this prop
and for this one since I I need to have
a unique URL per student
I have a dynamic component in my
route which you can see with the
angle brackets so I say that my URL for
student is slash students slash and then
the numeric eighty
this is my primary key made a difference
and that that is my choice
I I chose to do it this way
and the I say that this is gonna be
804 get like like the previous one
and implementation is very simple I
stopped my database
to get student from the 80 which of
last night lease end as an argument my
function
and a if the ID turns out to be invalid
flasks equal Oconee will send to 404
back to the client I don't need to worry
about that
and this is it think I'm going every
people are in this session
up my routes are a very clean
I try not to do I'll you don't see any
error checks
that that really make the cold camp
you know dirty so I net lower-level Co
handle my
evers I don't do here so
if s it's a sign that means that the
student exists
and its known and then on the next line
I I killed a student which is you know
one of my database models
to convert self to Jay some and
that returns it by conditioning which
then gets
Jason fight and now decline house
the student
so in some cases
collections are no not global
collections of things
are specific elections that apply to up
single resources an example that will be
the list of classes
student is taking so
for that you build a URL that Hasse the
uniqueness
since I need to include my student ID
but also need to make sure
it looks like a collection because
that's what it's so I
append a final component that
tells me that this is a collection
registrations and i ended with Slash
so up implementation is job also very
simple
pretty similar to the big collection of
students that we did before
I differences that I get my collection
from
every lationship my database so up I
have my student
and then I I say s top registrations and
that that's a wire to be
their relationship my database and then
from that I get the URL's
in 20 list and that list gets into the
dictionary of your else
and that gets church on if i and of it
goes to the client
so this is a POST request are restful
principles
say that when you need to create a
request the client needs to send
the request a supposed to the collection
URL so that goes to students generic
URL and the way to do this is I create
an empty student
and then I call another method to have
been there from Jason
this is the reverse of the to chase and
action before
so this guy takes the Jason from flask
flask its me that
in request Jason
that that comes in the form of a python
dictionary and and then
the student imports itself from that
dictionary
then I ready to the database those are
the two life follow
with session that that's how you write
something with flasks equal Oconee
and then I need to return a response and
the response needs to be
cold 2001 that means that the resource
was created
I'm successful I have anything to hurt
on site
I just Jason if I an empty dictionary
I said this does go to 2001 and then I
get the client
the URL of the resource in a location
pair
and now decline has this new era and it
can work with it
so last two are kind of
every catcher for we've seen so far this
is to update
resource in this case descended our
clients and to put request
and it sends the the fields at the CNN
on
ask a sign in the request and what I do
here is how I love my student
I call from Jason to update
its problems right back to the database
and
I return an anti response because
there's nothing to say it worked
and this is the case which which is even
simpler
I which load my student hiked elf sq
sequel Oconee to delete it and under
so let's look at you know all these
helper methods
that up and using to to make my
routes very beautiful
not so at the top you can see get URL
I'm not her coding might URL's that's
that's bad
flask knows what all the URL see my APR
so I can tell flask to generate the URL
for me
and for that I give it the name of the
function that handles that URL
which is get student and I get any and
arguments that the UN means and I
request that
the URL be external that means that I
want
the the scheme and the hostname all of
that in the URL
it'd you know fully qualified URL
the to Jason is the method that
returns Jason representation for my
student
and for this I just returned a
dictionary and I build it right there
I just up I put the URL unit this is a
reference to itself
so that when the client keeps that purse
or so somewhere
it has a reference to working from I
this is simply the ice I have a name
that's the only thing I have
for student and that's very important
I return he link to how to obtain
registrations for for that student the
client doesn't know this until I tell it
how to do it it's very important that I
don't tell
more than I need to the client because I
one ever serve
my right to change might URL's as much
as possible so
decline needs to know only top-level
URL's document only does
and of course that use URL for tool to
generate my registration 0
said this is the reverse of the to chase
on the from Jason
so I said before that I I don't want to
handle errors
in my top-level high-level cold
and here I need to do it and where do it
is
by throwing exceptions when there's an
error so
I I just put my you know that the cold
copy sold it
properties from the Jason into my model
up inside it triblock and if
there's a key error that means that
declined in central
the information needed to send and in
that case
understood to be an exception I don't
throw the key error exception that
pie from close I which through my own
validation error
and I include a have message with it
so that the client knows happened
which brings a topical for handling so
if I just do what you did in the
previous like then
class will stop it it'll find an
exception he will not know how to handle
its leave
it apart and a $500 ever to the client
but I don't want that
so what I do its II create handlers for
all my arms
you look at the bottom two of those four
functions
those IOU's it a crater from flask call
her handler
on these are two modes in which you can
catch errors
on first to the two takes a custom
exception that that's my
Jason validation error second one takes
an ever
status to them so you can catch errors
both ways
and then you can handle them your own
way and my own way
it's too call wrapper function that
generates
I never response that hath all the
information
including the message that that was
generated when that ever happened
I unit testing missus very important
flask comes with a unit testing client
I its a generic client that it's not
made
specific break the ice so if you use it
asses
there's a little bit of our bling
applicable to you need to do
you need to tell it that you're working
with Jason convert to chase into
constraints and its kind of cousin I'm
going to do that a lot and I don't like
to repeat myself
so I subclass if asked s client
and I have far a much more friendly
API test nine that I can use my tests
and he it is in this example
II I have my client ass self client
might unit test class
and up I just say post
to create ever source that sends a POST
request
I I passed the URL an 80 the data asset
by from dictionary
so we're gonna create something here and
then if that request I'll went through I
get
the response object from flask thats RV
response value
an able to get the decoded Jason acid
dictionary
in case I need to check stuff that came
with the response
in this case I make sure that on Ralph
returned to a1
and then I capture my location URL
now I know where susan let's so I can
continue on my test
and now ask papi to give me something
and I can make sure that down to got
written two hundred
and that the name is Susan and that the
URL is the URL
the correct URL and you can keep going
like this and if you look at the gate
have example you see lots of tests
like this they're very readable very you
mean my opinion very beautiful
so this was simple so if you thought
that was not simple then you can leave
now
because now it's gonna get really really
crazy
so
this very important unless you are doing
a
small API project that you're running so
your home
you should authenticate your API you
never want to leave an API open to
anyone
so when a look at that and
for this I initially I use to right
my own cold like you know like like a
with you
but I found that specifically for
authentication there are a number of
things that you always need to do that
they are the same for every project
so I ended up writing flask HDTV
all is an extension that on its
its very simple chest takes care of
handling the
HTTP headers for me so
all you need to do is provide a function
that verifies that the user name and
password are your back
and decorated with my decorator
this extension provides is the greater
so function gets the username and the
password
loves the user name and up and then
on personally your you sir knows
for the delay so you said yes the the
user knows how to validate a pass or so
like I just asked the model to tell me
if the password is correct
and the french would country with its
fired from falls from here
the extension will not let the requester
it will return 41
instead
so how does this work you need to tell
extension which routes you need to be
password-protected
you may not want all of them are
protected and
I'm pretty myself here but that is done
with a decorator
so each decorated function any as you
can see you have multiple decorators in
function in order
so you decorate the function and a you
know
that'd that's all you need to do did the
body at the function didn't change
that's thats identical to what it was
before but now I know that
if I if the client doesn't provide
correct credentials
this is not gonna run
so maybe repetitive to say
you know log in required on every route
of your API
if you have a large API and more often
than not you want to protect all your
API and points
with passwords so one little trick that
you can use
decades to set up a before request
handler this is a flask feature you can
set up
again with the greater function that is
called before any
requests are called so that this is one
function that it's called for any
requests
regardless of where Eagles will fight
and then needs to run
so did this is the one place where you
can do common work that applies to all
your API
and what I do here I I'd stick my own
decorator
siddig rate this instead of the rocks
so then I don't need to the great any
other routes
now some people are like to send use in
a minute
and passwords constantly its it can be
seen as a key
risk even though you should be using
secure HTTP
the fact that the client needs to handle
the passwords and its server needs and
the passwords
up could mean some some sort of risk so
did traditional way to do this is to
not use the password it use
authentication token
and you can decide with the tokens are
you you can make them expire double
you can make them permanent you can make
in Revo couple
there are many ways to do this and I
have one implementation in the source
code that you can
you can check out but up
essentially I just for plates my verify
password:
handler for flask HTTP of with
you know a function to verify still
talkin that'd
this case and I'm passing to talk in a
season name
inundate HTTP of education
headers and I don't use the password the
passwords and used can be empty
so thats that's a predication
on that's fine but that means
you using someone else's decorators &
you
its my to graders but for you I'm
someone else
what I think their real power a flask is
when you design your own decorators for
your API
there are specific to your case is so
only travel showed and with return
Jason if I right and sometimes
I did say to Jason to the object and
then I
Jason if I that that's gonna repetitive
I don't need to see that in my friends
so how about this
archer's decorate my routes with Jason
and then I can return it dictionary
that's the top case this is it an
example the initial before it returns
the authentication token so I just
returned
the dictionary don't worry about Jason
and then did the second example action
before
I don't even converted to Jason tax
return an option
model
and you may be thinking yeah but the
decorator must be
ugly long difficult
and this is the decorator that's all you
need to do
so when you write it by from the greater
you have a a small amount of boilerplate
and I'm not gonna go that I don't even I
can claim that I remember
exactly what those things to realize
that the top
are but I just copy them from the
greater
want to the next and they work
important thing as the body this is
the code that will run as a rapper
before your fun children's
went when you have the function
decorator and in this context
the original function is F so
this rapper can call effort anytime
so what are you hearing I collapse that
that's my original function
and then if if I don't get a dictionary
and I've got
model so I called Jason I
now I have a dictionary so when I do
it's like a fun fight
and done
but that's the simple we need to do
something more fun stuff
so one important thing we have any prob
openness to
make sure that clients on abuse it
and one way is to limit the rate at
which clients can make
calls into it
so how about this I decorate
any router I want and I David
limit number limited number of trying
and up
a interval so in this example this route
can be called up to five times for
fifteen second period
everything else to say I didn't change
anything just put the decorator
now a if you have an API that you want
to rate limit
globally so you want all did and
pointing to a guy to be
rate limit it together then weakened I'm
natin
much on this here but you can argues the
same before request
trick ratio for authentication just
decorate
the before request you're a limit that
one
and that would prevent you know the
whole API to be
access to more than what you want
and Isis this implementation still not
that
terrible what's things will come in
future slides
up I'm using a helper class
I don't want to mix things so
the rate-limiting functionality is in a
class it's called rate limit
implementation is it's in the source
code if you wanna
gun how to do this are its it is this
readiness
storage better than many other ways to
the way that they are even packages to
do this
so you can unity is my implementation if
you don't like it
are but anyway this works by up
signing a unique key to the function
that a it's getting cold which is F
that name and the IP address of the
client
which last gets me ass from out address
so that's why you Nikki and I give it to
my great manager
and if they rate monitors says yes
I then called af which is my original
function
if the limiter says that this client is
over the limit
I send a too many requests ever so I
could've said here
abort 429 that's the HTTP code for too
many requests
but remember that I said that I prefer
to wrap all my errors
with helper functions and when you see
this
you understand what it means if if you
say if I said
you know I bought for 29 you have to go
look up what that means
so this is better
agitation so all the time protection on
I just get older elements in my
collections
and return them that be a burden for
client and the server
may decline has a very small screen can
display only fight students at a time so
why get its house in
right if that's that's that decides same
thing for for the server
many in ABA expensive query to get
it I'll send any the client wants five
then I should be in a fight
so
this that said dysfunction
when it's decorated with my passion 8
decorator
needs to return a database query that
still
to be run this is a equity that's ready
to run but hasn't run yet
in this case and returning the query
from
my relationship and Isis
this is the the way the response looks
so that this is what the client will
receive
the very top you can see the URL's list
well for you for registration your else
and then
the decorator inserts a second key in
this response
cometa and in it the
us he list of things that are useful for
clients that want to build
pagination buttons links so he did the
page number
items per page: number of items to
number of pages
I have a previous link because this page
so it knows that there's no previous
this next
the first time last and this is how it's
implemented
so just make sure
that that the extended and in a separate
they simply parts
this it's the middle part this is when
I've run the original function that
returns to query
when I get a query II paginated
this is a feature a flask sequel Oconee
that's very nice
you you can give it a page number and
page cites
and it returns a pic such an Asian
object house
a lot of useful information for for
building
you know the links in addition to the
items themselves
so page and per page
coming from the querystring of the URL
so above the query
lines you can see that I get
questioning variables page after page
which I can get from flask a flask
request object
request or arts haz that that dictionary
with all the
all that questioning arguments
and I have to make sure that I use the
faults if those are not present because
the
the client doesn't know about these so
the first time he asks
about this collection it it's not gonna
send any pagination links
which is sake in the old and I'm I'm
gonna
I'm not going to be keep it all
I'm gonna get it in this case the first
10 up
below that back in eight call is where I
build
that made a dictionary with all the
links and
I'm using URL for to build links
produced
I mean it its few lines of code but
there's nothing really
you know no rocket science there still
the dictionary
and then at the bottom I returned the
chase on a fight
you know version of that the cherry with
the two keys the URL's
and the net cashing
so
I thought long about get example show
for this and I
decided to to go with a
no cash example are
so I have a route never turns
authentication tokens
and I want to make sure that
to client is not cash that because it's
sensitive so
about a say it like this by having this
decorator
their response will be enhanced
with the cache-control header who tell
the client
to not cash this to turn away
and this is how it's implemented for
this I decided to
implement the crater that it's a generic
version of the cache-control that's at
the top
this one takes in this tough
cache-control: directives
and chest sticks and in their response
and
that's that's I just make response
object
from response return by the original
function
and and Justin at the cache-control
and Inferno no cash specifically I you
can see that at the bottom I
just create an instance of that the
other the greater
with the specifics you know that those
three keys
data were directed staff to that mean
do not cash this
but that's not hold you can do with
caching
the the nice thing a when you follow the
rest for principals more or less
to the doc then you get cashing
you advance cash in for free if
if you have responses that are useful if
the client can cash
then you can save a lot on band with so
for example if
decline house response that on that it's
in the cash
Arctic Lankans ask the server if
that response is still valid and if the
service a
yes then does not need to transfer that
responsible for the network again
now one of the mechanisms that a
the HTTP protocol uses for this it's
called any tax
the tax and this is how I do it
the only change so the
how beautiful this you know i i still
marvel at
how concise and beautiful this rockets
I Q U you can read it and you understand
everything it does
so the eat at best
a couple things it generates any tag
and a tag it's basically a cold
that proper sense that version of that
request
I'm sorry that resource and when their
source changes you have to change
to and a purse or doesn't change you
keep the same time
that's it the client caches
divers the response and it remembers
attack
and then you can ask the server if that
tag still
you know batting so this
yes the implementation desist this is
the last one so I'm almost done
another ago you know in detail
but if you understand how the HTTP
conditional requests work this this is
the if match in if non
much headers ended
request then on this is hopefully
would be very simple for you to
understand the energy tax
that I generate on you can see somewhere
in the middle there
right after make response are
pretty generic I just take the Jason
taxed
and I get an md5 hash this is you can
say this is
expensive this is very generic it will
work with anything
of course for for specific application
you can
can have more efficient anti-tax
on depends and you know that's up
basically thats when I have
ok so
yes if there are any questions you need
to use the microphone
to the middle
I left everyone confused great
anticipation higher
I so am i was just wondering
what do you think it's best when you
gettin with for
creating a resource will be Jason in the
people's body
for would be like key values or at still
UAE it's your choice that the raffle
principles
don't say how we needs to be done I
think Jason is
it's good it's definitely helpful for
the client
because if the client JavaScript its its
gonna
you know native for the client and
yeah I it has to be in the body so
definitely in the body
not everywhere else you can be XML if
you prefer
that over Jason by Kapadia
its key values as Jason that that would
be my preference
thank you hi
and to questions my first questions
about your extension
on HDPE of medication I was wondering
does your plugin
sport digest authentication and
if it does not the nice where next week
and I'm sending you upon request
because right okay I am I said he
sometimes because it does
does alright you are my best man right
now
so yeah check it out outdated where you
use it it's a little bit different
so you don't wear a shield here I
twenty different packets in the docs so
chica okay
and my second question is when you
should when you show us
your route for resource collections was
a reason why you only returned with the
URL's and you didn't
returned deal that accompanied URL's for
example your students
why did you send on URL's not the first
name and last name for all the students
list users way a yes there's a reason
cell a lot of people who whatcha say and
it's perfectly fine
but if you wanna take advantage of
cashing then
I its best that you return
ever source in only one way right
so that's why my lists have URL's
and then the client can go get the URL
only so that I can optimize
my cashing there's only one place where
the
you know the students in this example I
cash and that's the individual
URL's thank you are so I
two quick questions are first one is do
you support patch
hi I don't but you can you can its easy
had it's your choice yes your and the
second one is it is a possible do
on specify a partial consumption up the
URL so in other words if you're
resource lives 45
path components deep you can say
%uh you know I can consume the first to
pass components
and that would return an object that it
would know how to consume the
last three autonomous Kurdish away in
flask to say
from this point on put everything that's
you note to the right
in one argument its cool path
so you get the path when you're out
there is an argument and then you can
person and whatever you need with it its
hi
earlier you showed the log in required
decorator and you also show that if you
needed to
decree all your routes did you put than
ever before quest arm
what's normal pattern you have to do
that for every route except for the blog
route cuz you're not that lucky and very
good question but so this is an example
code
on again have time to talk about other
things
last us so class imports blueprints with
blueprints you can create group of
routes that are I'll you know
that that have some logical you know
meaning
together so if you have to blueprints
are you have one for your routes
and 14 for this one
route that advertise talkin for example
if they're separate
then you can have different before
requests for each article
so
analyst um I missus is image 26 have
occurred but
a lot of what you're doing your
decorators
like special rate-limiting or %ah cash
turning off cashing
is the kind of thing that you'd often 1
p.m. you to configure like
deploy time configuration or even
runtime configuration
arm at I was wondering if you could
maybe elaborate a little bit
on any expensive have not had a period
like
for instance maybe you wanted I'm
what you're showing like if you were to
say 12
turn off rate-limiting in debt right
that's a code change
for that environment as opposed to just
configuration change those winning if
you could
so hot celebrity mitterrand that's a
good point at in show
configuration I according Omar might
parameters here
but I'll flask ass a configuration
object and you can
its it's very simple key-value
list so you can set any configuration
that you want in the configuration
object and argues it from there
that this at answer your question you
have to do it like I did
here which is you know for even even
towards
I can hear you my even towards like like
sys admin tools like
actually run time management system as
opposed to just
up should if you prefer to the outside
of this
it's not a problem but to
so we we saw Mike tactic
great in required Jimmy
it seems to me like years a lot of
decorator
was like you removed some them from
slide to slide
I am there was like a student query
and in my imagination like 10 decorators
before
and a was wondering if you
it's a critique worth hey I was
wondering if you know
miss library restful
last restful and I here
is very is there a reason you chose to
use like specifically decorators
and not something which is
X made for or making rest
I think last case made to make reflect
the ice
that it the way you express routes its
very restful
in my opinion I actually I don't like
last restful so done this in dept
because I
I'm not using here I don't like it I
don't like it I can blog about it
up but up
but why wide
perhaps like like I mean what what's
one what's the main reason like us
I like decorators said
this is very readable and a I I don't
think a flash restful
fights with their careers you can be
helpful optical
for example that stressful has a very
nice
marshalling module that you can use
instead of my
home-grown way to generate a Jason
representation
if you have a really big slurs then
it might be you know be interesting to
use flask stressful for that
for the robbing I really like flask
alone I prefer that
to the the class based up your structure
for
from fast national it's a preference so
you know as I said at the beginning you
know you don't have to
believe me on like what I say I mean
that the nice thing about
Lasky said you and I both can do what we
like and
you know it tolerate such bull so
think
first thank you for a great talk so
my question I don't require a remember
all the details for your
pagination decker so perhaps my
questionable be malformed um if I recall
correctly you first return all
the queer results but you only actually
end up
returning you know King needed
list that's not gonna but that's not how
it works
okay the the function returns a query
this is a query that didn't run yet so
it didn't
you know you didn't use any resources
yet it's just a query that still to be
run
you prefer to query and then you return
it
decorator gets that and instead of
running it the normal way
a transit through dispatching a function
that comes with flasks ECLAC any
and that gets only the one-page that the
client wants
ok great thank you very much a waste
thank you
yep okay I think we're done thank you