week
ok
up
hard
want
up
now
alright
it's about time to get started and the
first talk in this session is by
down minor is going to give is a scenic
drive through the Django
request cycle demand
thank you now see partial as I me my
name is Dan miner
me developer manager waving trial or
small or start-up
help small businesses be successful but
they're all my tools
and I'm gonna talk with generous request
spots like
that's why spend the majority my time
majengo now
opinion Django for a bow clover two
years
injector does have a lot of part thought
might come to except
enjoy deal with out but when you're
starting out
it's not all obvious how the oft usually
go on working with some guys on my team
were experienced as health dept just
coming to Django
they went was struggling with notions
like I have this very behind we get into
a template
which pair talked to me but apparently
if you're coming from
back doesn't have so many different
layers part something to talk about in a
particular
her request turned into response which i
think is why the most fundamental
not the most fundamental operations
check now
speaking abolished parts might have
given way the ending this is
somewhat how it all works that's great
offers awkward
but you can see there's a lot going on
here's a number of words repeated
there's
you shaking going on middleware in a
bunch places
soft talk about what this actually
indifferent to do that
which door with her quest it all begins
so in a long
a long long time ago a consul far-right
out
ultra someone type this shoes
said I wanna curl -o to Daniel Agger dot
com slash hello slashing to:
and the press Enter and then the cops
back
and this is crossing what actually and
that's what it's doing
sending her a HD 1.1 GetRequest
to slash hello slash Intel saying I want
a response from the host
Dec home and I mean except just anything
comes back
and from there one across the and I'm
not gonna talk but have how it works
that talking up itself but trust me when
that person
me in this case pressed enter they
requested or across the internet and
ended up
Tampa looks like this it more gonna call
webster
now in practice this web servers
probably engine actor
actually by that shit is popular
nowadays bottom line is it's a web
server
and the web server fundamentally takes
her quest
and gives back response and how it does
that
changes on what color us for talk static
quest something simple file it's just on
a machine the web server probably just
handle itself
through a response back itself but if
it's more complex
setting something that's powered by web
application like
check let's say get for more cock as it
we have to ask the question well
how does the web server itself which may
be written in C
or something how does I communicate with
I thought process the track and thus a
change in the past
so back in the day the early 2000's
there wasn't simple way to do it
different web servers did
ways different from work today different
ways some web server support my python
sometime
expert passage I and it meant that your
search your choice
web server and web framework was happy
couple together which
motivation has top web surfer people to
steal from our people
stuff from our people said care for web
surfers and nobody like
so what we ended up with was kept 333
called whiskey
web server key face its answer the
question how to Python frameworks and
web services
tracked common and simple way by web
applications on top check the Big Valley
whiskey in petrie came out was
simplicity in these damn as the guys
wrote it knew
if it was in Tampa life it wasn't easy
to switch no actually do anything
left so they want and they made it
simple and they made
one reelection point between whiskey
wearing a web server
want to rest are any web application in
this is about
your mental possible kitchen you can see
the whiskey protocol
which is call something called function
call it takes two arguments I'm which
have particular format
the standard talks about does some stuff
to it and then
returns and terrible strings I wish
is careful not to talk how'd to ration
just s5 given this
he can run in a particular way will get
back some handles
spot the other thing to highlight their
is that there's nothing stable and
every request has its own amber on
Sunstar response
there's nothing in their last by
definition whiskey
track response to another so any type
assistant
session management has happened web
application now
probably thinking if I said the whiskey
is the way that web service QQ
applications and Django is web
application runs
doesn't speak with you the answer yes so
in general and
your whiskey up whiskey where is in
Django decor
hammers scammers and with a couple
things
hold off for simplicity look something
like this:
if you look at the shape compared to
last light
very similar and that they're both calls
they both take two arguments and Bronze
Star sponse
which are customarily called up not find
sir
and they both returned something in this
case something
itself kept you can see what's up doc a
response is really the biggest thing
of doctors months after two interesting
things about it
gonna spend a lot of time going have
function works first interesting thing
is that's not to find on whiskey soft
based on which I thought was weird my
first looking into this
but it turns out there's one other class
Jack
hospital December only one what that is
is that thing around the jacket has so
that when you're ready
generation when you're fired task hi
as much as possible the exact same
copout
as you get your whiskey you go into your
normal I
you to skip the other interesting thing
about how this structured is itself
doctor response tix request
which you'll see is not part West 9
bronner start
request object to something that's great
and that first ellipses
here it's a Jager structure that
encompasses their question everything
that
understand quest this where check your
Stockport whiskey hammers it's the last
place in check we actually see deal with
whiskey
arrest check below it doesn't care what
have we got there just cares but what it
needs in order to run
so jump into court base hammers
this is really what happens in tears of
base hammer itself is how to rock a
response is that mean
about lipitor roster spot cycle to
understand how our questions into
response
through understanding how this works
these are the sort
basic steps but before we get into that
for the catalyst we see the wooden mill
workers there
fact on the six lines that are in there
for middleware is involved for them so
let's take
a progression to what I mean when I say
middleware before we see things
if you're coming from a more enterprise
background when her middleware
you likely think something big something
heavy something like or future J
daughter in common
something the bosses bosses boss of
seven million dollars
his department to run its rally paint
which article for the exact opposite
jacko
with talks to Skype Django middleware is
too late low-level plugin system for
globally altering
changed the two interesting points there
a globally all-time liked late
you'll see as we get into looking at the
structure have expected side have
installed
and globally is a really unique thing
but jail a middleware
a place the jack week a system is that
they're on every request that comes in
ever goto whereas everything else
gets far behind a viewer tasks
has an example what late means is
installing a middleware is really just
adding a line to accept file you'll find
when you
or proper settings file it comes in the
project template you've got a middleware
classes dictionary
add something to it it'll get picked up
when you look at first time you'll see
some things there
should probably been they're pretty
useful by should also add
grocer so with that in mind with
I thought on when middleware means
Django context
let's look at the first step which is
your quest or
across middleware what it's for is it
handles
things that happened on all in power I
say requests and not few calls
at the time with your her quest power we
don't know how
handle all we know is this: requests
come in to the whiskey where
down here have a look at the structure
will see some therapy a few times in the
other opinion what I said one little
Millers are simple system
of middleware is I know jack project as
a method
processors quest which takes her quest
the pact
an account early return only one of two
things
he can return you there HTTP response
which is a full-on
check response object and if it does
that the rest the pipeline stops
goes there missus this usually happens
if you've done your
medication in a general question aware
which is a good place to do it
if you use account is not authenticated
mill where would you shut down the
process
retract that you to a login page without
having to go through any thereafter
where's system or her turn
not as Miller's waves I have no to
I've done my business what happened this
keep on going to
stack so this middleware
tickle you can see just takes a request
which means it doesn't know the few
that's good
this missus to look stage if
what you are doing this request does
require knowing what you will handle it
configured 0 really just check as a
later step in the process
captured so
before he gonna take small break catch
up on where we are
we've gone and we start with her quest
came from
hi did something press curl already when
used with breast click
that request when I across the internet
guide land on a web server
the web server took her quest our state
using
gone through whiskey where went out I
times Django
in Django for stepdaughter cost or
so at this point we have request object
have some stuff done to it
have really done anything else which is
what's coming next
in the next thing up analyst is
resolving that URL
interview Oct is often URL
is the process by definition taking URL
like day like dot com slash hella
slashing TL
and mapping that to a few function it's
gonna
if you're new web framework sir come
from back static site
you look at your like I Daniel Agger
accomplish slashing to:
and you would think that somewhere in
the end below the Weber was director
called a low
below that to director called MTL book
that
when the next which would show whatever
you get a response to this
and that is how work but that's not
necessarily back officer
how doesn't work and Jack at this point
using
your %ah resolution all we really do
help slash hello slash MTL is just a map
shows we can specify using a former look
something like this:
what flash hellaflush until does way
relates to interview hartley gets used
we can in this case I've got a small how
to block bomb
what's called a URL of and shows two
different ways you can make them
the first one is supports just saying
but map slash hella slashing to:
hi Intel just a director mapping
in a sec 10 is a little more complex
issues a regular expression
and it saying I wanna map slash hello
flash
anything else in America High City so a
commuter
past like slash hello slash Toronto you
would end up there
now the important thing is that these go
in order
and we resolved URL matches first wins
so if we switch to europe think look
like this this is what used to be
now just switch the order in this case
slash hellaflush Intel would go to high
City comes in it as well
what is hello slash anything after
shallow slash India match is this a lot
still go deal with high City
enough to actually get hyped
now when we look at those patterns I
mention the first section which is
for the Mac damage in the second section
which is the view to get
by but the third section the name High
City
some or and it's a way that we can refer
programmatically what
this URL looks like what it does
front URL anywhere but using using
those two functions bottom of the screen
the world template tag
first function just for firms them that
way means that we decouple the
relationships between pages
the world selves which is an interesting
idea something you can't
status of we decouple the relationship
between two pages
and the way to generate a link between
actual content
self so all we do is we call reverse
High City
injectable give me what right now based
on how my world except right now
you rush doing that
means we can do something like this we
can go and change the URL structure
totally
we've gone change hello hi said
K hi surge I'll and now everything just
works
hasn't gone everywhere way you to
dynamic lookup
is at high tech to figure X URL
thinkstock this is an art thing but
trust or fine diversions on a couple
times thank you soft
so without a away and seeing how those
can have a backup OK Corral Africa and
see that slash Alice lashing tail
well goes and matches too high till we
figure that out
we're done with mister
now next long list we've got a few
Miller's
human workers almost exactly the same
thing quest
where agreed on our going to a except
at this point we now know the view
object
so where's your question aware just took
a request object humidor text her quest
and if you object in all honesty
I don't I never actually build one
myself
in searching through the Jager docs
examples I found one get one good case
for them
which is the way the jackal Django
handle CSR but it's there
if you find yourself in that situation
one your middle word to know something
about the view itself
you middleware is the place you do it
but the real point and the real meet
their quest response like
and we'll do all your work is the view
views are where botch work your side
rendering system where you going to cost
databases
but says when we talk with your
resolution
we said that's harsh hella class
champion mapped it high till you
and this is about the simplest possible
view that we could dude
no magic on here just function takes
request object
and returns top in this case the
something she took your spot
which you just give it a string and will
send back
heading love you back Stasko that's hot
the only thing
jagger could respond with some other
ones which you may find useful and
my you got your shit response.redirect
which is afoot Rasen back its
reject somewhere else there's a
difference apostle you wanna 301 or 302
as Jason response which is just coming
up 1.7
which is designed for if you're dealing
with Chase on it just takes a dictionary
will serialize things are properly
summary hatter's its
is nothing you can do now but we'll see
a couple lines process
and there's a skirmish response which is
are much different
marked whereas all our other response
types
couldn't ones I have mention take a full
string body thanks deal with streaming
it should check your response text later
instance on for sponsoring haven't yet
figured out what your
send you can enter also that want to get
back up to the top
whiskey where that's way to keep calm
here monitor
now on one hand this is cool because it
means you can have a very large
longer response an hour memory
had also as you have a long and response
an hour
so with cherished response it's there
it's an uphill battle for you
it will break a few other middleware as
per most those handle it well
but think about what you doing when you
choose to use it is
future cases for but a lot of criticism
when you think you want to use this
where you should really be doing is
looking what're actually try deliverance
well
is this better suited to put the
long-running task tears
this better suited to run of lining up
push notification
but if it's not you've got the auction
but for now
mystic aged spot because at some point
gets the point
now have called this a function a few
times cuz it is just function
but that's not the only way right your
other option
something that looks like this and it's
called a class-based few
because it's a few based cost like
the defining features that a subclass
checkered accused of genera
dot view and as a function they're
called get
as one compost times the per child work
to use function base used to use hospice
used
if there's 10 people under got fifteen
different answers
there is no one right one depends where
you're at track you
I like hospice use but I'm gonna stick
with transfer s this
there some particular so
at the I mentioned in those last use
that how with the views there are
actually
their simplest form but they're not
funny as they were going mixing
HTML i thought id share same function
blocks which
by your lodge do that you're gonna have
a bad time Chester scale up to start
work designers
what you try to do anything shall be on
basic stricter pollution
so what we've done here is set up using
a template
and so on dollar does you can't see
what's on high until
now it just sets a picture contact in
this case
addiction with key city in the answer
Montreal
and then passes that context down into a
function called render
which would give in template as well
using check templating language
and echoes the render function will take
that template function substitute city
in Montreal in to replace
action up in Tunisia response object
term
so did this works and this is a nice
simple way to do it
I am a lot so I wanna get a faster and
now I i the second thing to my check
template I've said I also want to say
hello to city from
your request I wanna do that on every
page on my site
so i cud both reach my views ID in that
second minor
by city people's goip dot something or
some other vendor
or after what's your quest back at night
about that Cinco de ver my side and I
have to worry about it
means that I've got also its repetition
or don't need it
but I really like something in the same
with a middleware works on all requests
I'd like something that works I'll
render of which does best
that's called come pick up it a contacts
processor
so temper Costco complex processes very
simple
they really just look like function the
tix request object returned Dec
but the interesting thing why they're
useful is that they're on
all across are on all grander of
once about it topic co-processor sorry
public context processor
list except so if we've gone mad
that we can go back are a few and
template will just look like this
in the view itself all we have to worry
about setting the city
because we know that in the context
processor
later in the pipeline it will handle for
know what your question
question now at this point
wanted one last pass before keep going
go back up
talk with howard got afford that please
look at
that picture this place is called short
is it
20 minutes away to first time to
Montreal in been here before
please go here I will be a cultural
experience for you offered
sandwich order a large plate medium shot
pic of life fries black cherry gonna be
tired afterwards but you'll appreciate
so with with that where I hope you all
will go for lunch
I'll let's step back and look at how we
got where we are
and we started with the choir we went
across the higher again to
the Internet to the web server which
communicate with genuine Python
3 whiskey where with an quest where
way URL resolution
dealt with the view middleware and then
dealt with the view itself view itself
django template template in and then
Welsh
the contact process a complete couple
and at this point
when our last ep and bass family which
is there a spot
on the way in at the beginning a
middleware a similar was interesting
and just filler in particular
interesting because it had
takes action both on the way in and on
the way
by in an hour how some insert down now
state picture
on the way an use your question or
middleware reason I would have no way
writing
mention never used before but on the way
back spot
and if you look at the structure it
looks suspicious and later quest where
which is again hope middleware follow
pattern
they're lightweight exxon some first
response man hours called with a fully
formed response object so at this point
no return which missing Aug 21 harkin
but it's really useful for performance
really stock so
one other quality me response but always
comes built in majengo
it's called national capital where what
that does is
goes textures of the comes back out at
the content like
onto it and looks hot texarkana their
past
if your browser has cash populous ill
just go Irish the whole cock
the whole body her response replace it
with an oil change response
so it it's useful for things like that
it's also useful for cock in session
management
if you wanna tak after field said your
cock in her pressure token each time
can do it there too now
the only thing actually defines this as
middleware is it being object with
process response
method so its original question it could
be combined
with the other the answer is yes you can
go on package up
are you different middleware hoax into
one object in this case were in a cock
or so it works both as a request our
because it's got that process request it
also works as a responsible
works got that process response or and
this is really handy
except you gotta remember one thing
which is
middleware lashed at the beginning I i
said its order but this is really where
that quite kits how
on the way so when we're dealing with
her quest
where's humidors process to this list
talk
so first we com where and see a ser our
hike
on the way back swear to God if you got
from bottom
talk so first a Commodore and sister
few cock generally this will do the
right thing
but not all it's important when you're
on middleware isn't
have to work together now if you packed
one object limit 1 spot order whereas
action separately
you can exactly
so the last ep on our five-and-a-half
step process is our friend except
and it at the bottom its happen because
it's a little different
it is whereas all our other middleware
fire
section middleware is designed on the
really if you've done some yourself
so you only get exceptional work if you
you function itself
calls exception generally what you can
use except software for
distracting is going and 600 bucks
system
if you use century which has downstairs
they how can there to go Cafferty
exceptions the concert last summer
to their service hi it only right
fires on tacos and hit like the others
returns
non-urgent scoff but in this case you
almost always water
spot that's when go into some handles it
redirect user back
sorry page if you don't if you get to
the middleware check
just return on for everyone just kinda
check myspace
higher much mayor or may not
which one ok so
at this point were three we've gone
come through whiskey we've gone down
we've gone back up
we've called the response function the
response function has returned effect
nothing terrible text
with costar response which whiskey
standard returning
and the stakes a boxer sir
at the beginning we started with this
first and I was a crow quest
to the host Daniel Agger dot com saying
I want
get on slash hella tale and I can accept
and then what we've given act is a two
hundred okay
which came from jericho said being
served by Amtrak's webster
said Scott content-type: Texas now
which is great because we accept he said
except I
it's got a content-length 33 which was
provided by check
response or act Qatar's on and it's got
to first-line
exposure host template in buyer
function a sack lunch says hunter
because that's where
West and mouse to click
now this view itself is not there's not
a lot to it
says too much text but that itself is
where you do interest
that's where you go you call it web
services collar logic
use the stuff underdog engines back
house you for this week
talk but now no matter how hard tic tac
toe
this is the basic structure your quest
the star
higher to go to the web server hey
webster
up your choice which'll committees
whiskey to get tax check 0
once earned Django you got your question
aware
to your earlier solution for he was
gonna handle it not your view middleware
which probably won't use
I'd with your view function actually
does stuff
on the way back at this time done
nothing wrong back to respond
were also contact headers gone through
risky gamble
act web server will send a fax to climb
tutorials
are any questions there's Mike from
there
thank you
here