make
nom Gartner 1
are you %ah get so we have
we have two very exciting talks we have
two arm hardware
our talks in a row in this room so you
you probably wanna
stick around are and starting this blog
we have
opera some homes I with his stock
lending art technology like
bite them for an active in real time LED
insulations
let's give a hand to present right lol
thanks for coming out
term means Preston I do few Python thing
they do some cloudy things
and I have sort of a closeted artistic
side that I'm getting some love you have
some interest in in Arden created and
actually argue that almost everyone here
icon is is a creative person because
code ultimately is
is a creative process so the Wyoming
antibodies in in the answer super simple
it's because for
forever we've been fascinated by twinkly
lights were there looking at the night
sky
staring at firefight in a forest
assertive
doing an awning at fireworks in the sky
and
in working with LED's has a lot of parts
and so when I'm gonna really try to do
is give a full stack overview
up all the layers here and go all the
way from electrons to motions
talk about LED at the material the
controller hardware in San the
integrated circuitry involved
interfaces and protocols that are
required to speak to these devices
summer software libraries that can be
used and finally some creative design
pattern so it's
it's quite a full stack on so conduct
dive right in
LED light emitting diode I'm guessing
everyone can understand what the light
and meeting part is by default here so
I'll talk just very briefly about what
diet is
that essentially is a Tulare sandwich
to semiconductor materials were 1/2 is
doped in a way that it is
as an excessive liked runs and the other
side is dope the way it has sort of a
shortage electrons is a cold electron
holes
and this result in a structure where
current can really only
flow in one direction for the Houston
circuits to act as for check valves
and in the case of light emitting diode
what happens is when electron dropped
into a hole it goes from higher energy
state to lower energy state and releases
a
a vote on which we can see is visible
light and
so we're many view from the witness
former up LED this is kinda blinky light
the US start of it as a hardware project
I just wish other
LED materialists or that one small
square and for
for more creative purposes were
interested in RGB LED's and these are in
fact
three separate LED's closely put
together into a package like this work
each of these have been chemically set
up to nearly the red green or blue light
in this case it's in what's called a
50-50 package which just means that the
five no nearby five millimeter square
and by having them this close together
when you apply different amount of power
that you took the red green and blue
LED's
the colors blend in we can perceive it
as a as a full spectrum
when you start working with LED is one
of the terms you come
come across really quickly as smart
verses done LED's and a dumb LED is
simply
one of these LED packages has no logic
circuitry involved it's just you apply
voltages and and they emit light and if
you have a stripper have done LED's
when you play voltage and you make
purple all the LED's are the same color
at the same time
smart LED's involve some sort of logic
circuitry insists
the Sumter integrated ship along the
along the way
that allows it to receive a data
protocol
and each light along the strip can be
individually controlled as its own color
on brightness et cetera
and they've actually now gotten to the
point where they're building these
integrated circuits directly into the
LED package
so so these things require these sort of
protocols and there's a variety of them
but a and before going into that they
these packages come in she different
shapes and sizes
so there's some varieties here where
there are more than one
LED per control chip so this
unit of control is called a pic so often
called an LED pixel
nan an LED pixel may have more than one
LED in the package the date they come in
a variety of forms but the unit have
control is called a pixel
and the datatypes take take tend to be
served
specialized very high clock rate serial
formats
that am essentially boiled down to an
array of bytes
and each of these chips will simply take
off pop off
three bites use it for our GNP but for
the remaining bite and then for them
down the line to the each
pixel along the chip doesn't really know
that it's pixel number five it just
simply part of tree by 10:40 remaining
and these protocols while they very they
are all very high clock rate very
precision timing or into protocols and
they're not something that a
sort of kernel-based operating system
based program can generate reliably
you need something that's going to
maintain really high
fidelity in the timing and so what what
kinda things can use to
to create the signals we can you heard
me know and there's really actually
fantastic art Mina library called
fast LED but limitations barred windows
are that
you know there's a limit to how many of
these people you can actually connect to
one at one time
and center here Pike on I just have to
be a loss are you can't really
effectively use
bite on directly on it we know so what
what's or some other choices there
and in in the do yourself hard disk
space there's a these are kinda the two
main players there there's varieties up
them but these
these manufactures and what these boards
do is they take as an input
a standard lighting protocol which will
talk about the second
and they have embedded in their own
circuitry
I'm in there from where the ability to
translate into the whole range of the
different
pixel specific timings and formats and
they have enough capacity to allow you
to plug in many other these pixels
so this is the kinda bored but that you
of news and I i have one up here they'll
demo democrat the morning so I said
these take a a lighting protocol
input and so to talk a little bit about
that I have to tell you about tnx
on actually not that the attacks this is
is DMX 512
and its and it's the lighting protocol
that was initially established for a
theater lighting so
real quick at their history is initially
all the best eight tonight in theaters
use have
manual de Mures that we read a bit from
the stage in that country become a
painful so
they initially created DC motors that
would turn the dimmers and control the
DC motors from the back to the house
and that was sort of cumbersome so
eventually became serialize
into sparkled call DMX 512 and it's able
to address 512 individual
channels have data in this in the SERPs
slots
a its lot and and initially I'm sure
this is this is called one universe 512
channels called one university a max
because I'm sure what are the cliche
have 512 channels ass has to be enough
for anyone right now and can any more
than five earned
chance what things grew things got more
complex and they didn't so
eventually they're you have to run
multiple have surface
serial cable to control more than 512
channels
for the evolution of the protocol move
towards wrapping these
data packet into Ethernet packets
as a very catchy name you 1.3 one as the
standard in the lighting industry now
for sending
DMX over Ethernet and it is in fact
this protocol that has now become the
most common way of controlling
the lighting circuitry well thats that's
a really now that we're talking about
even that we can start talking about
software that runs
in a familiar turf operating system
environment
not talk about that a there's a lot I
just
softer out there that's very specific
and as monolithic in it it simply
handles
the rendering up data and then the
translation of that data into a protocol
on if you're interested in quickly
hacking on something that's
that's not too interesting you might you
party more interesting looking at
something that allows you to use
a library that takes data and does the
conversion
for you and so
processor up Python programmers we want
to be leveraged something like an
interface library that handles all the
specific protocol format we just want to
give it an array of values
on would just give credit there's a
project called open leading architecture
its through the Swiss Army Knife
lighting protocols
tools it will you can get a data has
great python bindings and it will render
it out to you
any of the various hardware types out
there on
and it's very flexible but its it kinda
kitchen sink
that heavyweight and for for a while
until recently was hard to get to run on
something like a Raspberry Pi so
I went ahead and Rhoda a pure Python
implementation a minimalist input
implementation just that you won 3-1
protocol
in Python but there but they're both
perfectly usable now that layer
the software takes care of talking to
the hardware but it's not
where the creative process happens and
so when we look at the side of software
that is user focus user
sorta purpose there's a sense of
american talk about in the theater
industry
that's mostly around on scenes switching
scenes
a lot of the innovation in dynamic
displays has come from that the
Christmas lighting folks
here they want to do the crazy animated
Christmas light shows
and for a long time before there were
RGB pixels to work with
you still at a relatively small number
of channels to work within you end up
with a program
that often we just take the project
dividing time into slices
31 row is one of your channels and then
you slice it into columns and you simply
address
a leveller value in each square the grid
but when you start to get many many many
channels kinda
individually filling in all these boxes
is pretty tedious
another approach to the current to stay
Dr is
is DJ matrices you know these big
two-dimensional matrices that are not
quote in
and those kind of things and there's
very expensive you noticed several
thousand dollars to to use
test takes on a screen saver and Adrian
and projected onto a 2d matrix
so stunning run in 2010 I started
thinking about a wave
experimenting with another model of
taking a
an abstraction three three layers that
inputs
elements and outputs where the input
would be sorta events that happen
from some sort of device input device or
other sort of I'll
these would trigger actions in elements
would
take care rendering the data over time
and then ship it out
output in this library is called bird
fish
it on it's really just my East certain
testbed sketch pad for experimenting
with some the stuff you've got what a
rough edges
it's really a classic terminally pre
alpha psi project
so this is this is minutes it's what I
use for the demoss here but it's now
down
you know i win I wouldn't go around
Disney it shows light on it
I talked about the input so we'll start
there am
in a vent really in a sense falls into
two categories: either to trigger event
in a trigger event is you you can think
about is simply
a light switch on of on of and
these on of events occur over time
and each channel in your lighting system
can have its own Series event see you
get the sort of player piano
look to it and this a
player piano analogy is not without some
well you'll see impact later in the
sense that music
I've I've learned a lot from what
electronic music has done
around rendering a fax in real time with
sound
a lot applies to music to trigger
venture one type of thing these are very
discreet on of events and then the other
type up at the end are
were caught napping dance in the end and
long to this is it if you think I've
turning a dial
these are values a change there you know
in a very varied way over time
so the overall model looks a little
something like this you have a vents
that are coming in at the time I need a
trigger a map these
on a pencil and onto these
elements in the elements our code
objects that respond to
triggers triggers on trigger of and its
these objects to take care
generating data overtime and end up
resulting in sort of a torrent updated
because
the hardware itself only cares about an
instantaneous value but get any sort of
an effect over time
you need to continuously changing
streams have
up data to get the hard way to do
anything interesting
on in terms of the actual hardware to
create
the events I've Iveco use primarily to
one is MIDI which is
what electronic musical instrument use
its alder
army its it's pretty reliable but it
does it's limited to
7 did values are 0 to 127
I'm 16 channels per sorta minibus
and in they often involves a lot about
OS specific
am driver level stuff too can become a
pain to work with
open some controls a bit more modern at
UTPB East
on use it for the demo today because
wireless on live demos pretty painful
but
on and is very flexible that how you
specify the value
so this graphic is actually about other
program called touch OSCE for Iowa's
they have an Android version as well and
what it does is it allows you to sort of
give a a you are I essentially to some
value want
and and give you either floating point
values for any range of these controls
or you can set a minimum and maximum so
very flexible gives you that serve rock
controller input
you can then turn into something up your
own choosing
alright let's get into a a little bit if
actual pipe on now and some koto
um essentially this is the minimal
starting point for some sort of
british-based light show light show
itself is the object that takes care
rendering the main event loop its the
and primary orchestration
object in in this am you then
bring in a dispatcher for the event
something that listening to input
hardware
and sending triggers to the specific
light elements themselves
and then finally need some output where
the day to get sent to
to be turned into hardware actual events
for the
for the lights themselves the next step
is to actually create
a light element this is the thing that
takes triggers as inputs
and renders out data every frame as far
as what it should do
so receive the trigger on it says start
sending
channel date out lights trigger of stop
sending channel data out to the lights
you then have to kind of wire up some in
these pieces you get a
you have to add the output network to
the show so it knows about you at the
element to the show so it knows about it
and then finally here at the bottom you
you tell the
MIDI instrument in this case I'm using a
a Nana pad controller that
this button which gives me denote 49
I didn't decide that that's just the way
the hardware is built this is the thing
that should be connected to
that binding element
I'm so if the demigods will and then
finally we go ahead we start the
dispatcher
the MIDI listener runs in its own thread
the show is a blocking
you know run loop and
will see now if I can get this to
I've had some issues with my USB based
and the democrats are not working with
me
today so my backup is video
I can show you what this would look like
working
it was earlier
so you touch the button and you get the
light comes on
release button because of on that enough
itself is not very
creative so the next step really is to
look at
what can be done around giving things a
more organic feel
things in nature don't stopped and
start and stop very suddenly like that
and so the people who
first I work with electronic music
realize too that musical instruments
have
to have a new russia and sound in things
come months of planning of softly
on so there's a concept in in
sympathizers called
a an attack decay sustain release and
love and if you think about what the
volume up an instrument is as you hit a
key on a keyboard
things can come on gradually reach a
peak decay
sustain for some time and then when you
let go of the key in a piano the
cleaning up the pedal down
the sound falls off so we can use that
same concept
on in in lighting amplitude
up I'm actually without a border
so this is to show that and element
doesn't have to be a single light an
element can be a group of lights
and that the trigger in this case is
still a single trigger but in our fax
a whole group of lights
this is the demo to show what happens if
you have a an envelope so in this case
there's still a single
simple trigger trigger on trigger are
but the lighting element is handling the
rendering of the fading on
fading of overtime without it being
required from the control side and so it
still rendering 40 frames per second
worth
have control data
and the same idea can be applied to a
array of flights where the
behavior this element is called a light
chase
so that the behavior over time which
light in arrays let
is being determined by the light element
the trigger itself is still
just a simple on/off but in this case
we're getting to add
serve a slightly more complex layered on
the other thing when you get to these
this idea them lips is that animation
has
always brought in this concept of
twinning element so what we know I'm
into something that tends to
easy in easy out and the idea is to have
non linear motion
gives a a electronic
device a more natural and interesting
creative team or
creative flexibility so if you had
simple animations in a in a 3d animated
movie that moved
only linearly and stopped they wouldn't
look very interesting so you can apply
a range of these creative curves not
only to
brightness or motion but you can apply
them to things like
changed the rate of change of color the
rate of change in saturation
am the rate of change two things I want
in seeking create these
envelopes have changed over time and
build them as attributes have the
behaviour wannabes lighting elements
and I have more great times
love to show you but and
believe that once my once my hardware is
falling down it's fallen down
yep I miss my
my Mac Book to have a hard wired
Ethernet port alright so
not not to dwell on that here's just
some
examples have some other sort of
nonlinearity that you can get
so you can see a sort of a spray pattern
where
a essentially the velocity is changing
over time slowing down
that's one a fact
mister show some elasticity in the
motion where there's a will spring back
and it also shows
there's another envelope applied to the
edges up that light curve
the way it fade off from the bright
point in the center to the edges gives
it a
serve soft edges there's even a further
check in this demo where I have sort of
sub-pixel anti-aliasing so that the
center point out that motion is not
lockstep to a single
point and
just one more the server bounce motion
so the key is to remember that we
started with the simple LED material and
we're
working with hardware that isn't
completely dumb about
what'd renders out and intend to the
lighting hardware
it just requires an instantaneous value
to give a certain brightness
anything that looks like behavior has to
come from the software itself
and that sort of but I was looking at in
terms trying to build a toolkit for
building that's kinda
fax and in a way that could be reactor
have
worked within a real time that isn't
being pre-rendered don't see
so actually have because my demos have
failed I have one more
bonus material I will go into and that
is
around the idea of I've adapted frame
rate so I talked about
to get something to look like motion you
need to have the least ten to twelve
frames per second and that looks kinda
jittery if you've ever worked with the
books it sort of
flip books or maybe in the 10 frames per
second rate
to get something more fluid I mean if
you're a video game person you know you
want those
super high frame rates II shoot for
around 40 frames per second
the problem is that depending on how
complex the effects are and how many
other than you're trying to render in
real time that can be taxing on
on the CPU so the goal is how can you
come up with a way of consistently
delivering
the expected a fact to
and never be synchronized a certain
point I'm your frame start taking longer
to render
so in this case this is the ideal
scenario every every frame up these 20
frames across one second are being
evenly calculated and we and the color
fade each of these dart is sort of like
represents a a light and an array the
yellow lights represent for these
chasers across
went back in and that the color fade the
problem is that
if one is free and takes a while we
still want to and
at the exact same place at one second
time
and so the idea is to come up with her
this adaptive loop where
at the beginning of each loop I I
anticipate what's the
next expected frame in time frame
catlett all the values
and if I and done ahead of time I can
just sit around waiting ship the date of
and then begin the next loop
however five I'm overdue and I've missed
the mark
I can reduce the frame rate so that the
next frame I calculate I'm giving myself
more time to calculate
and and sort of give your feedback to
what the frame rate is at any given time
in this kinda
I'd I honestly don't know how other
games are other systems do it is
something I was kind of just came up
with to address my challenge here
and the result is something that looks
like this where we now have taken
16 frames to do an incentive 20
and a couple others frames have become
taken longer to render but
end result is that the end up one second
we still are where we
expect to be in the overall affect arm
that is what I have I am
so go forth and be creative and
we certainly have some time for
questions in and if you want to chase me
down I can try and reboot this demo on
and see if we can get see if we can get
a gun but non
not to worry about thank you
so take a person
and if you have some questions please
job form a line here in the mike
and and state your question spur stuff
we talk it's good to see offer you
brought this you know
as a medium on
obviously it's has the hardware
component on
but the idea like DJ is really cool
where'd you get starters for is like
equipment you know going
things and yeah I mean
the availability of that the smart
pixels is
is become better used to be I I got a
lot of my actual lights from China
director to only bother expresso one of
those types of places but
that the hardest boards available
they're pretty cheap you can actually
buy the risk it to buy them assembled
and then a number sorta spark fun in a
data type place stores
have some in the picture now but you you
really can't play with the software
until you have at least
some the hardware because the softer by
itself is pretty boring
higher
pretty on
I'm just wondering on there are other
their frameworks that seem wells needed
for this kind of thing
namely processing which connects to a
lot of different
hardwares and software owns
and so I'm just wondering year on
you think there's any particular
advantages
choosing hi time for an application like
this
and where its strengths my why
yeah I mean I would say that
against processing there is no
particular advantage accept that
I'm eitan Eastern its my by two
choice in and I'm not gonna I'm not
gonna really try to claim it better
I think one of the strengths hitman has
in many of the domains that
might be used is that there are lots and
lotsa
resources out there for connecting other
things
into it so there are lots of ways to
integrate
you know our web server duper there's
just lots of
that the Brett through the pipe on you
can ok system
allows you to hi this part delighting
system into anything else that Python
might be connected to and leverage and
as leverage to
the brat that the ecosystem as far as
the actual rendering a fax
you know processing is phenomenal I know
people done amazing things on our
cleaners with processing
right thank you