for twenty years I was a cattle rancher
in wyoming and if somebody told me that
I was gonna
by myself at this stage in my life doing
this they were found that little
improbable
but you know at that stage in my life
the idea that there could even be
this would have been more than a little
improbable
now I don't know it's fairly large group
people
and a have a hard time seeing faces 10
the later this bright on mine but to the
extent possible
at some point I wanna have something in
the way over
conversation with you even recognizing
it will be very asymmetrical
I know probably not a symmetrical the
conversation between Comcast and the
american people
his but bad anyway
and I am trying to to eliminate
broadcast media and I don't want to
become one so
I magnin I'm going to talk about a few
major principles
and in think that I think you're very
interesting but
the phenomena you represent and
and give you a little insight into you
know I I have to confess I am now an
elder
the internet I'm an old I'm in Internet
uncle
and for for somebody who spent most of
his time
a is life refusing to ever not be an
adolescent
the idea being elders is something a
drag
by it it turns out to be useful if you
can be a tad less in an elder at the
same time
BK his how you get the same desire to do
crazy shit but you
you know which greatly shit is likely to
fail better computer
for you and a that looks like fun but
let me tell you I remember
a no I
yet when I first came around
the thing that that I believe I'm you
know it was bill gibson's word but I'm
the guys are using it
sure what'd waited is when I first came
around cyberspace
I N in 1985
I it was very interesting to me
that there was already an identifiable
culture in this space that was not yet
space there was a
there was a I'm a flavor
that head and
it was just on the strength that think
with have culture
that I am got the idea that there might
one day be a
a new substrate for community to form
because I came from a small town in
Wyoming
and I could see that big the community
was based on
places like my small town in Wyoming
where
family agriculture was at the root of
the economics in
and there was a sense of shared
adversity and
real density in your relationship with
your neighbors in
and and necessity and I can see that all
those things were
being supplanted by television Landon
and
suburbia and large corporate working
environment where it was
it was considered to be good form to
make yourself out to be just like
everybody else is the corporation would
think that you were good interchangeable
machine part
I and the primary
impetus for privacy was so that the the
company that you wanted to work for
wouldn't be able to tell
that you like every other wanna the
masks that God wears
was weird as hell and everybody is by
the way I mean I
I use a marvelous you know he's very
ordinary people we talk about how the
crazy their friends word know the
friends are crazy
because because if you get down to an
actual examination people on the inside
and I their their unusual
and I mean I i'm I'm one of those people
who really insists on talking to you on
the airplane
and you hate does activity I know
I but I do it anyway
and mostly to prove to you that you're
more interesting than you think you are
and I'm which I almost always can
but I was worried about I was worried
about all those kinds of crashing
the aspect to
that way I can see my country falling
into your mind my culture or the world
for that matter with the generic aceon a
very thin
and I became and truly convinced that
that the answer this was to spread the
internet everywhere
and to you have the culture the
that shadow really
almost 2 a.m. say divinely given
inlex I and
and hearts that had been the original
uncles the Internet
have that become something grew embedded
in
in the cultures every space from there
very small point until it included
everybody which it inevitably would
and now we see everything as well I
and it I actually
it at first I thought it was going to be
a slam dunk but I mean I I thought that
you know the Age of Aquarius was gonna
be a slam dunk at a certain point to
now hype is already prepared for
disappointment
and but I really felt that there was
something that was so naturally
liberating about the Internet
and it was about connection it wasn't
about separation which broadcast media
on
I'm use the word it was about the
conversation it wasn't about that
it wasn't about the channel was about
content
which word only recently derived from
the containers my way
and I'm note that it's in code word for
word
where large corporation we own all human
expression we call it content
I am it was
it hadn't yet had the potential which I
still think in hand
giving a voice to everybody in spite of
the fact that in many cases will be a
terrible idea
and I have but led
you know I i also have faith in the
ability in
people third-degree a system where the
just because everybody
everybody has a voice says mean
everybody has to listen to it
you know so on the disc discriminating
digestive systems I think I thought then
and I still think
will devolve and I was pretty
I was pretty gung ho on this internet
and I and I thought that we were just
gonna actually slidin
invisibly into the gap that would be
that would be vacated by the nation
states as they realize that they had
nothing left
to do I after that after the cold war
and we'd gone to a global economy
and I'm I underestimated them
and I i underestimated the three
monotheistic world religions
who who naturally and I think correctly
regarded the Internet as the ultimate
harassing
because the internet is about authority
in
gathered by can sense is over large
horizontal plane
where authority is not only not
god-given it is
it is earned by a lot of other people
having exposes that a phenomenon to
their own
perceptions and judge them to be the
same views with those
this phenomenon may represent and they
need not be filtered through you
a a book or a document or something that
is absolutely positively right
this really plays hell with god-given
authority
which has been the system that we've
been operating under for quite a while
quite a while and when I say under I do
mean under United
great white column with gone on top in
you on the bottom
and mostly you know male figures in the
middle
and I'm and in three books that you had
to adhere to
and as as things are to come apart for
those
for those things they became much more
fears in there
in there demand that that their
constituents observe them
religiously shall we say and
and and moreover
I knew that the record business was was
the ugliest thing I've ever seen
but somehow I didn't think that it was
plays ugly as it turned out to be
I me what it turned out to be was ending
was so ugly that he would rather kill
itself
and everybody in it then do something
that was wise indecent
and and that's pretty much what it's
done
and I spent many years trying to explain
to them that that is actually not in
their best interest
to make expressions scares there's a
huge difference
between information economy and and on
Anna an economy have hard goods
in the sense that Adam Smith was
perfectly right about to
about scarcity in value right
it's completely different with
expression information
where familiarity has billion
scarcity not so much
I me if I've got the world's largest
diamond in my pocket
a as they're making a big 12 people
might be curious about
nobody will know that it's there and
or maybe not curious about I
met nobody will know that it's there and
on
and it will still be incredibly valuable
if I have the world's greatest song in
my head
it is useless valueless has no value
until I've started sharing with people
and then it gathers value fairly slowly
on the bases have how many people can
sing along
it's a very different thing and the band
that I wrote for discovered this
accidentally I mean we
we invented by remarking without really
meaning to
I like most other things which
effectually very
very improvisational organization
as LSD will do that to you and
doesn't give you a wide choice a
and we noticed that and that people were
we're taking our concerts and and
in the in the early days in you know the
record people Greg in folks at Warner
Bros
said we had to stop them because they
were stealing something from us and we
and we kinda went along with it around
and then we off and 11 are they feeling
I mean it's not like we're playing the
same show twice
so is a that people won't buy the
records the Phillies
10 seconds remaining and decide this is
not good for you to be mean to a
deadhead especially if you're the
Grateful Dead
because deadheads their hapless biatch
yeah it's just crew well
I couldn't do it and I think today so we
let people taper concerts not realizing
what was gonna happen with those tapes
were going to become this
unbelievably effective system
for spreading word about what we did
and and by the time we actually did
Dynomax
don't know we whether we died yet we
still seem to you know
cling to weird life but and
I would say that we were we were done
when jerry garcia was back in 95
but at that point we could fill any
stadium in in america and maybe the
world
without ever having had a hit record
based on the fact that all over tapes
had been big hits
and the fact we get all our audience
around with us
quite which yeah it's good if you can do
that
and but this brings me around you folks
anyway because
part of the reason we can holler
audience around with us
and partly the reason why that sharing
and sensitive to meet community was so
critical among the dead heads
is what intrigues me about you but I
think who's dis
I have because now there have been
cultures
associated with languages before I mean
I
not French is a good example do
I wrote here yesterday god bless you my
i
and movies in the eye inspector tire
Patrick Dale day and have I think it I'm
slaughtered your name correct when and I
who is French and
he was on both the hideous flight said I
was and we took great comfort in one
another
and I was talking about the French
Academy in French language in
and Python and how culture
and the language itself had a as
mutually defining
quality and where authority lay in that
system since
one of the things that occurred to me
when I'm when I first encountered the
end I
I turned my friend netscape or with whom
i started
the Electronic Frontier Foundation I
said at lasted two working anarchy
and he said well probably but
it's been my observation and rate every
working anarchy there's an old boy
network
and you know this case I think we may
have a
and young girl network it's coming
online to
thank you I and I that's not lip service
amina
for the reason I'm here is because that
there's actually
the you know very interesting thing
about you by fines
you you know there are a lot of music
despite the big phallic symbol for the
sack
further I
splendid anyway and I am
but butting he also alluded in fact that
there is usually a benevolent dictator
somewhere in there
and I believe you have when I I hope
he's here
being benevolent thank you
I and
and this you know I back in the
beginning a
for have computer languages
there actually were few things that had
a culture the UK to see with associated
with the language
on you see they were very small and
intense and
and often call like you know attack
TX people people would get
have crazy the realists
people that we going nuts and and I'm
and you know and then there was the
culture around seein' and Unix
their generally UNIX mean culture
where everybody look like Dennis Ritchie
but you know in those days ready to
everybody you anything to do with
computers
look like Dennis Ritchie anyway for I
but
you this is very different demeanor
Python
is you know high finance guy in stylish
and you know actually far more engaged
with
and with the party if the
over the whole then the UNIX weenies
every dream to be
you know why I went to a lot other
their gatherings and they felt they were
being pretty social if they were looking
in your shoes
I and
and this has a completely different
flavor and the and that's really
important because
because sent since I was wrong about how
the
governments in the industrial world
we're going to serve fold up their hand
and split
and since then come back with a gigantic
vengeance inner are absolutely convinced
that is their right
and do need to impose all the stuff they
had that didn't work in the physical
world
on the cyberspace given another really
nasty shot
especially game with the ability to
serve a leveraged body
on the planet in a way that they never
could have before
so you know I take a great deal
comfort in the fact that I have almost
daily conversations with aides snowden
that they can't stop
if they were elected they could pick you
make it so that we couldn't %ah go to
the bank
maybe they just wanna listen and because
it's more amusing what they're thinking
that burned and no I mean that they came
back
and they came back strong and and then
the problem is that
as things get taken over by things like
like Comcast which it certainly has no
bill rights and as things get taken over
by these new serve matter I
bodies love
international forum like the ITT
dreadful are defective and horror
I'm you
have not regulatory redress
what you have is cultural redress what
you have is
is something is much harder to wrap
opposition around but you know a lot of
things without having to say
you folks have a lot of unwritten codes
that are incredibly powerful in an
environment like this
and you are spreading the culture
openness and collaboration
and curiosity and human service
into the environment that will become
the foundations for the future
I mean I'd remove a day
and if is not a crazy dream
when everybody on this plan
who wants to know all that is presently
known about something
will be able to do so regardless and
where he or she is
and and I dream every day
where the right to know is understood to
be a natural human right
that extends to every being on the
planet who is governed by anything
the right to know what
its government is doing and how and why
and I rely almost entirely
on people like you who are building
the plumbing and who are you
really defying the politics I mean where
and one other things
in the beginning a BFF a
I
I was expressing dismay
that
he just suddenly dawned on me that
that for civil that the im the bill a
writes the United States Bill of Rights
was a setup local ordinances
that actually only apply
within the confines have
places where that government that had
supposedly advance those those notions
could enforce them by having at the same
time the ability to take them away
and that if you are moving into an
environment where they didn't have that
ability necessarily
you're also moving into an environment
where they didn't have the ability to
extend them either
that rates were not something that you
could count on any government
or body to extend
that rights had to be parted the
technical architecture
the the Internet
and you are the people and people like
you
that that you'll attract and your
numbers you are the people that will
define that technical architecture
and we'll make sure that that dream that
I think you share as well
will come to us and that we will end up
being extremely good ancestors after a
thank you
yeah we
when you're from music you like to be
able to do an encore not
ahead him now I would like to do some
Q&A
I ever get any be a long time right
who's the guy with the cards we got some
time
time is up 020 plenty of time actually
okay great now
I can't see sure what I'm gonna actually
at
depend upon is the guys with the Mikes
will
will take them to somebody that they
think might have something interesting
to say
I
thank you very much for your talk
on you talk to a bit about rights i was
just curious
how do you define a right well i've
I define a right as as the generally
recognized ability of somebody
to do something the
that some may wish they didn't do but
that they are
allowed to do because it is their right
I mean
and I'm you know when I think you have
the right to free speech
what I think I've is that you know
there is Sam's stonov a bitch
that I disagree with categorically
who has the most odious toxic stuff that
he says
and by god I I am I'm going to defend
that
mother fucker head that's what I think
about it he has a right to be
that person as long as he doesn't get so
toxic that he insisted I
share his views and that i right writers
like that a right-to-die
right is use
the ability to manifest yourself against
the powerful in a way that is generally
accorded
the a kinder sovereignty by
by those within your culture thanks
thanks for your top gun I just had a a
couple a
related questions one in the future we
read by the way they need me questions
you can
you can come at man united abner now
definitely
questions 'em what one just sort of
dealt with in this current
a row were shipping all over data to
clouds that are
controlled by few large big corporations
and
it in this future is is privacy
and part of our life liberty and pursuit
of happiness
if information is so freely available
that we can swerve
quickly look up anything about anything
and as the cloud
and storage and compute costs were is
where the race to the bottom seemingly
between
at the big providers on the the Longhorn
the tent has been connective idi
and now we see and initiatives like
internet go to work
emerging with Facebook trying to bring
collectivity
two places in the world it could have
probably never been before
answer curious how you think that may
play out is
the the future unfolds million
there's a lot done by more than that I
but
back like I say I came from a small town
wanna things
about coming from a small town is that
nobody has any privacy in a small town
me everybody's really famous small-town
and and so I grew up with that
without that sense that you know other
people to know everything that I was up
to but the thing was we had mutually
assured destruction capacity if somebody
wants his house I knew where their
bodies were buried do DeMint and then
it was best just not disturbing in
on either side and
the problem that I have at the moment is
that yes I I think
privacy is doomed and i actually think
that privacy is actually a little kinda
pathological
a mean that the the reasons that we want
privacy are not good reasons reasons we
want privacy here
because we fear the judgment have love
organizations that should not be
exercising judgment over those matters
as long as as long as we can as long as
we do our jobs and do them well I don't
you know if we go home in and also do
three bags and a cat that's our
thats argue I and
so but the problem is that we don't know
what judge miss those large institutions
are making
theirs is under a cemetery that is
getting worse
between the the loss and privacy and
party individual
and the rank No the maintenance of
secrecy on the party the institution
and this the secrecy part
were it partly to disguise their
complete incompetence I think you'll be
pleased to know that they're nothing
like his
scariest a they make himself seem and
they would be better advised to make
everybody
see how they are certain we wouldn't be
so afraid of them
but nevermind that I it is really
important
and it is important to everybody in your
YouTube you should find himself san
Leanna
in an ad snowden composition
I is very important to open up those
windows and let the light shine
in there and and make sure that secrecy
doesn't go on
units units uninterrupted state I and if
you if you know something
you think that others have a right to
know
and often is the case that you that you
do there's another organization I found
it with
with mine greenwald daniel ellsberg in
and more pointers in Jan
be sacked mention Jourdan very recently
did first did fun wiki leaks but also we
r
taking care of people like ed in anybody
else wants to come out of the woodwork
and so
if you are one of those folks if you
want to come out of the woodwork
we will we will protect you and see that
good things you have to say
get said no way that they can't stop
yeah
and I recommend your checking out the
freedom in the press the
foundation we gave it very innocuous
name I
because it we're also we're also
building open source tools
a for easy to use encryption
for journalists and whistleblowers and
we could probably
you like your help on that so check it
out
there's a so
Barlow is a guy who his arm build a
community that's right around
yeah corporate infrastructure with a
firm hand
what her advice you have for communities
like this
no have lessons learned from the stuff
you've been able to build both in music
and within this current space were
and the suggestions you have for this
community continue to grow itself can
prove itself
I resist ideology
I but but encourage believe
and it's a fine line but I mean
ideology selling it happens in your head
belief in something it happens in your
heart
and you know try to make sure that your
operating from somewhere south have your
head when you're when you
imposing opinions on people and try not
to impose billions and people who when
you can dreaded
figure out ways to get the consensus to
work so that
so the urine be rollin on this game
together and that's one beauty beautiful
things about an open source movement as
you can after beer this stuff doesn't
work
on IMEI really I think
my best advice would be that you go on
doing what you appear to be doing
I because I I know there's politics in
your
life among humans but
really that doesn't seem very political
by my standards that I've become
accustomed I think it's
I think you're doing the right stuff on
over here
you mentioned a minute ago
belts building open source tools for
helping journalists
a.m. with infected communication on
personally to me it seems like on better
access
too easy in cryptic communication for
everybody is a very positive direction
to go
on seems like you agree with that
sentiment what
technologies should how
can we do a better job that is there
somebody who's
his advancing that that we should be do
you think that we should be paying
attention to and
and how can everybody in this room
make help promote that well you know i i
I think the folks at you know that
generally are
in the in the senate or I
and its many manifestations are really
doing great work
and you know and our farming it out in
creating community
you know sir above the larger toward I
thats it's one area where i think is I
see
allies to level like confidence in do
you see that as something
that each did can and will move
too deep pervasive in all traffic that
everybody
II phases I think it's you know it's in
there Bradley everywhere now
you know there's a there an awful lot of
a to are packets on the Internet what's
up
and you know and I think they're all
kinds of things that we can do you
simply routinely make
things invisible or semi visible I mean
you know if F has is a ATP HTTPS
everywhere program you know you just put
a plug in on your browser in all your
your the communications are pretty are
been crafted Hurley's they were until
recently a
patton now I don't know I
with my head you know you're the people
who will figure out how to solve that
quickly I hope
the hell up
I agree with you when you say
government surveillance as bad and I
also agree with you when you save it
anybody should be able to find out
anything they want about anything
in order to do that I didn't quite say
that I mean I'm
I'm Synopsys Inc yeah your YouTube it as
my filter
okay on what you said so so my grip may
be flawed
on I
but yep get nevertheless both of them
require the same think the acquisition
correlation and dissemination of data
and
arguably the differences are how the
information is acquired
sometimes without consent or knowledge
and sometimes with
and the dissemination of data years
either controlled or free and open my
question
is how do you reconcile the fact that
they both have the same
needs and requirements
and ultimately goals other than
evil verses good well I don't know they
have the same goals
I mean and i sorry anyone im the
community that is being served
so anyone can find anything if they're
in the right community
government surveillance is the
government community and and the
security community Ryan the other side
is everybody well-accepted
you know that the reality is it doesn't
fall out quite like that i mean
the interesting thing is that is that
I've been consulting to the NSA and CIA
for twenty-some-odd years
on and you know that I have my
constituents in their
you really believe that the the
objective that the whole enterprise is
to figure out what the truth is
and tell it is in in as
on the influence and burnished ways
possible to the people who make
decisions
so they actually make the decisions on
the basis is knowledge rather than
then hysteria and both sides believe
themselves patriots
dade they they do because they are
agree you know on I've been recently
trying to get
the conversation going between couple
a friend to mind Mike Hayden in
in at Snowden guy this is so far been
steady work but I've
a I i think im
yet how I think it is possible if I can
if i cant
comp have a conversation with them in
like them both so much maybe I can bring
them around
to to sharing my opinion but I
you know you could just
and thing we gotta watch out for is not
just data acquisition data
you know actually the more data
something evil has the better off you
are
because it you know if if you're trying
to find information
you like in the needle in a haystack
analogy the first-order businesses not
to go out and exponential increase the
size the haystack
which one do is get a better magnet and
their magnets get worse
and and we're spared their despotism by
their incompetence
they they don't know the difference
between data and information and there's
a profound difference between eight and
information
information is something that a human
mind is found relevant
and making that transform is really
important important
answer really that that the thing that
you wanna
get down to you is is art what did they
find relevant why they think this is
important what makes this information as
opposed to something else
what do they intend to do with this
information once they have it
what are the empowered to do whether the
visibly impaired to do and not so
visibly powered
an those are the real questions it's not
whether or not they can get the
information because
at this point anybody even halfway
deadly
on it can take the digital slime trail
that you're laying down every move you
make
and roll it back up and know you well
that's not the issue its it's what you
do with mister
yes %uh first thank you for a
terrifically interesting time
and my question is you cited the roles
%uh
religion and governments as
the institutions that are sorta putting
had put the brakes on
the revolution have open this in
collaboration and they're coming back
with a vengeance
but I was wondering what you felt was
the roll up the corporation the
multinational corporation in particular
as well you said that you thought we
don't have any real
regulatory redress only cultural redress
and I would think that we do still have
regulatory
reject dress in the sense that it's the
roll up the
corporation and money in government
that's preventing our democracy from
being you now playing its regulatory
role on
I think perhaps the nation states really
have
mean their power away from their power
they no longer have much power but it's
the money now and the corporations that
are driving the government's
and as a late especially in the united
states for instance
you know the Supreme Court is enabling
corporations to completely
co-op our democracy but have you totally
given up the Hope Love
you know regulatory political redressing
rains on the corporations that way and
if so how do we combat that problem
well unified completely given to bed
hope I wouldn't have so many are BFF's
lawyers dredging up to
to do we re battle with those windmills
everyday
I but then
you know the the the problem is
everytime
every time you rest your face in
regulation you
you extend its life span in a way you
you give it
you give it credibility that it doesn't
deserve
I you know so people were we were
talking about getting net neutrality
from
from FCC rulings and I granted over a
short period time if that if the FCC had
done what
it's similar bodies were doing in europe
at the same time in terms in
recognizing the necessity for a
proliferation of the Internet
feeds we would be in the same shape
address in the world
industrial world is and having really
great
choice is an internet service in
you know and I'm being much more
advanced than we are in the United
States where
word you know the goal I make comcast is
about to set a standard
something that will really be outta you
know The Hobbit trilogy but
I anyways it it's a bad situation we
have here we could have made a better in
a certain critical point with
with I regulations and and obviously
getting the the public entities to
to rule on monopoly you know i mean
these guys these guys claim that they
rendered
they're interested in free markets where
you don't have a free market if you've
got a man are market that is dominated
by monopoly
that's not a free market I and
you know you have to turn their rhetoric
background I'm say well yeah I
were for free market let's break up you
got dem na please
now will have a free market
but
you gotta have government with faith an
power enough to do that and
you know the present through
yellow-bellied government league and
Washington
and do you think the Internet community
on the pipe on
or open source community has the power
itself to bypass government's control
over the corporation's I mean if the
corporations are themselves
you know a source up Reaper repression
and
you know holding up this revolution that
you seem to be
you're kidding how do we then without
the use of government
or in conjunction with it actually
battled the corporation you I think
they're I think you
you have the key word there by Best you
know be sneaky
and I mean they're going to get there
was a point in my generation where
people had
to had members occurs at resistance
already
and I said mine said get around
authority
you know just be like good soldiers way
you know smile nod and go out and do
what you gonna do anyway thank you also
for a great time
I think that actually a Korean
revolution is still coming
so I'm with you on that and I hear
is slow but steady this monster yeah
min you couldn't a I
actually here a contradiction what your
saying im hoping
this from a paradox yeah maybe so
I think that we need a very minimalistic
government because there are literally
crazy people
who will killers and win and they're
also
external foreign governments that
unfortunately
still are run by dictators who is only
goal in life is to
take us over whenever so I think we need
and minimal government
and a problem I see is that people are
fighting
like the lady just before and you seem
to approve more regulation
and I think we need less and what we
should advocate is a cleaner
as you say more visible very small
government yeah
I'm
I'm there's a there's there were a
number have
their Mike what you'd call prayer
contradictions
you what you just said but I'm
you know I
I'm all for I'm all for some government
I me I'm really
I'm really all for government does
things like you know
a mixture that that kids don't starve in
school
you know i mean and it seems like a lack
of sleep return a list ik but
I mean I i'm really all for government
that that makes it so that if if you
don't happen to have your medical card
when you show up in an emergency room
with two yr limbs of it they don't wait
around right if I know whether or not
they can admit you
and I'm no I I
they're just a lot of things that I
think government ought to be there to do
I don't I'm not
I'm not forgetting radovan entirely but
I'm
yeah but I
but I am for localizing it to the extent
possible
I because I think it that what we
what information technology is done is
to create this let
level a government that is exactly the
wrong level at about the nation state
level where there's so much information
that has to be processed at that level
that the whole system just urs September
late
and doesn't work anymore I mean is I i
expect to see the greatest
renaissance in the city state since the
Renaissance
because that's the part I'm that's the
pro-government that I think will work
and and and work interactively was irish
space well
then it is that a sign that says 0 also
saw
I digit very soft sup
certain okay well edges of stop sign so
I will be year today and tomorrow I'm
thank you all very much for being here
in
and being who you are