pleasure to introduce Kate Hudson and
nichols a comment
who are going to talk to you about
technical on morning
training and mentoring please a big big
round of applause
hey everybody
welcome to our talk sa house icon then
for everyone
Kenya play roller coaster
um so wanna talk to you today about
technical ongoing training and mentoring
and my name's Kate Middleton I'm a
software engineer I
and live in San Francisco California I'm
because Akerman
I'm that picture that's not her I'm
sufferance their
at membrane I'm also a graduate from
high grade academy
and I was there first senior engineer
love that ok
to join in and bright and I've been
helping on helping increasingly with I'm
already
each successive new junior engineer Jain
yes so the reason that a call and I
submitted the stock in the first place
is on we both had very separate
experience as a different companies
where we join the company we worked
there for a while
we reached a certain proficiency at
programming and we look back
on our time unlike we could have gotten
here much faster if there had been
any sort of onboarding at all and so we
turned around and create a program to
respective companies to help new
engineers get up to speed I'm in so we
came together and submit the stock
so what is
onboarding for the purposes of this talk
onboarding is
the process up taking someone from
outside a team and bringing them in
making them a happy productive an
independent member of the team
so today we're specifically going to be
talking about onboarding junior
engineers
am but a lot of the things that we do
mention today
are useful for people of all different
skill levels alright
why do you care I'm gonna give you four
major reasons why you should care about
on morning
I assume that everyone here probably
does already care since you came to the
stock
but I want to convince you that all
morning is important not just in general
but important
now so the four things I'm gonna talk
about %uh the productivity of the
individual
the park tivity of the company the
productivity of the team
and bonus diversity in at
the productivity of the individual so
this is a category that most people
think about building the skills at the
new engineer getting up to speed on your
tools
there's another category in this which
is their confidence and happiness
a lot of people think that confidence
follow skills when in fact
skills often follow confidence competent
people are outgoing
excited to learn new things they reach
outside the bounds so
ongoing is really great for increasing
both the confidence and skill set
have new engineers the productivity of
the company
companies care about money as they
should and so on morning is great for
her
for the bottom line more productive
engineers make you more money
and that's great and everyone's happy
because the company is making more money
the party of the team
this is really important because as you
add new engineers to a team
the team fundamentally changes with each
new person there's
a lot of things about how you don't
really know something unless you teach
it
and this is absolutely true for company
culture in process
if you can't explain your company
culture to a new engineer
and you can't explain your process for
shipping code
then you don't know it yourself and so
every time you add a new engineer
you should reiterate this post the new
person and also to the existing team
so you have something a little bit more
like this and as a team grows
this becomes increasingly important for
example at LinkedIn
at a certain point every new engineer
they added was decreasing
their productivity so the new ISP p.m.
engineering had to come in and revamped
everything
so that adding new engineers didn't
decrease the over overall productivity
other team
so this is one of my favorite questions
that I have ever made up
am I use to coach high school JV water
polo when I was in college
and at like 14 and 15-year-old girls are
beginners at water polo
and have these really philosophical team
meetings no I come in like posters and
so I come in with this one day just
trying to explain to them the importance
of teamwork
and I told them your guys ability to win
as a team
is the sum up your skills and talents
multiplied
by your ability to work together as a
team and this means that you all can be
less skilled
or more mediocre water player water polo
players who work together incredibly
well
and you can be teams are people who are
theoretically more skilled
or more talented but don't work together
as well and you can see this
in engineering teams this is absolutely
true no matter what the type of team is
am there's a lotta really big products
out there like
gmail was is one of them that were built
by teams have less than 10 people
some even bought by teams at less than
five people so a small team can be
highly productive
especially if they work together really
well
are a bonus category diversity how many
have you have read the doctor Seuss book
at see about the speeches anyone
okay spin again so it some to children's
poem about kind of this society where
some
some speeches have stars on their
bellies and others teachers don't
it's about the division that happens
within the speeches because I'll
the stars on some belizean and the nonce
as another cell
I use nature's to represent diverse city
diversity can mean many different things
so this happens a lot in tech what you
have is a homogeneous group
and they bring into the fold other
people who are like themselves and they
have no onboarding
and this works because the new person as
a lot like the people who
are already on the team they probably
communicate in similar ways
and they probably have similar hobbies
and interests so getting up to speed on
all the social practices within the
company
is easier for this person they need us
onboarding and it gives them an
advantage that they're like the existing
group
however if you would like to hire people
who are different
than the the team you already have you
don't want something like this to happen
you don't want people to feel
like they are outside the group and so
having explicit onboarding can help with
this
enormously a having a way to bring
people up to speed both on social
practices and team culture
in a way that doesn't rely on the
existing social structure is good for
diversity
and if you are not sold on hiring people
who are different from the team you
already have
feel free to come talk to me afterwards
him
alright cool shit on board at this is
either a picture up a bunch of and
scaring some food
or buncha people carrying a boat to open
to interpretation but
the idea is you should spread out the
load you don't wanna burn out on
boarding mentors
am actually a lot of people on the team
can mentor
and on poor people in different areas it
doesn't always have to be someone who is
incredibly senior
yeah at event bright I was paired up
with someone who was
really skilled and talented when I was
trying to set up my dev environment
initially
and for all his skills and talents he
hadn't recently set his environment up
so he didn't know you know the recent
wearables are not a bug that were in the
system
that say the most recent person to set
up their system did
so in the end I found someone who had
done it more recently
and he was a great help to me in setting
up my environment
so this is another great way to get more
people involved
just right away in someone's integration
into a team
alright how should we think about
onboarding at a conceptual level you
want to maximize the return on
investment
I think this makes sense to everyone no
one wants to put in more than they get
out of something
this is a really common inefficient wait
on board but I see a lot where
new ongoing mentors are like I'm going
to be the best
onboarding mentor ever and we're gonna
do everything together and we're gonna
take all these coding classes and by the
end of three months this person is going
snow
everything that I now and that's wildly
unrealistic and also leads to a lot of
burnout
and then companies are like we can
support emerging engineers it's just too
much work for everyone
so instead of doing something like this
I think bumper bowling is a better
analogy
which is it's also the only way that I
should ever Bowl set up a world
where the junior engineer can play
freely and make mistakes and you don't
have to hand hold them to the process of
getting up to speed on things are
learning new technologies
you can really kinda believe them check
in periodically and make sure that
they're roughly on the right track
track I am but they have the freedom to
explore and grow without burning out
ongoing mentors event bread I feel much
more
comfortable writing code and breaking
things with impunity when I know it's a
well-tested area
the code base so that I know that I'm
not gonna push anything that's gonna
break anything
production and give me a panic attack
yeah
so from a technical perspective having a
lot of automation are under development
environments and deploy
is really useful for hiring junior
engineers you can create
places where they can go and play and
not have to worry about it
it's also important to note that one of
the tenants have expertise
is the ability to set boundaries in
scope in order to scope you have to
understand the domain space incredibly
well
and so junior engineers by definition
are not good at scoping
and are not good at setting boundaries
because how could they be and so one
other things to think about is setting
these boundaries for junior engineers
making sure that they have this world
are they understand where they are and
what they're doing
so there are three major categories to
think about anything about how on board
a junior engineer
the first as technical knowledge
normally people focus most of their
attention
on technical knowledge like ninety
percent of it I think it's only roughly
a third of what you need to get someone
up to speed on
another third as the company knowledge
in process how do you ship code how do
you decide which features get built
I'm who is in charge of things and the
third the third category as personal
development
so like I said that confidence and that
a project we were someone feels like
they are independent
progressing is hugely important not to
mention the fact that if someone feels
like they're going somewhere in a
company they're more likely to stick
around
cell now you've hired a new junior
engineer
how you get this started really I'm
boarding should probably start from the
moment they accept your offer
but for our purposes were gonna define a
on morning
as the process of getting someone up to
speed until they can be
reliably independent you can they can
ask questions but you can set them up
for the project and know that they'll be
able to get it done without just
floundering around
so it there's really a critical first
week and probably the take at least
three months for any engineer to get up
to speed we're positing that probably
six months or years a better estimate
for junior people
so we call this week one it's really
arbitrary chunk of time number one
this is the things he should get started
as soon as possible
like a Devin by admin as I mentioned
buddy them up with
the most recent person who set up their
system
this is an opportunity to get multiple
people invested in their trajectory
introduce mentors and make those mentors
people who can be non-judgmental
as well as a technical resource
you also want to show them where you
keep technical resources
let's say a book that you consider at
your company to be the definitive way
that you do Django your company
point them to where they can find that
resource and they don't have ted flatter
and invited themselves
or not one thing that's really handy
is if they Journal our blog in keep
three things per day or per week
that they've learned or three things
that they didn't understand
they can do this for themselves but it's
also useful for them to be able to touch
base
with their manager a mentor regularly
and discuss these things
one thing that I do at a membrane and I
still have it right now
is document called things I've learned
and this is literally a Google Doc
that's fifty pages long at this point
and contain things like commands I
seldom need to run
but don't want to have to look up every
time in our documentation
like for example how do I update our
we run sconce we make sure that our RCS
everything is up to date and 22b inside
my room
outside so this is a place for me to
keep information like that
and also just things that I've learned
that I want to make sure I return
retain but I know I won't remember all
the information the first time I hear it
it be great if you can get on the ship
code in their first week but make sure
this is a
very small piece that's not very
technically complex
this is really just an opportunity for
them to learn your process around
shipping code
and not so much about the technical
challenges are being an engineer
I think this is Kate favorite slide have
a social event if you can so that they
feel like they're part of the team
the more likely the more they feel like
they're
and socially integrated with them the
more likely they are to ask questions
and you definitely want your junior
engineer to be able to ask questions
so this brings us to arbitrator time
number two
we suggest that you introduce them to
the
history of the company and any coding
philosophies at this point rather than
let's say day one when their brains are
already overloaded and they
can't possibly remember it this is still
useful information for them to have
their
so give it to them in are to return to
have time period to
one thing that I really wish I had when
I started at a van Praet was
a team at someone either hold a piece a
paper
or a document available online to say
this is
Alice she's great with automation this
is Bob
he's great at things that begin with be
so you should ask him questions about
that
and make sure this is a permanent
resource that they can find I know that
people move around asks and everything
but
even if they just have Alice automation
Bob
be related things let's really handy
especially when it comes time to ask
questions
probably my favorite part my own body
experience and a membrane was the
introduction of coat lads
this is an opportunity maybe two or
three times a week for an hour
for junior engineer or however many
junior engineers you have
to sit in a room with a senior person
and
ask in a totally safe space whatever
questions they can think I have no
matter how stupid
and it really does need to be a safe
place to ask those questions
otherwise they're likely to just button
up and not bother
when you do this though make sure that
the senior engineer is the kind who can
do so without judgment and is good at
explaining things
that's are really important facet up
this
questions that your engineers likely to
ask in this can be things like
what is rabbit how it is the Django or
am work
what is salary or even something like I
have this bug in my code and i cant
figure out what's going on key walked
through it with me
it's important to ascertain where their
knowledge begins and ends
so in this feel free to ask them
followup questions
to make sure that you're starting at a
place that's useful for them
and this is another opportunity to get
more people invested
engineer engineers development because
it doesn't have to be the same
engineer who's in the room with them
every time you can have someone friends
on Mondays for
questions about JavaScript you can have
someone on Wednesdays whose full stack
you can follow the Jenga request cycle
throughout and maybe Friday is a guest
star
every week or something like that so
this is an opportunity to spread the
love
and get your team invested another thing
that's a great tool
is shadowing either an hour a day or
maybe a couple hours a week
for a junior engineer to sit with the
senior engineer and listen to their
thought process
so the senior engineer will say okay so
now I'm importing this thing cuz we're
gonna need here
and then I was thinking about
structuring it this way and this is an
opportunity for the junior engineer to
sort of get a sense for
thought processes and the way that you
develop code and your code style
rather than getting serve bogged down in
the details about where that semicolon
goes
this brings us to arbitrator time number
three
we suggest that you introduce one on
ones at least by now
if you haven't already and this is a
once a week probably 30 minutes at a
time
where you can set aside to talk an
manager to engineer about
roadblocks or check in about anything
that
the engineer has on their minds and
one thing that we've introduced for
later engineers have started after me
is the idea love I'm five-minute
presentations so
a senior person or a manager approaches
the junior engineer
and says here you should check out Bloom
filters
let you go research that and come back
to me
in a week and tell me what you learned
as you guys
have probably figured out by now it
probably it doesn't really hurt to have
experience in doing presenting
early and often it's a really good skill
to develop
and probably one we should all start
sooner and
and if their manager supplies that topic
of conversation like
decorators our generators that they know
that is gonna be really useful for the
junior engineer
this helps them also home their research
skills which as we all know
is also really important and
murderer as Kate mentioned we learn
through
teaching so this will help them keep
things in their brains
so goal-setting is also a really
important
this is energy engineer and their
manager probably
sitting down and talking about where
each of them expect the junior engineer
to be an
a month or three months or six months so
if I say that I'm really interested
and pursuing data and my
manager was expecting that I would turn
into
a friend and engineer there's probably a
mismatch there
we need to figure out how to make both
of us happy and
this is a great opportunity for someone
is more senior tech help set up some
intermediate steps
to get them there
for example short term goal can be you
should be able to find and fix a bug
based on a century ever
or comment meaningfully on someone
else's code
and then once the junior engineers
achieve this to have a sense of
accomplishment
they'll feel like they're really getting
someplace lb confident when they
do for their endeavors
so it's also really important to give
engineers feedback on those goals and on
projects that they receive
I think a pitfall engineering is that
often we say well you could have done
this better
or here's a way that you can improve
which is really useful information
but equal useful is you did this really
well keep that up
that's equally good guide post for
learning and will help them
continue to feel like they're not a
total failure and engineering
and reinforce their imposter syndrome
which probably a lot of them have
so arbitrary time to time period for
one thing that I do periodically is
review concepts that I learned
previously
in coal ever examine ball I'll say okay
so
here's what I remember about response
and I'll go after a couple of minutes
and saying everything that I
remember from the last time we talked
about it and then my
buddy my mentor my senior engineer can
say yeah that's really good
this chunk that you missed is also a
really important so make sure that you
keep track of that
so this it is not only for junior per
engineers personal development
it also gives them the input about that
chunks that didn't exactly sink in the
first time and if you're anything like
me there are many of these pieces real
get
a large chunk of the information the
first time and then some in the details
will dribble out the side
make sure you check in regularly with
your engineer it's really important to
you just give them an opportunity to
talk to you openly
and it probably seems pretty obvious
that they can do that but you'd be
surprised how much of a difference it
makes if you say
are you having trouble with anything is
there anything I can help you with it
kind of opens up the floodgates in just
give them a really good opportunity
give to give engineer offer and maybe
this is an opportunity now to
spend less time shadowing and have them
start co piloting
on a larger project with the more senior
person
so this is where they can take turns
driving
and if you went to drivers ed like ideal
then the person
who's more experienced in the passenger
seat has a secret emergency brake that
they can use
if anything goes seriously awry so they
get to you take a bigger
role in a project but also have the
safety of knowing that there's
someone who can help them when they get
stuck
so once you've gone through this
continue to check on
check in on goals and Taylor projects
and collapsed you
how they're doing it's a really
individual on organic process
so one-size-fits-all isn't gonna work
here
stick with the things that work and
remove the things that don't
so one thing this really is what this
point though is assertive in formal
apprenticeship
where a senior engineer take more
responsibility for junior engineer
and passes on the domain knowledge the
junior engineer gets bigger chunks of
code that they are responsible for
and they're really serve under someone's
wing
and this has the added bonus have
training the senior percent if they're
interested in it
to play a bigger role maybe in running a
team are heading towards management
one thing that we haven't really
discussed though is how you really
assess
how someone's doing or how you fix it if
they're not doing as well as you like
if they're on this middle trajectory
anything they have the potential to do
much better
how do you do that and really the answer
is communication
and let's say you talk to any find that
they're not really is confident
in their coding as you want them to be
often suggests an
an answer will lend itself to question
at hand
so if its confidence for example then
maybe you set them some
small quick wins that they can do to
make them feel like
they're really getting it or if they're
picking up some bad code habits
take a look at who their mentors are
they may be picking up some things that
are
okay for senior engineer who really
knows what they're doing but
habits you don't really want to instill
in your junior engineer when they're
straight out the gate
but do remember that not everyone comes
out the same this is an
eighty a finish line that everyone hits
but you have the power to set them up
on a better trajectory and I'm sure
you'll take that seriously since you're
here
but it's a good thing to remember I
would like to mention that the
last slide was technically incorrect I
for some reason
drew asymptotic lines as though that
people can
like never achieve anything above or
below where they're at and that's not
true
on cell you should just know that that's
lighters and cracked but
when you're thinking about the
assessment categories for people if
someone isn't performing
up to the standards that you think they
should be performing too
these are the five categories we came up
with to take a look at so confidence
code quality communication judgment and
technical knowledge
we've all worked with people who are
insufficient in one of these categories
and so it's important to realize that
it's not just technical knowledge that
people
need help on so a lot of times judgment
is super important
are they building the right things
because if someone is building the right
thing it doesn't matter if they take
more or less time to do it
they're going out to the right place at
the end of the day
so this is our coda this is my
contribution to the slides in case
you're curious the rest
markets responsibility an I'm burning is
problem like any other that we face in
engineering and it's really best solved
through
iteration and feedback and revision in
if you take
one thing away from this presentation
let it be keep the communication
channels open
this is the best way to ensure that
you're both on the same page and your
really getting somewhere but if you have
space in your brain for three things
lead PB is 6s is not just
being the most technically skilled
there's a lot of areas where it's really
important for people to develop
it really benefits everyone in the long
run
and everyone can be involved it takes a
village to raise a child
I'd like to think that it takes an
engineering team to you bring
a junior developer on board successfully
okay so hopefully you guys are convinced
to start improving your process now
one other things we talk about a lot as
engineers is code at we all know what
this is
and were terrified of it and I'm sure
all your companies have lots of it that
you are sad about
but people don't talk a lot about team
that or
management at which is essentially you
accrued at
with the employees that you have on your
team if you don't take care of them and
you don't pay attention to them
and so on morning is the first step and
making sure that you minimize the
steamed at
so that a year from now you don't have
people leaving because they got off on
the wrong foot
wouldn't have any help at the beginning
so we have a repo
I at this link where we have some
resources to get like give new people on
Python and Django
we have some other rubrics for assessing
others
am so if you all want any resources you
can go there and if you have questions
please ask them now thank you
thank you very much we have about time
for one question
I and I'm gonna have to walk over to his
Mike stand where people will see you who
so one question please hi
thank you at great presentation I was
wondering if you could talk a little bit
about adapting these techniques and
ideas towards disturbed him
that is a fantastic question
um one other things I say about scaling
a team is that
the thing you're scaling is actually
communication communication is its
the bottleneck great you have a small
team and everyone can talk to everyone
and as you grow that's not possible in
the distributed team I think
communication is really like the cock
that's the crux of what's going on i
meani people to be looking in Kate about
the process ease about what's going on
and all the different stuff
so am other things we talk about will
still work
mean you could have a virtual social
event I'm you can still have people help
set up Devin fireman's but I think I
think the biggest thing is really
focusing on the communication channels
because you're not going to be able to
get information to
to a more developers without that with
you
resource on our Repo Men helps code from
afar when your parent helps pair from
afar
when your coding there we go and see if
you check that out
I might help right
thank you