time make sure my clickers working here
alright
an so I'm terrain as you mention I'm the
cloud security product manager at space
asa my job is to basically build
products that our customers meet
at are used to be very security needs
his partner configurations
and i'm paul caron I'm I saw for
developer on park and which is a key
management service for OpenStack
and in my spare time I unfortunately do
a lot of crypto
me happen so well today we're going to
talk about the the state a Kryptonite on
sale
we put this talkin months months months
ago
and account since that point we've
actually been working on a lab rat will
talk about tonight the kinda does little
bit have
trying to solve this problem and bites
the running joke in our
our community is organised libraries
that it's basically at library created
by people who make poor life choices
akers working in crypto is something
else for sure
Selanne and kinda get started 10 things
you want to talk about a little bit as
well you know what we actually want
out love a crypto library I don't know
why the want is no longer on the slide
but or pretend that it's there an so as
to what outlook
at am at the crib to libraries weather
products that I'm working on a rack
space is a protocol barber can't it's a
a key management service
for OpenStack which is an open source
cloud platform am in so 10 things we're
looking as well we're going to do a lot
of
crypto working mark and so we need to
really understand what the crypto and
kind of
landscape is and pipe on because
everything in up its act in Python as we
really want out there looks are what we
what we wanted a crypto library
and so the first thing we want to be
able to do was to make sure that we have
the standards that algorithms that we
need
right and so what are you reading
library for other people going to use
that are reported to be open source
Kansas in the knees in our ability to
make sure that all the standard
libraries are available
i'm for you know whatever use cases that
your customers want
in addition that we want to make sure
that was open source right so everything
that and that is an open tax patchy do
everything that we work on not
everything a rack space but most things
at work on a rack space or open source
and ends from a security standpoint you
know
it's always a little bit better if the
code is open source and you can have
access to it you take leaps off on it
yourself
competition what's going on and we want
to have a pretty wide variety of
a python sport right so we didn't want
something that was locked 227
we wanted to be able to do by three we
want to be able to do Pai Pai and some
the various options that are out there
and finally we wanted something that was
maintained
ends strongly test and 10 things that
would notice in a lot of papon
options that are out there now is that
there are kinda varying levels above
both those things
I'm is a really what we're looking for
in the grand scheme of things is
a consolation %uh features for these
libraries that make something that we
could build on for a long period of time
right crypto code is not something you
want to go in and screw with on a
day-to-day basis
am into something that we could go in
and build something on a provide
other people that would rely on for a
while discuss something that we were
looking for
sale we want to look at at what was out
there
right so we lifted you know open SSL and
boat and crew plus plus
and the crypto API and an assassin
coming crypto Angie crypt in porous is
Alan all these libraries that are out
there i mean they're just
doesn't does libraries the people put
together and one thing you notice about
all these
is dead they're all written in C right
am
and Sue why is that really the case and
for those of you who probably already
know the answer this its that see allows
love low-level control that you cannot
get with me as languages such as Python
are specifically there are things like
timing in memory attacks on
uninitialized memory I is but the timing
is actually wanted most extensive
problems on
when you do things in crypto it's very
important to do things constant I'm
that means if you succeed if you fail
what kinda bite you just processed all
those things need to be
that they should be relevant from the
standpoint of the amount of time and
ideally the man to power consumed by the
process
are so those are things that
unfortunately Python for all its
wonderful part parts cannot offer us
right now on
we obviously would like to have existing
code I'm well obviously we just talked
about that and
it turns out to be an extensive amount
of existing code in crypto
whether or not its goodwill you guys can
draw your own conclusions for the moment
but I'm
it is exists on review code
a now again some the more recent things
might imply that the reviews are in
maybe not as good as they should be over
in the seaside
but in general these projects have seen
a lot of views
most of their code is well reviewed
maybe not so much in the Taylors
extension component
but in general I and you can try largely
trusted especially I
obstetric primitives with things like I
did
GCM allows you to do that by low-level
behaviors using actual hardware
extensions to guarantee constant I'm
so these are things that have been
developed over a longer time her very
reliable
on in the future there are there are
some interesting languages that are very
fast like Rustin go that may have
in some ways it to get away from C but
the moment if you wanna fight then the
only game in town to see
think we managed to make it about a
minute half before we made open as
objects
pretty and it's better than I thought
Springett
alright so we kinda went what did at the
major libraries in series we were gonna
look at all on there are dozens and
dozens and dozens and dozens but we
decided to try to pick what we thought
was a reasonable sample of what people
actually use
rights open SSL zombies the king daddy
that's you know that the most common
that you see it
that's the most widely deployed used in
all kinda platforms all over the place
an and assess which was originally the
netscape library which is now mostly
used by Firefox to do
am hold its crypto although to use in a
couple other is he a red hat uses a
quite different
is a quite simply as well so that ones
out there INEC el cielo
which were actually was call salt but no
one ever does
an and then our boat on which is
actually a relatively interesting
library I am it's one of the C library
that actually has a
a little bit better testing store even
most and which is why we can include
here that kinda interesting that case
I would come a computer from Apple we
look at the the Microsoft
an outside of things and what did at lib
secret which
when we got into this neither mister
never actually heard of an
and we were kinda shocked when we look
at the download counts and with G crib
was like
super high up and I and it turns out
that it's mostly I think a Debian been
that arent
yet the debt debbie has some strong
views on freeze offer of course in so
lip Gy trip to New Deal SRR something
they push I'll libraries to use art
group art packages inside the Reapers
you
yeah 08 ended up being quite widely
deployed much wider than we thought and
so we can spend a little time looking at
that and say
if you look at the top 10 at the supper
we cared about why we like we care that
it was open source
we hear that it was cross-platform right
we cared that it
was maintained an we did wanna look at
kinda
ubiquitous is kinda a little bit of
subject to measure but like how likely
is it that you as a developer or
consumer
your library we have access to that
particular piece I want to make sure
they have a standard algorithm so that
you can go and actually
nope ass for GCM and a GCM right and she
one thing that
be I'm not sure how much we care so much
about one thing it does come up in
incur conversations especially with your
larger enterprise customers
I'm is its compliance for comic right
here compliance and both which
are have granted by the US government
these days so I'm not
sure that we care as much anymore I
cannot stress enough you do not want
phipps
alright yes if you're going is open as
is I'll don't use that range that's
that's messed up
an seow anyway it's one of the things
that like you do hear about it
I think you know the NSA is pretty much
screwed up for everybody at this point
so I'm not sure that we care so much
anymore but it was something that we
looked at
an and of course you know I mean open
SSL comes out on top
now which is not too much of a surprise
I mean it was kind of what we expected
going into it but
there is another piece there anything
like any sales really call unfortunately
it doesn't really have a standard
algorithms that means that makes it
kinda hard
am so many things are really hard to
build and they don't necessarily work
too well in certain environments
obviously the Apple stuff and then
Microsoft stuff
you a reasonably good but some others
not open source it's obviously not
available on different platforms
and so having access to it is is not
super great answer
we're looking at these these type things
open as I was kinda were will spend most
of our time talking
and but it will talk a little bit later
there is we kinda allowed for ways for
people to use some of these other
options
and some cases there are really good
reasons if you're sitting on top of the
an Apple device are sitting on top of
something running Windows to use those
particular platforms rather than using a
bundled up messes up
an in fact on people that didn't have to
patch for part leader probably happy
about that moment
although they might have had to patch
for good while
an so kind of stepping up okay now we
look at the C library so now we know
what the state in the world is in see
those are our options right
so now we can look at how old what what
how papon can actually use those
libraries rain so there's a a series of
kinda Python libraries here
with an empty crypto pack up to open SSL
the pipe on a Sat skies and boat and
also has a a
area pipe number seven so we cared about
here was kinda what back and optical
fiber used so what's the library was
using actually do its work
again we care about maintenance and we
care deeply about Python support
right so we wanted to make sure that we
could do you cry 3 a.m. we could do
pipelines and these are the kind of
options that are out there
am which tends to be somewhat of a
problem for libraries that are dumping
everything on it to see
and we wanted to look at the stated
review for all these you'll notice that
the answer is no one told them this is
not a knock on anybody
and doing reviews like having
professional curb their reviews for this
type code
I is really very expensive and if you're
doing it right and pipe on you generally
not doing any crypto operations in
Python anyway
and sell not super critical but it was
something that we wanted to come to call
out
I lastly come completeness is very
subjective the kind of that
musical notes or whatever that we had on
the structure and say oh
am one's attention to call out since the
time that we pitch the stockpile open
SSL has actually
up rebased all in their library on top
of our labor could party which will talk
a little bit about later
and still sony's answers with the ass
tricks are basically because if you
take it as it is today it has much
better options than it did
about performance guestbook an bytes you
know some big ones that we saw I mean
obviously no pipe higher pay three
support
an and you could do just are just going
to maintain a while ago
yep just a few months ago yep so he's
been getting it get it working again in
those types of things
an you know and mostly kinda pylon sport
was a big problem for us and then of
course
Pike richter which is by far the most
widely deployed by Tiger to library
an which is great is that has its own
see back in
so it's kinda bespoke see and Britain
for themselves specifically for that
library
it's never been audited by anybody and
doesn't mean it's necessarily good or
bad just means that that that work has
been done yet
an and of course boat owners really
quite simple to build and install
I remember correctly yes easy to build a
boat and not so easy to get the python
bindings
I'm you know but the most important
thing for us that you can come out is
looking at is that almost all these
Python libraries
basically require that you was the
developer have a very deep understanding
of how the C library works
these are very very thin layers they're
not really
necessarily by phonic it's really just
like hey this is like literally the same
name that you see in the open SSLC code
is exactly what it exposes
in Python and you better know how to
combat and you can crash pipe on very
easily and you can do very bad things
and and it will prevent you from doing
any about and CEO there's no kind of
you know non foot gun version A B
libraries you're almost guaranteed to
blow your toes off unless you really
know what you don't
an after all that we looked in that okay
well do we view as always options
right we just went through 20 or 30 or
whenever different libraries do we
really need another one
and of course the answer that by any
real developers yes
an so Wikia
we don't want and Sue today we'll beat
any limit I'm talking about
on labor which we got to talking ask a
target I L
ads on Gabbert under pipe argue I see a
slash retire if you can
plan a pattern the main goals that we
wanted to achieve with
I with library was one to expand are
tested to make sure that has all the
modern arms that we want Sep
especially all the problems that we have
a TLS which will be a lovely talk
tomorrow
about the state of the lessee shall go
to that an
you'll be able to jump to something your
arms like to see and making sure we have
afford security all these various other
things are becoming much much much more
important activity porn for a long time
we just
chosen to ignore them pets having access
those modern our names is now getting
very very important wanted to make sure
the library was really really strongly
tested
and when those things that in fact we'll
talk a lot about how we gonna do testing
photography
and want to make sure that there was he
was a CDP I was safety faults so that if
you as a developer went and tried to use
it the same way that use every other
library right you have a problem solved
you on you do some searching you figure
out how to do it you take some coding
hey it works
right right well we know crystal and
that's hard because and
working and not working can look the
same right and CEO
we want to make sure that if you did the
same thing that the same thing was safe
right rather than having to know that if
you happen to pass one into this
function it turns out that that
completely %uh validate all the work
that you've done
I wanted to sport i buy my dawn three we
want it has on it was maintained
obviously
we wanted to have no known broken
options are libras out there right now
that
kinda for historical reasons are various
other reasons include things that are
known to be broken
and they're just expose like everything
else so if you don't happen to know that
and you use them then you've just
rigors of and then of course we want to
offer high-level API which will talk a
little bit about
when we get there say oh I did want to
call on all the people involved in Qatar
be because
working with open SSL enough to drive
anyone insane and so that the top four
contributors up here according to have
her on the top
one of which being Paul which are kinda
general jokers the Paul writes all the
code in the rest of us just reviewed
am in there about 30 or so people are
not going after all modestly but
there lots people who come hang out in
10 things I wanted to kinda call out for
this is that a lot of times
people think they can contribute to a
project like this if they're not going
to experts
and that's really not true and we've had
this I think
and at least five or ten other people
down here helped us with packaging
obviously we always need people to kinda
read and try out the docs and tell us
where they suck
opinions on a TI design various other
things are always important
right so you don't have to be a crypto
expert to come and help right and so if
you're interested in this
security is a thing that that you like
to get involved in a creek is something
that the kind of
floats your boat then come hang out on
IRC channel there's a link to it
an at the end that the talk here and you
don't have to be a crib to master be
able to do in fact I most definitely not
help I am but I do have a lot
alright so let's talk a little bit about
the actual structure the project
as a cryptography is based on see if a
fire which is a problem
a python package that allows you to be I
think business if I fans out there
so devise a python package that allows
you to define either
at the Abir Devi level on a set of
functions and then
binding into your Python code so that
you can pass back and forth
from sea to bite on a vice versa I
provide a buncha rappers are not seeking
to put Claire
and I'm character pointers and also to
other things and translate them into
Python strings in backing for them
do things that nature I'm which is very
nice along with allowing you to register
things for later garbage collection so
that way you can actually a
can hand out of the Python runtime and
not worry about any that stuff
I so at the very bottom where we have
our bindings on are bindings are
exactly that I'm in the primary case
there are a whole whole lot of
open SSL functions they're bound i'm
open SSL has a very
interesting API but that is not
particularly reliable
from version to version or even patch to
patch are so
we have a lot of if deaths unfortunately
but you know that just kinda mimics the
openness is only be at this point
on so at this with this is the layer
that actually on pay
up sorry excuse me this is the loop I
open SSL consumes
as a 0.14 which I wouldn't like to call
out and think JP
very very much for actually going ahead
and doing that I'm that allows my own a
cell to run on by 2.3
my pie and also frees him from the
burden of ever having to deal with any
the C bindings again and soap I opens as
I was now pure Python package
I'm and if the m2 crib to maintain
happens to be in the audience I would be
happy to discuss whether or not that's
possible to do for you as well
I'm at the next level we have has met
layer
SoCal it is literally called the house
met layer on to do use it
you use I could talk if you don't have
met II
this is the layer that allows you to do
things that crypto allow so that means
anything that you can do in crypto you
can do in here that include shooting
yourself in the foot
on in fact this is the lair where
shooting yourself in the foot is pretty
likely
I so we would prefer people not use this
layer however if you know what you're
doing
well we can stop you we certainly
written a lot of documentation for every
single function that exists in it
we talked about every single block
cipher every single screen saver
all the different padding modes for our
say we've exposed whether or not those
payments make sense
whether or not you need to be no how you
do thought length recovery in
probabilistic signature scheme things
that major those are all there and it
has met
those are all things ideally you
shouldn't really need to worry about
because at the top where we have
the recipes now the moment we only have
one recipe so
your unfortunate have to you has made
let you into a whole lot
but the recipes are designed to be
one-shot russians a one-shot they're
designed to be box and box model where
you can
send in some data sins and bites get
back some bites
and not have to worry about anything
else on so right now we have
Burnett which is actually a on Azad so
that would be an authenticated
encryption with additional data but
are yet to really know about it is it's
encrypt the data but has our NH Mac for
authentication to verify that no one's
change the data
so you get to generate a key you passing
data and you get back your income today
to
and then when you need to be I'm the
crib that you do the exact same thing
and that's all you need to know you
don't need to know what initialization
factors are you don't need to know what
announces you don't need to know the
difference between the two is
which by the way even kept our first
will have trouble telling you the
difference
II and you certainly don't need to worry
about whether or not re you serve those
things is going to be a problem
or how many bytes you're allowed to
encrypt before you're gonna start having
probability of
for use and things of that nature so a
certainly a anybody who's interested in
in these sorts of things recipes are
where we actually your ideas
we want to know what your use cases are
and what you need to solve
because we can't build recipes or at
least trying convince crypto Gophers we
know
lbh is now considered you I'm
we would certainly a like to know those
that that information's week actually
build these recipes appropriately
alright so as part of this whole system
we have a concept called back ends
on our system is built to be agnostic to
the underlying C library
and that means that you can choose
whatever back and you want
maybe you really hate open SSL maybe you
think are clear is just the tip of the
iceberg
and you would rather go over news coming
crypto I'm come crypto is
actually currently are preferred back
and %uh no están I'm we don't actually
implement any the secure transport
component so
know the part that had recent bugs are
implemented
are you however I we also have a concept
called multi back in
and the purpose a multi-pack industry
eventually allow us to basically
composed
as many back and says we want such that
you can choose
I actually wanted use poly 1305 which is
a
a DJ beating from from the salt library
and I want to use that beat I'm
with a yes for some reason and why you
do that maybe Wed
are maybe when you charge I and you want
to add have you wanna hashed out against
Blake to I'm those are things that right
now there are it would be very difficult
to do wanna see library but within our
libraries that allow you to compose
across the
the different back in San it will
actually stitch them together such that
you'll be able to accomplish those goals
on obviously as part of this the ideas
that NEC backing can be included
on we've tried to structure that the
system such that the Bakken can either
implement
all the different interfaces that we
have or it can implement just want
so maybe on one back and you choose to
employ the cipher system and the cipher
system says okay I understand the
concept a block ciphers I understand the
concept a symmetric ciphers
upside block ciphers stream ciphers I'm
and then
it also understands the ideas behind are
saying Tsan
it can handle 8:30 p.m. TOTP which are
one-time password a
protocols that are backed by each Mac
and they the
you can bill all these things or you can
have one that just says okay I only
implement hasher's and
actually I only implement this one hash
on which when in this case would be like
something likely be too
which is an implicit implementation
oblique to public too was a a
cha three finalist a bit actually has
very similar security properties too
shocked though the finals for
the winner shot to on chunk 3 was
actually chosen because it was very
different from shot too because they
wanted
not keep all their eggs in one basket
yes i mean that
the idea multi back in as it gets really
powerful one we have the ability to
include come single-shot library is
likely that script or it would be to
your various other things
along with open as a seller various
other things right so you can choose to
use a particular library that you want
and then if you need a function that's
not part of that it can fall back on
another library in a different back and
and then you is a developer in the
pipeline Co don't have to change your
code media's things
so for example you know what when you're
looking at her bleed or something like
that if you're running Python clued you
literally could just
flip a switch and use a different back
and right and
that's a weird use case but it does
allow you to do those types of things
and also allows you to write a singles
and a python code that
on when to run on different platforms
will you different back and depending on
what the platform that supports
yeah I mean a more concrete example of
why this might be beneficial as
if you compile and so there are ways you
can use Python code in iowa's in their
ways you can use Python code
in up another unusual platforms that are
not dust-up
on on the Iowa side now we have not
don't go out and try this year cuz I
actually haven't tested
but common crypto is bug has the exact
same interfaces II says it doesn't know
is 10
so if you are actually capable compiling
a
the Python you need then this code would
work just fine
in Derry in theory deep am so i didnt I
meant before I want to talk a little bit
about
how we do testing the testing was a big
consideration for
the library that we want to choose
something we want to make sure we did a
really
really great job in so as in right now
every time that you
run what we call Crime a single test run
Inc retard a free
you're running about church the
sixty-six thousand or so
tests an and then it each run is
basically a combination of a whole bunch
of actors and white whatever back in you
using and what have a platform you're on
an all these various other things right
so for every build that we run which
includes every single PR that somebody
puts an anytime that we're running a
full build
you're actually doing 77 abuse runs
right which works out there's 15
about 15 bill today we average between
10 to 20 which works out to be about
almost watt 5.1 million tests per build
which means that right now we're doing
about $500 million tests per week
and to build right now takes about 20
minutes so it kinda depends upon the a
how how busy Travis is and whether
notching conceals like working but I S
in general we take about 10 to 20
minutes to run our bills
yep so we also do 45 docking station
bills per day most to this is don Travis
Sep there any time as people in here
thank you we take up an enormous amount
of their infrastructure
I think we're like in their top five
people for wrecking their stuff
an we've been helping them build a
python support though so hopefully it
works out
an and then we also have our engines
builder that runs on top a Rackspace
Rackspace gives us a free card account
to use for this and we've got
25-28 builders are splayed servers that
run down on it
there's 24 actual Jenkins builders which
means there's less servers but
we actually run our tests against Ubuntu
1204 I sent us five-cent 064
a because 65 plus real a actually have a
later open SSL that doesn't have a look
to curb disabled
we also run tests against I was 10 10.7%
10.8% 10.9%
FreeBSD 92 FreeBSD 10 and I believe
there's a few other things in there that
I'm not remembering
young might building open as OpenBSD
builder since we discover that they
forgot to include parts %uh vocalists
obviously
am cs3 the type of thing that has the
infrastructure actually fines for us
which is very nice
an but it is an absolute enormous amount
of attesting the kids are now obviously
when you doing local development you can
run subset to these kids are basically
running kinda business
myer which is not so bad and of course
%uh many things get skips depending on
various platforms that you're working
with and some other types things these
numbers are a little bit kinda estimates
but
yes %uh the biggest challenge we've had
with our testing infrastructure a plate
is that we are
we require one hundred percent code
coverage on ok
no patches ever allowed to land for any
reason knows no pragma new covers
allowed
on so the only way to land only actually
reminds me
we have a bunch Windows builders but
forgot to mention on the only reason any
patch neverland as if it's when I resent
code coverage
and its past peer review so no one can
ever merge their own patches
I and usually there's three or four
people who end up
reviewing any one of our patches so
at the end that we am into usually with
any reason we size matches about a
hundred
comments and mood we generally require
use putting a patch up a bit exceed
about a hundred lines maybe 150 lines
ago
there's anything we're good at it bike
shipping an
they realize what we currently spa right
now so I we have a good selection this
matter albums are out there now that's
what we tackled first
and lotsa stuff so any MBAs to the you
expect clearly a troubled as Cat five
any type things are all kinda in there
am obviously there's more work getting
done there I think there is a patch for
some
sows I'm trying to land sea but it turns
out that everybody per so subscribe talk
if these problems right now they're
probably all here so nobody's actually
going anywhere green
an at pretty good support for each
Maximus the h-back stuff that you would
an you would want is there we also have
a constant I'm bit that was
submitted by someone in this room Julian
cress you mean we will be in the room
like to thank you feeling
doing constant I'm comparisons and
Python by the way not easy
an when you just go down and see a UNC
Yuji
am so we got some key derivation
function so that
at PKF to use I with the track it KDF
I we did one time password stuff so this
is due to be an Asian if he is there
grew up in Decatur algorithms that the
use for their app for two-factor
an got RCA signing verification
an get the permit stuff we talked before
which i think is Soroka rate
so once again did you know those
rejoiced extracted from some guy
internal use cases at her local
and say we talk a little bit before an
you know we've
we pulled in a much tougher the process
a panoply things and cartography is that
first level kinda creating the bindings
right and we write has malware stuff on
top of that mankind up the the recipes
come on
come up on the top so as we pull in new
see back and various other things settle
you expose the ability for us to do all
these various to protect things
Amsale let's go back in and review
little bit I'm kinda but the beginning
we talked about what we want a crypto
library so we wanted our in support
rights to the fact that we do multi back
and gives us that rates if you want to
use
NEC Alan you some other weird you be
stopper whatever you can do that
and you can also have a back in that
supports the regular standard algorithms
that are out there
right and SIL gonna sell obviously is
the big one that we use our ways but
most the time on
but of course you can use whatever back
in it secretary sports
it is open source the holdings under
Apache two am most the people who were
involved at least the beginning
upgrading this were Rackers at this
point it's pretty much wide open as
people from all over the place
an and all the world to you add palin
supports so
am boobs bad competing John am
so obviously we supports an 26 27 32 33
34 in pipelines all this work
and then there after maintain from a
means test we talk about testing
as about over 30 people now that are
working on on Qatar be
I would like more if you did to join us
if you want to come in hang out
whether your'e crypto expert or not we
would love to have you an
so talk a little about kinda what's next
SOA on the future work side and there's
lots to do still
I'm we've been working on this project
for home she's nine months
no guess maybe not quite that much n but
there's just
I an immense amount of work still to go
a while we
you may have noticed that we wrote that
we have our say signing and verification
and that does include a relatively
complex component PKC is 1.5 actually
very simple but oh ATP are
sorry there with the PSS my case is not
at all on
however we don't actually we load keys
right now
I'm so if you guys wanted convert them
into integers and then load them
directly through
than the work fine but most people
probably want to do that so
one other things we really need to work
on is we are happy to see is one in pDCs
aid
key loads I world's gonna probably look
at OJ BK and some other
be keep the G cereals Asian stuff I'm
we also have of course DS a signing
verification and as part of that we will
be defaulting to deterministic a I'm
so those are you familiar with the essay
signing it turns out the DS a signing is
unbelievably sensitive to the quality a
random number generated I'm
and if you do not have great random
numbers especially the Jazz reuse it
every time
then you can lead the entire contents be
proud to keep very quickly
is actually how the PlayStation 3 was
cracked they had a new CD is a privately
that they were using to sign their
firmware but the use the exact same
signature
letters are the exact same generated on
Brendon Kay every time
and because of that they lead everything
and then that allowed custom firmware
which
I guess for that we shall thank them I'm
but im we will definitely turn it now
defaulting deterministic a
up and then of course we have a nice big
question there around expo ninety less
out we're pretty sure we're gonna go
ahead in implement this but this is
going to be a long term project
X 509 is a very large spec in incumbent
Nick as politics so now y'all September
all the San Juan so those are all things
there in openness is oh those are all
things that other libraries but exposing
them in what we would consider see maybe
I am
me like discussions and if you guys have
an opinion about those things come talk
to us
we're happy to hear more more opinions
doesn't mean are right
fact most the time and probably wrong a
and of course the less
a we have obviously much did there's
much to talk about it. last but I'm
going to let him do that at the source
said about the sale tomorrow so you guys
y'all
definitely attend that you can learn
about how everyone does everything
really really poorly
and there's no end in sight
however maybe there is an end in sight
at least on the pipeline site we we will
be spending some time talking very
seriously about what a teal SAPI looks
like
in the near future how you would
implement that and allowed to be
composable with other backends
such that we don't actually have to
implement the the semester credits cuz
we have no interest in doing that
on been the final days we're very
interested in some the last comments
metric minutes
a those things that are more about DJ
beware on which be things that salt
mackail-smith so those are you really he
calling itself an
so toucher 20 which is actually a so
just a 20 is a derivative salsa 20
and actually Google is very enamored of
it so %uh charge a 20% with poly 1305 is
a Mac
are the are actually cipher suites that
google has implemented in their Taylor
stack and actually supports in chrome
right now
now they're talking with I ATF other
people about whether or not that becomes
an official thing and he was 13 or maybe
even sooner who knows
but those sorts of things are becoming a
little more common as NIST has
kinda hurt their own reputation I'm
that's not to say
I that their crypto is anyway anyway
actually bad but
their reputation has been damaged in
that means that people are looking
outside of them
a either to things like crypt wreck
which is the Japanese body there's a
there's European one that slipping my
mind at the moment
there's I'm giving Korean ones which is
actually the CD album comes from which
is another 120 but whatever
I so there's lotsa stuff and there's
lots more work to do i mean there's even
things that aren't on here many many
things are near Lexie Mac
which is a way of doing max using block
ciphers
that is a wealth it will standardize but
its bill Italy unused
and there's something weird we're
definitely interested in like ultimately
we want to become
a cryptographic standard library only
hopefully better maintain
than standard libraries usually are
and i mean that that ultimately our Argo
the sale admitted to get a blank
obviously the
garvey Diana it on Pepsi can install it
we actually put a
minor wheels up their search should
install and a precompiled for most
severe
now now by
X white aggression by binary wheels are
not I i are very difficult to do for
Linux and OS 10 points are so you can do
them on Windows which is what we have
been for which is also the
a platform that small least likely to
have a compiler if you wish to install
pippin
if you wish to keep in stock photography
I would highly recommend having the open
SSL have
headers and also a compiler and then
most that
work we hang out on RCC weren't retarded
ass dev which leads to not only people
talking about this library but also this
many people to come to talk to other
people because they happen to fight
yeah we we didn't use the most data
specific name for our project
new now an so we can to happen to do
this little bit we can to tweak the
slides this morning's wanted a
to have a little bit more time for
questions am so that's all we're gonna
cover for now
I guess there's a at microphone over
here somewhere
so if you like to ask questions please
come up if you're going to some buzz
about cricket things ask Paul not me
please don't to me it's really easy
her a guy's great are thanks some I just
wanted to
ask you mentioned implementing in sn1
parser
are I was wondering if you knew about
pie sn1 in a few rejected it or what
so we have not rejected in any way I am
familiar with buyers and one but I don't
know enough about it to know whether or
not it needs some
what I need so I would very much prefer
to do it all pure my time so the fact
that bias and one is pure Python and and
supports
hypothetically everything we need is a
big encouragement but that would be the
very first place we look
cool thanks the use of it's on the list
of things to do we have decided how to
do it
speak in a pure Python feel free to
slimy know about this wrong but
did you guys actually craft and document
away to guarantee the minimum and
maximum runtime
love constant I'm in linear time
operations for the sense that things
like age max
for is that conjectured constant or
linear time
so its constant I'm comparison because
we do it down at the seal air
where we guarantee that it takes exactly
that long now there's a transition
period from
my time to see and back however because
that's the same number of bytes in the
way to copy which
should work that should also be constant
I'm however I can tell you that for sure
okay I had misunderstood you when you
said are what you're doing in Python
emergency
thank you yes I about that because all
the constant I'm verification we do is
actually done at the sea level
I think we do have a long-term goal love
having Qatar be audited
an maybe we can con Rackspace and paying
for it an
but that'll be a little bit further down
the road I think before we do that if
you can get somebody else to pick up the
bill asked them to do
you know Isabel formal verification that
a lot
definitely be good use a money in time
absolutely
well we're talking about money and
certification if you can do
assisi or something along those kind of
the creative
I conquered here yeah um my company
uses a I think itself for cover when SSL
arm that this trips certified I
how he's so I I miss most of your cart
this coming near the end but you said
it works with open SSL um I would
imagine as long as we don't mock with
their open this is all headers each work
with our
apps certified openness that's correct
so open SSL has a 50 module
and when you have the Phipps module
engaged in there's
inside the code there's a bunch if death
just send it down the Phipps paths
I'm so if you compile cryptography
against open SSL phipps
then it will use nothing but the Phipps
patch I'm with all the commensurate
statements that that accompanies like
that early I actually had said that
I don't really particularly care for
phipps one of the reasons I don't care
for that there's regulatory requirements
and then you just need to use it but
what are the reasons I don't
particularly care for phipps
is that it does not allow for the
concept of bugs
are when you on it code for phipps when
it becomes
its complaint you can never touch that
code again without reloading
that doesn't matter if you find in
enormous game stopping
everything breaking bug because that's
been found in the open this is off thats
module
and they are not allowed to fix it
that's only in
the dual ECU random number generator so
nobody's using it to don't worry about
did thank you abrupt
hi I'm which my elaborating on why the
the Python language all a part of my
cold is no particular suitable for all
our can sometime comparisons
sure so I'll in general pythons
attempting did to optimize and do things
and as quickly as it can and in in as
part of that behavior
my final short circuit logic I'm in
general you know if you know that
after valuating you trying to evaluate
the quality of two byte strings right
and after the first byte you notice 0
actually they don't match
on so why bother comparing the rest of
them on
so that that is our in the sling
comparisons
logic right month to I mean if if you
believe your own comparison logic men
that wouldn't Tom I mean basically
the problem is with the law that string
comparison logic is not with the
language are with the
pipe on my called so 230 semester but
when you start dealing with big numbers
I'm iPhone also has a whole lotta
optimizations for dealing with big
numbers
are so if you start wanting to do arce
rdsa operations are gonna be dealing
with 2048 bit in larger numbers
and that number handling even the actual
tonight
if you ask on papon how many bits it it
is with bit like
that actually can leak i win we did I I
don't remember exactly so don't don't
take this as gospel but I believe
whatever
when the guys we have working with us
Alex Stapleton was looking at it look
like
that there was a timing attack but
potentially available that leaked
something about the number up ones were
zeros in the pits
so it's it's little things like that let
you may be able to avoid each one of
those things
if you know about them but every time
you do that you're spending a bunch more
effort trying to
figure out what it is pipelines actually
doing okay thanks
I miss the same from you have even see
it it's it's not easy to rate I mean
consultancy right pick eilers are always
trying to get smarter and sorcery
because he wasn't going to look at some
the open SSL stuff
that C code is really nasty and hard to
follow specifically because it's
designed to defeat
compiler optimizations and some other
things that are in there and it's and
it's the charitable view
yes one of the many reasons it and
be by the United so as the papon
runtimes get smarter or as you run
different run times that behavior might
change of many
you see you may have thought that you
did it right first time but then when
you're running on pipe I that's not true
anymore whatever answer
probably not impossible just hard
heights so earlier you'd mention that
the reputation UHV
miss head kinda been downgraded because
I've
the I guess arce I'm
not on our ability but you know weakling
so
I want I'm curious where you're looking
for
other standards and resources on
as months that are more reputed ball and
and what are you
can i'm saying is that that I'm the best
ones out there
so that's a great question in the
answers I don't know I'm
in general wellness missus been
tarnished because either
mean the charitable view and the view I
actually personally subscribe to is that
they were probably a patsy
they didn't they they didn't necessarily
do anything wrong but they allowed
bad things to happen and that's not
necessarily a good thing
it seems actually self-evident
that means that to me there their specs
are actually still fine
am with the exception of one of them on
there's no evidence of any kind like
shot to shit
shot three certainly actually shot three
the actual even took
publica feedback into account and they
were originally trying to speed up for
a variety of what may or may not have
been good reasons
but they actually backed off that
because community was concerned so they
they kept the previous resistance at 2n
for that the bit like and then
but I I started back to your point B
there are really a whole lot other
bodies that do this stuff on
so like their script wreck from Japan
others keyser
which isn't Korea and again I and I
apologize I cannot remember
one the guys who do it over in europe
but a
nothing really do a whole lot work
likenesses constantly holding
competitions are constantly doing work
arm so in the end either its gonna
continue to be missed a mean shot three
is
well-respected well it's not technically
shelter yet but will be soon it's very
well-respected 0
I N while people are gonna be very
cautious to an initial uptake
overtime it probably will prove to be a
good idea
I'm otherwise I think maybe
you've actually got some shift into
academia even which is kinda surprising
given academia is kinda history of not
caring about actual implementation
other DJ B is a recently been running a
a
I forget the name of his is crypto
contest but there's actually a new
crypto contest for finding new ciphers
on the just but just close submissions
and there's been the room
undersea missions and they're actually
being evaluated now and that's been this
all that was their whole emo that's how
they built but I yes was built
because as: was set up a whole lot of
rounds of competition against a bunch
different block ciphers started with RIP
bottom
a whole bunch in the end it turned into
right all which became
a yes I so that may be workers long term
but for now it's pretty much just missed
now we're at it we will crack down on
the conversations that was going on is
that you may be nice formal methods to
talk about crypto in academia
where you can actually do security
purposes with him those are still
relatively new but like
there's some pretty good formalism there
and usually lotta times the
that formalism an academic ends at the
implementation where
and most at the the bugs in the problems
that were senior implementation bugs not
political books
am in Sioux there's kind of a lot of
discussion going on in the academically
and Mac green and some other guys come
in talking about it works like
oh well as script harper's if you want
to actually build
ciphers that people can use that are
actually useful for anybody you have to
worry about the implementation just as
much as you have to worry about
be criticizing so not we'll see how it
goes but
the answer your question is whose but
thanks I was also wondering you know you
said that this was
I guess point version point 14 what do
you
what features do you see is you know
being robust enough to
to have a version wine and and what do
you envision for that
so 14 is actually play open SSL which
has been around for over a decade soho
I don't know that he's ever going to get
a 1.0 you have to ask JP
I have however on our side were actually
a 0.3 right now
a I don't know what constitutes 1.0 we
may change our versioning scheme before
we ever even get there
there's the act the heck not here he
would vastly prefer us to be version
based on data released
but we'll see hi we're using our keys
are internally
and I'm has really good support for arm
for versioned
version key material which is really
really useful in our environment do you
plan on supporting some bike that is out
something that's going to come down the
road so we're definitely interested
we have not it has not been prioritised
because none of the people who are
working on it right now use keys are
over we're aware that and and its if
you're a interest in talking more about
how we might go about implementing I'll
be happy to talk about ashes your
yeah definitely interested in like we've
been playing around with it on the side
of it but none of us use in production
and so we haven't
the whole experience with it hate first
I'll am
what he called bike-sharing incident
parkinson's love to reality
would like China later and via the
constant time compare bails out if
they're different links why doesn't it
just exploded
as like exception I don't know the
answer them off the top of my head
seems like that would be a mistake and
would be something to fail about
rather than simply you know potentially
be could into a time
attack so are we currently doing that
you have to go to
I with documentation of the code but I
was co-owner
honest to beat me I hope it is if it's
not then we definitely should fix one of
those two things
but I will have to look at that I
actually don't know the answer I'm
certainly
I would prefer that we do the right
thing
it you would prefer we do the right
thing payments pack I'm very committed
to me that
yeah it and yeah so constant I'm compare
popular topic I guess arm you mention
that
all changes require foale test coverage
and you mention that there is a constant
I'm compare function
%ah what is your unit test for cut that
actually be in constant time look like
so you could UK you hit on the one piece
or infrastructure that I'm not really
happy with the testing a jeep
and I and that is that at the seal air
I'm we can't guarantee Falcons coverage
because
well we don't have the interpretability
introspect in to see if I from there
are so everything is just a stream that
we pass and so we don't know that we've
actually evaluated
in practice the only way we're doing our
valuation love that line is basically
saying
well does it evaluate true does it raise
when it's not when exposed to
on so and otherwise we've just had three
or four people are five I don't remember
how many was
look at it and say yeah it looks like
it's protons constant I'm
do you have thoughts on future
improvements that are it's a big
question mark
so it's a big question mark to me there
may be other members the team got better
ideas about it but from
for my part I don't know the answer to
that question yet like me I dearly want
to help
better test coverage on that side but I
don't know how to go about it right now
ankle thanks Anthony we got time for one
more question
so you know recent her plea stuff
home some people are calling the opener
so maintainers negligent for not using
lips he's American Free arm for
performance reasons and on earth you
know the recent news is affected your
confidence and openness
so I a good thing workers thousands of
question
I I've been down and open SSL long
enough that I don't know that my
confidence could be shaken it cuz it was
already shaken
a home I the base parts have open SSL
are very good on however there are
things like this that happen
obviously too often cause even once is
too often but ultimately it is software
I and its offer this very old I'm
me maybe not old in some senses but in
another sense it's more than 25
this year since it was started at this
point I see the best practices a change
dramatically testing best practices a
change dramatically
10 business as a solo star the C
preprocessor was considered the greatest
thing on earth
and you needed write a macro for
everything in your macros you call a
macro in that matter she got three more
macros
are those things are not usually
considered best practice anymore
%uh so and actually even when they
originally put in their Mallorcan free
implementation there may very well have
been a very good reason for like 15
years ago
Malik implementations could it better
absolutely been problematic
not the reason the more so that's not
really a defense a
really what ultimately at my concern
with open SSL is that it's
a critical piece of infrastructure and
it has one full-time developer it has
less
it has less work going on with it then
this project
on and that concerns me they had a
three-day funding challenge I think they
made nine hundred bucks
yeah I mean like this is probably one of
the most important piece is a software
that will deploy and we all deploy
everywhere
like as somebody who works at Rackspace
right now like literally rebooting every
device that a customer has because
leon we need to patch all the stuff for
them it's an enormous in about
and nobody supported you know and so
it's like that something that will be
arguing with with our people that
to try to get back to pony up some money
at least am
because this is one of those things that
needs to be pay more attention to you
and we haven't been paying a lot of
attention
but luckily yeah so I guess ultimately
the the answer question is
yes it concerns me but it doesn't
concern me any more than a good are
every other implementation concerns me
this is just that latest email
I'm I'll see reserve hopefully serious
wake-up calls for us on the way we do
these things
yes sure they do they would love that we
welcome summer 240 million that we can
find
yep alright I think we're done thank you
very much at
figure