placed a kissy
whereabouts makes starts and thank you
everyone for coming along
to this seconds session after lunch here
icon 2014 here in Montreal annex
presenter
has a PhD in developmental biology from
Caltech
and I am he says he likes piped into law
he currently works at Michigan State
University and today is going to talk
about
dot intensive biology in the cloud
Instruments Inc all the things
please welcome Titus brown right
alright a thank you all for coming um
so I want to start with a few up-front
definitions
first of all arm %uh there's a lot of
confusion about what big data means
and I'd like to point out as far as I'm
concerned it means whatever is still
inconvenient to compute upon
if you can do the computation easily
it's no longer big data I
data scientist you may have seen this
before two statistician who lives in San
Francisco
arm and a professor was able to find a
earlier a
earlier today by Fernanda Press someone
who writes grants to fund the people who
do the work
I'm and so I am a professor
and not a data scientist because I live
in Michigan arm
and I write grants so that others can do
data-intensive biology
I also like to dedicate this talk to
Terry paper so I
Terry is ur friend who helps run the
testing in Python birds of a feather he
couldn't be here this year
on for the last five years as they've
taken on my faculty position
he's arm he's progressively grown less
understanding of what it is that I do
arm and so every year like what i'd
I didn't understand us to be blessed
your talk this year than I did last year
so it struck me that um thus up this
winter we are stuck
I don't know how many people live in the
north the frozen wastes
arm this year we had lot of snow in
Michigan its I spent a lot of time
indoors
my six-year-old are doing puzzles and
and it struck me that she was asking the
same question the Terry was asking me
and I figured that
if I could explain what I do at work to
my six-year-old probably Terry might
understand it also
so what I do is actually a sample
puzzles for a living
and and I told us to my six-year-old you
actually working on a puzzle inches
she looked at me a certain wide-eyed
wonder it said you actually get paid to
do that
said well it's a little more complicated
I strategize about solving
multi-dimensional pas
billion to pieces and no picture on the
box but it's still solving puzzles
so if you if I give you
many many many many many pieces of a
puzzle and I
ass could come up with a strategy either
through three basic strategies that you
could use
you're all strategy used in genome
assembly which is what I actually work
on
and the three strategies are a greedy
strategy reset hey this peace or to fix
this piece that smashed together
arm which has some obvious flaws as my
six-year-old has found out
arm ence where did these two pieces
patch about these two pieces how about
these two pieces
arm and then the Dutch approach and I
figure for the for pike on
the Dutch approach is obviously going to
be the right one and so I thought I'd
try and explain it this way so that
don't approach is also known as to Brian
assembly
and the idea behind it is that what you
do is you you did decompose
each puzzle piece down into small
patches and then you look for
similarities among those patches and and
essentially with these patches that you
decompose things into
can be easily Hashim compared and a hash
table which actually ends up making
turning everything into linear problem
and you're finding the similarities with
your puzzle pieces
and algorithmically it's pretty awesome
linear in time with the number of pieces
which is way better than and square
right however it's also a linear in
memory of the via the data in this is
largely due to errors in the
digitization process
if you have small errors when you're
reading the pieces into the computer
memory
those errors will cause problems with
the hashing and you end up having to
keep track of all the different tight
little patterns that you have
and so this is basically the problem
that we've spent five or six years in my
lab trying to solve I'm just to show you
the practical effect to this for about
five hundred dollars
a sequencing data today week we would
require about 200 gigabytes of RAM in
order to
to put that puzzle together to put the
sequence together
I'm and so this was a real problem a
couple years back it's still a real
problem
I within the field although we've
prevent we've provided some sleep
some approaches that help deal with it
so our research challenges
a the research challenge that we talk on
my lap
right now the only costs about ten
thousand dollars and and takes about a
week to generate enough sequence
that really know commodity computer can
handle it and even really very few
supercomputers can handle that amount
sequence
in terms of us doing the sort a puzzle
piece putting sequences back together
arm and the other problem is that
hundreds to thousands of such datasets
are actually being generated by
biologists on a on a weekly
tempt a monthly basis and so this is
really a really basque data analysis
problem
so the inverse to the particle
accelerator problem where you have one
big particle accelerator generating but
massive fines a date and thousands of
people looking at the data
here yet many thousands of people
generating dated only a few people can
analyze
so the nice thing is that over the last
five or six years we basically solved or
at least
address to this top approach and what
are you talking about today is
summer the outcomes are attempts to
address this bottom-up issue which is
that we're generating lots of these
datasets
so our research I the computer science
at her research
is that we've built a streaming washy
compression approach and basin week
newsweek unbeaten
each piece it one at a time and say have
we seen this piece before not enough we
have seen the piece before
we can discard it and decrease the total
number pieces were looking at
I and it turns out to be a single-pass
algorithm it's really nice and low
memory and all that
we've also invest heavily in a lot a
probabilistic data structures low memory
probabilistic data structures
I talked about last year and we're now
to reached a point with a computer
science research where r Memory now
scales considerably better skills are
thematic information on the puzzle to
base the size the picture
which is always much smaller the number
pieces we have and this I is sample
dependent but typically it's 120 if
there are less than the number pieces in
the
in it that we have in front of us the
other research approach in
the other competitor research is arm
really was
was addressed very nicely by Fernando
this morning so I'm we've invested
heavily
coming for the pipe and community I've
invested heavily in things like open
source open science open access
reproducible computational research
using tools that are pretty familiar
here and I really never heard of in
scientific conferences
so use get hub we use automated testing
these continuous integration have a
literate testing framework that we've
just
put in place we r blog about our stuff
we tweet about our stuff and use I pipe
and a pic to do all over data analysis
essentially our papers do come as
Fernando says because here's the data
here's the GitHub repository here's a
make file tight makin here's your
cures all your data analyzed just as we
did
I'm and as part of this we've been
extending our efforts into more general
protocols
so our papers are on our software but
then we also want to integrate are
softer into a larger ecosystem
love of stuff that people actually used
to do biological sequence analysis
and for for that purpose we've actually
been developing these protocols
arm and applying them to tackle squishy
biology problem so I thought I should
put a real biology
slide in these are our two organisms
that we work on the find of the Costa
France they look basically like rocks
for
for disguise their sea squirts and this
is what they look like underneath their
tunic
is actually the gun at which we can
harvest eggs and sperm from and
Tom generate embryos which we then do
horrible things to
arm so a um these protocols are actually
directly useful for real biological
purpose is my me to talk tough the rest
to the debt for the rest my talk is
is are trying to understand how these
protocols perform computationally
so the the trick is rather than writing
a black box pipeline a set of scripts
the fee data into an
outputs something arm we actually
Britain a set of tutorials
for running through date announced from
start to finish
in the cloud so the great thing about
the cloud is you you know what machine
you're gonna get you know it resources
you have you can configure it exactly
the way you want it can be 100 percent
reproducible
it's we've written these tutorials which
can go fine on mine very easily a social
with my blog post
arm and we've written in English with a
buncha shall commence
just basically know how to use ssh and
and start up a cloud machinery to run
them
up and then us we've been using them for
education and actually on Monday I'll be
getting supper carpentry
tutorial that's running through some of
these I'm but then we've also
said we'll why stop there why not do
literate testing so what we've done is
we've written a a
arm a a very simple shell script that
actually runs through all our protocols
pulls out the
shell commands and then turn them into
shell scripts that can be run for
suffered for purposes
one purpose is for to competition so if
people wanna swap in different tools and
run
the same workload with one thing changed
they can do that for usually
we've actually implement them as
acceptance tests on our actual course of
her which is integrated into these
protocols
and then we are also using the for
benchmarking and that's what we talked
about the rest
and I think one thing that that we've
been seeing is that when you actually do
all this when you do these things
correctly you have everything and get
have you have everything automatically
tested
abuse it sorta becomes unstoppable of a
force for forward momentum in science
because I'm
we don't have to worry about bedrock are
our our our backs are protected because
everything that that we do is sort of
automatically I'm run on a pretty
regular basis
with a few exceptions okay so
this talk will be about benchmarking so
when I get to some benchmarking
sir benchmarking strategy was basically
to go out and find how are protocols ran
on real computers
arm and I real computers I'm in Fig
computers that you ran from Amazon
Rackspace
so we went invented a bunch of cloud
VM's weeks track to the commencement
tutorials using our leader
resting framework and instructions for
running all this and then we use this
neat package that
we'd never i'd never heard it before but
that several different people found via
Google and sent to me
arm cops are which is I am
system activity report I think part the
sister package 26
simultaneously sample the CPU RAM and
disk i/o that is currently happening
and from that we get output that looks
like this which is this is really quite
call this from an iPad for notebook in
matplotlib
figure I mean what you can see here is
for
data subset the takes about an hour to
run we have the CPU load in blue
we have the RAM a load in
gigabytes in red and the disc 2000
transactions per second and green
we can see for the entire run over
protocol which goes to quality control
and some trimming and filtering and some
assembly and some
differential expression as a lot of
different things going on but all the
various different
CP requirements disc requirements and
arm
this artist requirements and memory
requirements and just keep an eye on the
RAM
the whole purpose of our research
program for the last six years has been
to decrease
this red line to the fiery can run on a
lark larger right if computers
so each protocol as many steps right
labeled them the quality control digital
normalization which is our software
assembly annotation and differential
expression
analysis and we're really most interest
in the RAM intensive bits which is the
citadel normalization and the assembly
and again this takes about an hour and
when you're running on the entire
protocol
to a forty-hour so this is about this is
about how long it takes to run through a
protocol for
a Saturday the cost about a
about a thousand dollars and took about
a week to generate on a machine when you
can see is
arm things change one reason the whole
day to set
a arm the did you norm phrase which is
our software takes less time but then
the assembly actually takes a lot of
time is very
arm a fairly intensive CPU eyes and uses
a lot of memory is someone predictably
and then actually uses very little disk
has very little discs s
so this is arm this is our complete
protocol run on
a sorry is our our protocol on run on
the entire dataset
okay so we have all sorts of numbers
like this on a repository encourage you
to go dig through them if you're
interested
well kinda conclusions did we reach so
one observation is that Rackspace offers
by default faster machines
so for the 15 gigabyte machine that
we're using arm it took only thirty four
hours to run for our entire protocol
for cost about 23 bucks arm and then the
various hours on machines were
considerably slower although
given the different cost you can depend
whether you are optimized for latency or
for costra
doesn't either you can you can pick
about the second observation
and this one is something that I would
love to hear phiri's on is that the
the Amazon ephemeral storage is faster
than the EBS block devices
even if you turn the IOC's performance
all the way up so what we did was we
have three and wondered x-large machines
here
these are 15 gigabytes of RAM arm and
that's basically
and a couple 100 gigabytes love local
ephemeral storage
and when we added other for the data
disc or for a working desk
arm the max on my ups I'll operations
per second
onto the data disc for the working desk
we just slowed things down steadily
and I should say this all cost money
so we're paying more money to get worse
performance
and I didn't factor in the discussed
here this is just the per hour us the
distrust on a 24-hour basis are
essentially negligible
I'm and the only thing I can think up
here in this is Mike my current working
hypothesis is that
we're paying for with the IOC's is
better average behavior arm
whereas the federal storage frequently
can be better but they don't guarantee
that
they don't guarantee the the worst case
scenario could be considerably worse I
see a few people nodding
arm I'd love to hear from you afterward
if you actually if this isn't the gas on
your part
um okay observation number three
a so the new architecture is arm a
an important aspect a big mission such I
let me take a step back so all over
software
rights the all our software the cage for
I'm works with really large hash tables
what we do is we gone we allocate
you say I want to use a hundred
megabytes a hundred about memory
and i won its put on for hash tables and
he's a probabilistic data structures and
we use them in this way they implement
account minsk at which I talked about
last year
and we use them this way because I'm
it's considerably more memory efficient
than any possible
a exact data structure but you have to
specify how much memory you using up
front
when you have these big hash table the
%uh indexing into randomly
you run into something called the
non-uniform memory access Architektur
on multi-core on multi CPU machines
their different parts for the memory
that a preferential access to each
for creatures the CPU's and so if you're
on this EP if your computing on the CPU
and reaching over to this memory will be
a lot slower potential even if you
reaching
to sorta memory that's local to that are
sepia and so here
um we're showing the effects of the
slowdown what what I did was
a slowdown due to the sort of long-range
memory access and so we did was we took
a constant ask a very small task the
took about a minute
on ARM with small amount memory
and he did the same task over and over
and over again with increasing amount of
total memory use all the way up to a
terabyte a memory
we do have data sets were we need to use
a terabyte of memory sources all run on
our HBC because right now I don't have
any cloud computing machines offer
filter by the memory nor did I want to
pay for them so
arm VR the total time here
is in solid blue me basically see that
you go from something that takes a
minute or two some critics almost an
hour when you got to tear but a memory
now this blue line could be caused by
the fact they are allocating a terabyte
of memory need 20 it out
maybe the allocation phase is really
slow so I separately benchmark to the
post allocation phase and we can see is
computing on the same day to on the same
machine
but are in slightly in considerably
larger memory
you get it really significant slowdown
just from the fact you're accessing so
much memory
and he can get the ratio is the lost
time ratio due only to the RAM access
you can see that arm you get a 20- to
25-foot slowdown
for for odd increasing about a member
using by
by I such a great great amount so Bowers
a I was quite a surprise actually effect
we knew from running at that this was a
problem but
from watching while Granderson probably
never really benchmark to this extent
so the next question is quite can we
just use a faster computer while his
rent a faster computer
so turns out Amazon now offers an m3 to
axle extra-large
and M three types large is a computer
that has to forget about
SSD drives and it's about forty percent
faster cores
and we see we run our demo date is that
we get about a 30 percent
a speed boost goes for about 3,000
seconds about 2,000 seconds
so we thought we'd try it out on the
whole dataset and here's the fun bit
about data-intensive computing
arm turns out that we ran out of disk
space because
for gigabyte hard drive 88 about hard
drives in this case actually ran on a
2x-large
I'm 80 gigabyte hard drives weren't big
enough for our full data sets would have
had to complicate our engineering
in order just to spread the data over
multiple hard drives like I'm not sure
160 X would have been enough either
so at the moment with a lot of cloud
computing platforms you can have fastest
car lot of disk be can have both on the
same
computer arm or you end up becoming
really expensive
what does your options and so it's an
interesting lesson that you know
you really have to pick what you can
optimize for you optimize for latency
are you care about costra to you
what else what other one which means you
care about um
okay so soul for the data oriented
portions of the future directions I
think
arm I'm gonna repair ties investing in
cash local data structures and
algorithms
rather these massive hash tables that
are spread all over memory we're gonna
try it free I think
I think we should figure out how to work
more locally
arm up some of our our pain is caused by
reading the same data out to disk in
reading a back in because we can keep it
on memory
and I think that we have arms Albert we
have some algorithms in mind for
turning everything into a purely
streaming approach
which may cost more memory but might
actually be considerably faster
and then the somewhat surprising
conclusion to me I mean I guess I was
already leaning in this direction it's
nice to have some numbers
I'm worried I don't know that strict
code optimization infrastructure
engineers and
into a worthwhile investment force that
would complicate the protocols would
complicate what we're actually doing
and it's not clear that sinn give us
more than a 50 percent speed increase
compared to what like cash up to make
cash local data structures items will
give us
second thirty or forty fold increase
speed
okay cell I give a lot of talks
apparently 18
speak I'm somewhat approachable which is
something I'm working on arm
and arm so people come up an offer
solutions
so here a couple frequently offered
solutions so
I'm you should like totally multi for
that arm
and so we did this a from we we read a
chapter
a I'm from the performance of a source
applications and we can actually get
a two or four foot speed up before we
come release all the i/o bound
arm and it turns out that the code the
results from this is is is kind of a
mess and has a current maintenance
headache
and so it's not clear it was a great
investment actually I'm
how do people just crush that workload
dude I get us a lot
are it's unlikely be cost-effective we
have all talk about this in a little bit
but we have a lot of data
we have no locality in the data we can't
chart the data easily
arm and our individual compute per unit
of data is essentially trivial
and so I'm the cost to distributing it
fanning out in fanning a backhand and
getting it back in
is likely to to be the over dominate
arm the cost of everything but I'm and
then
arm I think Fernando talked about this
also have you tried quote my proprietary
Big Data technology stack
you got a silicon valley in a buncha
people are like hey I have a company
that that they can solve all your
problems
I can't give you the source code but
it's gonna be awesome when you run it
and the problem is that if you actually
trying to do science having hidden
methods that may have unknown effects
doesn't that can possibly work arm are
well it does for a lot of people but I
don't think it's good signs
some okay so arm here's the ratty
portion of my talk
optimization for scaling so everybody
wants to suggest a linear-time memory
improvements
and we actually spent two years eking
out a 20-fold improvement during which
we forgot a hundred fold increase in
data generation per
arm a per unit dollar
arm which meant that we were falling
slightly slower behind and everybody
else
was not a winning strategy the pasta
problem is a graph problem it's got big
date it's got no locality and it's got
small computer simply not a friendly
computational problem for today's
architectures
and what we really need to do a scale
our algorithms or rather the algorithms
are being used in the entire field
and we gone now down to the point where
machines things that previously needed
to run on really expensive you know
arm a 16 terabyte memory machines
can now run and single chassis computers
in about 15 gigabytes of memory
are because we chose to up stop doing
doing be I'll linear-time memory
improvement and go for
for algorithm scaling it to take five
years but
you know I'm an academic that's okay so
arm
optimization for scaling I think many
people forget when they see something
like this and they say why
gonna choose the black line because the
red lines clearly inferior in terms of
compute resources needed the forget that
if you zoom out any tackle a big enough
problem that scaling is eventually gonna
dominate
and this can be a better investment have
your time if your date or size is
growing
is totally made-up craft just in case
you're wondering
um and I actually see it Pike on an
online in blogging and so on
that a lot of people are focusing on
pleasantly parallel problems anything
that you can shove into her do basically
and I worry about a couple things one is
at hoops fundamentally not that
interesting
arm another is that if you're actually
doing research on the stuff it's about a
hundred fold improvement not about a
can be buy more machines and throw throw
things at the machines ultimately
depending on how your data input scaling
you're going to run into problems with
that approach a man I think research can
really
a there's a lotta CS research gets a lot
about press because
I'm we look like we're not doing
anything and maybe sometimes that's true
but we're also working on things like
scaling new problems and evaluating
creating new data structures occurs I
think
I'm we performing a valuable useful
service sometimes
I'm this is a talk by Pike on 2011 aside
from iPad Con 2011 talk so
I'd like to make a pitch to all love you
which is life's too short to tackle
these problems
you should come work for me for a lot
less money instead um
are academia more generally here we have
problems that are really hard to
paralyze
and for which we have no money
whatsoever its way better than going to
a Google in working on Google search
which is relatively easy
so arm you know come talk to me I was
gonna say um
you know Alex Gaynor some points going
to realize that is life's not a
challenging and is going to come
work for me for pennies since gonna be
awesome okay
so I think I'll conclude their I leash
in a min
as graduates who started the
benchmarking project I'm arm
I and then a bunch of lab is contributed
to this Mike Russow Louise Arbour
work it camille in QP arm all over stuff
is freely available under BSD license is
I have a blog post with resources and
pointers to everything
I should point out Michael the kit
Camille and QPR here
icon are you can probably afford to buy
them from me
arm I did put the pictures up because I
wanna make it a little bit more
challenging for you to find them
arm the reason I say this is actually
better camille's right over there
um I the reason I say this as i've now
II had one gradison get his PhD in go to
Amazon six months before he defended
and another graduate student got bought
by Google i sorry got offered a job by
Google
arm about 32 years before his defense
and he was like
hey they just offered be triple your
salary what he say much well should go
arm so a arm but is a little frustrating
to keep on losing people but there are
some people in Asia hire them so please
go ahead I'll cheer for them while
crying
arm and that's all I have to say thank
you for listening
sorry if you have anything to say I can
line up
is much from here the middle of the room
I we're taking questions for Titus
and job offers for taxes students yes
i'd as always on am
I think the answer to the question
advances
don't know but II I know I've talked to
you
but I work in a nother in a science lab
in a different domain
thats not related in molecular dynamics
and
this lab has built very custom hardware
and as a consequence got to three orders
of magnitude improvement
over the next best supercomputers in the
world for
this problem set and no good for
anything else
we do have like things like I'm
memory locality in the partition space
although I'm latency requirements in
is very crucial so it is a very
different sort I'm
parallelism issues than you have but
if you had a lot more money have
millions and millions to actually design
hardware
is this something that custom hard work
good make you to three orders of
magnitude faster present pastor
Chur so custom hardware so amor
yes so so there's a company called I
think conde
that that is doing this um and to the
the fundamental problem here
I'm in part for the fact that some to
gimme billions of dollars out invest in
people rather than hardware but
um or vacation but G arm the fundamental
problem for here is that the data
generation capacity has been so
democratize that there are
thousands if not tens of thousands of
laps generating the stator
and so that custom hardware would have
to be bought by all of them
and typically the generate the data or
provided centrally
and and the feel the there's a cultural
problem feel the files he just doesn't
like to play nice
that way and and there's a another
problem which is that I'm
the downstream applications change
applications change fast enough
that I worry about the lack flexibility
so I'd be interested in looking into
FPGA style solutions we can reconfigure
exactly how you doing it
but I worry that that the time cost of
investing in hardware generation
would be too long on the scale
the speed with which field is moving at
ano Justin intuition
but you know what give me a million as a
pilot project
and and we'll see and I can keep some my
grad students
high tide is very top at maybe its
different biology but
in my own academic experience in
computer science after engineering
unfortunately that funding agencies in
the journals tended not to care about
this incredibly interesting
awesome very difficult work necessary to
build the tools and techniques
to do that now quote real research same
field same field
are you see any changes in out I
yeah black beanie for a couple years now
are you seeing any changes in how
yeah children season journals look at
this kind of work for SES
your some there's a great post by Jake
Vander PLAs
on the Big Data brain drain and the
problem is that
anybody that knows how to effectively
develop software and has
any intelligence whatsoever fleas
academia for industry as quickly as
possible
to getting paid a lot more and they're
doing work but appreciated
and academia especially in biology we
have this problem that we don't have any
senior
we don't have many senior people that
are really focus on software engineering
and tool development and so that I
represent in the granite panels are not
risen
wreck represented the people that decide
how the findings allocated and
I
it's just it's a big problem because
there's nobody to speak for that I'm
it slowly changing in part because
myself and some other people are finally
getting to the point where
arm were senior enough to talk to the
program managers
and program managers are also seeing the
slowdown
in biology because all the pile church
I'll just for generating data
but they cannot analyze at all so it
slowly changing but it's gonna be a
generational thing it's always more
exciting to generate new data you can
analyze it that it is to analyze
them to do the boring dollar figure to
analyze the data you already have hi
and one green yours specific problem or
gin every problem apology
are the meaningful to you on
crowdsourcing or outsourcing
arm I have to think about it
are this one probably not but I think
we're trying to get to the point where
the data we generate the information we
generate from the data will be amenable
to human
analysis right now this is all fairly
boring
i'm ok I'm a human time scale we just
wanna keep you but
it means something down the road and and
that's where we should bring in humans I
don't think it's ready for crowdsourcing
at but
have to think about that thank you here
isola Amazon again each PC kinda
networks at
and I am think person but what happens
when commodity
together as well run ever learn
but I sleep so so I get the sky get the
kind of question
a fair bit what if you had this kind HPC
and I guess
what i'd say is arm were almost entirely
RAM limited
so soon as you have to run across
multiple chassis it's no longer
effective so number HPC offerings from
from Amazon in our local HPC at Michigan
State all have fastener connects
but the task the individual charities
are necessarily that powerful
and so we're trying to do everything on
a single chassis with no you something
to consider even like in in a band
they're going to these higher gas still
too slow
I I think it's a latency that's a
problem at the speed
Feb related to that
Braintree I think the reason believe the
reason I left is that the job market is
for nonessential like you get less but
it's hard to find a job at all
often her what do you think like
solutions for that event
okay so
home like we're just more grant money
solvency sustainable me
yeah I
maybe it's a systemic it's a systemic
issue arm
enemy more grant money is the is the
easy is the easy answer I think the
better solution is to become
I don't know maybe more bebe a little
more efficient her using grant money
allocated to people are doing data
analysis as well as data generation
and then there would be in need right
now yeah I don't know it's a very ca
let's get some beer went up a
replacement Titus brown