K thank you everyone for coming along to
this first after lunch session at Pike
on 2014 here in Montreal
I'll got three really excellent speeches
all lined up for you
our first presenter is a program and
data scientist based here in Montreal
she works on strike started team and is
a Colgan is all
hi ladies Montreal and the Montreal
all-girl back nights
to speak to us today about diving into
dot with iPod and MacBook
and handers please welcome Julia Evans
I A on sup
today when I won't talk to you about I'm
I worked on
added him I'm which means they're good
data on n/a
heavier but have different tools that I
use right up sometimes eight to dupe
I'm sometimes is paid on sometimes like
a czar once
I'm and my favorite old two years
like the things that I enjoy using the
most are paid on Tools
I enjoy using I find another camp and
this together
to answer questions up idea and what I
want to explain this talk
is why they're my favorite on and why
they could maybe be your favorite
if you don't use them already sup
on the way to start a structured
on against small not gonna get better
apparently
on is step 1: what are another camp and
as
Michael what do those words man you may
know a little bit already if you watch
ran oppresses
act looking at this morning on most
about time is going to spend
on practical examples on how to use the
is to answer questions about your data
and then I'll and would like a little
bit but it's not like where to go next
if you wanted learn more so first
question is like
what are I dunno but and pandas and like
numb pie
on and like how to this business like
Scientific Inc
computing tools work together on so the
first thing I want to talk about his
iPod lineup
on so I've read a book is like a
web-based user interface for Python
and everything like why would I want
that right like you can already right
papon maybe
on I had a why would you want to be on
the internet
right leg why would you want to be in a
web page so
on the way forever the book works I'm is
around the server on your chin
on and then you will open in your you
notebook
right I'm gonna be really short Emma
instead of listing I to Peters
step I'm the most important thing that
isn't always obvious is when used I've
ever notebook
you can Ryan like right any paid by code
that you would normally right
like it's not like a limited by mid
where there are only certain things you
can do
I'm it just paid on like you can do any
pipe on being in the US otherwise do
that you get up connect to databases in
you can like you do everything right
on so one thing that I really like about
it
is like but the important thing and I do
like string dot split
and I wanna know how it works right
normally you'd look at the documentation
here sees that I've hesitated at like
would you like some documentation
and they pressed have again and the ok
would you like even more
and the press have again exam had a
frustrated and a popular
all the documentation at the bottom
explaining a split works for me
I can like resize it and I didn't have
to leave great
and I didn't have to even know it just
like came up for me
on so funny really useful interactive
tool for doing
export a work but I do like string not
split
right like this on
23 and angular no that wasn't what I
wanted maybe eight celebs put on a comma
OST right so my workload around this is
often I do something
do it wrong as we do I'm and then change
it and I can in to rate really quickly
so that led by the notebook on
the next day on talk about it pandas on
sup
often I will do so kinda did an out this
little have a date is that
with every complaint call ever made in
New York right i'm for fun
and then I want to know that let's say I
wanna know like
every hour how many noise complaints
were made
arm except like I would like to sweat it
out Beiber
on and also maybe a lake I only care
about the period connect
temper in December I'm so I do it a lot
of filtering aggregating
I'd you might think about you might have
trailed like if you're reading a program
that would be like something that could
happen I'm with pandas you don't have to
write loops
on and also at like doing something like
IRI on the north by the filtrate things
you don't want and then grab it except
like
arm and then grab the number each hour
is like 512 Cup
like that's really come back it's really
easy on
and but it's not like I was there are
obvious how to get started
sudden unexplained about pat is kinda
the tool that lets you do all this
filtering
on and parsing the pandas bill I have
not pie
what is numb by if you want to brendor
the stock yesterday that paper
data structures you will know but if you
ever a pipe bomb blast had like five
million things
if you iterate through that list you
have to make five million object
which takes time even though computers
are fast so
I A but like thing like number its
pastors kind ever
like it's it's not as I A said again
right so i thought id example an example
as the topic a whole buncha numbers
right
and then find the sum of the squares so
did about Connor ever do like pretty
simple
recently doubled up 1.2 seconds I'm to
add up all the
those numbers squid which is pretty good
right like computers are about that was
a big number
on but if I do to number it takes like
83 mil seconds which is like
like 15 times faster on so when I say
nope I sponsor I mean umpires like 15
times
after another Asian taking about or more
right
um so and the reason it faster is
because it implements all the operations
like it stores your
on deserters alexi areas arms and
bend like when you operate on umpire is
you do it all at once so instead of
being like
reading a for loop you'll be like just
some all these things right
and you just like all number functions a
number i text having
Korea and them as a panda's bill another
number I
and you'll have panned assumptions which
are built up by functions
so on eyes pandas
inside I'd rather know book and no play
makes and as fast
okay um quick note how to install these
tools
don't use the like nobody packages in
stopping his in pip
or a little girl there's a
distributional anaconda
which I've been super easy to use and I
is a lot on
there yet never use packages like this
these things are evolving supervise the
by the community is doing amazing work
on
and use the latest versions on because
they're amazing
so I'm and you can run a weapon a book
by typing
I played on notebook
it's good and not to hide
on and then when you wanna grab another
you get this little pop-up turning in
your browser
and an evening at started so now I want
to talk about the practical examples
as I promised on so the first thing
I want to but as the date is that we're
going to be using were in Montreal
people it it's a bit cold right now is
much colder a few weeks ago
even when it's very cold people go
biking right um
so we have bike path here I'm their
centers on his bike that that's meant
meant measure the number of cyclists who
are going pass at center
every day on and that did as published
online:
so we can play with it and find out
things about when people go biking
for example do people go biking well as
-20 No
%uh except people do actually
which is what will you know we're going
to get there observers the data that
we're going to be talking about so I
downloaded it
I'm this is not big data rate this is
like
one data point for each day of the year
on
so I don't love the CSB and this is what
it looks like when I started right
hun if you've par CES is before you may
be familiar
with things that you're on um so what
what this is is it one bro for each day
of the year
I'm has the dates and the number of
cyclists on each
on on its back for and that there's a
man's ear and back that's
so you know is there could be problems
the separator above the common wasn't
home a
right and you may not be impressed with
pandas right now on
so the reason you should be impressed is
you can
also there's a lot of text year but I'm
I get home in two options as agreed the
CSP
the body including his loved one
separators xenical nation expertise to
parse the dates
and her purse today first because we're
not american I'm
and he a great day for Canadians I'm it
has all these are
these options and there are more options
if you haven't even weirder CST
and like that like the people over a pan
is have bought about this right
and they know that may be there like 12
lines at the top UCSD which are relevant
years the SD
so there's a skiff option where you can
skip the first time rose
because that happened when I was
downloading weather data from whether
died easy .ca
and then it was there on a need to write
code because it was just
like an often has recvd is the United on
and is also like
read Excel I'm I had a client at at some
point will be like sent as a home in
Excel files and it was fine cuz pandas
can read Excel
I'll it's great
on sup so the first thing I do
on so now you know that this is
beautiful right on
I would like that supper minute and talk
about what we're looking at right
like I said bike data is variable white
is it
on so but data is a data frame whose is
are
before a few if you a day to ramp and is
based on a data plan
are your intuitions are correct on who
hears you single
more view on a day dreams a little bit
like a database table
right there rose their columns on
there's a
and exits little bit like your primary
key I'm Zahir the date is the index
and on the way this is stored like the
way it kinda
like kinda things about this is it a
bunch of number I raise
which are either a which are the columns
I'm to starve them into columns
but its display to you is like a table
altogether like an Excel spreadsheet
I did except awesome on
because it's not an Excel spreadsheet
and much easier two years
as a programmer so
on to have a datagram om the first
operation I wanna show you is even take
the first three rows in a glamorous life
on I'm so that's great
on and let's say 12 plotted you might
think that you have no learn how to use
net problem in learn how to use the
plotting library
that's not true you just had %uh plot
and
on and NBC like we look at this on
I would like okay on in the winter in
till March
it's really cold outside and no one
really goes by King
and then in the summer people like it
summer this is the best
everything is the meaning everyone is
happy as it is not a huge surprise right
I'm so don't look if Isaac Plains crap
for a minute I'm
the x-axis is time and the y-axis is
like the number of people biking
on each day and then the different lines
are different bike paths
I'm select bury the blue one is bringing
my house century popular iPad even go
very fast
the super steep hill on and it's really
fine
and like a little bit dangerous on very
popular
on so let's say a I said that day was
the most popular
right I'm but I want like quantify that
and I was at airports like my boss in
charge a bike paths right
I would elected and a letter but given
the median right
on the way to do that is you like a dot
median
on and their love is like super help 'em
thanked like matt is upended get the
idea to braums
I'm per like finding out that is excited
on so am not there then one at the plot
comedians and gobbling up
bar chart does everyone loves bar chart
then I could be like bike data
dot median dot plot I'm
on and then to give me some weird air
pretend that errors in their
I'm that was then had a fun thing on
and the dignity that that like very is
the biggest right and then act like this
is the best bike rack wish to kill the
other
I don't know like whatever it right now
conclusion you're trying to convince the
people you're bored you board meeting
John this crap
K on a few other things i wanna talk
about
on even take a column place so like
let's say sometimes I have
like CST is it had like two billion rows
are like
50 I'm and I only really care about 3 on
you can give
a it a allister broza as an index and is
restricted and to do that
I'm and then you can also Lake say eats
it
take diversity rose innings with the
surrounding the gimme overseers and then
only his columns doesn't care what order
you do it in pen is nice to you
okay on the last kinda like basic pan
like numb hype and this feature want you
to talk about on
is my favorite wanna my favorite I have
many favorites sorry
home so on I talked about doing
operations all at once right
so let's say I wanted to find all other
days where they're less than
seventy-five people biking
on the very back flat near my house
right collect $75 is in a lot
on it's a pretty popular bike path I'm
so what I can do
is I can say when is less than
seventy-five and it gives it has long
black churches involved
strain and then what I can do with that
is akin put that into like I can index
with it
and it will give me all at the Rose that
satisfy that condition and I can combine
conditions
and they can use arbitrarily complicated
conditions so it's like a single query
if you've used that
except you can write Python code right
on and you can just like do whatever
sickle might allow you to do
you can do anything you want and to
Canada arbitrary queries
on and you can see it here that like the
days was unable or all days in
in January and February January and
February so-called
rights but not a huge surprise
so I'm but super powerful amazed at all
the time
okay so the next question I had on
is I want snow like what all of this
variation was about right like there's
this crap in it like
number of cyclists and I what silly is
this because the weekends like
is the variation because more people
back on weekdays on weekends
so here's here's a question like who
thinks that in Montreal where city of
commuters a good to me mostly bike
because we're going to work
some people who picked fifth group we'll
be back for fun
these disagreements we can solve with
data
this is the best again overnight his
right
so the first thing I'm gonna do I'm as I
have a datagram
I'm gonna add a new column the way add a
new column is like adding a new key to a
dictionary
because everything is nice I'm and like
his interests were kinda you might
expect on
so om tennis is really good a time
series
a time series is a fancy word for a
bunch of numbers
which are in next by like a date select
stocks right
I'm it was originally built by by people
who are doing like banja they denounce
this
I'm like was beginning on so
I had a weekday column and index of
weekday
and that gives me a number rate for HID
the air
I meant what I want to do with this is I
want to
on collect all the all other entries
would like the same weekdays like Taylor
everything with with the six
I liked at all those up and everything
2008 at all those up
and every day at the gay one allied all
those up and then we'll figure out what
the A six and they're actually means
on and then world are pretty graph into
it to our board meeting grady
so on
want to do that I'm if you'd done whose
use like a single group by
this is like that I'm if you have a
musical group by its what I said
right on you have like all the easier
than you had them up
had on abut like you should think up and
his group I like a single goodbye that's
why it's called
at on so we say good bye week day
and aggregate although those groups by
taking the Sun
you can use any function you want here
Yuki don't just have to use built-in
functions
you can write your own functions he's
any function that you find in the wild
you can use the miles
you know you can uses any function on
so I do this I meant I get a new data
frame which has all of the weekdays
as the index and then for each column
add them all up
and it'll work for me and I didn't have
to write a loop
because loops our work and we don't like
doing work we like other people to Dr
Acworth
are at least idea on right
I'm but like numbers like who likes
reading tables have a lot of numbers
some %uh view I'm I I feel you I like
members however I prefer grab
right on so what I did was that his
right index by hand I just looked up
like
iPad a date that was the 0 and they look
to be my calendar
to find out what day of the week it was
and I found out that it was Monday on
because I I want to do it fast
if you were like doing it the right way
you would probably find out some way to
programmatically
and do that I'm tho
attention XD right and it turns out at
Thursday's most popular day
the days of the week Mr popular in the
weekends and it looks like we're
commuters it looks like you back to work
yeah hacer
I'm so that's cool arm and then i buy I
J bar graph
no not that like if you want to plot a
biografia like pot
kind it was bar on that like one in the
main
kinda graphs a draw a lot arm
so that that's good right ion kno to 700
lips to do that right
like that which is like a few lines of
code alright
so but if you look at that this artist
chart again
like there is a little bit a variation
by Dave the week but that's definitely
not like all that's causing the huge
spike
throughout the year right on so
I like to do like a better investigation
into this on
cuz we're like data scientists or
whatever and Anna I'm
so but next thing I want to do is look
at the temperature
right like it's called didn't don't need
to be like
amazing a data statistics magic people
to the hague know that people don't like
going biking when it's called
on so I'm but this function don't look
at this function at kinda big
on but basically what I was doing was
like I went to climb a doubt whether
Dodd d-ct and Mike I found some
Lake place where I could put in things
into the your Alan
ever give me a CSP kinda have and I
could put it together
anyway it was a lot of work is kinda
what I'm trying to say here you can
imagine you could have written us
on I'm an I don't know whether data I
looked at it
and it gave me the temperature every
hour as a good that's good
I'm the main problem with this is that
if you want the temperature every hour
and one of the temperature everyday
right because we only have the bike did
every day
I'm so I decided to take the average
temperature
on and the way you take the average
is you re sample which apparently some
people do when analyzing like financial
stock data
because they're like I have my stock
prices every like two milliseconds and I
only need them every like 10
milliseconds
I don't know a about hybrid with these
i've been out estimates
on but when I did everything I double so
on but there is ample on resembling is
great you do
daughtry sample and then you get the
time period you want you can read it in
like
you 8d if you want two days you're it 2d
if you want three hours you at 3h
pretty simple on and then use say how
and you can see these days and that mean
when you get a function I'm cuz you can
all miss nicole is dependent think
functions
on so once I'm done that I get them the
average temperature everyday
right and you could argue for like hours
about whether or not this is a useful
thing
like this like the best way to resample
on but we want
you can down the days afterwards and do
a better job than me
that is what I would like sup I'm began
to lick
on January 3rd it was like -14 Southee
celsius which is pretty cold i think is
a good zero Fahrenheit
on if you're American on
so a judge a llegar
of a big bucks for 10 temperature and
you'll see like this
I'm gonna go over there really quickly
on because this is really exciting
to me on up in Rotana okay this bike
here
this within my reach and it went up to
18 degrees
and it was beautiful and I missed it and
all of my friends were like
all in a son Nathan I was up 5 nose ring
a tank top and a mini mart
Jan I was like why do I miss it
I'm anyway it was like kind in her death
but I get the temperature went up super
high and everyone went up by King evelyn
was so excited
and then went down again unlike
nevermind whenever their bike away get
right leg
I'm as he can feel like there there's
like a real correlation here
right but the rest a bit I don't know
Lake I'm I'm not like as stalled on like
the other specs Nisga'a
just kinda that one in March are there
I'm but that's cool we've done finance
him
by which I mean looking at Grafton point
and
not a real scientist so on
right so now the next question was like
there's more variation here right Lake
similar to go but it's raining
let's look at some precipitation
so I want snow like what percentage of
each day was it raining
right and here you might again bank and
we if we look at our original
on data weather data frame year
it doesn't give us like Arrhenius
quotient it says like
a string which is the weather right I'm
so you might think you have to do work
here
and you'd be wrong because pandas knows
everything
so palaces all is magical string
functions so what you say is like
look at the weather and then go to like
the bunch of singing bhajans
and Philip does contain rain and then it
gives you one yr 0
depending on whether or not it contains
a string rain and it does everything for
you
arm so a menu sample that again every
day
I'm so we get like the percentage hours
a day when it was raining right
like whether or not that's right thing I
don't now right maybe
arm and then we get this other guy a I'm
like this happens a lot less clear to me
on there's some spikes over here
where like like this one
and over here Lake maybe that correlates
like a spike down where they can kind of
see it like
like it like like this her and bit but
like also like pointing at
a spikes in grasses like a really
dangerous things to do in analyzing data
is not a good practice and because you
like you can just like over Pitt
with your brain a lot cuz we're really
good technique patterns that are there
on so it is better to look at a
correlation I'm with you could also do
but we're not going to do
on because this is all I have to say
madame applied yet I'm worth it the
glove save our practical example
right on this wasn't a lot of code
is the main when I wanna make rain on
except for the weather thing which is
like a disaster
but pretend that didn't happen home and
there were no group right
like we made these graphs to make we
found out if it be hindering me
like resample than we did others can't
kinda cool stuff
I mean after it leaves we had really up
to like six lines of code right
including reading in the data I was
super easy
on and raised experiment SEM
a beloved Xperia on if you want to be
using these tools
on I find it super useful 3some the
documentation
a minute on a documentation on and
what I often find is already considering
I learn a little bit
and the model look at the darkness Albin
things like totally helps Bionic I wish
I knew about that like six months ago
answers good girl looking a little bit
from time to time and brush up
a month you learned from the basics and
is a good issues PDF and really good API
documentation
I really enjoy it I'm was begin even at
a company
108 houses which I enjoyed has led a
really great examples
on one of the main most important things
is like
always ready use like these built-in
operations really dari sample
or like I'm things that have been built
these are built in on because Rainier on
dips is
a lot of %uh get merv your work I mean
BB
really slow it'll be like 20 times lower
I'm as we saw before
right and it's a bit like it doesn't
matter everything a second but if you
doing a real big competitions
that a problem on and
though you can if you really need to do
some custom competition you can use
tools like site on
on tutor to like right things that are
compiled see an actual on quickly
and that's pretty approachable and I've
done it before I kinda like Google two
examples and dived into the pen is risk
getting pulled from the ad and copy
didn't
messed with it and worked I'm its that
pretty virtual to do that
on but it's easier to avoid doing that
and he's gotten back to me whenever
possible
on and often where things are happening
on one thing that I did is I may depend
as cookbook if you wanna get started
I mister evans get have repository and
there's like 10 chapters which are like
differently like small example the
things that you can
do it panders together with like
practical examples to this this is data
said there's some other data says the
years
to kind of show off some has kept its
capabilities on
and is a few and take a look at that it
could contribute to it also
and examples like how to use it with
lexical databases
on and that might be a place get started
and method
and it's fantastic
on sorry if there are any questions for
Julia
upcoming lineup at this microphone that
with cleverly placed here
front of the room I will just give few
moments for like you to form
right this question thank you
going and mint
effectiveness prior different
actors said
that's really the question I guess I
think them as a look at the database
queries
I'm Xavier if you think that it be
through that little affiliate group
based way picking up thanks
on and if you're not I wanna lick the
more you practice it
the better get that like a not a very
good answer her
I
where's likes like it learn into this
the slides
to nigga psyche learn
another up oh yeah I talked with a
cabana abstract I'm
so like not by individual a second I'm
so anytime you want to use if you wanna
division in on your plan is it depends
I'll just work
on soap and if you feel like getting our
asses
secular modeling yes a gallon for
modeling
yet if you wanna make a matte model you
can bikes and like a pat is a demanding
but
and that'll that'll work seamlessly I'm
a time that I do
yeah I'm
so first of this looks like a lot of fun
cuz I said he's been releasing a lot of
open data lately
on but candid can this do geographical
stuff graphical stuff
or geographic to grab gotta that's a
good question I don't think that panders
does do graphical stuff by itself I
don't know that's chip not that I know
of on
but there are really good tools that
have seen
I'll get yep I couldn't I can tell you
something later
okay appreciate the talk
up quick question on customizing hype
different custom ship
was wondering if you had if you
customize
I'd recommend
surgeon mean that customers in people's
pockets
no customizing the actual con as
understood
customized tooth
different hype okay
even exam you would like interactive
JavaScript things and I found the
notebook
arnelle a different option %uh
so the edges I don't know I think the
answer there now but I would love to see
yeah I don't do that how do you make
sure the conclusions make
become
the attic the answer to that is like
learnt this is text
and acquire friend to know statistics
on yeah on
I don't want to say too much about the
curricula go embarrass myself
but on one thing you can do is be
really careful about what did he look at
Cilic so for example you don't wanna
lick look at data and the like
take up points a finger in dressing like
I was doing great what I was doing was a
terrible thing to do
right you can do that on my Hindu
is like think about the question they
are asking carefully before you look at
the data
on and I think that's a good way yeah
like
ok asking the question after you look at
the data is about choice
because then like you'd like me to
question right and the DS question for
you look at the deer
benefit a better chance like doing the
job Boyd
hearing your experience these years into
this this topic
everyplace like Julie Evans for talks
so much