now see thanks for joining us I'd like
to take moment into Scott Lobdell
his ass off right here hearsay social
whose reason that they are means we talk
about this big one pair
so get up up
Jeremiah how how have much tightest
thing
so this is a presentation about blimps I
didn't get the start of right to bear
with me
it's one on a clear I
if not hydrogen out so does get it going
to hell it is going to be really awesome
anyway special about me my name is Scott
Lobdell
left the army I work for hearsay social
now up
I do have some resources for the stock
%uh I did present already have them
posted at the end in sight showed
otherwise we just follow me on twitter
I have the resources posted online
apollo along if you want
obviously an outage put in a brief plug
hearsay social is going to be hosting
the blimp after party
the deer to party if you will directly
after this the
the West End in the our the reserve room
right I like big names gonna be there
action shots can be there for any fans
via
at him in his work cell without further
ado let me just go and get into the
plant here
so up what this is the semiautonomous
blame
so the idea is that I can incentive
piloting the sting directly I can click
waypoints on a map
the blimp will navigate to my own goal
for this was to do aerial photography
at so the idea behind this here is that
if any have you want to replicate
in your all this project this should
give you enough resources to get started
and to avoid some of the same pitfalls
that I had
so the overall architecture that we have
here is we have a
laptop at has a client application that
in Python
everything is in Python devouring python
skin boots no big deal
I so got a text box remote
its wired to a laptop the patrol that
x-box remote Sens command center
better encoded into specialized bike
man's I wrote
there said across the wire Wireless XP
connection which I get into
that then connects to the onboard
controller here
and the blimp which is actually a former
computer running Ubuntu 10 4
that in turn sends commands to the rotor
so
with any basic aircraft I know they're
just had a previous talk about
helicopters but your basic controls our
pitch
roll and yaw so pitch of course controls
the nose of the aircraft
role as good beer side to side and then
ya is going to be here
your compass asthma here so if we have a
blimp then
we have the same controls and we just
manipulate Petroni are different manners
so for pitch we essentially manipulate
the tail
up till elevator on to to
apply force as a result to the win the
can also manipulate the prospector on
the good ol a
to patrol the direction the rotors as
far as role goes blimp is
a blimp is naturally I has a very centre
a very heavy center of gravity so it's
going to naturally role
two-year your normal position so you
really only need to worry about pitch
and yaw
and of course with you are you could
just patrol the tail rotor and then you
can go left to right
cell the idea behind the autopilot
algorithm how this goes about working
is I don't care about pitch and yaw so I
have I need to establish a target pitch
in a target ya so the target pitch is
established based on your current
altitude
and you target out to turn that tells
you whether you wanna pitch upper down
and for ya you have your current as myth
and then you have your target as myth
which is based on GPS coordinates
so with both of those things you can
easily determine 22 go up or down
do need to turn left to right so from
there you have the intensity of how hard
you wanna Turner how hard you want to
pitch
and that's based on the differential
between those two so it's directly
proportional
to the relative did relative distance
between those two things
are
so here's the overall starts offer
architects behind what we have
so we have a controller which is
responsible for managing all these
different
a synchronous tasks and I just a task
because actually use G event here
so this isn't a talk about G event up
but gee event itself
is emulated threat emulated
multi-threading so it's not actually
multi-threaded
you have what's called Green let's hear
it so how this works is essentially
you spawn multiple green let's and as
soon as you create those
their kicked off a synchronously and
what you get at that joint all that's
going to block until
each of those different green lights %uh
finishes its task
so in this case case each one of those
individual green let's with an infinite
loop so didn't have to do that
I we can also do monkey patching
which will take anything that naturally
blocks so in this case we have a serial
connection for example so anytime
anything is blocking
it's going to immediately yield to
another thread so that's also going to
make it
when we do timed out sleep Sophie even
at bottom
bottom example we have the sample
greenlit and that's the basic structure
everything agreement we have we're going
to do something
we're going to do a little thing and
ever going to sleep which is going to
yield to the other threads
and once that sleeping is complete it's
going to be reactivated
accel the very first thing we have to do
is we had from to read from sensors
so I'll the sessions themselves
had sample code written in C plus plus
naturally the easiest way to interface
with them
so the basic premise behind what I did
as I took the things that I had to write
c plus plus other things that need to be
particularly fast
and I bubbled up the high level %uh
extractions to Python
and with Python it's very easy to create
an autopilot algorithm here
cell again this is Anna talk about
bussey there but here's the basic
premise we have eighty we have some
things that why do in C plus plus
and we want to create a manager class
for those different things and I we
wanna surface some others functions at
the Python
so here in this example if you look at
the very bottom were surfacing up the
function say hello and getting a jerk
and at the bottom is just how you go
about using that Python
so what this means for us then is that
we can create
these these drivers the rewrite c plus
plus and then here are just
surface this one function at the Python
just get asked that so here
python is gonna call c plus plus code
so week that was the example for the
compass
so now we can go and do that with every
single one OVR are sensors so in this
case I have a GPS
accelerometer compass and an altimeter
sell for all others things I have
drivers written in C plus plus I
services function that the Python
and I have a sensor manager that manages
all those things
and the controller is then going to poll
the sensor manager every one tenth of a
second
and as he gets those values it then
updates communicates with the other
green light and tells them
about the updates on this case we're
gonna tell the the communicator about it
which will send the data back to the
client
I with you know what what occurred GPS
is what my outside is
everything else and it's going to
senator the autopilot so the autopilot
relies on the sensor data
in order to think and in decide what to
do next
so with the camera this is the exact
same concept again
I use Boost and resided here in this
case is because
I relied on a C-plus plus library called
G photo to
it so what that is it's a 8 camera
library
written in C plus plus that supports
hundreds had with cameras
the can then take pictures with them you
can get the Live View I
in my case I had a Canon t2i so what I
want to do
is I want to be able to grab a frame
from the live you and I want to be able
to take a picture remotely
this is all down to the USB or USB
connection
I and then a disservice to such the
Python tactic pictures from there
so in order to communicate from the
client to the plan
I use an XP module and with this is it's
basically
you can imagine just a a really really
long serial cable that's basically what
this is a few
just think about abstraction up its
wireless module
the use the 802 top 15 dot for protocol
which is just a peer to peer
low-power protocol and here you spy
cereal to interface with it
so I can just dynamically find where
where the serial port is loaded
or the XP module loaded I can open it
neck and right to in read from it
I'm gonna do both those things from the
writer and the reader so in this case
I developed my own sort a communications
protocol which I'm sure a lot of view
back probably imagine that there's
better ways to do this but it worked for
me
but the basic pattern was that I send
ascend
a command value and sell the value
what the value means depending on the
command it said before so here it is on
doing I'm sending command in a value
I'm and packing those values in Python
into just two bites for short for
instance or
eight by to believe for a float and what
I'm doing as well
is an adding header by had a bite so I
can designate a packet
cell if if there's any sort of packet
loss
I need to be able to reestablish that
stream determine what's the command
what's the value so in this case I just
had some reserved by to 254 255
and that pattern only appeared in the
header bytes so that we as a bird has it
was a packet
so on the receiving end I have a I have
a reader and writer on both
the controller and the client it so all
this is just doing is just
interpreting that stream and do take the
appropriate action so the basic pattern
is up here
I have a dictionary that has the command
and in the appropriate function at Matt
maps Q
and going to call that function as soon
as it gets the command is gonna pass in
the value that we got
so this is just one example in this case
is the
the control the use with from the x box
if I press a button its gonna say hey
there's a button pressed
the value is going to be the button that
was pressed and then it's going to take
the appropriate action so
down at the bottom you could see start
issued to kill can't command
up would increase the target out
students so forth
right so to actually control the plant I
made another attraction
where we have a class strictly
responsible for managing the motors
one thing that I did hear that proved to
be very valuable was to make it to the
inputs were basically enumerated data
types
up in this may I could send command just
like pitch up pitch down
with an associated value with this
allowed me to do it it allowed me to
independently
independently validate the autopilot
and the motor control so essentially I
could do manual control
at send commands like pitch up its
down-ballot into the work properly
and with the autopilot I could
essentially validate paid depending on
the action I take my outputting
pitch after pitch down here so this has
to
two major functions are exposed to the
controller so we have
tech so every one tenth of a second
going to take an RTI
recalculate what the motors must do next
and then basically update from
instruction so we have other classes
that are updating information here which
is a
pretty good pattern to use its tell
don't ask
cell here is the illustration that
pattern here
have the autopilot and the manual
control that both subclass
a base class and that base pilot has a
think and a get instructions so whether
you're using a patrol the
autopilot you can get the instructions
from them but they're both
updated in their own respective manner
so the autopilot will take input from
but some things from the x box it roll
or the client you can essentially say
like
increase the out to decrease the
altitude I send in the GPS cornet
but primarily we're going to use the
sentence centers this case are based on
Saturday to
we're going to respond accordingly and
with many patrol this is based
this use purely on the x box which on
this case
which is booked up to the laptop and
custom commander sent across so here's
some sample code in the manual petrol
here
the two public function to mention were
thinkin getting getting
instructions its updated I
it updated its own way so separate them
sick or the horizontal
in this case so as you Senate commands
gonna update what values that suppose to
supposed to do and every autopilot it's
basically the same pattern but we're
just updating fans and as you can see
here
so this is that the sample code for the
ewe there's a lot more that goes into
this but in this case this was
I how to calculate yang left her young
right
any social intensity base on the current
asthma
and a target at math on so this is kind
of interesting actually because if you
imagine
with up pitch this pattern works just
fine because you have
naturally opposing forces so you have
gravity that's going to naturally slow
it down as you pitch up for example
with ya there's no counter there's no
opposing forces as you do this so in
this case were actually did
is rather start establish a target
position establish a target velocity
so you can imagine getting distant
relatives there and as your
young laughter young bright you
manipulating acceleration to affect
velocity here
I at so as you imagine an we could start
going left as we approach our position
we're gonna realize that we're going too
fast and you can imagine we're Pike
County forces as we get to that point
are for the hardware kit on sorry for
the client application here
we're just running a laptop and
appointed a laptop is to be able to set
waypoints
so here's have some video that's just
illustrating a point the circle
represents the radius
love how far we can communicate with the
blimp so it's a one-mile radius services
two miles across
and two miles high and you can click any
point within that range and he's XP
modules are supposed to be one mile
minus site collectivity are and then so
from here
I also use the Google Maps API and never
turned a PNG
nice open CV go ahead brendor that PNG
onto a jury
I wrote some other stuff on there and
took mouse input and things like that
with the x box it roll I can use Boost
and here you cannot
other c plus plus library which is STL
and a gadget surface those highlevel
high-level I am things to be carried out
to Python
which tend to care for everything else
so
al bomber and pick up the sound so
here's the the actual min flight so I
did is
I had this theory that if I could take
make the center's work in concert
manipulate the servos and everything
then we could go ahead and
it make a test platform and change the
autopilot algorithm
but as you saw action work because that
had a big center of gravity prom at that
point I decided to just go ahead
and shipped to the blame so
now for a hardware at the preamp some
questions I'm sure like you might have
white and I use a Raspberry Pi
the honest answer is that when I was
putting this together I didn't really
know enough about it and just
after some googling I found the single
board computer iro Board RRB 110 which
is x1 hardware but it wasn't very well
documented
but a few advantages had a had over the
Raspberry Pi to begin with
this variable voltage is I think it
supports anywhere from six to 24 volts
input I and you can connect service
directly
get a guy to see directly and then
here's a summer the
you can see some the other sensors that
are you charlie talked about but we had
XRM the accelerometer compass I we had
which we use the accelerometer to find
out what petronella was
the altimeter was a a temperature
pressure and humidity sensor
the cat then calculate a relative
altitude are based on a0 wised
the rise out to the city started the the
application
aren't cell the
most difficult part of this project was
independently balloting everything
so with a blimp especially we have them
it's very large
very costly to inflate it so this is
about a hundred dollars where the helium
I so if we could Valatie everything
independently and then bring them
together that was a much better
option better thing to do so on the top
left that's an example up automated
pitch control so you can see it as a
manipulating
the gondola its the sensors are
responding appropriately and
telling the servos to manipulate the
prospector and the center images just
me actually doing ap full-blown plant to
address the videos
top right I'm going left and right I am
bottom left I am manipulating servo to
change the prospector
and the bottom right I am just changing
the motor controlled actually speed
upper speed down
cell I this demo is pretty wild
I works a lot was I can actually build
any the hardware here
I didn't build the plant I just did the
softer portion of it
and I was working with the guy in San
Diego from a company called eap lamp
and I went down with him and work on
this project together
and of course testing the right here we
actually filmed wasn't the best of
conditions
I got down there and this'll small park
in the guy told me like all right you
got power lines here to get a free way
they're so
good luck I so that was a little
frightening because
when we we have this blimp which
if the motors are on is going to fly
away and its optimized for a prolonged
airtime so this is quite scary because
if there were some sort of exception
that I didn't account for
the motors were just keep spinning and
we just go off into the distance L
actually bit did add some a safety
mechanisms in there which
actually pretty be very vital so for
example if it doesn't receive
communication for five seconds I'll go
ahead and pitch down
and I kill the motor so that actually
proved to be invaluable because
the very first time I did manual testing
if the other guy that flew it and a
I did in fact make a mistake long story
short and he flew it up
and then Kalol excited and ripped the
x-box patrol outlets or just flew away
so five seconds later came back down now
onto a roof
hey go get that but dori was good
so the pump itself is not actually
lighter than air it's about 95 percent
plan so as you can see right here
it does just rests on something on but
creating left is very easy
and as you moving forward the blimp
itself axed like a wing
so are some of the biggest pitfalls that
I had so
ironically the most challenging part in
this project
was getting when X installed under the
single board computer so
there's limited ran to begin with so you
can just install from ac/dc soon if it
is dismayed by tram
I and you also have to install a custom
kernel because
there's a specialized chipset here so
would if you do you want to use this
hardware I do have resources that I put
on my blog so
actually have a working Ubuntu 10 for
image that you just copy onto an SD card
and get this working immediately another
problem I had was the initial setup a
boost
I for any Python programmers are really
recommend that you just do a hello world
program with boost because as you do
that it's really going to open some
doors to some libraries the UN otherwise
be able to use
so if you know in your back pocket you
can use in DC plus plus library that you
want
it's very useful to know how to use
Boost and if you get that make file
working once
and in my case I ran into some issues
because the
version a python on my path was
different from the papon headers that I
to piled against
and took me a long time to figure out
that
that problem was going on so another
challenge here
was that the the communication mechanism
I
and using as a mention is next module to
that a serial connection so
you're sending commands linearly and
interpreting them linearly
so not only is is that somewhat slow I
but yeah there's also not much
throughput cell
the autopilot itself actually flew way
better than I can
because it the I mean the response time
for me human is much lower than just on
your calculations in recalculations
an act creating a response so
another big problem was properly reading
the altimeter so
as I mention the ultimate I have was a
pressure temperature and humidity sensor
and so the problem there is that Augusta
when will that affect both the pressure
and the temperature
and the result is that the out touring
change so
essentially because the wind is gonna it
comes that's the plan
it's going to thank on at a different
house 222 pitch so
Augusta when would cause a thing to
basically pitcher random which would
then push the plank
plant back cell I wanna had switched to
GPS
and apparently you have the same problem
so the GPS still gives fluctuating
readings for altitude
which then causes them to pitch happened
at random so I
I guess with with GPS satellites its
easy to triangulate the action live
because satellites are spread apart but
I guess the z-axis a lot is a little
more challenging because you can't do
that same kinda triangulation
ass I learned about that so i havent
entirely solve that problem
up and then be on that in just a matter
of accounting for the wind
because any problem that you have like
the the pitching prominent mention
or the yelling problem I mention
nationally where it would cost like
I started out by using position so idk
awesomely overshoot the on because in
the absence of any sort counteracting
force
so when you bring the wind into the
picture that's going to exacerbate
any flaws that you actually have so
those were some the biggest pitfalls
mom art so i'd I do need to go ahead and
give some credit where credit is due
here
so as I said I worked a guy named Larry
Fleming from the plant dot com
is a hardware guy so was really the
jury's to have his party this
I Roger who is one of my coworkers and
he was
amazing athletics was the only reason I
was ever get it installed on the board
and I also got a little help from a guy
from Eric am
dot com
so I if you want to get any of these
resources
I have all of the parts list so
everything I use
I've sample code in Python for every
single module I
and I have I have like the the laser cut
design for the acrylic peace to you some
out the board in all the screws and
everything associated with that
the working robe or damaged it running
Ubuntu 10 for to a contact me
others my email and once again we have
the plant after party
across the street at the west end so you
can come find us there
so at that actually brings to a close
I can take any questions
if you would
moving this to look inside area where
you can have GPS
kinda about how you could get like a 3d
representations
location internal space so there are
certain to solve that problem
and I don't know much about them but I
do know that they're very expensive so
you have something that like basic
represented UPSC
at I really can't answer that with
confidence but you have some for the
amount I ceiling
and you can try angulated position I but
yeah I mean that that's that's not a
problem you can only use the GPS
outdoors
even then it takes a while to get a fix
thank you good to me
thank you couldn't talk my name is on a
bond
bismarck I don't absolutely excellent
here
media at thank you yeah
the only question I have is but I didn't
repeat helium
want to keep money cheap hydrogel
matches have a fellow who's this
II so ash well I the answers that I did
up but I thought people might not like
it if I had this hydrogen filled
plant in here and of course up my
company as gracious lease
the %ah spots on my efforts at this
point and they are actually paying for
the healing never just me I would use
hydrogen
I and I actually did take the time to
manufacture my own hydrogen using
electrolysis
planet that was not very easy it also
the math is basically that one and power
will generate point for one leaders of
hydrogen
so that's the first problem is that not
very efficient and then be on that
actually get that amperage
with electro house is very difficult to
actually made this little contraption
with carbon graphite electrodes I put
potassium hydroxide in the water
that the graphite made it so the metal
was in part a reaction and
but then the the resistant to the water
was still very very high even with a
really large power supply
so I can only generate a small amount
hydrogen and what you got to that point
I you had a gas that wasn't pressurized
so is very difficult to manipulate so
that point it at hydrogen
blew it up and I burned my finger and
that's where do with that
what's up her
your up so
following offer what you said a little
bit do you have any tips on how to
convince your company to purchase
wannabes
I I don't know I'm
know will hit I get so the story behind
us
I actually started this project before I
joined my company I
so my initial goal was to do aerial
photography sybase I wanted to build a
django application
that has a buncha pictures an automated
when the way
like building a counter view based on
when the pictures taken extracted from
the exit data
now wanna just go to public places and
take pictures and had a domain name on
the plan but others and whatever
but I stopped working what I got my
company cuz I had to do real work
at so if you if you get up I can talk or
something
claiming to have a plan then I hope you
so that that I thought
yeah similar questions first
one which is yeah I I guess do you know
if the
on South Tower locations like
contains its hi and if it does strangely
so so you're saying basic get a better
GPS signal
by using do the same thing itself wants
to triangulate your height data with
cellular
you trying yellow certainly be a better
way to do it
the done with the cost have time in
getting this done so.
on yeah I would certainly be a better
solution but I'd
did not do it short yeah I was wondering
if you
found a solution to the from the wind
and the pressure changing
same it's just capping like how fast you
with expected to change in
waiting for two so their I mean infused
different things to do with that I have
exactly
figured out what to try next I the point
is I haven't really been into the test
that you never leave actually doing a
lot preparations coming here are but a
few ideas I had were too
for instance take the average altitude
reading
over the past second and then use that
another example would be to go ahead and
assume that I can maintain
an altitude like so once I reach it then
stop stopped reading for a little bit
until I change the target outfit again
on to the a few ideas that I like to
play with I just haven't got a chance
actually test it yet
thank miles talk
I do you have any experience with any
other like
drone platforms like a zombie
33 robotics are about two sons are they
like a did you choose to go with
ago you know for Linux computer incident
using that for specific reason yeah I
guess I'm departed
I I don't know enough about it like
I know I mean this the short answers
that no I didn't do that and we look
into it much
I I kinda felt confident his writing my
own but presence I know like
typically with these auto pilot projects
he would use an art we now are but I
know I can I I don't know much about it
but I know there are limitations with
them so I know like are tweeners for
instance don't have a lot of RAM
so you actually acted be Koch said that
wire coating
I where's here with my system I really
don't have to worry about that because
I'm actually just running a full-blown
version of Ubuntu awesome picnics
and fish that is basically and kinda
said
driving hey what's that and cassette is
driving
if oh yeah I wanna put a saddle on top
in STL right around but
it all has eight-pound paleo in SAS cell
little too heavy whereas ness is a hot
missing would you be there
trying to make something like this
run-up
I yeah so that actually was a fairly
common question was a people that I was
working with I like honestly I don't
know enough about how to
how to communicate between the phone the
controller or I don't know how to
like what the best way to go about doing
that and this case I just got these XP
modules which
I think total cost like $70 dollars so
that was just the choice I went with
nice if
yeah it
the great up couple questions
what was the total cost how long
actually taking
its okay yes that's a good question the
cost
its okay so the cost I love
building it was much so okay so the
plant itself is
several thousand dollars in get these
from I get from a black dot com
basically
depending on the size it's going to
affect how much it is but the magnitude
is several thousand dollars
the hardware that I bought all cost less
than a thousand
which is actually much cheaper than if
you were to go would like an analogue
solutions so like I know there are some
systems to like
record video aerial video or whatever
with purely analog systems I think
there's a power drop problems as well
the draw more power but short answer
yeah but less than a thousand dollars
the helium itself a in total about to
enter fifty dollars for
three cubic feet which fill this up
twice
yeah oo sorry
I started this project over year ago put
on hold for a while
and then for the past few months have
been spending I mean
a bit I short probably about three
months total like seriously working on
it
okay i guess im at a time the thank you
very much
thank you