it looks like it's still a few people
coming in
on fact a steady stream of people coming
in if there since placing your order if
you could please defragment would
make life a lot easier
squee up
well as German it's great to see a
completely packed house here for our
our last session after lunch here at
icon 2014 in Montreal
%uh it's quite clear that our next
speaker needs no introduction
no I every please welcome pythons
favorite mad scientist a paisley
I
all right there thank you very much that
that this by 10 to come up the most
boring talk title in pie at the pike on
defected 12 reviews in there
soonish Africa vet have terrible tile on
so what this with the stock is about
kinda weird topic in 2005
as a higher take a look at one have
terabytes of source code in a secret
vault
will talk about how you get that much
source code in a second on
and then at six years later ended up
testifying about concurrency an event
loops and US District Court
I'm you think oh good god what was that
about
it was if not to judge Wapner by the way
on
and so what this talk is about it
actually discovery in with pie pan
are basically bringing pipeline into a
legal battle
I think in this picture the chair is
Python okay so like
with what this is about I'm and just
kinda kinda Sep this out
on I don't disclaimer everything this
talk is true
but all the names and details been
changed I could've non-disclosure I'd
have to kill you ever take a long time
in this room and
on so so basically just a bit as I know
nothing in your gonna learn nothing so
just keep that inactivate much on
now ther to set this out on gonna meet
Allah
donated Alice and Bob I meet Alice
meet Bob I every time a crypto graffiti
on okay so
out about a bob for whatever reason
wants to send Allison message
that that she will understand to do this
he's going to employ attorney bob's
attorney
ban be in there and the attorney is
going to
a in new calyx with a patent
infringement lawsuit along with an evil
laugh
on I don't know what happened between
the two of them because this but I a
patent infringement lawsuit
on Alice been fortune has somehow
managed to find
Lawrence Lessig to Def and her I was
going to crush
van in this in this battle here
basically with this talk is about
is essentially patents in some sense I
mean
you these are things that you hear about
a lot the news a patent infringement
softer patents or other bullshit
novelist up
on I'm not I'm not gonna we talk so much
about that
except to say that if you ever get into
a patent litigation
it will turn your world upside down the
reason to get into in a sec add
on and it's also something that is kinda
that the background at the talk
I meet a world okay why did why did Dave
said in a fault with wanna have
terabytes source code on
he was basically in the context of a
patent litigation
and and where it came up is sorted in
this
this time-line what happens in a patent
lawsuit what happens in these lawsuits
is that some you know the Super get
filed
and then kinda goes quiet for a while
I mean like it kinda follow the news you
know it's like us and company sues
there's only one answer goes quiet on
be the cases such a goes into a phasing
out its packed
discovery which might last a year maybe
even more because it goes on for a while
on and essentially what in what's going
on in that fact discovery phase
is the lawyers and the teams are trying
to figure out just what in the world is
going on
on essentially what you have if the
plaintiff in a case
is saying while there's obvious patent
infringement right
and earthworm persons a snake great know
what that's about
I have the defendant essentially saying
well know there'd but things are
obviously
different right there is no infringement
on
yes they have it yet these two sides at
what is happening
in in this artifact discovery is that
that that that
the two sides essentially have to to
take
data from the case which might be things
like specifications and drawings and
documents and software and so forth and
sort of figure out what the
a quote backs are in in this legal case
and
you know it in it if not usually are
really clear-cut thing
many times right i mean it's it's it's
not an obvious thing or two about
obviously different or its obviously
obvious obviously them
so to do this on usually what happens is
a fact expert
were an expert witness or something like
that is called in to look at the
look at the facts in the case of
something involving software
it could be. something this room
myself in this case I mean to you
typically
what that what lawyers are looking for
some cut technical expert
I that is unbiased me not employed by
either the parties or have a
relationship with them
I would be something that wouldn't
hopefully know somebody so they they
typically tend to target what university
professors
people like that you know that that know
things in any sense they're gonna
they're gonna look
look at the facts in the case and what
you have is kinda burn
you know a team to look something like
this you know me bob attorney
you have a a bunch of coworkers you like
we got these are the fees are usually
like the
people the law firm who haven't made
partner yet they're like they're
jobs on the line fact expert I'm in
reality
it's actually probably more like this
arm Bob attorney
with with coworkers the fact expert I
looks like that
in my case that that's me on that picky
when it looks like to bike
in the Chicago winner by the way I'm I
don't know whether people thought the
first talk in this session but they're
talking about
biking in Montreal so I would assume
it's kinda similar to
how so so that's that's kinda the team
and if this happens to you it's actually
a really fascinating experience like if
you get
get the call so to speak said a when he
come in and look at some source code for
a patent infringement suit
are you're essentially gonna be trapped
into just a huge firestorm
hell actually I because what what's
going to happen is there gonna drop you
into this case
with no technical guidance really I'm
and the reason
that they don't there is a kick in the
guidance is that's because the
why they called you actually they don't
know what's going on and so
I'm so some other things that they're
gonna happen is you're gonna get end up
getting into the
really quick learning say phase would
like we have to learn with the invention
accordance with Patton is a that BS like
what is it about
I'm to do that you're gonna get all
sorts of really fun
reading assignments like you have to
read the patent itself which might look
something like this where it's like
you note the system of claim 5 or 6
wherein the display and input means
comprises display means that maybe they
can read that
and and like get out it's like your head
just take a
head explodes I yes from the movie
scanners which is
ago a great Canadian work apart actually
sup I so I so you have the you do you
have that
I'm in in the case if in the case if
this thing the Patton
actually had six hundred pages at C code
attached to it as a PDF printed in 1989
unlike a dot matrix printer
on and you get these fine job so it's
like
okay at this the we do with this convo
on
I ended up having to basically compile
the code from here
I mean that this is something like
you're going in as an experts like is
this patent
exit BS like that even work I'm could
you explain this code to
to other people so on the very first
thing that happens is you have to
your you have to figure out this
invention in the case if this thing
on actually printed out all the code
inside owned a highlighter
over the weekend and highlighted of
function definitions and of function
calls
it's only available in paper basically
Isaac printed out you highlight all
function called how highlight all our
all function definitions and so forth on
in a diff using Python to manually
linkage I
did to you censure you would you entered
into despite my data structures
I from you know paper copy and then you
just crank it
through Python to do with a manual
Lincoln what's going on here
the measure trying to figure out whether
that code is actually complete to the
nafta vote that have holes in it other
like missing chunks on it
chunks in the code that kinda that kind
of thing I'm
I'm not going to explain that Python
code and in great detail
except to say that if you're not using
this comprehension and set apprehensions
in the collections module
you're missing out on an awesome secret
weapon for getting all sorts of problems
solved okay so
I'm so you you he said after weekend
you like this code argue would say why
would you why would you do that
one of the things that that will happen
in this legal case is it at some point
if it continues far enough
you're going to be asked about that
cologne maybe
like under old or something like that
and if you don't know how it works
you're gonna look leaf freakin bad right
okay so
I'm it so you what you will die
basically later if you don't understand
ago
so soap part of what happened is you
have to understand your like
your own side go that's gonna be
interesting
so horrible in a way I i might be the
only person who had the link
a six hundred-page the program by hand
on paper and
python script so as they do that but
then it but then it actually gets
get even more interesting in these cases
on you actually have to deal with the
other side
so so you have hours here I'm what's
what's gonna happen
you know on that side is a you're
essentially dealing with
like a whole different organization
dealing with some some company
there very hostile to you so you have
alice is group at ninja
Rockstar coaters you know they've been
they've been doing things
up because you're filing probably a
packed like a
like Center filing a lawsuit you would
actually
probably not be suing somebody with no
money
but probably actually not a bunch of
ninja Rockstar coaters actually instead
probably what hours has is a bunch of
Engineers
and they're probably SEIA CMMI Level
four certified with like an ISO 9000
certification
okay so arm your it but this is you get
the other side in something like this is
typically not
like a startup company okay it's some
something else and what they're going to
do
is essentially kill you with
with with documents now this is it
insane so it's like in in this case
show up the lawyers actually took me to
a room in a sec a year we could get a
printout
you know and can you take a look at the
print out some just to put it like a
number on it
on rema paper is 500 pages
a box of papers 5,000 pages
they had a up 100 boxes
have printed paper five hundred thousand
pages printed actually literally printed
out
in a room stacked up they didn't know
what it was
on 300,000 pages if it were TPS reports
softer change notices things like that
on
the other they don't don't do it I'm
summer the other stuff that you find in
there are on
quote source code
but you don't know anything really okays
like all the other says print out the
object file to hourly math
right okay so you know turnout has been
a source code on
you might get boxes emails you know
here's a email from Guido
RE said hey fire design language FIU's
braces
rightly you'd like you can take that to
the lawyers and they all and I found the
smoking gun in the email about some
itself say fine at on you get things
like alleged prior art
from all over the place like schematic C
Mike its software were you don't even
know what in the world it is from
like 1983 year you know assembly code
are you know it's like i don't know
the ECB anybody actually recognized that
and added that plat 6
now forget to get a whole bunch
unrecognized stop
on but legal team might actually be
deposing people at the time to make it
like a
deposition up some crazy gray bearded
guy right now so
ob cell you know it it will help add you
know bring out some stuff
saying well yeah I spotted this in my
basement wellville
no further winter holiday or something
like that so so
you get your gift that I'm and then in a
really fun part is you're gonna get all
their software
to this is in some way kinda awesome
because what when you get into a legal
case lingered on the other side they can
ask for anything
and say hey when he just give us the
whole code base handed over at all
proprietary
proprietary software in the case that
this
David after the software it was actually
sitting over in a fault
on the west side of chicago on and
just just add up with some perspective
on this so it's a match in that this is
the ad what they've
Chicago here essentially be a
bio to my kids here you have for this
fall
in kind of a secret location that is
actually a picture the your fault by the
way
outside nondescript nondescript building
acid in national by the train tracks
and coincidentally right next to the
rock band rehearsal space
said I was there you can see it
I'm actually in that picture by the way
there's a party rock band there so I
it's always gonna
it national in this very sketchy part of
town I
the protocol for the ball is can't have
any computers
no phone electronics no storage and that
you bring a pen and paper book that
that's pretty much it
on they had a PC locked in a cage
along with the printer in a log book on
so that so that that was what was in
there
on as far as what be found there was
just at large collection up
hard drives basically immediate 1/2
terabyte hard drive
and as far as it what it was there look
like they took
maybe up a gigantic box of compact discs
and I just copied it on air in no order
it whatsoever all say a little bit more
about
what it is in a second but just you know
you just imagine tyke going through your
closet use them in a fight every compact
discs but I see in the whole room and
I'm just gonna send it over to the other
side
nigga put on this machine so no no
organization at all
are and just a just put a little
perspective on how horrible this is no
way I'm
database actually produced like the
software archive for pretty much
everything related to this thing on
to you can have the invention and the
things that they were producing with
things like
you'd like embedded microcontrollers you
had keypads display module seven segment
displays
your PC they had made a custom PCI board
with its own custom operating system
custom software for that
on system action: involved a second PC
so you have like all these different
components she had all the software for
all of these things like
so if you wanted to know what the
firmware was in the display like the LCD
display module you got that
yet so that they can I gave you the
whole the whole works on
infection or a distributed system in
fact there's like a custom router
multiple copies of devices up the
software for this is out what I would
describe
all stack not to force back but like all
stack so
I'm they have like effect about a
million lines of code involving c plus
plus
see assembly Java Visual Basic
asap you know it it's sort of things
like they had their own distributed
object systems decom korva
hope the whole the whole works there are
and then on top of that the time frame
at this
that this thing was basically over 15
years so that turns out how to get one
and a half terabytes
you basically hand of God 800 snapshot
to that system
over like a 15-year period with also
took multiple hardware revisions
on configurations different operating
systems OS two
Windows NT and so forth and they don't
happen at
they had like custom to the skins on
this software customize for big
corporate clients so it's like there's
like a big corpus system there but all
these custom skins on it
also 200 interlocking versions and so
forth and so
on it's also what my job is it is it is
basically did tell the lawyers like what
is this thing
and be provided tools or Windows XP
awesome on the Windows command prompt
possum at the search my I itself
yeah awesome I don't know whether I yeah
people
trip remember the Windows XP search
might but yeah pretty pretty awesome
I you could use notepad ball because
that came with Windows and then
up because they're feeling generous
they've had visual studio
okay so time you had all these a
all these tools on their I'm you could
print anything that you want it turns
out no fault
out but had to be flogged and it was
copied in given to the other side
nothing really happens and likes secret
a lot of these lawsuits like if you're
gonna print something out
because you think it's interesting the
other side is going to get it to
okay so you are you could you could you
could you could do that but
be at the other side would know what you
were doing and then there's some other
constraints as well
on there was actually no working
hardware setup could run the code
on US you can build the code either
because missing libraries I'm
no tech support you can't call up the
other side saying hey we're a
market for the guys are suing you I'm
kinda confused about this code in
you know tell me about it so those that
in a very fragmentary a documentation so
so you look at this shelter hadith
horrible tho
here's the here's the interesting thing
on it turns out that
on in the fall want to go over there
I fired the command prompt I type a fire
on it comes up
and what how did it come up like like
now I know it's like
I mean this is this is I write this is
odd I mean if you've ever use Python and
Windows
does it get installed in the path no
right it in the past like who put it
there in the path I'm
the only the only gas on S
is that it was probably used by IBM is
an
as part of an OEM tool I was actually
talk to Brian curtain about this at one
point he could he doesn't up with the
pipe on Windows is likely a we get
we got occasional like virus reports
from users thing he wants is Python
thing on my machine I just bought it it
was used by something by the vendors are
took turns out it was dare
for reasons unknown and of course that
so to change the whole picture right I
mean if you've ever had this this this
spot like are you up i dont be really
awesome
desert island language this this is like
the perfect chance to like tried that
theory out right side
bad battery batteries included up by
a good fortune I actually wrote the
Python book
right so on I thought I was allowed to
bring books into the vault I'm like okay
I'm gonna
I'll be back and I'll be in my book on
and
kinda the that the strategy on it is I'm
gonna go in there and I'm to build
basically
software entirely from scratch in the
ball to do this
i download a talk about that before it
before getting to that
I do wanna just race one questions like
What What Rd what are the objectives of
this
exercise exactly like me that this is a
very unusual project with like the
lawyers are just saying hey cookbook at
the code names like
book yet but what is that up so
if I ever had to describe it the
objectives and they're kind of this
I'm one of them was just sort of this
what question like what did they give us
because nobody actually knows they know
that there's a bunch of hard drives in
there but like what is it
on that the other things just how does
it actually work
we'll get to that in in the third one is
the more weird one is like
because as the patent case ultimately
you have to answer where in that code
does the patent exist that's the weird
is that the weirder one so
I'm talk some other time the horror on S
I'm essentially the first part a bit
is your gonna have to reverse engineer
the whole building firemen of whatever
this is like finding like what are the
components
how do they get built for the complete
what are they are the BX these are the
deal elderly plugins
are you might have to do something like
just pick
like some you just pick like a directory
of code ECP could pull it apart
you might look at things like make files
you know thing
okay what your sources years libraries
this is a lot of like just pencil paper
like
right we're we're just like up gaddis
horrible
on it's like the last iraq assembling a
actually
don't ask how I store this picture from
Titus brown's last talking last section
here
on its copyright infringement right side
up
notice and I think it's at effect checks
are puzzled words like you
units like okay here all the pieces go
to put it together
so from for some other ways that you
that you do this is
but the first thing it should be obvious
if you have to re implement UNIX
okay so on so that's the that's the
first the first step so a lot of it
I'm decade that the search might
it now I mean AKC have you have to do
some basic tooling to
to do this turns out to be like pretty
easy
to do a lot and want to think that you
can do is use the like a pipe up nigga
like you just
implement like basic Unix commands using
like simple python
statement you know what basic navigation
stuff
job this is rare that 6 like the six
line program that will do
DF between two files
michael has def live like you know you
need a you can we can you can to defeat
you can build up with a little likable
collection tools
and you might just use the Python
interactive shell to just do your
navigation isn't the Windows command
shell kinda
Sox out for you know what you that so
I'm so
in actually in one sense what you're
doing here
is if you're kind of building your own I
Python
from scratch alienated the yard admit
the tickets ticket to
very stripped down one but you're really
just sitting over there with the book
saying on to reinvent everything I need
as a need in the in the ball on charge
that is sorted sitting in their unique
gifts in fines and
and and and so forth on but then what
you been we start do is you started
started way here on this thing he said
okay like that UNIX but now I'm gonna
start doing some
some some workflow kinds of things where
you might
you might do things like okay and I'm
your FB like my to start with a python
pancho here's a function that will
produce
every single directory name and file
name on the whole machine
I I tested this out with like every
pipeline version
that existed as a sample you might say
okay well wake up I wanted to find all
files in all versions of Python
just fire this at it you just start
spitting out file
and then that with that would become you
know media component in your sister
need to start building things on top it
were you'd say well you know what what
it would give us exactly like water all
the file types up everything on all
those one-and-a-half terabytes have
a desk you'd say do something like this
a harmonica histogram all file types
and just couldn't come to see you were
to their Lee County Python files are
there how many see files are there
you might actually look for things that
are really interesting like unusual file
format I actually
something more interesting things would
be things like PDF files and Doc files
for
reasons that will get into later but
because it can inspect what's there
maybe that would become a come and other
component maybe you would write some
code to find
like find things you know your say now
okay I wanna find all tight on files
onto a search
again you're trying to you try to
uncover things on this huge collection
of hard drive images
CD images to do things do things like
that
are you migrate little utility things
where I want concrete a manifesto all
versions of cold crypt
we are provided to us just like you to
put a regular expression
in and talk to your cell you we do
things like this maybe
run it and identify like all versions of
Python and
and and so forth so you can't build up
bike tools for you would say things like
okay identify which
there and maybe start writing out
manifests up
YouTube you century doing a big
inventory job
searching through all this day to find
all the versions of things trying to put
it together
on the whole time you're you're sorta
you know consulting with lawyers in a
way saying I was over there and I found
you know 700 versions of the software
noticed f.y.i you know there's you know
700 versions that a million mines at
Seco Road I'm
that that kind of thing and so you do
kinda you can't you can't build up the
fees were closed
I'm and then you can just start piling
it up on
sorta sorry even higher one of the
things that happen in this project
is that the beast snapshots were just
sort of scattered randomly overall the
desks it was too hard to deal with
so sort implemented kind about on a
absorbed virtual file system if you well
as credible layer
where you could just enter in like us
like a software version and it would
just take you there
and you didn't have to worry about all
that the way that was actually structure
kinda clear it up on and
some other stuff that you would do there
are just take all the software versions
you would find out things like
development timelines
all the versions like how Ranger dates
did they go over today
debate overlap in some sense your most
reconstructing things like i'd get high
you know like you know 14 you know like
history or something like that you're
doing it almost in reverse actually
you're taking a much snapshots in trying
to recreate history
prominent up some other things that you
would do is is are right like right
coder you'd say things like ok give me
every version of this file that has ever
existed like you could say
on you know quite yet but you could you
pick
like a version: by I'm using Python is
an example that you could say hey give
me every
version of thread that CD that has ever
existed
and would it would go through these like
800 snapshots and it would produce like
some history saying well you know in
inversion 12 and 13 was exactly the same
and then like you know all
like version to all the way up to 2.1 .3
there's like no
7 versions of code words exactly the
same again we're trying to do is take
all the stuff and decompose it break it
down and
into inventories on it popular also
a lot navigational tool in like if you
needed go somewhere you can write little
few functions read say hey I want to
look at see a bow
in this version of python and maybe
would launch a visual studio or
something
because United have a whole lot a choice
on editors write you can't you can't
install anything on this machine so
for work with work with what you got so
you to build up
you build up all the stuff and you don't
want one comment on this
I'm not actually I'm not sure that the
other side in this case
ever anticipated that we would figure it
out
like me I think that was kinda the
expectations like we take every CD in
the closet
you know in archive we're gonna send it
to him and let him figure it out
on ethnic in reality I which he almost
knew everything about everything
like when you all versions of everything
that they gave us in like timelines and
also to study was all
inventory I don't think it would have
been possible all Alpine
like I can't even imagine doing that but
no patter like
search like the searchlight and notepad
by Howie Day
I I was actually I was actually thinking
about it recently a pic
how would I have done that I I guess in
the the only alternative would have been
to
you fire up Visual Studio and then to re
implement pipe on I'm
as probably the only II just on how you
with how you how to do that so
Sox other colors that out and then you
get into these other
like horrible things with this column in
one of the things that that okay
like to think we just described as
programming what is there
we haven't even talked about how it
works it's more like just what his I'm
so you have this other thing which is
well how does this how does this code
work are
and this includes pretty much everything
like the software architecture
interaction between components
algorithms the
you know that the whole thing I mean
expert
what you're gonna have to do is take
that million line program
and you can have two first we'll explain
it to the people that you're working for
and then maybe later on you might have
to explain it to
potentially like a jury or something
like that so you can't just go in there
for like 20 minutes into your kinda
again
so you really have to pick your have to
pull it apart I'm and in the thing is I
reading code
is terrible on your do really wanna read
like a million line program that you
didn't
right I mean it's the top horrible I me
what you want is you want design
dachshunds backs
and stuff like that but the best thing
is the other side for a hostile
they don't wanna they want to help you
they don't give you that kind of stuff
so
so what ends up happening next
is you go on it when I can best describe
is a gigantic fishing
expedition opera things like interesting
documents like pdf doc files RTF HTML
text files
you do mine enough code comments action
one of the things we did a lot of talk
about his next fight you to search all
source code for the word see
and you see what comes up because what
you're hoping some developer has written
out like a comment like
this function really tricky you're more
detail see this document
like you you what you're looking for is
like a Michael Michael boost threat or
something you looking for
something to to make offer you my goth
looking for all those TPS reports
hoping that somebody dropped a clue you
look through everything I mean is
actually
your cat kinda thing that you would find
you might find a comment that would say
something like this: no
CFS 6541 AP to oversee details
night %uh it interesting and this action
when the cool thing about fact
like a been a fact expertise you can go
to the attorneys
and you can pretty much get them to do
to unleash any weapon you want on the
other side
right you can so so you can go to them
and you say hey you know I think we
would really be really cool to have this
document FS 6541
EP 20 on and so what happens you know
the attorney will drop the letters and
it often is kinda silent for a few days
you know it the other side is like how
crack like you already know about that
on and then
you're magically out at the paper you
get some document you now
Acme widgets functional specification
version 2.0 and inside
you know tag proprietary and
confidential and then
you know if he senses company has their
act together the very first pages that
related documents content then what you
do is you rip dad of
and give it to the attorneys in say no
every week or get all that stuff too
odd and you out you but you basically
what unwind the whole access to market
action all the pieces
I'm doing things like that any search
everything and stop or change notices
unreal you might actually looks up for
software on something like a display
module like firmware for the display
module because I might make
reference to the main application in
some way
and you're just you're just look at the
base but what we're trying to use pipe
porn tube loose thread
you can pull on it as far as you can
pull on it and sand to see you how much
what their pain point is you know before
they
they do that so up so that that that's
another thing that happens on want one
comment on this
I actually think that this is an awesome
exercise if you ever get a chance to do
that regardless of what you think about
patents because if you ever get thrown
into a cup
i'd like the fire thing that you need to
understand this million my program he
did right
with no help at all like no
documentation you gonna learn
tana stop reading that car actually
about
everything even like like I'd never seen
stuff with like CMMI Level four
like the software engineering gonna
staff which this group was practicing
you get to see that stuff like all the
procedures in their documents and
it's really fascinating to to see that
aren't the only thing is you're gonna
have to teach attorneys about it
on attorneys are not done by the way pat
attorneys
usually have science and engineering
degrees they're not of a not a softer
engineers but they're there to pick
their smart guys feel smart smart
men and women know they can understand
it but they but but but you do you're
gonna have to explain it to them
are the other side doesn't want you to
to succeed this so it's a little bit
hostile
arm so you will learn a lot some other
things that that I learned of this is
going to get me into
serious trouble here but this is a these
are the
the Sox rocks lessons up having to look
at other people's code
I don't they were doing this project on
c plus plus
an assembly code up turns out that in
assembly code the code is so
minimal but it just does what it's
supposed to do the C pas pas code need
at least
18 levels of indirection a design
patterns terror
on a synchronous and threats now I'm
really in trouble here
I'm you know that objects functions
there
ID's make filed a pretty much anything
on
actually developed since the nineteen
seventies
I'm it out sorta
so distorted this sorted sorry for not
getting notice it's kind of amazing
actually guineas in these cases that
what they're gonna do is try it out
things like prior art enough they ever
get this prior art from 1975 can you go
take a look at it
and you look at it like this week 3
pages a code
it cool I could understand it right then
you go to compare it to the million line
C plus plus programmers like
God like we've done everything wrong so
I had so you know a Chris Chris like
could you could be wrong about that
are event and then the other sorta weird
thing about this is getting into kinda
the weirdest part of this whole thing
on in this fact discovery
phase I'm the attorneys are actually
plane
a very different kind of game with a
patent infringement suit
mandate that you're over there looking
at the software and there's these
questions like when I you know dissident
free and you're not and so forth
the attorneys are actually playing in a
kinda weird chess game
that you only understand if you
understand bill clinton's com at
about I am you know these famous quote
comes with a mean the word is
but what people like laughed at that my
idiot you know it's like
at the obviously never been and I like a
patent infringement suit on
what it what is going on is the the
attorneys are basically dealing with
that language in the Patton
like you have this horrible claim that
like major head explode earlier
they're actually going through that
entire claim
and fighting about it what it means like
what does this claim mean
and they're gonna fight and they're
gonna fight in front of a judge over an
extended period of time about what this
thing means
and I'm just just just did give you some
background if you love arguments
about things like the Oxford comma this
is
your battle right okay like like if you
love grammar art
act like arguments and and things like
that this is this is what they're kinda
fighting about these things like
on terms and languages like helped I'll
take a claim in of a central processing
unit was at me
in the defendant will say what you have
to be like a model 800 486 you know
version to exactly two hundred mayors
the other side will say what could be
any computer at all
and then you know the plane air force a
while display could be anything the
other side will have to be seven segment
display
and they're gonna fight over this I'm
extensively about what the definitions
that these terms are
and the thing is here's here's the
catch: I'm whatever they decide the
terms are
it actually has to exist in reality like
you can't have a definition
resale here the CPU is this and then
that doesn't exist anywhere like you
actually have to be able to point at the
Patton
say will there it is in the pattern and
then on top of that you have to point at
the other side you have to say whether
it is or there
so they're fighting over these terms you
know such a trying to find things
and I I was trying to ban about this
what you're the other night to get this
is like a knob looking like they can
return it upper gallery
I'm to any level what abstraction they
want like down to the
Adams at the universe or all the way up
to like
you know planet earth I hit its very
sorry ive
you know Malo boy away so that that's
the two sides are fighting about this
but ultimately what's gonna happen in
this
on in the software fact stuff you're
gonna have to build a point at something
specific like
if the attorneys say what is the
definition they have to go to court the
code and say you know what
in this file food at sea line 230 255
that's where it is
and so this is a this is a problem to
which is well how are you gonna do that
on 800 version that this million mind
program like me to just pick one at
random and say well we looked at that
one
or are you know what would you do on it
the the thing that we did in this
project is we've decided to do
all of them at once and the way that
that was done was doing something to
America fragment version it's kind of
like
I'm source code control but applied to
individual code fragment the censure
what you would do
is maybe I'm identify like some piece of
code that was pertinent to the patent
saying okay well here's this piece a
coding question and you would market
office it may be like up code fragment
think this is
you know this is the file that it and
then it starts with this you know this
Boyd crockett ends with this boy blog or
whatever
and then what you would do is write a
script that we go through all 800
snapshots collecting that fragment
across all versions and then what it
would would it would do is collect all
the unique ones that it found like all
the band
three versions turn up at this was this
was highly effective by the way like you
would find these versions that code in
the
like you over the 800 snapshot you might
only find liked 6 persians
some fragment and really kinda the the
thought here as you're trying to reduce
this massive data set
to some kind of scene structure where
you could say well you know this claim
that you have
matches this piece of code by waiters
11:06 version
and here the six persian that's the kind
of thing that you could present
to like a judge or something whoever
same get this this is
this is what what's going on so so is
some comments on S
you know that that have to pay a fine
thing on my dick
take away on this whole thing is that
papon in some sense makes Impossible
Project like that possible I mean it
it's like
cadmium take horrible were any not even
been able bring your headphones into the
vault
was just like torture I mean it's it's
like you're in this fault code in its
like
using pipe you take this Impossible
Project you gonna break it down into
something that's sane
that you can actually do in my computer
reasonable amount of time
it I mean actually occurs to me that
isn't expert this is prolly the wrong
approach I probably should have used
notepad
so I could charge like 4,000 hours a
a work but no reply fun really am really
broke it down
I was just at the parenthetical comment
that even pipeline
3d makes a makes makes and the
impossible possible
on and so and for some final some final
thoughts on this thing
if you ever get a chance to do something
like this you know worldwide
I'm not sure we want to do it again you
know there's a lot of things like that
weird thing at character building but
you don't wanna
don't wanna go there again ob but videos
it so interesting
but here it but you you might say happy
senior the and this is
how how this thing end you know I'd like
I i just bike talk but his legal battle
on I don't know
this is the weird thing about our tony's
legal cases are
you might be called into it as an expert
might work on it for months
and in all this and think disappears and
the just pack everything up goes away
it might've been saddled might have been
thrown out of court I'm
up to this case I do know some details I
know that they lost the case initially
I don't know the the exact details of
the judgment on that but
on but it is it's actually mysterious
like your you're basically only privy to
the
but the technical part in the case
you're not privy to things like
like they have a settlement or something
you're not you don't know you don't know
how it went
usually so so and even if I did know I
couldn't tell you anyway so I'm
but the effort for ends abruptly as a is
kind of a footnote on their
getting duty and here on my and game on
this is sort of
curious but arm I learned a ton a stuff
like
generator functions using this doing
this exercise
because it was so much data and I
couldn't read into RAM it's like
when we gonna me to do this it I think
it ultimately was the background for
this really well known
generator tutorial if you can carry this
online you wonder why did Dave do that
op it it basically came out the ball
figure of bigger TV actually enough to
actually one cool thing about working in
the fall
is it all code that was written in the
ball stay in the fall
I don't have to maintain I have to do
bug reports it's like
its its god-like not my problem you know
at this point so it's a
yup state say they're are 10 10
postscript on this too
if you get involved with wanna do you
think you might actually go all the way
to writing and expert report
the gets used in like actual you know
the court proceeding
on this is something that is actually
really interesting
I'm that all men should just speaking as
an academic sake I used to be at the
University
I we've had this this fear or thought
that nobody ever read anything I wrote
you know this number academics do that
with anybody read what you write
tightest you thinking
you take the fifth day I'm is always the
Spirit God even for like my dissertation
and grad schools like and I don't know
if I'd
visor you can read my dissertation so on
so here here's the thing if you write an
expert report
but if you do effort with it should have
to write a report I can absolutely 100
percent guarantee that it will be read
and read at the level up up each satins
down to like things like commas
and stop their gonna they're gonna take
your cycle take it they're gonna one
beach like 10 para we'd like legal
assistant fire
like attorneys I'd they're gonna read
and then they're gonna Hall you into a
deposition
which is usually you a bunch of
attorneys
on a videographer about what I put like
a huge kick it is really cool I get like
that
biggest video camera that they can find
right in this little tiny room and shut
your face
you know like timid AU on and you're
sitting there for eight hours and I get
asked about the report
are it isn't awesome experience because
you're here's the thing is awesome
if they have read the report and they're
gonna discuss it indep
every detail with you and it's going to
be a big conversation about your report
and they're gonna they're going to try
to basically destroyed and so it is
it is really awesome or horribly bad
experience
on be it where you could be horribly bad
as a few went in there too I kinda
looked at the patent for like half an
hour in
he kinda looks similar you know that
that's how you would die basically
from there I thought so there's that up
court court testimony i I mention that
actually ended up going to court up
talking about concurrency
like what was that about are it turns
out it was related to this
claim term definition stop there is a
huge battle involving like concurrency
and the judge was so sick of people
battling about he's like okay
everybody come in you gonna teach me
about it are in a love you and i got
three hour power point presentation on
concurrent programming
in like I courtroom that the only thing
that was different for like this in a
way
except the whole audience with attorneys
and then are
and NP afterwards they had their own
expert come up
and then brief you everything that I
just said to the previous three hours
and then I'm and ending haddock this
huge battle was kinda
cut kinda kinda entertaining there so us
let's that's
that into the into the TOC we might have
a time for an hour
quest a cluster
how long did you spend in the fall
and how long did you spend specifically
with your pipe on automation
develop so most that this took place
I meant the pride of five months in the
law it started over the summer and it
went for like five to six months what
was the second for the question
on the automation arm
I think that that the automation part
was probably stuck outside
under a hundred hours on it the biggest
the the biggest
time sync above all was actually
figuring out how the code worked
i mean because it was like you have this
massive like how do you figure out how a
million mine seaports Plus program works
I mean it's a lot of that was like
pulling code fragments and building like
three-ring notebooks
like things really like what this
Talkster that in this talk to dad and
water
a lot of discussion with attorneys
involving claims like
if you define this like this you're
gonna die
this is the reason why you're gonna die
because like this coat over here doesn't
do that that like with that way so to
what I've like
behind the scenes like like consultation
about how things work
how the case has been framed and so
forth yeah
last question so
good heavy lifting just the searchlight
you might have been dead in the water
how they feel about using Python I don't
think they knew
I don't think they know I'm wealth its
ok to call this
their question how did they did they
know that we are using Python
on the up so all that Python code with
living on the fault and wasn't personal
never printed
so there's no printed record have
anything
coming up the case you know if if it had
actually gone to trial
was fully expected that the code would
have been produced probably would have
been part of the
production but I but in this girly stage
a fact discovery I don't think they knew
I don't even think are like the side
that I was working on knew what was
going on they just knew that what day
would go over to the ball
but you'd really like David go to the
vault for like a day and he would sort
merge
other at all the other kinda weird thing
about this by the way that the attorneys
asked that I never communicate via email
this is like the art this is like the
the ultimate think I'd like don't talk
to us at all
because I like if you'd working as an
expert that can't be produced
later as evidence in there just like
where we don't really know what we want
to do with you just don't talk to us so
attend like the alternate work
environment like you have the client the
client doesn't even want you to talk to
them right so
so what you do is you go over to the on
take over the you go to the vault
you can't work away and then you get mad
from their point of view day would
magically appear from the ball
with this thing like a one you asked for
documents FS
861 dash be two or something like that
they're like much interest in and then
yes there's a lot of thing a lot of
things like that
thank you became this gentleman place
like david beasley
there's of like downstairs things get
started getting
of an hour or so bookie programs are
thank you very much thanks