good afternoon everybody
thank you so much for coming in joining
us today after lunch
I know you are quite sleepy but I hope
this is going to be a very exciting talk
arm Hitech is going to be talking to
us a little bad about like access al
you now that thing years please a big
round of applause frantic and Estonia's
cell shot quick poll are whilst the
difference between
SSL and TLS okay
mechanic it's good the S a few cedar shy
or in a very right room so I Munich
this is how I look on internet arm but
I'm not allowed on Twitter
are writing some other sort of the
program a good am doing infrastructure
at a small but friendly German opposing
company called are a major
where if you speak German to get you all
remains from but I want you to talk
about myself
I'm here to tell you I'll let those
shiny look i cant to tell you that
you're safe because of military-grade
encryption
our ally in fact I
you're on the road never really slept
and why the statement seem to
bits a controversial last week I assure
you
arm that in the grand scheme of things
absolutely nothing changed since last
Sunday
I'm arm you simply need to know how
things
fits together in are two assess and
minimize risks
and up uke you and your your search of
TLS
and others al can do much more damage
than any but will ever do
so before it
do our first trip to better and I'm
introduces only got the right down today
every other link and project and for
material I will be mentioned today
will be there especially more mature to
dive deeper into our concept I'm
introducing because at him
my thing forty minutes for a such
complex
I'm topic like RTLS way too little
cell now just relax and enjoy the show
what it why is the state of as all sorry
maybe should start at Ground Zero
and discuss what it actually is so what
as al
and what elle has it to do with Hillis I
think those terms are best explained
with a short history lesson because
everybody loves history lessons and all
particular one starts in the mid 90s
when it gets thought it might be pretty
cool if entering a credit card number
on the internet would entail people
buying drugs of your money
and so in 1995 they released their
completely host as a2 as the foundation
for a GPS
but as it stands for Secure not for us
as outcome
and the fix the most rock burst martz
one year later it has all three and
another three years later it finally
became an official
ATF standard and was renamed to key last
so again as El is a product from
netscape
from 1996 TLS San official standard for
fifteen years now
cell are basically a trick to inherit
the name
but everybody knows that deliberations
are always awesome
and I wanted to reach everyone I could
so if I had to trick you into the name
I hope you learn to first thing today
and will stop saying as a cell in a
future
you and 2006 and 2008
though largely ignored killers 1.1 and
1.2 have been released
both fixed several security problems
brought really nice features but nobody
cared
fast-forward last year for some polar
unreasoning
people started scrutinizing on security
habits again and what their phone calls
really not very good
so 41 all mainstream browser support is
only TLS 12 last year so kilos won from
and the discoveries from arm
last year change everything the times
are just using TLS
are gone arm for price of Greta makes me
barry a suspicious than reassured and
some softer
claims to be secure because of TLS
actually
the mostly safe as a salvage make me RR
suspicious
sup you really need to know roughly
what you doing because this technology
has still very shop
edges and getting it wrong can have very
grave consequences
sup 10 Steelers actually want to provide
you with
first just pure entity using
certificates so you can verify
Europe connecting to do appear you
actually wanted to connect
another some crook who tricked you into
connecting to server
don't get to confidentiality using
encryption
saw people a disturbing on red rope
which is not
arming and a dark magic can sniff out
your secret in a password
this is what most people think of
anything else as LTL as encrypt are
cryptography in general but is only a
third of the whole package
the test pattern is I am message
integrity
saw I yet it the protocols able to
detect
when packages arrive mangled order
multiple times are not at all sought
thats
that's basically key lesson at natural
now
let's look om how to use those and
explain for details along the way
sup after spot to be able to from
spot reversed smells of parochial issues
such
and you will not want to be awarded on
and will start its servers unless noted
I'm sticking to open SSL
throughout the rest of the talk because
that's what we'll most likely be using
where you like it or not
sock an if you deploy server software
it's a duty to ensure the maximum
security for users because they can
neater see more affect your setup
so the first step is to use at least
halfway
up-to-date versions of their party
software if you deploy anything already
threatens today
W negligent lazy and should subduing so
and I'm generously assuming
that your installed all the security
back backport
pages from your solutions these are
the future releases you need to have a a
half a secure setup
a few TLS if if you don't
use that they're eleven back ports
there's obviously no up
no way you're deploying Obama's as a
Alderden 1.0 0.1
G which came alt Monday if you may have
hurt so
on the for think you do when a client
connects to you is that you present them
a certificate that's safe
Rio are which declined should verify
arm in order to make the climb a tree
trust the certificate to senate
it has to be signed by a trusted third
party called
our certificate authority RCA
the set of all public either all trusted
CA's
that can be used to verify the
certificate the signatures
is what we call a trust that the basal
trust store or
system curing depends on architecture
and a um operating system
outscored and to proof the certificates
actually yours
after all you send it out to everyone so
a secret keep a long siege certificate
this key is then used for signatures
that can be verified with the
certificate and the proof that you're
actually in a procession of the secret
key
already for mister roberts. heartbeat so
I'm
in the simplest case CS bout should be
verified that a certain host name
belongs to you by checking
that you get the money and control
against freedom and it's called host
memory vacation
and all certificates are really cheap
and Tom
you take the you can get them in for
free nowadays
on our side of the spectrum is Extended
Validation that obviously also means
extend the payment
and arm but get a company name into you
all bar
and it's basically or is to know
information about the validity
plus signature from personal for party
equal certificate
your job now is to make sure your
certificate setup is trustworthy because
a TLS
its rebirth less if connecting plants
have no way to verify
your identity sup you won't get
a certificate from signed by a trusted
third party arm
when you get a supply chain filed with
contains one or more intermediate
certificates
the complete the trust past 21 so in
this case are that
and trustee a signed some komodo
certificate which
and kept intern find some 100 promoter
certificate which in turn
finally site my certificate now when a
client connects
it gets all three of them and it can
verify to trust chain
so take care of the trust chain
forgetting chain certificates is a
typical rookie mistake
and sure the certificate is valid for to
host them up a server
and finally make sure that the
certificate is not
X expired because arthritis people make
fun of you
there's enough like not use plugins and
everything will for you in time so don't
let it happen
next is able as a to chances are it's
not necessary
bad for infant above Apple's a mess as
El still needs that
but I'm suggesting in any way that you
should deploy servers analyst and
because it through shouldn't
so arm if you don't have to support some
entiende operating system like Windows
XP
miss a bus 03 as well and finally
disable TLS compression to a white crime
attacks
that's about it the next objective is to
configure Cyprus it such a
every client gets the best possible
encryption and the best in this case
means
the most secure and also the fastest
I pursued is just a tubal there is
cryptographic primitives
one of them being a separate self that
are used together to secure connection
and other wanted to serve as the last
say about which supply pursued is used
so use the powerful powerful good and
thus efforts up
is the easiest to explain little star
them you can just imagine as a black box
it takes a plain-text paint if they
don't and a key as import
and return cipher text which should be
ideally interest
indistinguishable from random data as
output kill snipers are symmetric
that meets if you want to decry just
never text arm
there 11 function of the same for Neath
exact same key as the sender to
be able to be cryptid so far I think
it's pretty straightforward
these give up complicated on because
most diverse
on not maybe on most but though
currently most
popular once our blog re-entered I miss
you can just put
1 gigabyte move into it and reading for
a separate text come out
if your data is bigger number saffir
text then up
site for books I S which usually is 128
bits nowadays
you have to chop it up a bit smaller you
have to pet it so
obviously usually have to do both and um
the most common way for to do that is
are separable chaining
bitch unfortunately what's implement
that and ethical suspect poorly
in TLS which piece does with a wide
variety of attacks
I think the most known one is beast
cell the most common way it I'm to miss
a white that
at are still clan site fixes and through
ciphers like rc4 in the past
and touch up twenty and future arm
yet it's basically that current state
then kill us 1.2 brought
a shiny remote call to go lock on
promote which
does much more than just are chipping
and putting but more about that later
now we know what's my purse %uh are
which one to use
sup I would say that the to best current
SciVerse
are ates 128 in a goal a contra mode
and a stream cipher catch up 20% from
dan Bernstein
now ASU cm is better in heart rate and
trisha is better in software
so ideally you'd support both and the
clan decide which one to use and is
actually what Google does now a days
unfortunately it's not three Leah
available to us mere mortals
so simple catch up twenty is not an open
is ahead its
own in chrome up as far as I know they
are working on it to get it out
until then ATSG cm it is for now
so even for to latest Safari and IE
browser still have to fall back to AES
CBC same pfeiffer different mode works
perfectly fine details 1.1 and 1.2
I'm not so much on ps1 again beast I'm
concerts
so I you don't have really much choice
it them hoping that the client
has the relevant existence inode which
fortunately by now
are is true for all mainstream browser
so a poor Celeste wanted
sup and if you need to support engine
clients rate
in those XP in a paroled but there on
earth I would suggest triple the switch
is a decent
but very slow cipher the three basically
means that it's
takes the DS I phrase it three times so
you can imagine it's not the most
efficient
efficient thing to do and as it you
don't need anything else
to support everything you will ever
encounter in a net
and especially wary of the following
once so experts I first for
intentionally written and
when expert of crypto software arm
from the US their poems restricted so
where the middle coast at designed to be
easily credible
DS is the Dez attention pfeiffer
with 56 bikies are also it can be.
would force pretty easily so awarded
also
and finally RC force a bit more
complicated
some people considered as the syllable
the two of the most problems
does I'll beach till book Cyprus
have are shown over the years but on the
other hand own little cryptographer
I know of arabs I'm
of the opinion that it may be broken
waste that a national agencies
maybe already able to decipher it all it
it will be very soon so
based on what I've heard from people who
are way more smart and I am
a general and white against that cell
north to encrypt and decrypt Cyprus
needs a key
and since you're of talking about
symmetric encryption
it has even to be displayed in two key
so either way to agree Inc
on key East over for to encrypt them
connection which is not contribute yet
so we have a nice checking a problem
fortunately math come to rescue am gates
are several ways to
are exchange keys over and in secure
line
with alec you the keys and often three
are currently deployed
first there's are 8 which is not just a
company that took a lot of money from
the NSA
but its its also I'll
a public key cryptosystem so medical it
you have a public yes secret keyed
public you for encrypting secret you for
the crippling
straightforward the you that in kilotons
of very straightforward took
but as soon as a secret key
bleeds out of the server I am
I prepared at 10 but
all future and past communications
become plain text attacker
so we say it like perfect forward
secrecy ordered its not PFS
this bears repeating our one court order
one CE
are once they're a break-in and the
thief can decipher everything they
captured kept rebel capture
this is really bad no but its path to
peep
so especially operation folks really
like it
on Dell turned it used to be a are a
formal diffie-hellman
which is PFS but slow so apps don't Los
don't like slow and
finally nowadays we have though are
relatively new is CDH here is just that
the crib to
version of th you which means it's
faster and it's better to more secure
and you should really do everything
humanly possible to ensure perfect for
secrecy to everyone
and for that you will you need eat both
eche and DH
E and since CDH is faster s
suggest to prefer prefer it and ours a
should be really just a fallback
its should really on if you have to
so finally
message authentication codes or max our
youth message integrity
messages in TLS just means RTLS records
or
a lump of data that is sent out and arm
received an impact
the up makes I'm not kill a specific
don't let the broad
a message comp are confusing anyways
song they combine some magic crop dust
together with our shared secret key is
to ensure both the integrity
and the authenticity of single messages
so
if you have a message you know it at
this exact message how you had
arm will send by the person who knows
the shared secret key in that or
sup pls uses a so-called keyed hash make
your age make for that
you at least arm and before that as
you something similar but slightly
different
them and kill us 1.2 com
it was introduced that some efforts can
bring to own Mac
with them and this is very
aforementioned de la contra mode tryin
speak ass
it integrates to message authentication
within the cipher mode
which means it's not an ex extra step it
can be a nicely implemented in hardware
this is the future sup
finally if your list does not contain
only are throng
perfect forward secure certain a Cyprus
make sure that your own list and order
of Cyprus
has the higher priority casts its
its first light left the latest and
greatest arm yes implementation
if the Klein sense you a list with ours
a triple than a top
and you comply although you could both
have done the CDH a yes DCM
top and you're done wife told you here
you're basically done however thinking
and you've got it right
does mean absolutely nothing you need to
test a result
on desk really a much lot of confusing
stuff that can happen the for example
just run into our
rail slash central 6.5 which has a
decent
up messes oh now but the engine X is
to compile against the OPP although
missus all that means that almost as old
house you
oh yeah I can do is to be achieved no
problem and then you scan your own are
engine expand nato soon open so that
always tested and if your service HTTPS
it's your lucky day because then you can
just use the Qantas as is also a test
and sis is a pretty common case I
figured
I'm going to show you how to reduce
output using the results of my home page
I like to ask stressed that they test
much more them I will be able to talk
about
so after i've done the basics and three
years go back and get it as green as
possible
always m from a plus it's not that hard
sup this certificate as valid from my
homepage both with and without trouble W
it valid from March until next May
and as a for KR a key and this case to
meet Starz
a is used for are cryptographic
signature us not for key exchange the
same algorithm
but the different use cases and it has
completely different implications
other possibilities would be a ideas s
which nobody uses
and ECDs a richest gaining some traction
lately
because it's pastor truth about arm
its grossly under supported by both CA
ce and clients
so you first have to find a c8 science
hooky and then your have to find
I now and then you have to do a dual
threat to get set up like Google last
saw you
support both um
as farce a key step for case the current
state-of-the-art key size
2k is badly enough and 1k is a serious
security problem
sup it whilst issued by the como to see
a and they signed a certificate using
ours in shot to
which is nice shot to it which should be
our striving in OI days
show one has been mostly are being
deprecated in but honest
so 00 it has no Extended Validation
because I don't support it kinda Reckitt
and um it's not revoked and that
stuff its trust that which is wonderful
self protocols
always ensure that kills 1.1 1.1
are ek active and as a tourist inactive
because we have customers the demand
minutes XP support you now
you have to keep as a three on but if
you don't
don't carry that burden drop it
sup seven suites Terry go their dis-
currently
best widely supported Cyprus it if you
want to have it up there
you know it's readable nice sup let's
look in detail
it is the fast and forward security 384
key exchange
it uses Rs a four signatures
which is not something you can configure
its depending on the type of Yuki
arm yes I first already priced 8 yes 128
in Golconda mode and finally to use a
shot 256
for a key derivation are
if the cipher will there are classical
one that uses
external age make it would also use dis
hashing function for age Mac
isn't so it wont arm as you can see the
Cyprus strictly prefer earth
PFS I first all over non PFS once
which are again just because 1106 Peter
now heartthrob the privilege bro the
view if you are deploying something
different than about applications
compared to
I use six some some SATs are
especially males the server setups which
are some
in turn set up in the nineties and it's
the running
it can look like a sweet dream so your
mileage may vary very here
sup a thought about writing plan for
their next and turns out
that browsers aside the translators of
TLS Syniverse triple all
just slightly off because they're on one
job
verify verified a certificate to serve a
sense you
is it valid or is it expired it does the
trust invalidate
and finally is the certificate valid for
the hostname
you want to connect to especially host
the modifications
Sina such a pathetic state there's even
a scientific paper about it helped
foster does not verify hostnames
saw and unfortunately it
ok matters I'll has no little part in a
says Khloe solar thermal stress change
first thing is that certificate
verification up im
I guess what you have to tell Obama's
explicitly which the age to trust
and unfortunately it trust or so how the
platform dependent every less held
elsewhere
fortunately there is a function on
properly configured systems
in other read your default Russia ca3
compared and Pat
not for some very odd reason arm it
completely under command that I had to
dive into darkness
a source go to our verify what's
actually doing
and also near Oxford file and directory
bests
trust source which basically means that
does not work on Windows or west 10
well and as if ab muscles of cycle some
bad enough
our the year operating system vendors
make it you know a bit more miserable
soft of
do you have to install your trash out a
visit by hand are you get very
beard errors so for previous do you have
to install see a rude and assess
on keepin redhead you have to first
glimpse of
across but from consistency because the
pictures the set name:
om are sent you can either use
Apple's engine up messes oh that you
shouldn't and figure out the crux of the
page to entrust elation
agent which cost me like a week of my
life
and are you going home brew which
picture does something nice
I'll they just create a copy on
installation of the system trust other
base and use that that it's not optimal
because if you change something to
assist in kitchen for a reason it's not
reflect that but it's better than
nothing
for Renault stairs min Thurston pappy
I'm which Ruth
very fine and finally if you want to
dodge the bullet completely
which sometimes is the best I you can
just use 35 from pie PI
which is a python package of months of
trust database
so going on to a hot summer vacation
it is even worse because ok mothers out
literally say yes
there's absolutely no assistance
whatsoever from old masters else I'd
to verify better a certificate is valid
for a hostname
nothing there isn't information on their
argumentation
so everyone has implemented themselves
using our cease
and %ah bogus are advice from Steak
overflow and
up of course it's raining security
problems all the time
I meant I think the peter is no
exception sup
failing to verify certificates is really
bet
because it makes 63 miss a special tool
man in a middle attacks
so if you don't verify birth certificate
that all bitch
as I'd like to remind you est the up as
to our default
you for behavior I can pretend to be a
Google
with the south and certificate I can't
read in five seconds
if you go to fight a certificate I don't
compare hostnames agassi be a Google
I just have to use the certificate of my
home page was perfectly trustworthy
invalid
Justin for hosting but you want now
because he didn't look
so but if I'll thinks
on if there's only one thing you take
away from the store please let it be
this
everything else is that if a crisis just
Monday in
limit acceptable ciphers to strong once
four times with pre-configured service
like every day
and there's a bus is a2 thats all
and yet so if you do it it the perfect
storm of ignorant on one side
and operating systems and opposite all
making it unnecessarily hard on the
other
stop and real finish with the weakest
link up a security cheney users
up you
they can make everything fall apart art
no matter how much the rest of the
spektr ice to
keep them secure and usually starts with
for the middle misconceptions
sup what the skills that you want to do
for you for example
it's nice that you connection to your
mail so are you up Tessera secured the
latest and greatest cipher
that's great because people won't be
able to steal passwords
art keep doing it but from the
person disconnect but that your pot nice
connected using a plain-text connection
are
some intermediate server is compromised
which happens
are you confidentiality level for this
conversation is zero
and since you can tell if that's
happening you have to always assumed to
burst
out killers only offers security for
direct Pierce
you will need some additional are layer
security if you need confidentiality for
n2 and connections for example or PGP
for email
RTR fall up for chat
then there's the problem that certain
data can't be interrupted
if you serve a job site you broke over
HTTPS
take you'll still know that you're doing
at the cast your DNS queries in a
traffic patterns which
all give you away for that you will need
BPN
or poor to get to your privacy but
I'm bpm route all your traffic 30
network
so arm you better make sure that you
trust them
and this just as well for example
applies to content delivery networks
succeed in pryor's can read oil traffic
unencrypted because
they do TLS termination for you so arm
St could sniff oil pipe yeah I password
if they wanted to
which Dept don't want to go to great
guys as Donald told me but
they could sup does another reason
to never ever reuse passwords in any
case because you never know which the
party is gonna see it
sup makes are if you have a click away
such warning
you may have been MIT and you
they're awesome book investigative arm
Inc and then
use your best judgment so I am
if the certificate mismatches just the
supplement like here
and you know to circumstances like that
twister didn't support us and I in 2014
them you're probably fine if the
certificate is OK
and arm just expired five minutes ago
you're probably find two-income
to some snarky tweets them make fun of
people on IRC
but if you don't understand what's going
on there
never accept always decline man in the
middle a text ap really really easy
on public networks all it takes is that
it's a rogue DHCP server
cell and the next level of picking
mindlessly is the sum crook
tricks you into installing day root
certificate into your trust other base
because that means it every other I'll
certificate is signed
with that will be considered trustworthy
by your system
so we will never ever get a morning
Quinta MITM you
and if the user doesn't screw up
there's so much that can move wrong so
trust on a business
assist quick recap is are with a brozak
barry's
I try to determine that a certificate
chain it got from the server
is ultimately signed by trust 30 CA and
it happens to be true
that you browse a trustee a switch make
us some discomfort to
this means at the United States
Department of Defense
can easily sign any certificate in a
vote for any host them in a row
and there will be a a nice little lock
in your
not bar and fought like China standing
back or something
every country has some CAD CAM
compromise
and it alone unheard of of CA's being
hacked
making fatal mistakes being forced to
cooperate with authorities
or simply belonging to corporations
those priorities maybe not quite match
yours
so for example just Wiley examples
Microsoft and Google are both CA ce
whatever it means to you
and this wall system is just broken
sup
speaking of broking
let's talk a lot path now and its
let me sabra simple rule of thumb: as
i've seen people love to scrubbed TLS
thought if it somehow possible lead
battle-tested saw for Hannah lead for
you
especially if you just deploying that
applications a properly configured
engine X Apache in front of it most
really save you a lot of grief
I am there but what is it and
there's to plan your information on the
internet how to our
how to configure improperly which is
simply not true for some random
patton more you on pipe EI which just
ended killer support because someone ask
for it on my bike trigger
but since life you were in that simple
let's get our hands dirty anyway by 50%
less
landscape can be roughly divided into
two parts on one side
as the standard libraries as italian
mature I don't underside
are espy must sell and we'll start with
a
include batteries it turns out that in
all versions before 3.3
a pretty rusty arm
and money even that even the latest
Chinese version 3.4
has due to backwards compatibility
requirements
pretty terrible default so for example
host number to get you still up
in all the code is der at mad at the
situation
you wish for unpacking to because
I'm the coverage of of messes else
API really really poor so it's
impossible
too bright forward secure servers in
Obama to celebre says
a model which means you should never
ever right as killer servers
with opens me the can start library
it's also missing a bunch of option so
you can disable as a to you can't
disable
are kiss compression it's all a reset
and finally arm it bound
Tudor are open SSL your papers is
built against so if you want then you up
messes elders in
you have to recompile apartment which is
not very nice
also missing 2.7 is host memory for
cation ma'am I think stress enough how
important this
so that has been edit in Python 3.2
and fortunately and has been back ported
for piping to answer bail on pipe EI
however you have to remember install it
use it it's double
up in piled miss L
comes from a talent stomach libraries
I'll support was even worse than what
you have
now I think it even started his left for
and hat you make the state
how much quite sure they're arm
drunk on all relevant path in Greece and
although it has been a bit dormant or to
time
om it has a much better are API coverage
then marched at library
on I thing to the only notable omission
of TCD sorry on another long mission is
currently CDH
you for servers about the pirate pull
requests they are
and I am I have high hopes the discs
will get merged in its Prince
but what's more important and you
project give piled missus L
I knew my god cryptography if you've
been to talk of Poland Jerrett
arm if you learn you should watch the
video because it's highly interesting
you may have already heard about it it's
a bunch of piping people with more time
and sense
and with %uh average favor
a bad life the decisions arm came
together to write
a pattern cripple a break without food
guns be cast we don't have such thing
om a site product update a pipe I
friendly see if I bindings
problem as a cell so and it's trivial to
choose the opposite other room
and arm a bike ends like secure
transport
are in the works so get your go to fail
in patent to
am arm the skiff poemas are some serious
momentum a cast
nigga throughout all their rusty see
coat and
stuck concentrate on building Peyton
obstructions on public debts or pay
almost cell is something less release
a patent only version which a patent
only package which is nice
Anna what unfortunately missing their as
hot summer vacation
maybe see a pattern here although
in this case poems that three tries to
be a prepper for API so
M I would cut them some slack here bad
yeah
but again how does on poppy I sorus
identity gives do just that
plus some more obscure race 2 verify the
identity of a server
arm which nobody will ever use but they
are specified in RFC so there it is
and again the blood in install
use and let's look at
I knowledge through somewhat first you
let's look at common frameworks and
packages and how will behave tell us
on since the Oct ok sorry
are they will serve it service again %um
pledge event G unicorn
and tornado all suffer from the same
disease which is called star Larry
up they cannot have PFS they cannot have
good default because it
they can't use it options sop put an
engine X in front all of them
arm twist that you its
then
on it's probably one of the few alleged
reasons to cope with TLS yourself since
its used to implement much more
protocols than just arm just HTTPS
arm a little known fact of to assist
those ships had a nice risky containers
so in other words you can be plotted
your
you can deploy HTTPS but applications
with it
I without putting anything in front of
it and still have great healer support
and I can assure you arm that the plane
was kept on Twitter does not mean that
you have to use called XT for arts
or use can look at the new coats
cell finally micro is key it's not
packed with pacific despite the
convincing name
I'm so they just went on and brought
them see themselves
so that made a masters of their own fate
and indeed their implementation looks
pretty much fully featured
I personally with all still always put
an injection from it
because I have a general distrust
towards arm
ok masses are using CP coat I'll your
mileage may vary but
shouldn't really saw the only way to fix
only thread acres there is to your move
to Python 3 write your own SSL support
like my crew risky
or arm and poor to impaled myself
as long as we stay on our on standard
library of patent to
now gonna stay well maybe not but I've
talk about the letter
so client site event and you meant are
they are just as bad as before
although it is possible to do better.
despite a standard library
and tornado shows how the ship I'm not
entirely audited
trust database from a tool up and depend
on the hostname a chip
hostname matching arm back port from pie
PI
so they verify certificates and
hostnames by
d-fort imagine with on writing a paper
engage in a truck from Peyton ideas
but on the other hand this to run into
problems like the inability to
disable as a tour because that option
has been added in Python 3.2
that causes some really funny a roasting
a try to connect to certain service
on August 10 which still has as a to
incite to just get a protocol are only
don't know what's happening there
om yeah to STATS a client site is
complicated but for reasons you might
think defer to also man kamel case just
government after a while
it's complicated because nobody left
them glitter conspired with all current
Release Manager a hawk all to sabotage
my preparations
on you frankly started
to pull all nighters after he saw my
original slide 22 just had to use a
third-party library
from the dentist for two threat and arm
the current state as of this morning
when I checked the last time
I'm is that there are
up in up in low-level waste to verify
all %uh think so the plumbing his status
is great
I wondered high-level API Slyke ATP
agent or
as island point are still oblivious by
default
are this is not optimal bad at least it
is possible to write secure code which
is
was not before Sabha 414 not 0
and yet we take this issue 3 seriously
so R
this is going to get fixed its all its
all underway
am i expect to that fourteen point one
will be pretty good
what's never going to be good this
system will embrace your lip
comp it doesn't verify anything I
it doesn't said any options just hands
all but you ever have to open the HTTPS
you're aware that insert is requests
I'm something
oh man I have to carry up something %uh
the request is great because it simply
PI I'm
already ate like even more is that it
uses Europe 3
to get the best possible results cell it
always very bright
verify certificate always very feisty
hostnames
and everything just gets better
beautiful piled missus elena few under
our modules
yeah thought let me sum up to kill us
out of pipes if you can use requests for
HTTPS curry's
make sure you're using in the pile
misses a bike Marin
and red Kia sorus interested
if you need Lolo TLS use the latest
version of piled missus 0
it's greatly superior to pipe B-two's as
only you and it will follow unfaithful
if you have a part to play in three
final it you still pat me too standard
library
only for a client and only have to
really need to a arm
and it leads to say whatever you use
make sure you use the relevant back
ports and tools to verify all the things
soft let's answer a question from the
very beginning why is the state of
SSL sorry
it's alright because people still say
SSL although it's been a plea for 15
years
it's alright because implementations are
terrible
all of them I'm not sure if you expected
me to ran for an hour
about how and why implementations are
terrible in my bed been fun
but I am it for the reconstructive way
to I love my speaking pamphlets
leave it at that if the state of a
message I'll makes you angry
which redshirt I consider donating for a
project or tell your boss to donate to
the project because it's literally three
guys and one of them gross full-time
so it's better than it could be
salt it sorry because you just run to
lead software
the click certain I'll certificates
morning awake and out the mercy of third
parties
and other parties let them down
regularly service from completely
outdated software
that is confused configured completely
poorly
clients and verify anything although if
their only job and
we're not talking yell so obscure free
very here this January
I O active found forty percent of Tesla
banking aP's
to be vulnerable to make him a text and
up
finally it sorry because patents in the
forefront of being terrible
the current state really is sorry even
without heartbeat
artist the title of this talk is not the
tension bed but there's help
for the vault people started to Karen
question for that's probably be by your
here
arm acceptance is always the first step
good ap
standard library support the better by
making it uses the 3.3 release
so if you're ever near the reason for
patent 3 for your boss
here you go and even for Python 2.7
Nick colon is working on a pet that
should bring in SS among your roughly
into
out to 2014 so there goes who argument
for Python 3 a.m.
arm I've already mentioned a
cryptographer project much much more
than that in a proud tradition
of the piping packaging authority a
python cryptography authority from
formed on a bit obvious already adopted
several projects
and it's supposed to be a once a place
for solid purpose of her fur pie from
at this is a real huge deal because the
standard library simply moves
too slowly to a response to the pressing
issues of security
arm but hope also means there's work to
do
therefore I call selection
stop believing that the look I can't
makes you and your data safe
do not click away certificates warnings
away do not in Seoul Roque
route certificates be a critical user
configure or service properly
install security updates immediately if
you connect to servers
verify the circum- you verify
certificate
and hostnames and finally help us to get
paid out of this mess
pixel libraries fix your software report
backs upstream
huh a few pics he's backs there's really
a lot of two to do
and that's all I have for you today
I hope you learn something and more
importantly I eager to fix things
now so go out stay atop H follow me on
Twitter get a comment from our media
and look out for a trip to open space
that will have it probably tomorrow
thank you
thank you very much
unfortunately we have no time for
questions but where will you be
in Eq yet catch me our kitchen outside
I will have a real cryptographer next to
me will arm
hook kick me if I'm gonna say something
wrong
I would have been more comfortable two
and three on the record anyway so
catch me outside him thank you very much