good afternoon everybody
our next speaker just the McAllen area
is an entrepreneur
software engineer an open-source
contributor from cambridge massachusetts
she is coordinator a boss in Python
the largest tight on me up in the world
and runs the bite
the Boston Python workshop she's
maintainer for the twisted an open hatch
projects
and on top of that she is cofounder and
CT oh I'm still up
in enterprise messaging service that was
acquired by Jack box last month today
she'll be talking to us
about security solutions and sandboxing
with Python
please give her a warm welcome everyone
thank you so much RSS never going to
talk about building and breaking a
python sandbox
in this is me I'm also director for the
Python Safra Foundation a
I am probably too involved in the Python
community
I hear a couple ways to get 100 okay so
W sandbox
why would we ever want to do this this
actually comes up in a lot of
a surprising number contacts I'm when
learning a language
I want to write some companies on a
provider hosted scratch pad for doing
arbitrary computation
on their son researchers using
distributed computation across major
platforms we need to run on trusted code
your contacts Anderson cases are you
want to inspect
running processes safely worse and Mark
might be helpful for San Martino di to
run on trusted Python code
on and their lot examples of us know
what and wild
I'm seattle is an academic peer to peer
computing network
I've Google App Engine has a a Python
shell you ever use code: Academy
are the uses and Python %uh service to
to profile on sandbox and check I know
who i think is the first startup
row here I is there's an online coding
gain that you execute arbitrary
I thank God and if you have visited the
Python org
website post redesign friend center on
the front page
is I a python rebel as this is running a
arbitrary code in a sandbox
and we have two big choices
but we were too big options when
building a sandbox to do language level
sandboxing worse or going to focus on a
stock
I'm in OS level sandboxing on
end users or to model by the pie sandbox
project and pipe I sandboxing model
are and they're will talk about so the
pros and cons of each letter in the talk
about
we're gonna stay with my we love them
back in because a lot of by and it gives
us an excuse to dig into some fun
language details
okay is our most fundamental question
here is how do you execute arbitrary
Python code in the first place
I we have two main premise for this we
have al
which compiles and evaluate expressions
an expression is really just
some stuff it reduces to a value like
one close to you
and an exact compiled evaluate
statements statements are
you know the smallest stand-alone Chung
said Python code
I'm exec is more general because yes are
all paid on programs are made up a
statement so use exactly as the basis
for sandboxing
model also have a little test harness
here we have a sandbox in class is
really simple it is has one method
execute
which takes occurred string and execs
and okay cool so what left testis
I'm so we'll criticism for sandbox class
and we have through a simple cable as
print hello world
and will execute that code and his works
great okay so it will now her in a
sandbox that will execute anything
and but it works good okay so what are
some things that we should disallow
in our sandbox has rang I'm trusting
user can
I a lot of options are you
we definitely I'm we don't want people
to usable the file descriptors
we probably gonna be able to start a web
server is doing it on paying
I'm aviation you were a router the
sandbox said maybe Signori in sensitive
information for the filesystem
as is the partial is there a lot of
things to worry about for gonna run I'm
trusting can
to you know focus other discussion let
let's use the ability to write to the
file system
as a good example of something that are
our most basic sandbox not allow
because I represented only two probably
do a lot of other things that are going
without system
a reason to think that we're going to
focus on the stock is i the ability to
write
to a file we definitely want to possible
took early this as possible
on how can we prevent okay well
what is file exactly
if we do some poking around the rebel
I'm off I'm at
on every program in this dubliners were
built ins
I'm filers in there so files one of the
built-ins
in Python and are a lot of others are
filed kinda problematic there a lot of
other potentially problematic
daughters that we might want to disallow
INR sandbox so how do we disallowed the
execution a problematic built-ins
starting to build up the functionality
for sandbox
so we are you an idea just the amps
divine what a keyword
blacklist so I okay here you can use
file you can't use a Val
you can't quits was just like you were
passing the code string
if we see the word file in our code
string
I raise a valuer and is that a lot you
actually exiting and
okay tumbling apostle idea and I've ever
tried this with a keyword blacklist
this one fact fail with our value where
good start can get around this blacklist
3 thinking we're scheming thinking like
attackers
ago here's why do you have an encryption
and not even super sophisticated
encryption encryption what if we
just did this well we just dropped 13
incurred the word file
so the literal text file never appears
in our program
but we can be decoded and lookit up in
the built-in dictionary now we have a
reference to this file object
I'll we know we can write to the file
system
and so we do this unit in fact works
right because we know our block you were
blacklisted ever literally peers Nick
your blacklist
ok it's a blacklist not so hot an idea
an enemy I'm sorry she hears I can get a
reference to something that I can invoke
I can name doesn't super matter is the
actual reference that matters
okay well how can we remove all
references to problematic built-ins
ago a blacklist didn't work so well but
how to whitelist
a building's whitelist so you know we
could we could literally have a set that
a numerate saw love the
adult and that we deem okay and only use
out the ones
that we think are bad on and then before
we actually execute any code
we could I'm take this original bill
clinton's
on and then iterate over I'm all in
the original dolphins IQ's and if it's
not in the white list was deleted
does not in a myspace anymore
got some pretty good let's write so we
removed file file was not in the balkans
whitelist
if we try to execute are our sample can
exact fit
fails so files literally not to find my
files on a continent space anymore
sweet built-ins whitelist
because I can use file anymore what else
can I do to write to the file system
you'll but for import something
can I import I can import OS right
like Edinburgh eso no es has an open I
function that
as for similar to file I can use that to
write the file system
and so far this is allowed
Harry print this from happening well the
problem is I can import OS right
how to disallow problematic imports
okay all the while inside you worked
pretty well for the built in so I don't
try to import white list as well
but im pretty is kinda interesting I
because there's this mag there's a whole
mechanism around importing
we're going to hook about importing
mechanism so I guess the first question
is
how is importing a model work in Python
and every poker an adult is a little bit
we see that there is this double
underscore
import on in the built-in dictionary and
if we if we get a reference to that when
given a mauve
a module I'll that does the work and
actually loling at Marshalls appreciate
the namespace great
so using doubles honors were important
but you know we can
to manually do the import ourselves
through built-ins
and and what is the expected function
signature for the import or we can just
look at that
on you know in a little to help here I
know see that we need a name
and there's some some global the locals
as much as some other some other
and optional arguments in in a country
singer
call okay so what writer an importer I
meant for starters it
is just gonna print that work here to
prove to other user and own importer
we're gonna print that we are and then
we're gonna use the underlying II
underscore
import I don't pull a little tense
the video this I was it works call
so we've got to the import on mechanism
particularly importer
and now we've done as we can extend this
to on here before actually trying to
import something
we can check if if the name that we're
trying to import is in a modular
whitelist
on it is we we use that underlie
important mechanism and if it's not
we I you know block him for you as an
importer
call okay so it's a maybe we want to be
super conservative in the only models
you can import are
like string and Ari and we
replace the on importer that in
built-ins
with are safe important limitation
that's using our save my of my list
goal okay so now if we try on using OS
that open
0 I have warnings about meetings
cool let's make that ever happening and
where's my
point okay produce gonna gonna quit this
Avalon meetings that I'm missing okay
Zealand really getting a video and it
okay where Am I
God okay
read-back her back okay okay so
we're gonna try to import OS and it
doesn't work anymore because we have
and Pia hope the importer and it's not
on my list
I said okay so while a surfer been quite
for over a sweet
what else to do. can import a case file
what else can we do.
okay was is all hypothetical but what
we've been doing a lot is reminding dole
tens
and if I can play with built-ins then an
attacker could
to: the water really fundamental stuff
in there like me if this is a part time
to you we define true and false
in buildings like what if any Thacker
like set
true equal to false and vice versa
at the very least I could do yeah it's
possible that I could cause all kinds
checks to behave unexpectedly it is it
seems like a bad idea to let people
modified offense
so so what's take that off the table but
the questions are how do we make
unable to modify built-ins
thriller Middleton's read-only so how do
you make
some theory only in Python
you another dictionary am we can
subclass a dictionary
and why we does raise the value air for
all the things that were done
heated exchange got I guess we have a
read-only built-ins
class you can't you know add or remove
items from this dictionary
but I'm pretty good and we can you know
again before executing a brand has
occurred
we can replace the original bill tens
when are read-only version
call
okay so what else can I do' now the main
lesson to be learned earlier
is that if I can get a reference to
something that I can go get can I get a
reference to something bad
anywhere else within Python where can i
poke around to get a reference to
something that I can use to write to a
file system
okay well there's a bunch of funky stuff
in the inheritance hierarchy
why don't we just play around at like
what's his poker an issue we can find
I also like to take a less truth render
unless there's always double unders crew
members I usually just ignoring the two
output
is there anything interesting in here
well as this class after it okay so list
is a typed list
fine the class actually had his own
Ashley bases which
it is on what the objects based classes
are
so this case listed jazz just subclasses
object not not super interesting
and but you can get the base classes
have an object
and you can also do the reverse you can
you can find some places to you
so in this case list doesn't have any
sunglasses but
into does to balls as a class a dense on
stirring unique code both subclass base
training
okay so we can get the base classes have
an object to in get the sunglasses an
object
and at the base class have list is
object which everything inherits from
right
why are the sunglasses objects
I mean interesting lesson things well
okay so that would be a lot of things
okay so this is all over things that
subclass the object class the most
fundamental class
and it is pretty hard to read so why do
we write a little for look make it
easier to see
okay so so we're entering a recycle as
much as per the name or some scanning
through this
okay sweet instance ellipsis member
descriptor
wait a second you thought you were gonna
file but you're not okay so file we
still have a reference CO
in the wanna sunglasses objects
and what we have a handle to file its
game over right we know exactly what to
do this
so we pull up in a museum we have the
sunglasses we
I'll nope may cancel dictionary mapping
the name tend to the actual reference
I'm iPod reference for file we use that
to write to the file system
okay how do you stop that from happening
and even if I hear is that we really
shouldn't be exposing
he is implementation details like maybe
just want some cases been made over the
vast majority a program use cases we can
just heidi is from the user
so so let's see if we can just get rid
of the is comming the weak bases
sunglasses okay so we're gonna del type
type a sous
shoot but did not work
and the reason it does work because this
is actually the check on doing mess you
can actually set attributes have typed
is imposed by the underlying C Python
implementation
so so we can delete them from C decipher
Python
but fortunately am ever want to invest
will be never would actually work around
that so there's this thing called see
types a Seat Ibiza foreign function
interface that allows us
to its own dig into the underlying C
Python gots
on every you see types we can work up a
little
on function that'll give us the
dictionary attack tributes on the
underlying
C Python implementation for something
okay cool also so we can rewrite a
missile dictionary I love
of functional we can pull out those the
underlying type text by passing
distillation check and we can tell bases
and sunglasses
that way got ok I'm
okay so no subclasses no super classes
our Q&A what else can we do to write
this filesystem
ok well
back to playing around here okay so
let's say it you know it was
it was fruitful first orgasm is random
double underscore
attributes on lists why do we were
write a function see there's anything
interesting in a drought put their
guess hasher name right near you
funk code at that sounds
interesting what what is it what is funk
what else is
with Ashley to funk had
court considers the CEO code Ashley have
anchored if you look at see occurred
so yet learned this in some hacks
gibberish I'm a lot which looks like
the actual bite kit that Python
interpreter is is executing
but school on surely we can change that
raid
okay so what does I saw a prototype okay
we have our are nice function foo
we're gonna ride around evil function
that Prince kaboom
Anne every run through a prince me our
but if we
said but fun kurd attribute on foo
what happens
okay that works okay so that seems bad
okay so this brings us back to an idea
we discussed before which is that
'we're careful expand exposing
potentially dangerous in 20 she tells
you up probably the vast majority in
these cases are users don't need access
to a fun kurd
object and actually we can use the same
c-type should come before
to get rid of this so we can use our
dictionary I have function
to to pull out the the attributes I love
that function are you up the function
tired
and I'll be fine cut so it's not
successfully more
cool okay
let's recap okay we try to cure
blacklists then having a bad idea route
30 in with a
big problem for us there don't invite
list and I was pretty good
and import y listo hooking the importer
are making important objects like
built-ins read-only
subclassing decked I we do we had a
couple problematic imitation details
like bases inside classes and punctured
and then I we deleted the ability to
construct
arbitrary code object which seems pretty
dangerous
sweets and actually I'm we run outta
tricks we have implemented I would say
eighty percent have a full-fledged price
on sandbox where the remaining 20
percent are just edge cases to Ted
you know details in the language on but
if we zoom way way way I can imagine a
single file containing all the coney
written
where first we produce a dozen white
list now we have an import while is to
make buildings read only in like before
you execute any code we believe in these
problematic details
on and then we have a pretty cool our
sandbox
it's pretty cool although we do limit
important functionality either their
deadly cases where am I gonna be able to
write
to a file even in the sandbox and also
we think back to the things we say we
should disallow
were not hitting all of these bases yet
like this language level sandbox does
not give us a lot of
I Hawks 4 per any resources ashen like
an immigrant likely if someone decided
her
like create a freedom bit quien minors
on my
server I like I their new ways to stop
them from using up all my CPU resources
on with this implementation
as opposed to going back to serve our
choices here our choices elaine was on a
sandbox really fun to explore
or no es little sandbox and actually
that
the code we're in which is based on
price and box relook at Big Data get
herb
page for price and what is even a I'm a
nice strong morning at the bottom
I'm by the author %uh who wrote a really
a thoughtful retrospective on what he
discovered while
building up I sandbox over the years
which discusses a lot over concerns that
we've talked about
and fundamentally it just becomes harder
to you
on rights a language level sandbox that
allows you to do useful stop
on but is also safe
and so his regulation thriller
Commissioner love mostly talk to a
is well who have worked as a box is is
that you need to at least parrot with OS
will send black celebrity OS-two
importers
to enforce resource constraints or I'm
limit your visibility in the filesystem
things like that
but is a fun exercise now
here's a look at a food for thought here
so what questions do other languages
have these and boxing concerns
well as JavaScript pajama jam
and also we were designing a new
language we have the ability to discern
scratch
and we wanted sandboxing to be a as a
reference a first-class consideration
when designing as
waters and design choices that we make
and you're a couple of I experiment this
is the kind I would do on the weekend
family time
I'm we could look at how pipe as this so
we knew we were looking at we weeks
I you licensee pride on specific details
what you are going to use experiment
house pipe I do it
how exactly does the C-five on an
interpreter compound run by code
I'll what does the Python stack a look
like you know coming from 0 to have a
very clear picture that but is it more
complicated
I found world see types this foreign
function interface you'll have been a CK
that seems like a very nifty trick how
does that work
and then how exactly can be operating
system help provide a secure environment
in this context
suck up a fun experiment so we can
together
not a little bit a bedtime reading you
can see the full price and by
implication
with his eminently readable and I'll
mostly what we've already talked about
on the slides actually I said I get home
on and then again it's really thoughtful
retrospective on pat pat on doctors
challengers another UN are you can read
your pipe I SMIC litigation and how
private anywhere
on the servers that host step and that
org
a sandbox how that works as well
so thank you for coming me on this
journey through this tricky sandboxing
asset up to learn a couple interesting
I language tidbits Anderson exploitation
tricks as we
watch do this thought experiments I'm
not as I have reason to you so much and
also if you are talking about this or
anything
I will be a rally booth at the expo hall
tomorrow morning
are you free boxer sup thank you
under any questions there are Mikes
on the sides yeah
I thanks for the talk on this man I
really change the fundamental discussion
very much but what i want.
sandbox something like by Python
notebook have people work in that at all
I mean is that something that you could
rent a pipe I use their sandbox like
any recommendations on how to do that I
yes I think
I mean there are various mature send
back seat certainly OS level say
martinis and a pipe I definitely have to
support an operation to be things like
this
on so yes I was they don't roll your own
sandbox
and do use one that established at
Sandboxie horror stories and his work
maybe JavaScript rb8
take pride have some now okay thank you
so much there a lightning talks next
first eighteen per day