good afternoon everyone
now we have my friend Julian palette
with from San Francisco
and he'll be talking about and Mon
techniques for babbitt function testing
Union thank you
thanks everyone for coming today
I'm gonna start just very briefly don't
want to bore you with that
just couple facts about me so you know
why I'm here today I've been happily
programming with by phone as my main
language
for a number of years I am also a joke
or commuter
and I occasionally tweet from this
handle sure
ever interest in what I have to say I
work at near on we are aware the agency
with a few offices ass gathered
scattered around the world I'm
personally based in San Francisco but we
also have
and his here in Montreal and we do
require carry encourage you to check out
our web site or commencing after talking
to a lecture on
more about us okay so
starting with a few definitions just so
we're clear on why
I'm gonna be talking about why we talk
about
many testing it is to ensure that small
part of our code
each work in isolation integration
testing is about ensuring that
some other spots when combined together
keep working well
and then functional testing is wants to
be on his 21 make sure they are you
happy occasion as a whole
functions well a in particular from the
user's perspective
and one we do believe
functional testing for the web typically
it comes
down to using Brotherhood two meters now
why would be using
Abruzzo tomatoes first because heat
brings us closer to real when his
environment
all the media on study files such as CSS
images et cetera the old automatically
get looted by the bra so you don't have
to worry about any of that and semi
naughty
any JavaScript code any a just calls
implicitly get
executed by the brosser and then when
all that is put together than
allows you to test use interactions
browser compatibility
and very importantly it's a lot of fun
now
the the most put my second most popular
have web a brother to me they're out
there these days is silly name
I was actually curious today a who
a ok you have ever you silly names to
could raise your hand
well thats clearly the majority that's
exciting I really hope that as you look
at the stock actually
learned a lot of new tricks so silly
name
very briefly in pain as they were driver
API which is about to become the
WC w3c standoff and is currently in
draft
he works across multiple browsers for
example Firefox Chrome IE
Safari an Oprah he has
trying to have a reason for sanguinis in
particular by phone that's what we're
interested in
on it's very easy to install you just
round peep in store sitting in a few go
so for those of you who
do not know that Selena for just give a
very quick the known
just to get an idea of the kinds of
things that he can do with it
and so here it is going to run
I a subset of the Django admin
te Street which is for a return with
synonym I'm gonna be holding my hand
serbs
so you know 90s a automated I'm not
going to do anything and everything is
gonna be running by itself
what's going to happen is that you will
see honest answer Firefox that we open
and then a bunch of views are action
being executed
in an automated way so he received
Firefox is running
running a bunch of user action is so
going very fast
and hear Tpke we using
selenium in Django mostly to test the
fracture eighty
so that means a form submissions
for submissions and JavaScript any a
little JavaScript admits that help
improved experience
in the Django admin so we which one have
some test to make sure that as we keep
adding more code power to Java scripps
or even and
I think ok sometimes just make sure that
a
everything keeps working that there are
no regression overtime
so that's it's
just to give you an idea of the
cannister you can do with synonym
now than I thought
I show she think that may not
necessarily be ok just one start using
Selenium
are shoot for simple you you you've
created responsive web sites
which responsiveness something that's
become really popular in the last couple
years and for good reasons
because with a single code base you can
do
display content optimally for various
screen sizes for example for mobile or
desktop a tablet
now testing you what said was him
sexually read really simple
you know comes down to using that one
method which comes in that which are
very PI
said window size which allows you chew
at any point in time during your test to
resize the browser window
and then for example you may stop a
we've
a 6-under be so we'd run some tests make
sure everything works for mobile
and then expand the window size to then
ran some test
to ensure they are worse on desktop and
I just had a very simple devotion here
again
I to do that actually used the by
Khan which site wish which I'm sure
you've all used
and interacted with I'm just country
running it
locally to its it actually happens to be
a genocide to
and issued here at the top for example
there's a menu which you can expand its
very
no traditional Canada interaction and
she resize the browser
that mean you will hide behind that I
can he run down can expand it
and then again interact with the same
menu
SAR wrote a very simple test
to make sure that this works fine
and again opening automatically comes up
to were to magically openly a a
and two bras are a
opening each other's menus and then
resizing the window using that method
aunt checking the that many works on
mobile says very straightforward
something that just may not be totally
obvious
once you start easing synonym
so that was very quick Dino now
something that's
and i think is very very calm he is that
you can also test
no need a fresh I ET so you're just
repetition you can also tested visuals
so you CSS images et cetera anything
that would be
visually rendered on your page and that
can be done with a nifty little
perhaps that's corny don't I it's
available to get her to study but men
freshman and I
it turned out that I call to help
maintain
it's based on synonym and he we catch
any regressions Ian the displayed
of your site by for example there may be
lost I saw your CSS typography is VG
images
basically anything that would be
visually represented on a site
and he would do that by actually taking
screenshots an
comparing x-men shot over time andy
field sports
any any differences between dispensers
ninety would sell
with her a standard test failure
so a just to give you a very quick
example minutes
extremely simple to use I again I'm
gonna use
I the bike on which side as a as a an
example
here I'm interesting in that a nice lead
a banner here he has some cool graphics
some nice colors on the also has some
text in it
so how would we go about writing some
test to make sure that Dez
visual keeps looking the same over time
as we keep making changes
in a CSS just make sure we never
introduce any regressions
and only takes is that really done one
method a sub screenshots
which comes with which is provided by
nato
so what he does that too thats cumshot a
suspension method
accepts to parameters the first one is a
CSS selector to
the element on your page if you wanna a
target and take a screenshot
of the second parameter ease
charges that define name that's going to
be stored buttock ng5
a screenshot is going east on your on
your disk
and divers first time you gonna run this
test is gonna pass in a flag
at which going to instruct needle check
she say the baseline
kokia the screenshot and every
subsequent times that you run a test for
example on CSR
you we're under stairs without that
flight was going to do so is going to
take a new strain showed and compare it
with
the Best Animated you've previously
created
so I'm gonna do you agree to something
can
so it's a it's a very first time going
to church
for the clear K
so the very first anime running be so
I'm gonna pass it
that flag save Beistline
so it's gonna run that that Co data to
show you
tremendously bigger Mary she can see arm
okay
so running a test so now you see it
opens Firefox
knows the leukocyte take a screenshot
all very fast knife we take a look here
it's created for their with that one
a screenshot so it's all well and good
so far
a particularly useful I'm just gonna run
the test again now without this flag
what's gonna happen now is out again is
gonna do exactly the same thing
has gone open the page dated take a
screenshot compared with the baseline
that previously created the end it
detect any difference she so desperate
now let's go in into the code and insert
a mistake
a I'm just gonna chance here
accidentally a the call of the blue sky
an inverse it away here instead of five
I was going to put a zero
if
I reload the page here its
ok it's really hard to see that
anything challenge to just look at it
you know it premature the same very easy
to miss that
within so did that the tape a window
into CSS
but this is where need to consider risky
so
here I'm going to rerun that same test
setting up as a brother a Texas man shot
compares it with a baseline and it's
time to test the test failed
for you go back up you see the research
for the newsprint show about a bad in
much the best night but its
doesn't just stop there he would
actually also create a defiant between
been used when showed on the best time
check Chile highlight
what actually one wrong where did you
the differences so he created and if I
had been ordered beefed-up Angie
and here actually highlights what's
basically different agenda baseline in
the screenshot so here
it's obvious that there's something
wrong with the the the Scottish and a
car
so damn gonna go back in here on and do
my mistake
rear under test
another test passed
another another very common mistake
when dealing with CSS is one missing up
fun sizes
so here again another example on going
to change the font size
for some other text in a banner and then
we run that test
my hair done test failed
for Luke again now that the file aids
the text actually changed within a
banner fits
extremely simple to use and its read a
really powerful
alrighty so now just to show your down
if I'm doing mistake here and I put it
back to what it used to be
and run a test there now
we back on track okay so moving on
I am 22
few a few tips about you know the best
lines control tacky actus fixtures
for you to street to typically want to
store them in your repository so that
their ship with the rest on your team
and the CA server
so that everybody can run a test against
the as baseline
screenshots it's awesome extremely
important to ensure the consistency
between
a different environments Heath a
the CA server uses a different browser
version or has different system trance
in store for example
the page Minot render exactly the same
so you wanna be very careful
I that or environment sector use the
same and I can be done using
configuration management systems like a
share fanciful puppet or salt
than I wanted to touch in topeka
continous integration how to you use all
this stuff
in the real workroom so when you gonna
be
a raining a sea ice are typically letter
is not gonna be using
a a physical monitor so instead you want
to
run your testing headless told which
means basically using a virtual display
very simple to do on your says however
you want install a
her brother is possible very specific
version of the riser
you want to stall and all system fonts
anything we need to make sure that
no consistency between your environment
and then you won't install
Expedia which she's a program that we're
on
a dual display memory:
that is very simple to use again randy
is VBS command and then assign a number
for that displayed a stand gonna be used
by your browser
if you use Jenkins you can also use a XP
bf again
that's basically gone around us two
things for you were too much cream
for you every time to test around she's
Travis sitter
also very simple use does run this
comments before your test actually start
you can also use by their choice pay
which is nice little package
which will allow its military
wrap-around text PDF any will allow you
to start and stop
that there to display using passion code
or you may also use ban on JS which is a
headless brosser as gonna deal with its
own virtually spay
it's a super easy to use a silly me in
sheep's
a an interface to dad browser
so it's it very easy just get started
with
so wanting to show a very quick service
that his cock also slabs
and what's a slut does it actually runs
I remote in the cloud has a whole bunch
of different VMs
and what's really nice is that he
actually gives access to multiple
different browsers
tonight I year 54 scrimmage any any
brushes can think of
even including mobile processors and
that saves you the trouble
of eat managing your own a set of
no different environment different
browsers locally
also allow us to run tests in parallel
and something's really useful we also
keeps video recordings of all the
sessions that you run
it's six particularly useful one test
actually fail to see can go back and it
a point in time
and look at the video to see where test
actually failed
so hearing I'm gonna show a deal
I I'm gonna run I am
some other gender test to show their
earlier this time
only this time a remotely on this to
slap
platform
just realized I am actually have to
restart a server cedar
to spare with me for a second
here what I'm doing physically stirred
create the initial connection with the
source web server
just make sure everything is of
frantic aged
came
sahnoun going around does test
okay it's an on going to go to lead us a
slam website
refresh
so now you see that some tests are
currently being run can actually see
them
in real time so you can see the test
around I speech
in a performance that I was very quick
one and the cool thing is at it again
eater a video recording of that test or
any point in time to go back
and then view the video in this
particular instance I'm running does
gender tests
on I think Firefox on a Linux machine
yet
and that same test which I have been
running
on I think I E eight yes
midst try yessir dads
I E eight on a on it Windows XP machine
again it's just currently being run
so he can
just a YouTube video
so why I'm currently have been trying to
integrate into Django te Street
we've passos Lasker there there can you
know try to provide a sour
and a an account for us for open source
projects and
ISO we're just now in the process of
integrating the whole test route is
going to be very useful to ensure that
the gentleman's
keeps working in all different kinds a
process K
sorry I encourage you to check him out
it's it's a case it's very handy
especially if you don't have to do with
the trouble
dealing with all those environments
yourself a photo so touch
on a topic thats a beat controversial
when selling your own car
sammy's often criticized for I it's
known as in shaking ass
really there should be a target of
dedicated to this
I their solutions for but just about
everything but it does require
some effort I just thought I would to
provide a few quick tips
for some moisture really concerned about
ski to encourage you to use fat NGS cuz
it's much more lightweight and Firefox
any
him we were in much faster ice encourage
you to use paralyze a sham
action actually can show you an example
here
I'm gonna run some tests I'm gonna
stud the social at taps test here camden
around some other test data showed you
earlier
only jean-juste a multiple
processes at a time that's a future
that's provided by nosed
a knows this run our school that s
runners also have this kind of russian
teen
where you gonna see here is multiple
versus
instances a Firefox running at the same
time in each
each running a different test said
that's going to you
a reedy speed up the
did the time education time with your
test and so again very easy to use
now actually concerned about robustness
II can exercise this enough it's really
really important to pin down versions of
the whole software stack
there is so much so much stuff happening
when you run factional test because it
exercise its so many
laser of your software stack its report
and that
I everybody on your team in NCAA servers
using directly the same versions
all the ways any subtle differences
between to her shower software
may caused a did bring a you would say
to you
behave or look slightly differently and
then cause I
a false positive in presences in your
apt issued
extremely important also you want to
master the use of explicit wait it's a
very common
salsa mistakes when writing singing test
a a very common mistakes actually to run
your test too fast
be forwarded to state in the browser is
reached for this test to be run
so you wanna make sure of i suppose you
have a very long Ajax course being run
you wanna have
ways of tracking that a
the the web app he's at a stage where
you can continuing your test
and the whips driver API I gives you
the kind of functionality to test for
particular condition
on for you to wait on and then resume
your test
that already goes a long way into
increasing robustness on your test
but it does require to be me for the
call and and meticulous
and there are a lot more cheats a
that I don't have time to call for today
but I encourage you to check out those
two books which are
both really useful I'll I shared links
in induced when a publisher site
the size area later on those are really
should have
really good tips for increasing
efficiency a test so
in conclusion I 20 a
what a question integration fashion test
are slow that's an obvious fact
to use them with moderation you should
also only you silly and for why did Demi
test time anal
already achieved so focus your singing
test on complex use our workflows for
example or visuals
and let the dummy try and take care of
everything else cuz it's gonna be much
faster much more reliable
and finally integration and fashion test
are important I really encourage you to
include some in yo te street because
stay we'll
increase you can finance in your code
greatly
there when Craig increase your test
coverage
that will increase iron added that will
allow you to test
the interaction between a friend on your
back and ensure that the user interface
works and looks as a spit expected
and its is again it's a lot of fun to
use down through and
if you've never used it I really
encourage you to use the stools
because at the very least you're just
gonna have a lot of fun
thanks very much for listening and i'm
happy to answer any question
you may have
we have time for a question and answers
do you have any questions
on Union am so just one very quick
question
and you mentioned and ask for had less
testing of course given that JavaScript
tends to work very differently in
different browsers
am have you got any suggestions for
headless versions of other browsers like
Firefox or I'm
well
Tpke when using and headless mode I
would
use a virtual display so we could still
use the same and
engine is possible I as far as find OJ's
his concern actually really impressed by
how
robust an efficient and easy it's pretty
much on par with
Firefox and Chrome in terms of
Franchitti at least as far as as far as
I've been testing it
and it something actually use very
confidently with my test I really
recommend you to check it out super easy
to install and spurs EU's
I thanks very much for talking
I learned a lot am a so just a tiny
little thing really I'm case you didn't
know it
as they a command it comes to the latest
versions of XP FB called
XP FB dash from which will just run the
next money put in bash
in a virtual frame buffer is really
useful even on your own machine if
you're running slinging tests
that they'll be in a federal crime
office and are popping up an annoying
you literally something else
has a ex bf b-12 compaq's I'd
thanks for the talk but that is really
interesting I just was wondering if you
could comment on how you decide what to
test
like would you test the basic path
through your app
or edge cases Mar so
I mean it's a common problem you have
with test in general
you know you could spaniel days you know
writing tests and that's that so good
but
you you really want think about what's
really critical what's really important
but really make sense to Fannie really
differs from a
website to website with that's where
maps if you have to raise up on top that
it's extremely crucial that something
looks pixel perfect
all the ways you up one may can stand
stand is something that will
definitely makes ass too would you want
put some effort
into I using you know sitting in for
example
East it's not that important the way it
looks if it breaks a little ways no big
deal done
don't worry about a senior and again you
saying you should be can have your last
resort always think
how can I achieve a this test using
something like a demitasse client
if I can then don't even look at synonym
are you sitting in for what you contest
with anything else and for something
that's really important for you and
Europe
yeah
thanks to talk is ur the way to evaluate
what code has been
executed on your murmur yes
you can use the coverage package which
we basically
least every line a code in your entire
stack
that's been executed during the test and
that that definitely works with sterling
%um
yet if it ends in the same process
that's right
so if everything runs in multiple
threads within the same process
you work note each it's raining magical
process that's a good point
I thank you for the presentation
how does sauce labs are even to let him
handle
data-driven web site so for example if
you need us there's some sort of an Ajax
grady that gets the database
a value from here from the from the dow
and
and then matches against it so how does
it handle that as a general
the values by itself are d have to
provide those values
are does there need to be a database
connection for that so as far as I
understand
processing actually happens a
so every any custom code any database
related code we're on
locally so it's a on your see a server
or on your laptop
associated with just only take care of
the rendering
and exiting of and whatever JavaScript
inside
that VM but then you wish to communicate
with your local app
as far as datas concern for example so
that means deliveries needs to get
accessible for sauce labs no to you
to do that I know as far as they're
concerned a that
only needs to be eat that we only be
executed
on your machine and then he will just
Soundarya basically DHTML in the
resulting
I did the resolve your up would be dance
and over to social and that would be
rendered
so it heard so sad only takes care of
the client side basically
I C thanks as a that they have like um
if you're running serves locally they
have a lil encrypt a tunnel at No
but between your machine so you wanna
proxy server on your machine yeah
and I'll tunnel over to the source a
service they can look and if you go
running locally or on your network
that's right this is this is the thing
that I was running that took a minute to
to get started earlier
how to use the Lord multiple different
browsers if you're trying to do visual
testing in Internet Explorer
say 6 because one kill yourself
yeah hey a it's very easy actually you
just need to use a different
you know it's up to you they're there to
KC that's a he he really care
that both process a Firefox and IE six
would render
a particular component on your page
exactly the same
than you wanna test against the same
baseline image
issue a acknowledge that there may be
differences they're not
so important but you do want to make
sure that a key sparking the same and I
E
keeps working the same Firefox than just
create two different sets of baseline
images
to you can you know maybe have a class
that we inherit from your
say and I eat s-class that we inherit
from Thai folks
Iran exactly the same tessick said you
switch
the the webdriver and you just give you
know different fine Amos
so they don't conflict X
right demolition
both them for the Don Julian thank you
you have a couple of time