hello everyone and welcome
to the second session on the security
track this afternoon
it is my pleasure to introduce dan
Callahan from Mozilla
we'll be talking to you about quick wins
for a better website security
a big hand thank you
so what I want to do with the stalk is
give you a very broad
overview of techniques some Witcher
really
rather underutilized that with minimal
effort
you can use to dramatically improve your
site security going to talk about
security in three domains
when you're transmitting content when
your rendering content
and when you're storing content uploaded
by users are
generated otherwise the most important
thing you can do
to improve your website's security when
transmitting data
is to use a cell this has been a pretty
rough year for SSL
in 2014 Apple had the
the double go to feel bug which wouldn't
be possible in Python because we have
significant white space
arm but unfortunately have not yet taken
over the world
this short-circuited certificate
validation on I owe us and
Western devices and then just last week
a bug in open a soul refer to as her
bleed was disclosed which
leaked private key material force to
remove million sites on the internet
which is also not an ideal situation
from if you're running a teaser site
over a soul please go
update your search in her book the old
one but seriously
you need to use a cell because as the
souls the only widely deployed
technology the only tool we have to
protect
data in transit from you shoppers and I
see that what I mean is when you
normally go to website
say your bank dot com we take that into
your browser's address bar and hit
return the first in your browser does
is presumed be mean to it attempt to
connect to you the
in security each EP only version that's
a beachy pecans lash lash pink dot com
statements under clause that says hey a
bank give me your index page and several
usually respond if it's a banker some
other secure institution like
Hacker News or get hard with the
redirect it says actually please go and
talk to me
on port 443 me sleepy ass my secure
my SSL version of my site 00 resubmit
the same request to wrestle
get a response back and you actually
have content you're off to the races
of course with each request your brother
is going to send cookies as
browsers do you for that domain
fortunately by using a cell
um you protected in case
sorry baby messed up the transition
a mention attacker in between you in
your bank
if using us all your protected in case
attackers listening
your communication because everything
over the SSL secured link
is imprinted the attacker without
knowledge of
your service keys which partly from
I know has no idea what you're actually
transmitting to that site or with the
responses
but that first round trip that
connection to the HTTP the insecure
version inside is still visible to
anyone is listening units on the scene
at work
were between you and say you're trying
to reach and with that request
game session cookies normally when you
log into a website
so we'll set a cookie that identifies
you be some served
long may be a sign string in a cookie
and if you can see our cookie I can copy
it they can impersonate you on that say
because that's what the site when used
to identify you
for subsequent request a a little while
ago someone actually weapon is this in
Firefox
and create an extension called Firesheep
they did you really beautiful sidebar
with the big start capturing button when
you click that button would listen
on the local network and look for any in
secure a bust
that had a cookie cutter with the
session cookie
and give you this wonderful really easy
use menu
all the accounts you could just hijacked
by cloning that cookie
and sort one click you to be logged in
to Facebook ur Twitter depart as someone
else if you'd seen
love a request that they sent over HTTP
before they got redirected to the SSO
version of the site
to using us alone is enough because
there is still that initial
in secure a quest and the way you can
mitigate that
is we're using secure cookies so
normally the way a browser will
what's up the cookie from website is in
the responses there'll be a hater called
set-cookie:
which has a key equals value parameter
if you pander to the into the header
some econ space
secure you construct the browser to
only transmit that site or the cookie
back to the site
if it's communicating over securelinc
the attacker would still be able see
that initial request and response
but the session cookie wouldn't be
transmitted along with that first
request because
was marked as secure
however if the attacker can see button
for pasta response
be very well may be able to tamper with
it the commodified a request
they can modify the response you can't
really trust anything coming back that's
not secured over link
with SSL as a real-world example imagine
going to bankamerica duck confit take
Bank of America duck on my web browser
hit return I go through a series of
three requests
to rear experts like that HTTP
bankamerica dot com
that redirects me to dub dub dub Bank of
America com
which then redirects me to https
doctor dub bankamerica dot com salud
that bank's website
I had to go through three requests into
redirects before hitting a secure
channel
an attacker if they were able to you
insert themselves into the middle that
communication
could potentially alter that redirect in
simi to you a malicious domain say bank
0f America dot com which could be a
legitimate do mean
with a legitimate SSL certificate but
it's probably not that I mean I intend
to visit what's worse is the attacker
could decide
instalove just modifying the redirect
they could just serve you wholesale
it completely fraudulent copy the
website and never forger cost on
whatsoever again if I'm not you taking a
rest so I can't really trust
where the data is coming from or that
hasn't been tampered with
the Electronic Frontier Foundation has
published a blog article urging
what sites to use as a cell and in
discussing this
it provided a screenshot of Internet
Explorer 11 looting
the Chase Bank website both over a
legitimate secure connection
in over a hijacked in secure connection
and were things that if you can modify
the response if you're an attacker in
that situation you can change the
favorite icon
say to the icon of a lock and when you
load the page you end up with something
looks like this
and how we view in this room are certain
that you know which of those to you
screenshots is the secure version of the
site
and how confident are you that your
friends and your colleagues
would be able to detect the same and
avoid
logging into a proficient site
so what can you do how can you prevent
an attacker man in the middle
from serving up an altered a forged copy
per side
if they can observe that first
transaction if they can modify the first
transaction
and you can do abuse extra Transport
Security
so we're going to make america I went
through three requests the third being
the only one that was finally on secure
channel
if I go to get Hobbes even if I type
explicitly HTTP not s just http://
get a dot com and hit return my brother
only makes one request and it makes it
to the secure version of that site
its able to do that because in every
secure a sponsor the Gibsons on every
sponsor
arrest assault it's in the header called
strict Transport Security
let her little bit like this you provide
the max 8 answers
for the next in seconds
remember this domain in only attempt to
connect to it over SSL
and what allows you to use it allows you
to completely eliminate the first in
secure oun trip
you don't have to get the redirect your
brother knows but it should be talking
over SSL
you can complete your move that initial
and secure channel of course the very
first time your brother has to learn
about
that her somehow to the very first
coaches still has to happen but only has
to happen once
for all subsequent connections saw your
browser's cache hasn't been
cleared to be over secure channel
Firefox and Chrome also ship built-in
a list of preloaded sites that have
opted in to stir Transport Security
which helps bootstrap that system and
get you to your bank slip cider
to Gmail or to you get Harbor without
concerned for
maliciously get that first up
super transmitting data Michu using a
cell
to print you shoppers from monitoring
your content
should you secure cookies to ensure that
someone on the same network in person at
your users
and you should use to transport security
to ensure that
user actually meeting with your site and
they're doing it over secure channel
very easy to set up again secure cookies
usually just a single
configuration line most web frameworks
as a sole
as usually minor copious copious guides
were saying about Patch your engine x
ray us
sir transfer security gets a single HTTP
header to dramatically improve your site
security
we're not rendering even though we've
been selling cookies even sing them
securely
so they're not visible to that use
dropper if someone's able to inject a
script into our page
they could still access the document
that cookie property and retrieve
the text to that cookie and then the
good X will treat that
that session ID and send it to some
militia server and then
impersonate user that way
the way you can mitigate against the
sort attack
is we're using HTTP only cookies no
person should be sanitize your input it
should be possible for someone to get a
scripted your page
but suffers hard things happen
in the same way that we added the secure
token to our cookie
with an attitude called HTTP only which
instructs the browser
to not actually make that cookie
available two scripts on the page
its tone requests your web framework can
still see this can still read it
Django in flask will do this by default
for their session cookies
but it's protected from malicious
scripts on the page
but again you have a problem if there is
a malicious script on your page
and what can you do about that
a relatively recent addition to all
major browsers including
including Internet Explorer is support
for content security policy
this is the single most important slide
in the stock which is not a widely used
technology yet
and it should be water content security
policy will let you do
is a stylish the whitelist I've every
single external resource
and where can actually come from on your
site
this could be things like font style
sheets script tags images
videos anything that you can embed link
out somewhere else and CEO Gopal this
from
cloud from Drupal is from a maxi DNR
bridge rap CD and
in a content security policy can a new
marine saved by default only allow
things from self
which means the same domain the same
origin as the current page
or allow images from the same origin or
to be made directly with the data
protocol
or prints and scripts in this directive
last group related from the same origin
or from AP I dot example dot com
this allows you to create district
whitelist to completely innocuous
yourself
against injected scripts there's a
special directive I think it's
unsafe in line or something for in
sitter in line scripts
if that's not there if your browser sees
this content security policy and then
runs into a script tag in the middle of
your page
see just alert hello world it'll look at
that it will check the security policies
will see that that's not be valid
police first trip to be coming from
that's not something you expected
and it will ignore it completely blocked
her from looting or from executing
missus incredibly powerful of course
like this can be hard to add to existing
sites
so there's a sister tag called content
security policy report only
you can send with the same parameters
and what that will do you
is allow you to continue with everything
working
and whenever the bros would normally
block something with a policy allow it
to loot allowed to run
but will also log message to developer
Council tell you that
you hey this policy would have allowed
this thing to run are you sure you don't
wanna just a policy to you
within or maybe move your script to a CD
and somewhere that you do allow
and take an audit your partner's
translate for a sport a given policy
if you doing these five things you doing
extremely well
especially if you have a content
security policy again this is
relatively new has broad support in
browsers
Internet Explorer still requires a
prefix and has a slightly restricted set
of directives that it supports
but broad support this is your best
second line of defense
after because you have good inputs and
is Asian making sure that things are
coming from re expect them to you
nothing else can you a CSP can you
what you the other three other 100 you
can set the provide additive security
in different as a turkey since you can
set free martians
instruct the browser to completely deny
premium your page say I can't you know
I'm not allowed to listen i've room
sorry science not going to loot your
this will prevent clickjacking attacks
you may have seen huge water bombings
like
I believe is not a year ago where a site
had looted
a Twitter page with the pre-filled sweet
ex in a big Tweet button
in iframe said invisible and then put
that on top of
Sumter gamer some some other buttons so
when you click you think you're clicking
on this button below but you're quick is
really hitting this invisible iframe
and sending a tweet extreme options then
I'm
will prevent that from being possible
Django super the middleware that will do
this for you by default
a flask pyramid do not you can also set
same origin as the directive to allow
other documents on your own domain term
but that
that page or if you need to allow
betting on other domain you can set
allow from
the given your eye free single domain
importing that's not as widely spread
across browsers but if you do need to
allow embedding the site
in a frame somewhere else that's better
than nothing for browsers that do
support it
you can also set exercise protection so
are exploring chrome support
her called X assist us protection
witching Sutter one mood block
with elders will use heuristics to look
at the scripts that's about to execute
if it looks like that's good maybe
vulnerable to some server floated cross
site scripting attack
but sees query parameters reflected
inside the script itself
it'll simply prevent that script from
executing
again this isn't spur across all
browsers but its a very powerful tool
as the third line of defense if you're
centralization your content security
policy
somehow allow something to support
through lastly you can disable mime
type: sniffing some browsers will look
at the first you buy to a file try to
determine what it is
regardless what content type it sent als
which could be to you something you
intend to be
plane taxed being misinterpreted as HTML
and come to be you the start was static
turning into active
live scriptable content you can disable
that by setting the ex content type
options
new sniff header so
again 300's plus content security
policies
and you've dramatically improve your
site security all the sanding hunters is
like one line in middleware
very very easy to you dude in single
afternoon
what store India their two principles
and restore user
generate a deal the first is to
completely Eisley evening
that is coming from users if you're long
upwards at sea images for
avatars or other content you need to put
the content on a separate domain
not on your mean to me not a subdomain
you mean to me in but a completely
separate domain
you'll see this Google recently moved
although get her paper sorry
group moves all its content to you to
use our country dot com and get home
recently moved
all the get HubPages content to get held
up
I O and what that does is it allows you
to avoid some
esoteric session fixation attacks where
content on that demean might be able to
execute as if it was appear
to your own legitimate content and us
touch local storage or set cookies on
behalf of the user
by isolating on its own or under mean
its own origin
you're not at risk for those words
attacks
the other principals to avoid storing
data that you don't have to store
if at all possible don't use passwords
their number federated login solutions
social things like that happen Twitter
up if get hobby is appropriate to your
audience they also offer login
solution I work a muzzle on and I worked
on the personal project which isn't you
know based
walkin solution that doesn't required
site-specific passwords
the general prince was you can't lose
access to data that you're not storing
of course is important when you're
looking authentication system to balance
the need to view user's
so forcing everyone through Twitter get
home
might not be ideal because he might not
be willing to give your site access to
those
to choice of some sort of neutral you
know based while this is my other person
or judicial your password system
but providing alternatives to a
traditional password based
authentication system
will lower your your servicer your risk
lower the severe yunis or compromise you
might might experience
so in summary when transmitting data use
a cell
to ensure that you shoppers can see what
you're transmitting set secure cookies
to ensure user sessions can be hijacked
set strict transfer security hunters to
ensure your users are actually talking
to your site
and doing it over us all by default
when you're entering things make sure
you set HTP only cookies
so that malicious scripts can get access
to user such information User Content
Security Policy different
malicious scripts are injected scripts
or other content from leading on your
page if you don't intended to you
supreme options to work for checking
turn on axis us protection and a stable
mimes nothing to avoid other esoteric
attacks
I sleep content generated directly by
users to its own domain
if you can all boarded don't store
sensitive data that you don't absolutely
have to you
now before I wrap up I wanna point every
one to two other resources that are
absolutely phenomenal the first is OWASP
the open web application security
project
that can be found at a wasp .org and
it's our wiki based encyclopedic
reference
top 10 lists love major vulnerabilities
explanations a
what the problems are how you can
mitigate them developer cheat sheets
it's a really fantastic resource the
second his qualities a sellout
site at a cell labs dot com
you can point there'd tester to your
domain
in all give you back report card on how
well your demeanor supporting us a cell
what cipher suites using doesn't support
per perfect forward secrecy
is vulnerable to heart bleed and
information for how you can improve your
deployment vessel
the fantastic resource so that
but you are agree about five minutes for
questions and later dropped the one that
has questions to the mike
in the back corner but you
hi arm so if chrome and firefox are
shipped by default
with our what sites use strictest
our transport security and to avoid it
first potentially loses connection
arm what what exactly does the h
guess everywhere a plugin do so
HTTPS Everywhere which is a Firefox and
Chrome extension
there may be other browsers where that's
published by your truck Frontier
Foundation
is kind of like and opt into you a
sulfur sites are currently setting the
header have adopted into you
the preloaded lists so the brother since
you can use
on your computer to say he please avoid
this
first connection anyways the AZT yes
header is a way for the site
to do that for everyone okay
hi I I was curious when you're talking
about
making cookies ATP only that scripts
just can access them
I was wondering if you have a javascript
have the application that needs to do
a JS based off arm is that going to
interfere with that at all
I'm you should always be performing some
partner authentication on the backend
server
and the cookies will be some but that
request for normal and ship your tree by
the request
if you need to retrieve the cookie
princeton's in Django the CSRF token
is sent in a cookie that is not each DP
only by default you can turn on/off
per cookie as needed go
what's the way other recommendation for
browsers to try
aged BS before in an encrypted
connection
I probably just history from there a
lotta misconfigured sites
particularly if you RC naming out to
some other service and it might support
us all but
a up until recently a solder church in
being
one IP per site and so things could just
imagine the web to break when would
otherwise work
if their mobile site on single host for
instance
you mention log into the console for our
report only mode in
have you seen people doing plugins are
other types of extensions to
forward for the report on to the server
itself so that we can get tight
aggregated logs but what's breaking your
what's what's working
and we were actually is a a directive
you can
add that will do that I didn't have a
chance to you look at the only
ran across reviewing slides I would look
at the last page
and I'll tell you more otherwise I'm
sure their extensions out there that
will
gather that much
any other questions thank you so much