alright good morning everyone I'm so far
next talk we have
Porsche Britain who be giving a talk
titled know thy neighbor
psych it and the k-nearest neighbor
album so please give have a Porsche
hello
on thank you for coming this
presentation is going to be
on the k-nearest neighbor and fight kit
learn on
we're going to keep this presentation
high-level so we're not gonna get too
deep
and most this presentation will be based
on
the I kit learn documentation so for
those have you
who are part A up keeping a
documentation thank you
a little bit about me
on from Portland I'm the organizer
I love the Portland data Science Group
we're basically
om again the people like visualizing
data
like analyzing data once a month we have
talked and once a month we have a half
day it's
really I we love this group I'm also
volunteer are hack Oregon hack or again
is
us civic organization that takes
campaign
data and makes it more I accessible to
the people of the state
organ and I am also founder
I love the company PLB analytics what we
cover today
a brief intro to machine learning
will go over psych it learn will explain
the key
nearest neighbor algorithm and finally
we our demo will be based on the like it
loan package
and K&N machine learning
what is machine learning we've had many
presentations during the icon that
explains machine learning but I'm just
going to get to the Corbett
machine learning is basically when
algorithm learns from the data takes the
data
and and it makes sumptin what does
machine learning algorithms use this
data for
well to give you a sampling
it creates predictive models classify
unknown entity and discovers patterns
once again this is a sampling up what
machine learning algorithms can do
today we are mostly going to concentrate
on the creaking up predictive models and
classifying unknown entities this is
my basic workflow and machine learning
when I'm dealing with data
I spend about seventy percent
cleaning standardizing data putting in
to post crest
chasing stray commas away on
20 percent of my time issues to you are
preprocessed
train and validate the data and
10 percent issues too analyze and
visualize my data
way I visualize might data I a try to
use of d3
on JavaScript it's a great package for
interactive on visualizations and it's a
lot of fun to use
like it learn
so I can't learn is basically hyped on
answer to machine learning its up Python
machine learning package om I can't
learn it's great
because it has very good documentation
it is well
in and finally it has up
great dataset on for example the boston
housing market today
we will be making use all a psych it
learned
data set that already part of the
package
if you're new to machine learning
and you're using Python this cheat sheet
is a great way to figure out or navigate
the I can't learn package first you can
figure out well what is your sample size
do you have left in fifty on do you have
1,000,000 data points this is a good
wait to figure out what to do based on
your sample size
and this is a great way for you to
identify
what exactly do you want to do do you
want to classify
clustered you and your regression or are
you concerned
with dimensionality reduction
that being said it's very common for
on data scientist to use more than one
algorithm
they can use several different
algorithms in order to make sure
that their result their outcomes are I
to increase the accuracy
many companies use I can't learn I
actually used to work for a company
that you stomp like it learned
and but this is not wanna fuck ever know
I did not work revenue
ever know is great Evernote saw good way
for you to organize your notes
into notebooks and a use case
of I can't learn forever no is
are you a recipe I don't know about you
bought
when I use Evernote I have different
types %uh notebooks
ever know is a great way for me to keep
track MyRecipes
keep track of my friends and keep track
I love om
work and documentation so
whenever I go online and I
on find a note
Evernote suggest which notebook
I should put my note in to you on
suggesting a notebooks is
classification problem and implemented
naive Bayes classification
album which we're not going to get into
today
that being said I'll just give you to
form your own
the naive assumption up independence
between every pair
featurette
supervised and unsupervised learning
in this session up icon icon 2014 I
think
many of the presenters who will on look
that machine learning
did a really good job love defining what
is supervising what is unsupervised
learning
and we're going to go over that today as
well
unsupervised learning is when your data
point are not
labeled with outcomes so its
your algorithm that actually finding the
pattern
of your data
supervised learning is when your samples
are labeled
supervised learning can comment two
different flavors
on classic classification and regression
this is the theoretical model are
supervised learning
in supervised learning if you aren't
making a prediction your predictions
based
on your features so you put your
features in
and the out com is based on
on the dim your features and your
predictors
remember when you're coming up with
predictors and features on predictors
keep your sample size hi want to make
sure that you have
plenty of samples but that being said
you of skipping keep your sample site hi
but keep in mind to keep your feature
set low
the reason why it is instrumental to
make sure that your feature set is low
because you do not
want to run the risk of overfitting
here some examples of how supervised
learning is used
handwriting analysis it will all
familiar spam filters
right next we're going to talk about
Kate nearest neighbor Alka the Katie
nearest neighbor algorithm if considered
to be
simple lists machine learning algorithm
it is also considered to be to leave the
algorithm
which means that it will not run
computation
on your dataset until you give it a new
data point
that you're trying to test
in our demo we're going to use K&N
for supervised learning that being said
we have a little problem now where we
can
implement the Canaan near stable Apple
algorithm
problem number one
let's say you have Apple's those apples
and oranges
but you also have a mystery fruit
our goal is to figure out what
it that identity all the mystery fruit
so using can Canon were going to say
K&N to 3 which means we're going to look
at the three
closest neighbors in this example
we have and Apple and two oranges
so based on our closest neighbors we can
infer
that our mystery fruit is and
are inch
when you're looking at in nearest
neighbors you're taking
up majority vote majority vote can be
done in two different ways
on a majority vote can be giving equal
weight where each cane and neighbor has
the ways equal you can also set this
parameter to
on distant week where eat Canaan
neighbor vote
is based on the distant how far the
neighbor
it away from your sample
can and it uses simple a fag I'm the
wrong
it's something that we learned in middle
school and its
basically middle school math being
useful
as you everything our research see
downside to K&N sent this minimal
training
if the high computational cost in
testing new data
another problem that you might encounter
with K&N
if that sometimes a correlation is
falsely high
which means that data points can be
given too much weight
live Demel time before we get into a
live demo
I will tell you that we're using ID
defect from the thigh kit learn
documentation which means are
data is going to be
irises for those %uh view who have taken
a machine learning 101 class
classifying irises is considered to be a
very
comin problem typical
typical dataset
the iris dataset actually predate I
can't learn
it predates Python and it predates
most of us in this room the iris dataset
was a multivariate data set that was
created in nineteen
30 6 it was analyzed by Sir
Ronald Fisher but it was gathered by
agar Anderson
the problem that we're trying to solve
today were trying to identify
which height of iris that we have
weekend a dent defy which type iris we
have
by measuring delaying and the with up
the septal
for those %uh view on Inc myself
included
who need a refresher in terms with a
supple is located the supple
is below the pedal as labeled not
diagrammed
something I wasn't aware until doing
this
and to the right you have three
different types up iris
this is actually skipping ahead 131 our
dataset
this is going to be a result this is the
plot from our use case
did dots that you see actually the
training data
and the red green
and lilac would be are test data
the red the green channel I like it
actually are decision
boundaries and if we move over to our
second slide
the collars referred to the different
tight up iris is that we
the different species okay
so I am going to
but E the moment we're going to you i pi
fun
I python is great I Python comes in
on two different flavors you can use I a
python
in the command line and you can also use
I Python
18 your browser see
we have a bit of an issue so when I'm
using I Python notebook
I go to the command line that is put I
pipeline notebook
and ill give me the instant out by
notebooks here we go
right so we begin with
importing our packages and
I'm going to display different flowers
this case you want to see irises again
and in this example
we're going to set our nearest neighbors
in this section
we r importing our dataset which irises
and target means that
these are the labels for our date sense
we're doing
vacation I'm printing the shape of at
actually
tells us how many on
training testing point so we have chain
point excuse me
here we're actually making our mash
for the merger
we're going to actually have two plots
are plots are going to be
uniform and distant in terms of majority
vote this is our estimator
in our estimator on recruiting instant
up
neighbor classifier and fitting the data
we're creating
the min 0 max and maximum bar X&Y axis
finally were predicting
our training data and we're going to
create the mash
and this is what we week get as a result
so
in Figure 1 are week is uniform
which means that each om training point
equally counted and for distance
our training point is based on
the distance to the texting data so yes
you can see
on our decision boundaries are different
in order to illustrate
and bring home the important I love the
majority vote
why don't we run this again and in this
case
we are going to say our nearest
neighbour
from 20 250
every member a 150 if the amount of
training data that we have
in total
so a reading
so far distance our decision boundaries
are more or less
the same however if you look
at the majority vote for uniform
our decision boundaries are gone and we
just have red
the reason why we have read it because
instead of using
instead of using defense
it actually looks at the amount I love
training data we have
we mostly have red trade training data
points
and not influences our decision
boundaries the great part about
I Python issue can play around with the
parameters
and it just gives you it gives you
different result and it gives you
on a more robust way up analyzing your
training and testing
so that is it
for my a prison tation weekend
on have questions I like
I it for any questions %uh please come
to the microphone in the middle and
Justyna either
I'm outta some basic method I'll
logical questions on ok as you mentioned
two things
on the number near issue looking at in
making that judgment of classification
what's the criteria to determine
how many neighbors should be picked
that's the first question
on and y'all mention the risk of
overfitting went to many primers
on I introduced so is there any criteria
a test that can be done
to assess this risk of overfitting
well this I can't learn package
on have excellent documentation on this
end
what I did not do and my talk
is I did not talk about validating your
data
so once you're finished running either I
think the best way to deal with this
if you're over 50 is to on validate the
data and test the accuracy
hi
thank you for the talk I noticed in your
results I it's that
the some the decision regions for
discontinuous
I was wondering if you could talk a
little about a little bit about
by that was and whether that's a feature
a bug I
I'm sorry on
that with not a feature that was
appalled
and Dom we can talk more about it third
the
talk I can tell you about how howard got
beat and how I am Alive
day and yeah I'll get into more detail
really enjoyed the talk
home one if you could talk about to
leave real applications are working on
right now
is inching the real applications that I
am using machine learning for
I do a lot of natural language
processing so I'm using natural language
processing
to help assist with Search any more
questions
right please give her up you I'm
I couldn't quite read the code that
you're showing but is that just
is that K means that you ran with K&N no
knowledge is pain
as k-means is clustering were doing
classic
okay I thought you were bus transit
things into
oh yeah ok and your question
right please give a half a Porsche