I'll it's my privilege to introduce dan
crossed on
with the Leapfrog prom in junior
magnetic from Adam
K
hey everyone I'm thanks for coming out
on my notes and other day but
I hope that there's going to be exciting
and interesting for all views so
my name's Dan cross to I work at
magnetic
I'm here today to talk about performance
testing
and profiling arm but first I'd like to
just give a little bit a background
about arm why this matters to us and
sort of what my experiences with
performance task in profile
so and magnetic um
we work Mr online advertising space um
we see on a given day somewhere from
route you may be five to 10 percent
US Internet traffic so we get a lot of
requests or servers
I at peak times the sands up being over
a hundred
sometimes a 150 year a little bit more
thousand requests per second
as as you can imagine performance
matters for quite a lot to us and
and to our applications arm stability
and uptime responsiveness
arm
so that's why I'm here um you guys are
here
either because you've heard that I'm
very good speaker or because you care
about me want to learn more about
performance testing
on the good news is I'm gonna be able to
to deliver on one of those promises
I'm so here's a little bit about what
we're gonna be talking about for the
next 20 minutes or so
arm a suspect that most people are
working in the store web application
space on a focus
on web applications by these techniques
are
pretty generally applicable to any sort
love performance estimate you might want
to do for any others are about occasion
um look a little bit at what some other
standard library offerings are as far as
Sir getting
profiling which is sort of in-depth
information about how long things are
taking inside your application
and then finally will soar to close the
loop with
instrumentation which is a a real time
where performance monitoring
and I'll describe what I call a virtuous
circle love
performance improvement arm
so what his performance testing a at the
end of the day it basically boils down
to this: to generate a bunch of requests
against your application
on what we call loading and then you
measure how long your application takes
to respond to those things
and perhaps you care about error rates
we do in our performance tests
arm and that's basically it so it's it's
really just you throw a bunch of stuff
in your app and you see what actually
happens
arm one thing that's really easy in that
we
the use a magnetic that's a to best
practice redeveloped is just
will take logs from our production
servers arm
run through setup scripts to adapt them
for load testing environment
and then jus replay those logs guns that
were testing program arm
but actually John to head a little bit
arm gonna take a step back so there's
several different types a performance
testing that you can do against
when application arm today wanna talk
about
the the top two which are sort of the
arm the ones we get the most value
up I'm not gonna talk about spike
testing and soak testing although those
are very interesting topics as well
and if you're interested in that sort of
stuff I recommend doing some research
online
arm
so a stress test arm this is I suspect
what most people think of when they
think of the phrase
load testing our performance testing on
their deal with the stress test is
is to take your application and really
push as hard as you can arm
and find the spot where break somewhere
falls over where response times become
too high
arm typically this means during a lot of
requests their application may be a high
degree of concurrency
I maybe you pick out those requests that
are serve slowest her heart is for
application to process
arm the serve
goal here is to find a you know how much
cum Application do before totally falls
over
on this is interesting in this can be
exciting I'm specially if you're sort of
stressed as in someone else's
application that can be a lot of fun
I actually think that it's not the most
valuable so to perform in testing that
you can do
on because almost by definition when
your application is breaking
armed you're not getting a very good
picture above what's actually going on
inside that application
on PSO the one thing that I do recommend
is to
to use a load test arm and the
difference between a low test
and a stress test is that a low test
you're generating some specific amount
of load
arm typically will run more tests with a
sort of level concurrency in a number of
requests per second
that's typical of our servers and
production arm in some cases we use a
slightly exaggerated amount upload it
matter represents
what have we got 10 percent more traffic
or if a couple of our servers failed in
the others had to take over that traffic
arm blood tests are yours or bread and
butter performance as the really good
for capacity planning
arm and preserve learning how your
system performs and as we'll see it sort
of fits in with his performance
improvement
I'm cycle that we can get into
so a few other best practices that we've
developed a magnetic over the past
couple years and during this
arm I hope these are obvious but just
ate them
for the record anyway I'm arm so you
want to isolate your performance testing
from any external influences that you
know about and that you can reasonably
isolate your app from
arms what this means for us as we have a
dedicated performance testing
environment
arm it's much smaller than our
production environment obviously because
we don't have
sort of gobs of money to spend on it arm
but smaller in such a way that we know
how to solder extrapolate from
performance as a result into production
arm and we do this by sorry just scaling
down to the components so the
application servers some other database
servers
arms on the login servers and and pieces
like that
on the other really important thing to
remember arm is that is very important
to generate loading
in a consistent and repeatable way arm
apps a
sorry about that %uh so a lot of people
will
think you know okay arm I'm gonna set up
a load test and I'm going to you
you have a pool up ten different URL's
I'm going to just sort of picked
randomly from
and fire one off after the other arm
that's interesting
but then if you run to those in a row
they're actually not the same test and
so if you want to compare the results
between those two testing runs
you have no sir principled way to do
that um
finally when you do something like
report from production replaying your
performance test environment
arm if you can sort automate this whole
process and get it down ideally to us or
to one click testing
I process right one click to start the
test
arm that actually means that it's its
serve at the level
love a repeatability where people
actually use it
and it could become part of sort of a
daily development pretty
okay so um once we should have our
are performance testing setup arm we
might find that things are a little too
far a little too slow
arm too fast as always good and so what
we wanna
understand as you know where is it slow
and why is it slow arm
so profiling assorted the answer to to
those questions is the technique to
answer those questions
on following papon's batteries included
omphalocele be
there's ways to profiling right within
the standard library
arm unfortunately the documentation
around profiling
is sort of not that good I and some the
API's are also
pretty terrible in my opinion arm so
wanna do is show you sort of the
the right way to do it or at least the
way that I recommend to do it
arm and so for profiling that looks like
this so you import the sea profile
module
arm you set up a profile or objects were
profile object
you call enable on it you do some stuff
can you call disable
arm each time you saw repair this enable
and disable call
the profile object is going to
accumulate more results
arm by timings for everything happens
between those calls
comments 0 you consider sprinklers are
on your program if there are only
certain sections that you want to do
im arm you can also obviously just sorta
do it around the whole run a program
arm it would be really nice up a
standard library offered these things as
your contacts manager or a decorator
are it doesn't but it would be fairly
easy as you can see here too
disorder make that
arm once you collected those profound
result and save them to a file
you use the key stats module two begin
to interact with that profiling data
arm so the sort of simple as possible
thing that you can do
look something like this: you look at
the stats are you sort them by something
in this case the number of calls to each
function
and then print them out
so what's actually see what this looks
like
I okay so what I have here
I is a very simple low test against a
very simple web application
arm and there's basically three
different actions that we support here
so
there's a log in there's a lockout and
there's a sort of say hello and point
arm and wanted to find a couple
different behaviors that this low test
is gonna carry out
are now I know I said before that random
is not a good choice
arm so please pretend that I'm not using
random here but this is just sort of a
simpler way to go about it particularly
since this is an
actually a real application is running
anywhere
arm so one-fifth the time we're gonna
perform an invalid login
the one for the timer in a login and
logout
and three-fifths sixty percent of the
time we're going to login
and say hello to someone so using the
sort of third and point the application
arm so I can run missile test here
I as you can see a shorter run a couple
times in the past lips
had it
on our run it in a loop
I'm so we can see that it's are making
summer class that's the longer the
application above
okay women fifty your question four
seconds the average latency the average
time it took for the request to come
back
I is a few milliseconds on but the
median is three male seconds
I'm so immediately what I'm seeing here
is that there's something going on right
so the average
as much higher than me dinner or vice
versa that means that there's some sort
of an imbalance and how long the
different
apart some application take
arm sock with the app a Python shell
arm and has run a coalition the previous
slide okay so
a what we can see is that even for a
trivial applications applications like
maybe 25 lines long it collects a lot of
data
I'm there's a lot of noise in here so we
can see that there's something going on
with basic HTTP Server Error there's
some CFI going on
I don't really know how to make sense of
this it doesn't fit on the projection
screen
arm so fortunately the keys that model
although it doesn't really documented
very well has ways to sort of narrow
I'm filter this down arms to the first
thing I might do
arm is provide a filter to the Prince
dats function where I can say
I'm only interested in in certain things
I'm in this case I'm actually only
interested
in things that are in the file called
web app top I
how much is the name of this application
arm so here we can see the three
different and points how many times
which ones called
a the total amount of time that was
spent
arm calling those functions up
so that a lot of time spent in the body
and those functions and that divided by
the number calls
and the next column is the total amount
of time spent in that function plus all
the things that
it called and then that divided by the
number calls
arm so it's pretty obvious there's
something going on here with the login
function
arm so how can we find out what that
actually is and what's causing your apt
to be slow
arm instead of calling Prince stats
we can do print holly is
in other words everything this function
is called
arm and as a filter on going to just
basically copy exactly that
arm and pass then
but
it's just right this
there
arm so now I think we can finalize or to
see what's actually going on what's
causing the imbalance and performance
and its applications about logging
function is doing something with the
crypt
arm be crips up for those who don't know
about it is an hour then thats
actually designed to be slow which is
why I chose it for this demo arm
the way it works is it basically will
take your password and sorta repeatedly
hasher
some enormous number of times ominous
designed to be slow to make it harder to
crack
arm but I thought it made a a nice hors
d'oeuvres example
arm so some of the other things that are
good to know about the peace that model
that you'll definitely want to
to sort of having your from your pocket
when you're working with this
arm the print methods there are 3 items
are printed at Sprint holly is
I we've seen by those imprint callers
arm which is everyone who was called
a certain function on so you can see
what that looks like
say hash
PW I'm so that we can see about Ashley W
function is only being called from login
arm so these things Baltic strings
that act as filters in with bill filter
is basically everything that shows up in
that rightmost column
arms which typically is the path and
file name
arm up the function that's being timed
um
you can also give them a a number which
says a
you know only print but top and have
something so resort by calls
and print the top 15
print stats on then it's good just
restrict with a prince out to
only 15 rows most I'm you can sort of
combined these things together
arm I've been sorting by the number of
calls so far but there's a few other
things here that are
but I use pre frequently so cumulative
asserts by the column here that is
labeled hume time
on what you have to pay out carefully
arm
and so as you can see it or sort by that
column arm
it doesn't in all cases take the name of
the column
as a value that you can sort by in fact
there's a list of like
28 different specific abbreviations and
prefix is that it will accept that you
can sort it look up if you take into
this model
what I've done what I recommend as
disorder play with it
eventually learn what works and adults
or become habitual for you
so your for instance 0
smaller okay
Sonic is actually does work arm let's
see is anything else I wanted to say
about profiling no I think that's good
so arm what profile is going to tell us
is why our application is slow
arm so performance testing load testing
and stress testing will tell us
that it is slow arm profiling
will tell us why it's slow release where
it's as we saw here if you don't know
the details would be cryptic might not
be obvious why that's much slower than
the rest the code
on its very good personal identifying
areas for optimization
arm in fact I'd recommend actually not
optimizing anything
into your profile didn't proved that a
it is called very frequently
and be that it actually is slowing is
sort of a target for improvement arm
one other thing that a we'll do a
magnetic is
in our performance testing environment
arm there's a future flight that we can
send your application that will
basically toggle profiling are off
so that same one click on performance
testing run
we can use to trigger a profiling run it
all clicked profound results and
basically save that file summer for us
to analyze after the fact
so that was the
standard library profiling model arm
there are many other profiles that are
out there on third-party profilers
there's
to you that I want to call out today %uh
the first
is one called line profiler on the way
the wind profiler works is it gives you
a decorator that you can wrap around a
function
arm and then it's going to measures or
literally a huge line in that function
how many times that line was called
on how long it took to execute that line
some cases where
profile herbs or tell you that a
function is slow but you don't
understand why it's slow this can be a
good way
to dig in a little bit further arm and
secondly
there's an alternative provider called
gappy arm
which has a couple love me a additions
to be on what the standard library
provide so first is that it lets you
profile
arm cold across multiple threads of your
friends and your application
arm yeah people actually capture
providing results
on because that executing on any thread
arm
and additionally it will let you choose
whether you want to measures or wall
clock time:
or CPU clocked on arm so in most cases
wall clock time is what you actually
want if you want to sort of disregard
certain
external influences like how long a napi
took to respond
during this particular profound run than
the CPU time is is really want the
measures or how much time is spent in
your code rather than
waiting on the network or waiting on the
database or something like that arm
mine profiler the output is just thing
that it prints at you
arm yeah people actually save the
profound results in the same format as
see profile does seek inspected using
the peace that model
I in the same way as we just
demonstrated I okay
so the next thing i wanna talk about it
instrumentation arm
this can be more two different things um
what I mean here specifically
is a certain type of performance
instrumentation
armbar you actually add code your
application in order to get
absorb performance metrics out a bit so
what we do a magnetic as we use
something called stats d
arm and what that does is it gives you
a serve named time series metrics
us so I came I can go in and say I want
to count I
how many times this function is called
are how long it took
each time I call that function arm
Saturday the
and then the syrup community of tools
that exist rounded I'm also let you sort
of graph
and computer and compare this data arm
look at you know maybe a week ago verses
today on you can
combine it so you can say arm you can
divide to metric so if you have
as we do an ad space will have a certain
number times that we bid
as are numb times that we win arm a
particular ad then we can compete to win
rate just by dividing those two metrics
on that has become sort of a valuable
tool both for
performance monitoring production but
also for to
business monitoring so if we see that
that ray Cooper down
that might mean that we have a you know
some situation that we need to
investigate
I'm possibly an engineering on the
engineering team and possibly another
two
so this is what are musings that she
looks like
for timing functions there's just a
handy decorator that you can wrap around
your function
and that's gonna log basically every
time this function is called how long it
took
are meant for counters for those how
often did something happen
army use the stats do that incoming call
arm
if you're just going to buy one you
don't need actually have that argument
here but I've shown it just for
completeness
arm so what's happening behind the
scenes here is that every time we call
into stats tea into one of these
insurance arm
its firing a you keep active of to you
another service that's running on the
same shem
arm and the way it's coded in the way
it's designed
is too sore to minimize the impact to
your actual running application
I every time this is called so it's it's
something that a
not only is it safe to serve have on
production I'm it's recommended to have
it on a production is designed for that
sort of Use Case
arm and I actually have sort of a demo
of this but just to give a
a sense for what it feels like once you
have these metrics
arms here's a graph love the number of
requests per second that we had
this was I think earlier today arm
here we've actually serve subdivided
this this one time series metric
into two different graphs here's one is
for East Coast data center and one is
for West Coast
arm and here's a sort of the result to
that timing function arm
so sorta looking we don't happen on the
same side here but
looking at these two you can see that
you know there's a relationship between
his two metrics
as a number for press per second goes up
%uh so does the amount of time it takes
for us to actually service that request
I was not particularly surprising but
it's good to actually be able to sort of
see that
and know what your applications doing
so instrumentation much to learn you
know what's normal for my application
how many requests to actually get
how long do they typically take arm
hours that's the package as a bonus also
let us alert about this thing so
typically work or not I'm staring at
these day today are all day long rather
arm was or learn for particular metric
what looks good and what looks healthy
arm and set alerts so for instance if
the 95th percentile request I'm
grows above I think 50 milliseconds
where we have our alerts at
on for more than a couple minutes it'll
actually shoot an email to us and no to
fire on covert Asian
arm there could be many reasons why that
situation is happening but at least now
we know about it
ongoing investigative
arm instrumentation also is it serves as
sort of a backstop particularly like
after a new code release
arm you know that thing which I did what
I thought was going to make things
faster
is it actually making things faster are
we actually handling more question
production
arm the fastest way to know is is just
by looking at your stats the dashboard
and pulling up a metric and see if it's
actually true
um so finally now I think we have all
the pieces to to put together the
virtuous cycle so we have
our instrumentation and production arm
which is going to tell us
basically when we need to look deeper
and when we need to optimize
I mean that's when production is to
slower when we're not handling number
for bus that we need to
arm we have load tests and maybe in some
cases stress tests which will help us
sort of
isolate the problem in be able to
reproduce it so we can study and
understand what's going on
army profiling which is going to let us
sort of dig really deep in find the
actual underlying
recalls arm and then we have ourselves
right programmers and we can actually go
and
deal with that code and optimizes or
rewrite it if it needs to be or
at cashing I'm whatever the right
technique is depending on what that
recalls problem is that we found
on that we roll it out in production we
use our instrumentation and are
monitoring production to make sure that
actually does what we wanted to do
thanks everyone
as
anyone have any questions
you talked about
like so sorry first well thats tend to
have a lot of lightning
parts like maybe there's a TV caller
there's some key-value story reading
from
how do you serve minimize that when you
doing from assisting how to make sure
that those factors
don't impactor test yes so the question
is
on how to howie take some compile a
database or key value cash
and make sure that we've sort of
isolated um
in Quincy might have on our performance
test I'm so there's there's
for two parts to the answers the first
is um in our performance testing
environment we have
a copy of it so it's not handling any
load other than what's coming from the
performance test
arm and the other is that it is actually
a part of the application and so if in
your performance testing environment I
maybe you're testing a new version that
you haven't ruled out to production yet
if that's too slow and too slow because
your overwhelming memcached let's say
but that's actually really important to
find out about that before you roll it
out and production arm
so to a certain extent you actually do
want the influence of it in the results
and performance test because
at how things actually do run in the
real world for a
loading up the results from c:\program
as one point out that to Kohls runs Nick
run
who actually had help you visualize here
age it was a square metre going window
handle
like is it quick overview what is
actually taking the most part time
individual
fashion yahoo.com every ship it to
I've looked around saying run a little
bit I've actually
a rather my preferences is to be to work
with text
common or more comfortable there but I'm
glad you brought it up and I i should
have put in the sides just so folks can
find it some
I had a question on have you ever heard
talk all our mechanized
for Python and what is your opinion
other arm
mechanize is it that's a load generation
we're testing tool
I arm I've never actually used it arm
so I have no opinion about it in
particular um what I can say is that
a for our use case at least um
were a little bit different so we're
dealing with lots of requests but
there's no sort so
sessions or anything in our applications
each request is totally independent on
which makes it really easy for us to do
that thing that I recommended which is
just taking production logs and replay
mom
arm we can basically take large for any
server %uh
just sir quickly reformat the data arm
and we throw it into you know the
fastest see you are testing tool that we
can find
arm Tucson minimize the influence a
below testing tool on the results
arm but I i've as far as mechanized as
if you have never worked with it thanks
beat-up I wanted to ask if you recommend
any load testing
up by then based tools um
so do I recommend any Python baseline
testing tools um
as a researcher saying so for our
application the
amount of clothing to generate is
actually arm
probably more than we could easily
generate from Python so we use
aren't actually a custom testing tool
that's written in C I'm wrapping with
curls
it's just sort of the smallest amount of
code you can write to make libcurl
actually make a request
are now that said the part of our
testing environment
um we use bees with machine guns which
is a python tool and what that does is
basically got Amazon
a spin up some number of machines and
then launched protests from all of them
arm so you can generate a lot of load
from a lot of different machines
basically from one command and so that's
I actually really important part of our
culture me better
act things around