I'm yes so let's let's welcome
vandenberg
so one of the things that I can do
that is really really the best part
have I love descend this entire thing is
that I get to say thanks
so I'm gonna begin by actually taking a
survey about who's using few different P
features in Python if you wanna rip use
one of these features please raise your
hand
I bisect collections
de small punk tools
keep cue inter tools
Jas on math cue
random names to pull
enumerate sets
the new conditional expressions reverse
iteration
ordered X have a generator expressions
if you use any of these features
you need to think Raymond Hettinger
Raymond is the originator maintain our
pep author for each one of these
features
and he's done an amazing amount more
he's been around the pad thai community
for well over a decade
I believe about 12 years since his first
post on comp in Python
he has three thousand 812 commits to
the Python depository he has a 160
commits to the paper posit ori and 8,000
89,000 716 lines and Python repository
where either added or changed by him
he's also served as director the Python
Software Foundation
and been a mentor to many many people on
a meaningless
so I'm happy today
Raymond coming up here
and
the Distinguished Service Award is the
highest award given by the pipe and
stopper foundation
signifies essentially a life and work
and sell thank you a min
I also get to highlight a couple other
people on
David are David Murray come up
young
dollar where the switch to unit code in
Python 3
well one of the places in which that
gets the most hairy
is in the email module and
david has spent the past several years
untangling that because
all up the email RC's were written
before you know code literally
and so it's a complete mess Masham
understanding
sometimes it stayed at sometimes had sex
in going back and forth
and he's also been a longtime mentor for
new contributors
he helped people in the car mentorship
main less some pipe and av
on the IRC channel he's a Google Summer
of Code mentor
been a big help on-boarding Google
Summer of Code and
and unknown ok and its his patience is
really unparalleled
and so I am happy to award the community
service work AR David Murray
the
I also wanted to recognize Benjamin
Pearson
%ah Benjamin is since so many different
places
in Benjamin are you here he's probably
fixing code
and I think I don't know if you noticed
that
Fernanda per said that he needed
something had I think was pat 465 maybe
3465 and Benjamin a couple hours later
he did it
and he the release manager for pat on 27
who works on the six compatibility
libraries pics many many bugs on the new
bike and our org
he artiste received eight community
service were in 2011 but we wanted to
give him a special recognition for all
the things he's done in it's actually
one more word
i've been searching about the code and
people who have affected
almost through the code but there's one
way the
other thing that all of us in this room
share and that is that we have been
touched in affected by this person
this is the largest gathering
I love Python programmers that will take
place in the world this year
and there are so many people to thank
I Matthew David Yanick Stewart
all the Montreal Python but there's one
yes
there are literally too many to name but
there's
one person who has put in literally the
many many hundreds about hours
to chair Pike on this year
and that's Diana Clark
in own
it's amazing to have so many people who
are willing to share in contribute
in our community in a community that's a
really important word for us
three years ago
a couple professors actually I
war decided study code diversity
instead the study community actually the
the growth and development various
communities
and the fountain indicators and growth
and development and well-being and
happiness
and they found various communities that
had had
historic record a history going back
thousands have years and some that had
been
isolated until relatively recently and
they studied these
and they've decided to stand see what
made these communities successful
don't wanna share three things from
their study
the key question their research was
is it better to be more similar
or more different and they look at a lot
of different
end indications I'd I'm entered a look
at economic growth they look dead
well-being they look it migration
patterns they look at the ability
have other people to get there they look
at records from other people visiting
and look at all these things and they
tried to figure out
it having more and different people a
benefit
or is it something that that it really
hold you back
and what they found was really really
interesting
they found that when a community with
very new
it was being having people be very
similar be very homogeneous
was a huge asset and the reason why is
because
when you were new you didn't have to ask
what your neighbor would think about
something you just knew because you knew
how your neighbours think you know
they're
how they would react you
were able to be aligned because
everybody was unlike
now here's the surprising part debt as
society started to become more complex
through the Renaissance and especially
through the Industrial Revolution
devalue ugh similarity
plummeted and the value of being
different
skyrocketed it actually turned out
that these communities that had had a
little bit
%uh the head start earlier earlier in
basically agricultural times
started to stagnate and the ones that
had
these influences from all over had
different viewpoints different people
different values different points of
view day
started to really become successful a
model on many different direct
dimensions so
this is the first point diversity
is a necessary response a complexity
unless we are willing
to accept many people with many
different viewpoints into our community
we are going have been the different in
all the different inputs that we really
need to grow second
is that date at that look further into
the data they found that there was a
rich get richer affect
foreign many these communities some of
them
at society advances the communities that
are relatively more diverse
tend to attract more opportunities they
have more growth
and so that brings in new people and new
ideas and new viewpoints
which sets of a virtuous cycle but
it also they also found that the
communities that were relatively less
diverse
tended to have fewer people in few
opportunities
and two people left opportunities dried
up and they stagnated
this is the second point
is that diversity creates a virtuous
cycle
if we are willing to reach out
we can outgrow and out thinkin
out-compete
the people around us now this is true
in open source communities as well
particularly this is true in the Python
community
when first started out it's true we had
a as substantial
group people we were very similar who
had a couple people and I'd like to
especially I highlight people like lynn
route
and Jessica McKellar who've been
we had these people who are dedicated to
helping us reach out
and we've had about five years an effort
and since then we've been on the path
for greater growth in greater diversity
and you can see it in this hall
reflected at this conference we have
people from fifty did two different
nations across
all inhabit six continents mosey it even
more in gender diversity
we don't ask for gender on on our
registration form
but we can do a little bit love machine
learning on your names and we can look
at T-shirts
I we conditions Disick assist this is
statistical sampling
and sometimes I can say that weren't
sometimes I can't
and it will it appears to us from all
the data that we have
is not only do we have one-third women
speakers we have one third win in
attendees the
so I'm really excited about that number
because the most recent survey from the
computing research associations
I graduation numbers indicated that only
12 percent
computer science graduates in the in the
year 2011 to 2012
where women that means that we are
pulling more than our weight
amongst various communities we
and
we are winning we r on that virtuous
cycle and sell
when I look out across as through icy
community
that it better prepared to meet the
future and better prepare to win and
compete
than any other that brings me to the
fair point
and that is that diversity requires
individualization
diversity maybe 8 necessary response to
complexity
but diversity itself brings
with it its own complexity think back to
the professors in their study
when people are very similar it's really
easy for people communicate again
because they're
all like because there are they're all
lined because they're all like
but when society starts to become more
complex
the communities with greater diversity
are able to prosper because they include
people with different points of view
and who think and value different things
who have different use cases and want
and may at hugely different number
to go ahead choose a different number
directions you can't predict
what your neighbors going think anymore
though so you need to take more time to
communicate
in our own community we need to think
about this in terms
up acceptance an individualization
greater diversity means that we need to
work harder to understand those around
us
and to be empathetic to the very man the
various places that they're coming from
you know I was talking with a couple
attendees the other night
and one of them said and this is calling
it as close as I can
said I consider it much more important
that I was raised in New York
and had a liberal arts major before I
started code those things do much more
to define me and Who I am than the fact
that I'm a woman
it was well said I we can't be lazy
and treat people like their
one-dimensional on any line
be it race or gender or politics or
culture
or anything because the value comes in
understanding
that we have many different viewpoints
in are many different people
at this is were Frank and
this is were affected in the code of
conduct for MPS after I know we talked
about this
%uh the codes of conduct a little bit
Brett dead
on the first day so many are familiar
with his and a pipe on
and what how that has guided us in
actually
creating iconic code but there is really
a then have Python community and i think
that that was the one that was written
by Brian curtain
you know
you can see it
my favorite quote from this conference
so far came actually from Lawrence and
cut then
who said that just being at Pike and
make some more optimistic around the
world
so the colored contact this
den a python community is says and I'm
gonna read it to make sure I get it
right
the Python community is made up of
members from around the globe
with a diverse set of skills
personalities and experiences
is through these differences that our
community experiences great successes
and continued growth
when you're working with members to the
community we encourage you to follow
these guidelines: which help steer our
interactions
and strive to keep right on a positive
success on growing community
and member the Python community is open
we're open members of the community are
open collaboration with their time
perhaps
patches problems or otherwise were Sep
22 destructive common criticism
as experiences and skills that other
members contribute to the hole in our
efforts
work setting up all who wish to take
part in our activities
fostering an environment where anyone
can participate any everyone can make a
difference
considered members to the community
community are considered up their peers
other Python users working at toppling
addressing the efforts of others keeping
in mind that oftentimes the labor
was completed simply for the good of the
community
where attentive in our communications
whether in person or online
more tactful one approach approaching
different views
highly respectful members the community
are respectful
respectful of others depositions their
skills their commitment and their
efforts
we respect for the volunteer efforts
that permeate the pipe and community
we respect for the processes set forth
in our community
and we work within them when we disagree
we are courteous and raising our issues
overall we are good to each other we
contribute to this community not because
we have to
but because we want to if we remember
that these guidelines will come
naturally
you'll notice the Python code of conduct
and quote by the way
is about who we are and what we value
here in the Python community
we recognize that we are different
people with different experiences and we
explicitly value that
we reach out but where does that leave
the PSF
it's clear that as a community we have
turned toward the corner toward greater
growth and greater diversity
and we're starting to rate the the
benefits at that
but I have to say dad as
an organization PSF hasn't kept him
hasn't kept up
it's over the past year and a half their
Ben many discussions
and boats and a lot of work thinking
about what defines us as an organization
and how we can better reflect the
worldwide Python community
and so I'm happy today to announce the
combination up that effort
cell love those who are here now how
many are currently members at the PSF
be courageous and
gate now others who are here how many
members at the pad thai community
you see the difference that's completely
unacceptable
our communities become bigger and more
diverse
and stronger and we as an organization
were in keeping up
that is why as it today the PSF is
transitioning to an open membership
model
everybody who's in the Python community
is welcomed and encouraged
to become a member the PSF
the
in fact if you go to the new Python a
dork and you scroll down to the bottom
you'll see a button that says become a
member PSF
you fill out a form you agree to the
code of conduct
he say I am a part of this community and
I agreed to these values
I will be kind I will be respectful I
will be considerate
and you are a member the PSF we've also
said it
we've also created a new structure
called working group
where people can we can
bring up the things that they are doing
to help support
others in the community we don't have to
think about all these ideas are cells
and the PSF can in a structured way
help you and recognize you and those who
are working in dedicating
whether it be in organization whether it
be in cold weather been documentation or
Tess
or leadership or outreach we want to
support you
and those who are involved will have the
opportunity to be
do to actually be eligible to vote an
exercise
a role in guiding where r where the PSF
goes in the future
we've reworked are
the bylaws to be radically more
inclusive and representative
Python community as a whole and this is
one of the things that
where we're just starting on this is
a new direction that frankly no other
community that I'm aware of has gone in
especially with regard to creating
the way for us to elevate empower and
support
individual efforts from across the
Python community
so I ask you for your patience as we go
forward
because we're gonna have various places
where it's going
word gonna have glitches and we're not
always going to do it right but from
here on
I hope that I can how to coming out of
icon
I'd like every single one of you to be a
member the PSF
by the end of the year I'd like to have
30,000 members
at the PSF worldwide or even more
because Dad is true that the community
is about
so we can support each other we can
empower each other and we can truly
represent be representative I'll this
community
in all in in all its diversity thank you