with that our next speaker is Tabish
Armstrong
attempt is a sovereign young student at
Concordia University
last year he added the performance have
open source applications
a collection of essays about
optimization written by the maintainers
various
open source projects it is pretty beefy
noles nusa Syria's
are that if you buy all the proceeds go
to Amnesty International's II super
recommended
am so please give a warm welcome to
Tavish we'll be talking about
suffer injury research for hackers
bridging the two solitudes
thanks
is this on aka
thanks for coming and I wanted to start
up by
thinking Dana Bauer who encouragement a
similar talk proposal the pike on
I A yeah and so you have her to blame if
this goes badly in you have her to think
if it goes well
two-minute room in talk for you
and first light min talk mood with the
star gazer
at using data analysis to
a analyzes the open source projects that
we work on
to learn more about how the development
process works
and learn more about how we work I think
this can help us make smarter decisions
Abboud
how we program and a
incur to serve better more productive
conversations about this
so fundamentally the sarcasm
conversations to vote what we tell each
other's trooper programming and now we
decide
you know on this knowledge what we know
and how we know it I was reading a book
on how scholars on the
and this line junto a mi
it surprised me is it Iran to an
important aspect of her skills power
lies in the compactness and the code we
rape compared to working in popular
traditional languages
when we develop it has girl we often
very much less code and substantially
less time
and with fewer bugs this is an
interesting statement because
as far as I could tell the author is I'm
basing this completely on
intuition on their experience which is
great we should talk about it
on the experience so we have reading
software and compare let other people's
experiences and this is a totally valid
thing to do but it's a limited use
not everybody agreed to me in the
comments section actually
I'm challenges person the my impression
is that how schools ranking factor
averages around four but obviously very
is allowed
this is a surprising amount of precision
for some years also
making this number up and
that's okay I mean we're talking about a
our experiences writing software and its
um this is how this person feels
but wouldn't be so much better if we
knew
whether or not this is true we knew this
was truly we know something more about
how software works
if we knew that it took less time to
rate house coco maybe we would
switch to Haskell I don't know so this
isn't about somebody being wrong on the
Internet
the vote so you could be more right on
the Internet we say a lot of things to
each other that
arm you know if they were true if we
actually a
evidence for them I think we would act
differently you probably heard somebody
say
papon's more readable than other
languages you know
behind if you think this is true core
on I actually think this is true but you
we could do usability testing on
languages and find out which ones
are actually more readable do that
forward different
kinda programmers novices we're experts
or whatever and
if we know this then you know the next
series languages that were inventing
want know how to do that better you know
we can talk about unit testing whether
or not it's useful
I'm python is a good for beginners
that's an interesting question
if python is actually better for
beginners we should
teach I don't beginners it and
this notion that happy for hours make
better programmers I'm
like these are old if we knew that these
were true we would act differently I
think
we're talking about could review
weekends a lot of things like this like
a lot of people recommend that you keep
your paddle slow
on some people think that could reviews
was nitpicking
when we look at code review in the wild
and see whether or not this in the true
see how big patches usually are
to phenomenally were talking about it
facts that have no foundation
the race on intuition and based on
rationalizing what we feel
and there is value in that
people who do science really get this
right when they make claims
they need evidence to make those claims
and
if their claim that they're just kinda
taking for granted when they're doing
the research maybe somebody else is
already
convince them that something is true
then their citations to that
they tell you where you can also be
convinced that these things are true
but works pretty well can we do that in
our communities can we do that for
software engineering
we do benchmarks to test performance we
usability tests are you eyes
we use analytics on our websites
so when we turn these in
this kinda inquiry on our souls
I think will be happier and better
programmers that we did those
the person you got me interested in this
topic was Greg Wilson gave a great talk
to other student conference
and 2010 called what we actually know
what software development and
why we believe it
thanks um we talked about it he talked
about it
and through cutting-edge suffering
research
um through what academics who research
software developers know about house of
parliament works
you put together a book called making
software where every chapters
written by researchers who you do this
nasa's or are doing a survey of existing
else's
covers topics like officers you know
should you keep arm
each should you have private offices for
developers should you have a complaint
I'll
open-plan offices and what kinda
situations
are these useful
0 is per pair programming useful me the
more more useful question is in what
situations is a useful
and is a cost-effective to have to
developers working on the same thing
the talk about modern could review and
how it actually works
and really interesting chapters on
failure prediction using
organizer organizational structure the
developers working on the code
so what that showed was that on
the a the number above that would be
caused by a file had more to do with the
communication structure of the people
working on the
on that code then things like
test coverage or I'm complexity metrics
were
any of the things that we talk about so
often it was how the developed with the
social structure
that's out on top in the technical
structure that was more important
great also added a blog called The it
will never again to your blog
where the summer as researchers the
COMESA in
you know in words that aren't completely
eliminating two people actually write
code
it's a it's a great blog you should
check it out
min ago for some interesting papers that
I think our chemical on teachers
in things we don't know about software
or maybe we thought we knew but
we outline a performer so
here's an example what can we learn
about could review I just mention that
people like to savings because review
and
might not actually have any evidence for
it
security who was my supervisor last
summer and Chris Chambers who
as with a Microsoft Research published a
paper called converge in contemporary
software purity packed practices live
very basic statistics on
a couple large open source products and
some closers products including being in
SQL Server and circum- comparing the
weather could really work on these
products
as you might think that open source
projects were differently than so being
or something like that
this is assertive violin parts
looking at pipe sizes on its products so
the sizeof the patch they get similar to
a code review system
and their pretty similar across all
these products
the very between 45 and 150
certainly if you're working on these
projects you want to keep your such a
small
and it's interesting that on all these
particular converging on this practice
it might mean that it's a good thing my
part but
it it's certainly something that we
didn't know before
this is some learn it looks heard on how
long it takes for the first reviewer to
take a look at the pageant where you at
and
they're pretty similar across the board
%uh this is the number view
reviewers at each patch gets so the
notion that many eyeballs
make all the shallow I don't know if
that's true but
it seems like to eyeball are sorry for
eyeballs
seem to work in most cases or at least
if you are more eyeballs the stop early
being effective
a some researchers from Waterloo a
handle and friends
in 2006 they did what i think is really
cool here they they took sort of
contribution data on some answers for
the concluding once you all
and they did offer a transformer these
events
and if you do that and you plus
spectrogram other you can troops you the
you can detect periodicity in the data
you can
duties owed some structure Adam what you
think is the
disorganized open source product so with
open source it's often not
there is structured it's just hidden and
sort of explicit as it would be a
and closers I get agreements hard
writing papers they're reading papers
and fun let's write some code instead
so in September I to on a Friday night
when I am I think
I made this a I dunno book using a toy
to a bill called get touches on to
pollute
could committed a from A+ from the I
don't project
his pen is to analyze this data and I
had one question which was you know how
long does it usually take to review a
posh
on I Python you know the result is this
plot
you can see that they're usually pretty
fast
and this was like really simple it took
me in an hour
um and you lose a lot of fun we don't
really know that much about it
how I played on polar bus work now to be
clear this is not mind-blowing research
but we know something we didn't before
and
put this on the internet and cable some
very generously call this the future
software engineering I'm flattered um
Fernando Perez poster as well and you
can see that
you know it's on you know in the
thousands agree to it but %um people
people read it and they acknowledge that
it existed
0 which I thought was pretty cool cuz
they just gonna do this on a Friday
night
I was looking at those with a friend and
talking about this weird Mathai
but it done wrong and we look at the
code and
you know he pointed out the problem in a
fix that and so now that this lake
pseudo paper that I have online as it's
been
it it's had a book expert to apply to it
some report my repository and then ran
it on their own product and another the
rent on their own project because
I got this bug report the tool that I
wrote to
purse get logs was choking on
this person's product which was simply
the the symbolic
math library for Python minute and it
was breaking because somebody who
contributes a semi has an accent in
their name
so I picked up on and then I was
interviewing for a job recently
and on the ass for a simple no book
showing like how I do details
something that's and they said oh this
is pretty cool
and why don't you try doing the nozzles
like this
the user model called lifelines to plot
on the kaplan-meier curve which
should've
is much better way of looking at how
long it takes for the things to get
merged
so this little experiment I did people
rather
the reproduced a they fixed it improved
on it
that sounds a lot like science
so that was fun a couple months later
the
International Conference on software
engineering a few people publish a paper
on something very similar they look to
purpose over
hundreds love reproduction I get home
and they found the some other things
they they could find on that you a
personable herb butter merge within
three days
3 percent emerge within an hour and Sony
personable purple our bus
were merged you know this is for that
sucks a
Ruby product at the that they were
working on
this is me and they also bill the
decision tree based on
through what factors actually affect
what patches get merged
they found that the most significant
doctor was how active the area affected
by the patch
has been recently so if you are trying
to get a patch into the system that is
being modified a lot by other people
right now you can have a hard time
the size of the product was an important
factor and the number files changed by
the polar ice was also important so if
you're making a blurb us you should
probably try to
on place few files as possible on this
is something that people a
sale I like this is useful place that we
already know if
we write software but now we actually
know it
so here's another interesting question a
lot of issues get
and you know how do people Andrew
individuals use get differently
my friend Julie able to stool that you
can arm you you
taper one-liner bash thing into your
terminal
and up up with the results to reserve
your
and will generate you were directed
graph like this
shows what commands you use her
frequently and
on what command you most are most likely
to use after you
do that come in so after eight commit
I most likely to push that whether rosa
fat
we can look at julie is graph
we can talk about why it looks different
than mine if
arm it my friend Greg really doesn't
like get
I can look at his draft look at my craft
and see what's different about his
maybe I can suggest something that he
should look into
and maybe this will make him happier get
user who knows maybe lost cause
muzzle other taking this very seriously
there on tronic likes to read our data
from all over the organization
and the 10 answer questions like and
why do people give Missoula why do they
lose contributors
if we know why people are leaving the
product we can
key people happier thing this is
something that we should strive for
think
so here's an interesting project idea I
think people have looked into this
before but
I'm it could be fun to get started
this committee has been pretty famous
recently
this is the commit that added that her
plea but to open as a sole
and I don't know if you can read the
date on the back but it's
December 31st and I'm not sure where
this person is by it looks like it was
pretty late in the evening
a New Years Eve
can we look at the project so we work on
look at arm look at all the bugs
see when they were committed and can we
learn something about
you know when bugs are most likely to be
committed
if we know something about this week and
maybe stop committing stuff
after 4 p.m. when retired
and there's a really interesting talk by
Michael fathers on answer on this topic
is on a lot of course talks like this
and you can do things like Paul um
through architectural elements additive
software just by looking at what files
are committed together
and i think is look at this issue as
well
so we have all this data and we're doing
science on a
we learn things the software development
and I think we can also build tools
using Stata
the I I built this model call get to
Jason which alters analyze the data
but if you have that tool then you can
build something like it coach which
a Mike Williams a little it looks at
what files you commit together
and before you commit you say get coach
and it
tells you oh you've modified upset about
high file
maybe also want to modify your history
File
because they look like you're but make a
release
we could build something like Pearland
so when you make up a request for
project looks at how big it is
it looks a I'm how many files in touch
how poorly written the description is
something like that and we can
give scientifically valid suggestions on
how to
make better pitches this would save
reviewers time and would serve others
time
so what I want you to do as I want you
to go out there
study the software that you pray
teachers friends something cool that you
learned about house offered a woman
works
back up with evidence share what you
learned with others
upload I paper notebooks tell people
that you're doing this
build on the work that other people are
doing bill tools to make this easier
would would really like
is if in Pike honor 2015 which is going
to be here next year
on something as audience to give a talk
on what they learn from software
I want you to go do this and give a talk
on us next year and I'll come
and I be really excited about that so
thanks
maybe so much I'm super fired up by this
I we have
a time for questions there's only one
mike is over here's a pic please cue up
over here
hi I have mean a question as much is a
statement but the purulent
ideas a really good one and I have a
project that I've been working on Kyle
called inverter that will that does PR
went
and and it does it more on a source code
basis rather than
as a run things like happy and this
kinda
static analysis tools against report was
made comments as appropriate
and an I would love to talk in or maybe
it and some sort of open space
on this topic totally done on I'm gonna
put some notes on
at this URL and if you send me emails
because stuff they are working on
I will post to my blog I will tweet
about it and and yeah if you think this
stuff is cool
we should be friends because they don't
think there are that many of us
hi thanks for an interesting talk I've
been reading
code complete and through the course of
a couple views and its
and really interesting to see just how
many studies there are about
software practices when so often we hear
is just
conjecture and but
I'm just wonderin United
I think this is the kind of thing where
it's been a self-fulfilling prophecy
some other time
and added the you know
the culture is a determines how people
go about things so we tell each other
you know shorter pull requests a better
I
therefore there are more smaller pull
requests
therefore if you stay that you find that
there are more small upon request so
it's not common organic
thing where that come bro and especially
the
with Python for example the the design
and the language
a favors certain things and that make it
you know harder to you go about things
in a different way so you gonna see
you know more the thing that the
language favors if that makes sense
so I'm just curious about how you think
that interacts with like
and studying these kinds of things
so one thing that's interesting but this
is you know research setting and change
in with every threat software Berken
changing that thing that we're studying
in space idea and that's them
usually not a good thing for
the issue a vote on like why we merge
pull request and why we don't
as a good question really be we probably
merge
trip older post because we keep telling
each other that we prefer
we merge for poor person on us early
because
their actual users review
Vera we got a letter
another question I I find this is really
fascinating and it is an anecdote
someone other contributors to twisted
and twisted his front with for a long
time we really struggled with
on having enough review bandwidth to get
through I love the
and contributions that people are making
and deserve an informal observation that
a way that we tried to incentivize
people to
you heavy informally observed as we try
to incentivize people to do reviews by
creating this
and little a bit high scores list and
you get points for various kinda
contributions in particular reviews
and it's surprising how and motivated
p at least I A B come to if I have an
opportunity to get
to the top of the leaderboard as this is
actually really effective it was the
community if you think it might
work for year your community as well and
is also reminds me i think im
that the sea Python keep damn near
corner elders are also me actually right
now there's a thread on Python dad about
and struggling with not having enough
for you can with I bet that if we had
data on where in that to Bible life
cycle
things stalled and if we actually could
look at how bad the numbers are
that would really kick ass in a biit
about addressing
and those weakest link so I think a
project that I O
wanna pursue an hour I'll do a poster on
to next year's you can come and look at
it is
and pulling out on this data for core
price on and on
given the number is trying to make those
numbers better
so they can go
hello i think is a really important
questions that year
exploring arm I've also been doing a
report on 'em have new emerging open
source project to try to
understand you know how the dynamics of
the community are working
%um both looking at get have data as
well as looking at
I'm in a mailing list data on and I was
talking with
a friend some who's doing is master's
thesis at UC berkeley
telling about is the questions that I
wanted to answer and he said oh I'm
I'm working on it I'm building a tool
right now that can in a purse through
mailing list
archives and figure out all kinds us
%um things about how people make
decisions on who the influencers are in
a community in
and so weird you know where is the code
is a go it's not ready yet
in you know it it occurred to me that is
probably a lot I really really really
amazing research has been done in
academia
and that researchers not really getting
out to the community in
me sir touched on this in your talk with
him QCB have any
thoughts about how that could be
shared with the wider open source
community so that we years
practitioners can actually use that data
to
become better what we do
this is an interesting topic for sure II
did research in a lab last summer
and a you know the sort of code that
I'm gets written in that environment is
home operate generously billy gets
it's not think
very stable taught maintained um
nobody's
checking to see if it actually works
I'm but I think click in this community
we cabal you the things more
and I think the more tools that we build
do the stuff rate
more assertive immature and also that we
do pictures to see if we can kinda
you trick people into kiddie into using
our tools and
gonna doing this stuff better by to
gonna be in by example
showing them how we want it to be done
and then have them actually do the hard
work
that make sense maybe some I place my
notebooks with best practices for Howard
how to do this analysis
yeah go thanks
thanks hi arm
yeah I like science I like programming
and
I like the intersection others arm and I
agree that your collections great
Mike asking are versus Oregon
applies scientific thinking to the top
so excited about
and learn new things from them given how
little research there
is on seventh making more of that
%ah scenes really important but the same
time like
there are some bindings within academia
that answer at least
a few for questions or at least give
hints at the retraction
but those findings don't seem to get
disseminated
and so we have myths about programming
they've been debunked for decades but
still get you know show up for the
Chilean like agnew's threads
so it's like it's like we need a
programming snoops dot com
a for like debunking things that are
just like
known to be false or like known to have
no evidence
her for them and so it's like
I kinda ring wondering like how
committee via
evangelicalism happen how like what
resource
could we use to make awareness up the P
result we do have
a more prevalent so it touched on this
earlier with
comes on the work to Gregs been doing
you know the total number into your blog
making software 'em I think
encouraging programmers who are curious
to
read papers is great doesn't work
a.m. the you implicit
approach in taking as the I think
that stuff is light user to engage with
and
you probably understand it better if you
try to do some other yourself like the
best way to understand the study is to
try to reproduce that
so I can I want to get people in this
community doing some innocent souls
and so that you know the star asking
these questions and and
and they can go and look up a paper that
already answer their question
occurs related so you know week we we
like it when other people have answered
questions for us already
was also a really good book called some
facts and policies a
saw for ensuring both rubber glass which
serve is a bit like snow to come to that
exhibit all but on it does go over lakes
through commonly
a.m. repeated myths
did answer your question on the shitter
ago
a so is it it was fascinating the candy
collected
what you've looked at is basically
meta-data
about changes and software you put it
you know what the numbers a files paldon
committed in
maybe the number of lines have you
considered
already know anybody who has looked at
sort of the actual data
there's a commit it has you know a
particular deaf but that def
is about certain sort of code constructs
and it either
you know get review quickly a dozen
targets approved or it doesn't get
approved or gets reverted or it doesn't
based on you know something about the
structure the code
itself that goes into their comment
and Anderson question sir am you know
like
now I driving example but I am you know
is a
revision to a method within a class more
likely
more or less likely to be accepted then
a revision to function by itself
or you know I remove the variable is
that more or less likely to be accepted
than a
change about math formula or something
user these are just questions so
I i don't have a good answer to lick the
specific thing that you're saying
but one thing the I'm some people have
looked at is
unlike some people been doing code
complexity measures and slightly curly Q
you probably heard mccabe complexity and
stuff like that for measuring like how
complex
PC softwares and some people looked at
inside looking at I'm you know the code
as a static Pisa
solid object it through appreciates that
arms of urs in motion
so looking at home with the culture meh
tricks like how much a file has been
changed like how much activity
gets and his son to the
like they tend to predict bugs more so
like this tells us that the software
being moderately modification is more
dangerous than
like reading her in the first place
yeah it is there's always however
questions you need to do some open
spaces later D closing ceremonies are in
10 minutes in the keynote
space thank you again 10 ish