over one
up review hearing from Michael Backes
topics real-time predictive analytics
using cyclic
learn and rabbit
thanks everybody so
a thanks for coming out my name is
Michael Becker
I work for their data analysis
management is at a waiver
a Weber is any now a service provider
located just outside of
Philadelphia with over a hundred twenty
thousand customers
if you've never heard of a Weber before
that's cool
on we're the company with the MP booth
downstairs
so anybody else from the
Philadelphia area okay so
I'm also the founder the day to Philly
meet up
with over 600 members if you're not
already a member well
shame on you so
you can find me on Twitter i'ma at
Becker 44
my blog is back for 4-4 dot com and
I'll probably post a blog post on my
website
with of follow-up material oh and a
also you can find the slides and other
material
on I get home so working
on the damn team at a Weber I've
introduced
several predictive algorithms into our
application my coworkers
think that I'm some sort of math
superhero reading scholarly papers by
day and fighting crime by night
the truth is much more sinister
fortunately for me
I don't have to be a math genius to look
like a superhero
I just have to use I can learn I am so
while cover some madness talk are mainly
became things high-level
and this is because I'm not a math
genius I'm
the developers this I can learn our math
geniuses and
if I get in the math wrong feel free to
call me out on the Internet so
this talk will cover a lot of the
logistics behind utilizing a train sigh
can learn model in a real-life
production environment
I'll start off by giving a brief
overview of supervised learning
machine learning and text processing
with psych it learn I'll
cover how to distribute your model I'll
discuss
how to get new data tear model for
prediction I'll introduce rabbit MQ
and why you should care: %uh demonstrate
how we can put all this together
together into a finished product
are discussed how to scale your model
and finally %ah cover some additional
things to consider
when using so I can learn models in a
real time production environment so
the demo in this talk I I we I'm gonna
demonstrate a supervised learning
algorithm so let's start off by defining
what the training process looks like for
surprise model so
you start off with some input that may
or may not be numerical
for example you might have tax documents
as input
you also have labels for each piece of
training data
you back to rise your
your training data which means
converting it to an america form
then you train your machine learning
algorithm using
your vector ice training data and the
labels as input
so this is all often referred to as
fitting your model
and at this point you have a model that
can take
a new piece of unlabeled a big data and
predict the label
so again you need a victory at the back
to rise your new
data point then you input into your
train algorithm
and you're our them spit out
a predicted label for this new data
point there's all types a machine
learning algorithms but today I'll be
concentrating mainly on supervised
learning
so in this talk
I'm going to demonstrate when the first
models I ever created
and it's a model that predicts buying
which for input.text
up input tax and at the time
I needed a way to identify the language
of content created by our customers
so to create this model I used 38 at the
top Wikipedia is based on
the number of articles and I don't
several the most popular articles from
each of these Wikipedia's
so going back to my diagram from before
the first thing we need to do is back to
rise the text
so to start of I converted the wiki
markup the plaintext
and I had read about this approach
online that
worked well for language classification
on basically involves counting all the
combinations
out n character sequences in a dataset
an
bizarre commonly called n-grams and
n-grams
are lot easier to understand if you
visualize them salami
show you an example so
to generate this work loud I downloaded
up HG Wells books from Project Gutenberg
and here's what were the world looks
like if we visualize the brawl bird
counts for each word
and you can accomplish this with one
line a psychic learn
so the size of the word is based on the
number of times award shows up in a
in the book one thing you'll notice
looking at the
text is that the word martians
occurs about as frequently as the word
words people and time
and this is counter-intuitive you think
that Martians are much more important to
world the world stand these other words
so fortunately there's another hour then
call TF RDF which
that can help solve this problem Scotti
FIDs
stands for term frequency inverse
document frequency
and it reflects how important a word is
to a specific document in a collection
of documents
so the TF idea value increases based on
the number of times an n-gram appears
in a specific document but this is
offset
by the frequency of the n-gram in the
rest at the documents
so in this example a document is one of
the six
HG Wells books that I downloaded
and what you'll notice here is the board
martians is comparatively bigger
because it was rated higher than more
commonly words again like people in time
and this is because martians are
important too
the book world the world and
however RTF here idea does have some
trade-offs
on very large corpus is a text it may
it might not be computationally
practical arm but for my particular
classifier I ended up using TF I DF
because increase the accuracy of my
model by about 1 percent
and every percentage counts
so let's see how to put this all
together with a simple classifier
I we call this typing out about where
the classifier because you provide some
input tax and classifies it as one of
multiple classes
so in the case of my over them you
provide some taxes import
and it will classify the tech at the
language overtaxed
and to start of I define a pipeline
combining
RTF I T PF idea vector riser
with a SBC classifier
so a pipeline is utility use to build a
composite classifier
that TD DFID F back to rise are converts
the week EP articles to mir
numerical form the back toward the first
counts the number of occurrences
each and Grammy each document to back to
raise the tax it then applies
the TF idea algorithm and then
the pipeline understands how to connect
the output affect a riser to the input
at the classifier
soul that's what to do is to fit our
data to our model
arm which is the last line and let's
take a closer look
at X train in white rain
so X train is the portion of my data but
I set aside for training
generally speaking you don't wanna
training algorithm using your full data
set because many our times can suffer
from an issue called overfitting
overfitting is when a model is very good
at making predictions about your
training set
by when presented with new data it
performs poorly
psych it learn has tools but I built in
to help avoid overfitting
I I'm not gonna go into much detail
during my talk but
there's plenty of details in the psych
at one doc such act those for more
details
on X train is an array have taxed from
the Wikipedia articles besides stripping
out the wiki markup I don't do anything
else to promote
to prepare the data on the back to riser
handles converting the tax
to the numerical form required by the
SPCA algorithm
okay so why train is the labels for our
training set
so in this code here why is a
one-dimensional array
in this case it contains the language a
beach article
unlike X train I do not I do need to
convert these two numerical form prior
to passing them to the fit method
so for each Wikipedia so to do that I
can you can use the word and the
labeling coder
and but that does is assigned numerical
value to each of your
in parts and for each Wikipedia page
in X train there is a corresponding
labeling why train
so one trick I often use
when dealing with TextEdit which speeds
up the training process
and lowers memory consumption is to use
a technique called
dimensionality reduction so
dimensionality reduction
is the task deriving a set up new
abstract features
that is smaller than the original
feature set while retaining most of the
parents
variants of the original data one such
algorithm
for doing this since I can learn is
randomized PCA
so PCA which stands for principal
component analysis
allows you to really express a set of
data points
in terms of basic components that
explain the most variance in the data
so in this case with specify that the
number
new feature should be fifty its either
at PCA to my classifier
I just have the added to the pipeline so
let's break down the pipe lines that we
can see what's really going on under the
hood
so if we just run the vectorized by
itself it produces a dataset with over
one million features
up because this is text data the data
set is sparse
this is because each column in our
dataset represents
an n-gram that was seen in at least one
a the documents
an for any given document most these
n-grams
will have accountants 0 so let's see
what happens when we run PC and the
dataset
okay so now we've decrease the number of
features from
over a million to 50 but how can we be
certain this will negatively impact the
accuracy of her final classifier
the PCA algorithm has a primer called
explained variance ratio that cokie
that calculate during the filling
process
you can see are you can use this to see
if you picked a good value for and
components
we can see by adding all these values
together that we retain almost all be
there
variants from the original dataset all
while significantly decreasing the size
of the input to our classifier
so this is really awesome but one last
thing
don't use randomized PCA on sparse
matrices
such as those output by TF ID affect a
riser
so there's another hour them called
truncated SBD
which was designed to work efficiently
on sparse matrices
ansa support for them will be dropped
from randomized PCA
in a future release a psych and Burn so
I use randomized PCA here because
truncated SPD doesn't currently
calculate the explained variance ratio
but I'll pick probably be added in a
future release
so one last tip before I move on psychic
learn
comes with a ton about rhythms build-in
and many of them have multiple
parameters you can tweak
it can be daunting to figure out which
are written to use
and what values to pick for the printers
Walkley
there a lot of tools built in the psych
you learn to help you to your models
that you
get a the best performance out a bit I
recommend randomized searched
CB you give it some random you get ready
my search arrange a values
to try for each parameter and then it
randomly chooses some other values and
test them
what the search is completely you can
get the highest scoring classifier
along with its core and parameters and
you can easily run this kind of search a
multiple algorithms
figure out which one will perform best
for your particular dataset
alright so now that you have this
awesome model
now what one of the first promise you'll
want to solve is how to distribute your
model
the recommended method for disturbing
your motto is to use the built-in pickle
module
to serialize the model at to disk and to
distribute as part
at as your part of the application so
you can store it in a database such as
great a faster Amazon s3
in the case of my model it took up
roughly 200 megabyte memory
is a pretty big but its is at least
orrible on and on desk and more
importantly
in memory so one caveat to this approach
is
if you upgrade cycle earn your pickle
model is not guaranteed to work
so it's very important that you keep
detailed records
other training set and your models
training prior manners
if you want to be able to upgrade cycle
earning the future
so take care when up getting psychic
morning production to make sure you're
not going to break your application
right next to discuss how we're going to
get data into our model
so you did it could be coming from many
types of sources
a web front and a database trigger in
many cases you can
easily control the rate up incoming data
and you don't want to hold up the front
and/or the database while you wait for
protection to be made
in these cases its use will be able to
process your data is synchronously
so in the example given today we created
a simple web front-end
someone to Google Translate where a user
can enter some text to be classified
and get a classification back we don't
wanna hold up a threat or process in the
client waiting on our class prior to do
its thing
so rather the front and sends input to
read REST API
which will record the text input and
return a tracking ID
that the client can then use to get the
result there are several other ways we
could
design this but for our particular
application this design works fine
so decoupling the UI from the back and
in this way solves one design issue
however another thing to consider is
whether you can afford
to lose messages if all of your data
needs to be processed you have two
options you can either
build in a retry mechanism on your front
and
or you need a persistent herbal cue to
hold your messages in the back n
so anti-rabbit MQ one of the many
features provided by robin MQ is highly
available cues
by using rabbit MQ you can ensure that
every message is process without needing
to implement a fancy
and likely error-prone retry message
mechanism in your front and
surrounding cue uses aim QP which stands
for advance message queuing protocol
for all client communications using MPP
allows clients running
on different platforms are written in
different languages to easily send
messages to
each other from a high-level MPP enables
clients to publish messages and allows
other clients to consume those messages
it does all this without requiring it to
roll your own protocol or library
for anyone who's new to MPP I would
recommend you check out the peak a
library
which has some pretty awesome
documentation
I rabbit all thank you also has some
pretty awesome resources on its site for
beginners
and their blog is also a really
excellent resource
finally for anyone whose interest in
learning more about the nitty-gritty
details that using rabbit MQ in a
production environment
my coworker up Gavin Android who is the
maintainer
speaker has an excellent book coming out
called braddock you in-depth
and Gavin if you're in the audience I am
happy to accept the commission check
finally if you don't like robin MQ this
kind of solution should work pretty if
work fine with pretty much
any other message queuing or any other
message queuing system
so use whichever one you are familiar
with
so what you have p.m. the your data
input source into your message queuing
system
and you start publishing data all you
need to do is put your model in a
persistent worker and start consuming
input
in the case of my language
classification model we met implemented
a simple consumer
so firstly on pickles the classifier and
subscribes to an input queue
it then runs an event loop and the event
where polls new messages as BB
as they become available and passes them
to the to process a bet
process event calls predict on our model
and converts the numerical prediction
to a human readable format this
prediction is then stored in our
database in this case
among a DB and for
for the front end to retrieve so that's
basically it
our design a little something like this:
the input comes from the UI where the
user enters syntax they wish to
classifying
the UI hits a flask rest baby I be a GET
request
the API stores the request in the
database
papi then sent a message to rabbit MQ
with the text to classify and the
tracking ID for storing the resulting
classification
the API returns a Jason response the UI
with the tracking ID
the consumer polls the message of the
queue in rabbit MQ
the consumer 'cause predict on the
classifier with the taxes import
the classifier returns a prediction and
then the consumer
stores that prediction in the database
finally Puri displays the result
so there isn't really one right way to
design a solution like this
for example you could in Singapore
having the UI Paul the API
you could utilize something like
WebSockets alright so let's see what
this looks like an action
so I'm not I wanna start off by saying
I'm not a linguist
so by I've read that Danish
Norwegian Swedish and Dutch you similar
character sets so
I'm any use them for my demo
alright so this is what are front and
looks like what's just test it out to
make sure everything's working
can everyone really in the back
how's that
up we can see the result about that
at alright what they would have to do
so let's let's test this out real quick
for a day
alright slickly something a little more
interesting
so
I
so I as i said i have some data in
a few different languages here I let's
start off with Danish so
i won't. get some a information
from in these different for different
languages but I wanted them to be about
the same topic so what I did was I found
news articles
about the heart be I hardly open SSL Bok
Bok
in each of these four languages so let's
let's see how are often handles this
so
this one according to Google is Danish
and it
we also think its Danish sorry for the
advertisements
I this one
is Swedish we also think its Swedish
this one is Norwegian we also think its
Norwegian
and
finally Dutch its Dutch
alright
so
beside the basic design concerns I've
already covered there are a few
more things worth mentioning the worst
thing that can happen when you're
processing data is synchronously
is for your Q-tip cue to back up so
backups will result in longer processing
times and
if up there on bounded you could crash
rabbit MQ
so the easiest way to scale your
consumers is the start another instance
using the strategy processing should
scale roughly linearly
in my experience you can easily handle
thousands of messages a second this way
also if you want to prevent backups
consider using
of rabbit MQ feature called TTL cues 22
detect and prevent backups another way
to scale your consumer
is to convert it to processing request
in batches
many of the algorithm since I can't
learn scale
super linearly when you pass multiple
samples to their predict method
so the downside of this is that you will
no longer be able to process results in
real time
however if you're restricted on
resources and this trade-off
is acceptable for your particular
application this might be a worthwhile
alternative
I keep an eye on your Q's
the their site the queue sizes and alert
when
they back up so scale your consumers
as needed possibly automatically you
could use something like a.w.s or skill
for that
on you can also monitor other things
such as how many consumers are connected
to your queue
your message ingress and out press rates
and other things
so understand your load requirements
blood test end to end to verify that you
can handle
the expected vote for your application
so
a predictive our them is a lot like a
piano if not in tune its gonna suck
so how do you make sure your predictive
algorithm is performing well with new
data
one solution is to periodically review
our fire
algorithm using new data I depending on
your use case
this might not be easy to accomplish so
in the case in my language classifier
how would we collect
new label data maybe we can add a button
that allows users to report problems I'm
then we could go through some of these
results and label them manually and then
return the hour them against them
another technique
um which I I'm sorry by but your name a
which I learned from Libya gravel is to
train
a new classifier to predict new verses
all data
so bennett the accuracy of this
classifiers hi maybe above fifty years
55 or 60 percent at the distribution
a few new data has drifted from your
training set so this means it's probably
time to retrain your classifier with new
data
in this scenario you'd still need to
label your new data
before you could retrain your armor them
so no matter how
you handle to near our them make sure
that you first control your classifier
and keep detailed change logs and
performance metrics
I on your on your on your changes
alright
so I'd like to thank Kelly O'Brien and
Matt park for helping me with the back
end and the front and respectively for
my demo
and
thanks again for coming out my talk
here's my information if you'd like to
get a hold of me I
I'm Mike at Becker purple dot com if
you'd like to email me
thank thank you may give any questions
for most good online right here
I just was curious about how
will text you could put in eyes just
copy/paste
things dual-key repair so arm so
some something to keep in mind as I
didn't that tune my over them to
work with small amount attacks because I
the training set was from Wikipedia
which are
and they were like the top articles in
these Wikipedia so they're generally
larger
arm I I haven't writing it for small
text but I can say from experience that
doesn't work great
on small input so for example when I've
tested out the very beginning
I gave his input hello world my was
getting ready for the presentation I
actually typed
hello world with a capital W and I
thought it was Malaysian
so thank you very much for your car can
impressive library and Mike Russian news
lol to me and bass these library support
any distributed
cheney because his pre he critical
to Chambery lives date
I so a lot of the algorithm supports
a setting a primer called and jobs which
will scale across CPU's I'm not
certain about us scaling across machines
arm by yeah I would definitely at
II by the way I'm I'm not gonna the
contributors to to psych it learned
by a I would definitely recommend like
asking a question on the secular mailing
list
did you find
there anyway which is a group of
languages that were particular difficult
to distinguish
arm so the ones that I picked my demo I
picked specifically because they were
there's at least two in that group that
I chose on that use the same character
set
it actually really at not being a fling
with its really hard
to find languages that use the Stig Zack
same character set
so and if you try to look it up online
there's like all sorts of
at noise out there so I'm
I would say in general I tried to pick
the hardest
a example possible hi
you mentioned that the we use in the
model is through pickle you know if it
supports
others realizations I'm not sure
so prior to my talk I actually a asked
to Olivier
what's that is is pickle still the
recommended way over
serializing model and at he
he let me know that yes it is and he may
have gone into little more detail but
I'm
I'm forgetting right now arm so maybe
hype
you talked about the problem of over
fitting the model
amount hat worsen the problem was
classifying images and
pet project of mine do you have any
recommendations to
Lloyd arm so their is a
um there's a algorithm that's part if I
can learn called extremely random forest
and at least according to the the the
papers that I've read and keep in mind
I'm not an expert
I it the paper claim that
extremely random forest aren't not as
susceptible
to overfitting so I would recommend
checking checking that our them out
thanks ima questions
thanks for coming out thank you