well over the line thank you for
attending
I am I would like to present our next
speaker
who is Jeff skank who is going to be
talking about
straightening out angler JS with Python
be round of applause place
hello
thanks all for being here on I'm
really excited to be appearing from you
all on I'm going to be walking you
through
I really basic and
kind of starter implementation of what
you would do to take angular JS
and integrate it with a python back and
on
is going to be like I said fairly
simplistic
so if you've already done and your JS
on Python I could probably not learn
anything
and if you look at a person who never
wants to write a line of
a javascript and your life your also
probably in the wrong place
I'm cell I
aisles or warn you
just briefly I'm not a pro at this my
only experience is
having done in production for about a
year so we learn things the hard way and
this is kinda what I want to share with
you today
so at thirty seconds on angular and
what is this thing in case you don't
know I much about it yet
so it's a javascript Mb
star framework om it's a little bit like
any old MVC framework you now except
and a little different also I'm
it's it's basically for
you know if you got a lotta stuff going
on in the front end of your application
I you don't wanna hook it all up with J
cleary and
spaghetti code dealing with on that on
angular or
really any of the other front and
frameworks I amber and backbone
are gonna be your best friend there om I
like angular
I it's interesting I am it actually
as fired according to Google Trends
which as we all know is a very
reliable source India overtook backbone
are quite some time ago higher a year
and a half ago I believe
I'm which was surprising to me cuz I
always heard a backbone as Canada
granddaddy of them all
on so anyway what is angular
I its claim to fame what makes a really
special I think
is it extends the H&R Block have you
learnt us what that means is
you know you're writing HTML by
you get all these extra things the you
can play with and declared early write a
bunch of HTML stuff
that angular then I turns into this
beautiful functioning
ap om through the magic up to a data
binding
are so you know you change in value over
here and I automatically update original
the match
on this is all really cool I really fun
to see you
really good too play with I but we're
not gonna do that here because
is a spike on and if you wanna go to
JavaScript kono whatever they call their
thing
on you can do that on your own time
I'm like I said it's getting kinda
popular
I'm and I do highly recommended there
still some rough edges it's still a
fairly young
I have framework but its
it's really good at what it does on an
NBL fair's fair
so if you've never heard a python before
I am
it's pretty great um it also has a
number I love
MVC ish or MB star frameworks I am
and at least one of them is actually
pretty good
I am not here's tony fights but at work
we use Django
and so I love the examples I menus are
all from
Django I but the concept should be
fairly easily translated
comment if you want to yell at me about
came in flask at the end you're welcome
to do that
I'm yeah so the point is all these
things are kinda MB star frameworks
on angular Jaz on the front and and then
Django or pyramid of Lascaux whatever
you're doing on the back and
cell step by step what are we gonna do
first off we need to I have our Python
back and
serve up angular now for starters
and that's just a base HTML page no big
deal
its normal HTML like before
JavaScript even existed on
and usually all service on on the
the root URL depending on how you wanna
set it up but if painkillers going to be
you're kinda end all be all application
I'm you're actually gonna wanna set it
up so they're
all the URL's om all serve angular an
annular handles all of your routing
I'm so what does that look like on
this is a very basic angular ap about as
basic as you could possibly make one
and I made a little bit a hand waving
around angular again this is I con-
not not JS whatever on so there is some
cool stuff to be done
had to be talked about in angular world
and we're not gonna touch on
om but happy talk about after World Cup
on the inside
I'm so what are we doing here first of
I'm we're loading up angular right so
we've got that angular I library there
and then your application code which
again we're not really gonna go into
I'm you've got to tell angular way here
happy is with this Angie ap command
I instantiate a controller and then
here's the magic that we talked about
with the two-way data binding
arms you can see this looks more or less
just like a regular HTML
on but it's got some special attributes
and somewhere curly races and stuff
on so the energy model attributes is
what sets up that two-way data binding
on the double curly braces are
where you're putting that into your
template and so you know
the the really called mr. that you can
go see on a dealer's home pages
you type into the implant ants
automatically updates in
in that that paragraph to there and
it's magic and it's wonderful I'm
so then all that's left is nothing
really special or unique your you wired
up in your
URL patterns again as a jailer
Django bed you know you don't want to
have it serve essentially all URL's
and then allow that angular ap
to manage all the URL routing which it
does
kind of on its own
so what else do we need to serve up what
else do we need to lap
at template partials and this is what
angular does so that you don't have to
send
your entire monolithic crazy ap all down
to abhor browser all in one go
on it has what are called template
partials missus
and what it sounds like it's little
pieces a template the you can load into
and the angular ap as you're going from
page to page and it needs that but have
tempered
on but you need to serve these up now if
you can get away with it it's perfectly
fine to just serve those up as static
files
on that works well it's super easy and
there are going to be cases are least I
found cases
where you need sort of a two-phase and
rendering where you need Django or your
back-end server to render some things in
the template
om you know maybe a special I D you're a
token or
or something and then yuan angular to
get that damn plan
after its been rendered on the server
side are meant to do that is a little
bit more work
am so here's what we've got you need at
another URL
just byron up to serve more static I had
to render out some templates nothing
special
I'm and then the machinery to actually
render the template
I'm see you can construct a template
name for example
on do your special specialness make
whatever craziness you need to make in
your app
om and then render the output arm and
then you've got these template partial
that you can load up
everywhere in your anger lap
what else do we need to do I'm so we
need to
communicate with our server and this is
really the meet up what we're doing
right
on all the data changes all the data
that we're pulling into the app
on we need to communicate with the
back-end server om
and the best way to do this is a RESTful
API
on and it's a big enough deal that it
gets its own section
so step 2 I'm you're gonna build an
application API
on and i actually on like to think that
this as opposed to a developer API
I made these Terms up but they're useful
to me I'm an application API
is one where your application is the
primary user and developer API is one
where
you one other developers to build things
that Internet interact with your
code in with your data om obviously
you could have one API list serves both
of those functions that's totally
possible totally doable in some cases
probably a good idea I'm but there are
enough separate concerns that I like to
think about them separately
on and what we're talking about for our
purposes today is definitely the
application API
almonds will talk about some the special
considerations there
com the first of so we need to build a
clean
restful chase on API I'm
depending on your free market choice and
their loss a tool to help you do this
I in Django the jingle dress Primark is
pretty solid
om cornice and flask a restful there's
there's tools for whatever
and whatever your building om and mostly
they're pretty good
although and I think honestly
for and for application API's they could
use a little bit more
functionality there a little bit weak in
certain areas in
and I can talk about that and I
hopefully
we can contributes to new features back
to them at some point
arm and then on the JavaScript side II
you've got at all call rest angular
which also I feel I could use a little
work but
is still helpful and that helps you
integrate
with om a REST API on your back and
om and so let's take a look at this
if all you want is a simple clean API
this is all you have to do
I'm sea star by subclassing model you
set which is this thing in NJ no arrests
framework
and tell which model do and its
that's it on then you have to hook it up
into your URL routing
which is also fairly straightforward you
generate the routes for free with the
pew said
tell them which matter to get into and
looking up into your URL's om
and this works great in cases where all
you want to do
is the bare minimum simplest simplest
thing
I am and the world will be a beautiful
place if that was all you ever had to do
but unfortunately am there's other stuff
I'm so inevitably their issues were gone
and we're gonna head
where I kinda the standard clean RESTful
API
doesn't really cut it for our purposes
on
so let's talk about those what is it
sort of clean API
look like I'm
cell and first of we need to do some
authentication
I'm and it's not the easiest thing to do
right off the bat
I am mostly these
paid on back ends are very well
accustomed to doing cookie based
authentication
om you know it's what you would get on
the login page
I without a neurologist standard login
it's the server
gives you a cookie makes you logged in
you're good to go I'm and that's what I
ended up using
with angular I'm but they're also
benefits to
I switching up and going to a token
based authentication approach
numbers work on Jason Webb tokens om
which have some benefits over
I over the cookie based approach and
across domains if you want an AP I dot
your side dot com om and their
day and every better with mobile devices
there are some reasons why am I want to
do that
on 1 I'm gonna show you here is how to
integrate with
that the cookie based authentication
perch
so om please don't look at this
um its gross its terrible and it makes
me pretty sad
I'm and this is just one small
acceptable we did
I'm to get authentication working I'm so
lucky through its
I'm the first thing you do is AJG arrest
by mark
allows you to create these kinda custom
post and points
arms you're posting to this login thing
which is
I hung of the tale love your
real RESTful API comments already we've
broken the restful thing going on here
I'm and then what we do is we actually
authenticate
I by and by hand ourselves the user
log the man I'm and they were handling
all the responses are self
on definitely in urging arrest by Mark
provides some other machinery here
that's really nice
om you now serializing and that kinda
stuff
I but it's still kinda gross to have to
do this every time
I'm and again you know this is just for
login
cuz you also wants presumably a way for
users to sign up in the first place
and you also presumably want them to be
a lockout
am and don't even get me started about
the whole password reset flow its
messy and gross I'm
by if you want users you can I have to
go through this tough
I'm so NeXT's and
so you are permissions now to I
you know if you're going to have users
you're probably going to want them to
only see their stuff
as opposed to everyone's stuff on
and you know if with the traditional
methods
and just processing everything on the
back end this is fairly well understood
stuff
on you're probably used to doing it I'm
when you're accessing everything through
the API
I am it's not a totally open API there a
lot you
a lot of things you have to do is here
on
you now it's not just is not just
you know 1 person being able to see only
their things
it's a much more nuanced kinda ecosystem
up stuff than that right because
you guy some things that you want
everyone to just be able to see
ride like you know the tags that are
available on your website or
the stuff that shows up on your About Us
page you know whatever else you loading
in that everyone should have read access
to you but not write access
then there's row level permissions
there's the stuff that the user should
be able to see only if it's theirs
and then even beyond that the probably
supposed to be able to read their own
data
but you probably only I want them to be
able to write certain things
in that data and so this ecosystem so I
scare really really
complicated really fast i'm new show you
a little bit what we did
by honestly I think we need better
tooling around this
I like I said I think this is tied to
these and rest frame marks
being mostly built for the developer
version
on the API rather than application
version of the PI
I'm so I'd love to see a little bit
better tooling around these and if I
ever get to it
are happily work on that I'm so let's
take a look at what's
permissions looks like to see wireless
into
to the Django arrest by mark on a kinda
handles it this is what we did
you start off by subclassing their base
permissions
om and then we have this thing did
allows
you the keys to the kingdom if you are
an admin
I we've got this thing they if if he
said it up even a global
read and write permission and then if
you do this thing
you can have global repercussions only
om by again like I said this is only
half the story
because you also have to do
you know read verses write permission
you want them to bond to rate certain
things
arm and it turns out you you pretty much
have to do all of that by hand on p
you set definitions I'm so as a writing
a particular API endpoint om you need to
handle specifically
which people can access which things in
what ways
I'm sorts it ends up being quite that'll
work in that way and hard to keep clean
I'm yeah and then you want children to
which makes perfect sense of course you
do
I am so you want to be able to say
you know I want to see the users who
signed up in the last day
or I wanna see all these widgets that
were approved
on all these kind of filtering
mechanisms on those also don't come for
free
so you have to kind right those are self
I'm
how do we do that well so
you start by writing a filter set but
this other library called
chingo filters on the subclass the
filter said
I you creates the filter that you want
and this case we're doing less than or
equal to the created date:
I the name it was created relates the
underlying model which field on that
model do you want to filter by
and look up tape less than or equal to
and the input formats you specify
and then you tell it which model you're
talking about
I am and which fields you're allowed to
filter by
at this point you hook it up into your
view said
and it works but of course then you have
to do this again
if you want greater than or equal to
you have to do it again for every field
you wanna filter on
and the ISO virginity time filter
doesn't come for free either you have to
write that yourself
I'm so again I think there's a real
opportunity for better tooling around
this kinda stuff
om but at the moment it's it a little
bit amassed
you on sellers talk about a few
a outta left field kinda things that hit
me
is urs Sourav as signposts for you as
you go about implementing
I your angular JS I am back and on
firsts and it was this
when I'm calling mm TV star star which
is not a swear word
on this is I you know what happens when
your friend is in MB star saying and
your back and as an MP starting in you
want them to cooperate
show you know where do you actually put
your code how do you organize things
what's the right way to do this
I'm so there's some %uh the kinda rules
of thumb that I found to be useful
um first off you know irregular your
models on the back end
he set those up the nice and clean and
then you mirror them
in your front on and so the front and
knows what's going on the back and
accesses it is a PI and ideally
I you got some magic glue between them
that syncs everything up
and depending on your use case
I the controller this this is kind of
standard NBC
at labeling so controller and view code
I in my experience tennis just kind of
be all in the front
I'm so I love the in an angular
in all the controllers all the templates
they handle most of the work
I'm very little other stuff actually
ends up I
in the back end now
the last thing the kind of stays in the
back end or at least in our experience
did
was a lot to this background processing
stuff so sending emails
and you now doing a lot of background
processing
I'm doing can assume some big
computational stuff so there's data that
she's ready to ask for for the front and
on these are things that you know we
still do on the back end and there's
quite a bit of work going on there
you know I was I i get a lot of people
who say you know I know you got you got
angular so
he basically just have an API now right
om and sis
in some ways that's true and in some
ways there's still a whole lot going on
in the back and
I'm I wouldn't want it any other way cuz
I love writing Python
I'm see other still plenty of work being
done in Python it's just different work
I other fun stuff and interpolation this
was this was good
I'm so and the template interpolation
symbols those double curly raisers
I'm it seems everyone kinda wants to use
those
angular Django & gingerale by default
use these double curly braces I'm and so
if you want to do this double rendering
where
you know Django for example as rendering
the template sending it down angular
and an angular runs the template you can
see the problem
I'm but the good news is there's a
simple fix
I'm in angular you a dick and Fig
and this interpolates provider you can
choose our own start and symbols
I think the double square races on ice
ombres also came with their own problems
but that's another story
on and a couple other
and little things CSRF wiring
I can often get broken if you don't make
sure to kind of set it up correctly
om so you wanna make sure that that CSRF
token
I get sad on the on the client side if
you're only ever loading one full web
page on that first page load
if there are no forms their I often that
that
that token won't get set and then you
have access to it
I'm seem to make sure they get sent down
with that first page load
and then as you are i doing posts
through the API you need to iron
absolutes in the headers
I'm that was a there was a lot of fun
and then the last 11 then I ran into was
ac
API pagination I'm so
and when you're working on the back and
and you've got a bunch of data that
you're you're going through
and that's tends to just work fine I
but when you have an API yuan pagination
cuz you don't want to return all
three million records I but the flip
side a pagination is
its paginated and you need to deal with
that
I'm so if you have a page is expecting
more than 10 or more than a hundred on
this thing to come in
suddenly have to write all this coat
around pagination on
and it's not at least for me when it
first cropped up it was a non-obvious
sort of bug
om which was which was funded dealer who
gave you have no idea why those things
just work showing up any
on the page on
so step for enjoy angular project
on this you not like I said I think
there's
a lot of room for improvement on the
tooling
on it's still kinda the Wild West out
there alone on nearly as much as I was a
couple years ago
I'm and so angered you all the to try
this out
angered you all to contribute back your
good tooling improvements
om yeah that's about it
I'm I would i'm jeff has as I said I
should give a quick
and and shout out to choose as a paid
for me to be here
and if you get free lunches at work I'm
makin
we can do them better cell talk to us
I'm but thanks so much for letting me
talk at you and
now you can yell at me
thanks
yeah so is there any questions there
makes
there and their height
up devoted to point out that up here may
not have the permission stuff built in
for anyone else looking at this tho
if you want to I don't have a pair made
dad they have their problem solved at
least
onto the other when they don't bite that
wannabes awesome
thank you very much yes on yeah we we
actually
we'd kinda made this transition we were
we started with the Django app that had
nothing to do with I with angular
and it was sort of a slow transition
over to angular which is an interesting
story on itself but
I we did not have the at the luxury of
kinda examining all the options that are
out there
but that's good to know a
at so I recently developed a personal
Python where that and I didn't using
killer but I use knock out which is
kinda similar
on and so some other gotchas that you
described they
really rang true my experience um one of
the things you mentioned
the concept of having back and models
that are mirrored
with a friend JavaScript implementation
that was prolly when the biggest
struggles for me and I
I sorta Senate meeting at for
performance reasons did you find any
given your experience with that or any
tipster best practices for
skating as and synchronization how I'm
yeah God I not a lot
now it's a little bit painful it a
little bit case by case from what i've
seen
I'm so you know some other the models
that I'm dealing with
on it's fairly straightforward I
when you would need to sync that that
data backup to the server
om what I've wanted to do II
believe backbone actually has some
mechanisms for this
or so I've heard on by kinda doing dirty
tracking
on the fields in your angular side
representation on the model
on so that you then no what to send back
into Patrick West arm and ideally when
on by honestly now I have done a lot of
good solutions flat
if you come up with any should let me
know thanks sold my experience was a
little different
I was ready with flask instead of Django
and I wound up where was pretty much
just
an API from a nap by was their reason
you chose to
redefine the interpolation I characters
and said abusing gingers
raw tag %uh
be let me think so
gingers raw tag would allow you to just
kind of
not have ginger not process this portion
of the temple is that right
right on not particularly I didn't want
to have to
think or worry about it the riot act was
just a little bit more
effort every time you wanted to write it
there's no I think both are part
perfectly good solutions
is the reason why he chose his jiang
arrest three Maya content like tasty pie
did you evaluate several different API
packages in like itself could you expand
on that
yeah I'm I did do some research
up front I'm I don't have a whole lot of
experience directly using the others
on I'm sure other people here have
better answers than me on this
I waz I was jingle dress Primark was a
pretty robust set
a functionality I and I think that
proved out it really is
on the other ones some American have no
longer very well maintained and some
other time seemed
I top for a little bit less
functionality arms this one just seemed
the most robust
at the time we were making that choice
om I think the
the design patterns in generous for my
karma honestly a little bit strange to
me
on given kinda the way I know and love
Python arm it's very much have the mic
since
idea which I and others
a lot of and opinions there my name is
bed 810 see it really confusing really
quickly and
and at not being all that helpful so I
don't love the design patterns but
overall to pay robust re helpful
at all use it again CDs it again
hi yes I am back
question a so do you have any insights
into
I am in effective ways to test the
state's integrations when you're working
with
eitan Abson these JavaScript frameworks
on the front and
and canoe elaborate a little mark is
definitely you know
testing on the Python side which is you
know more or less what you
always done and then anglers fairly
robust its testing architecture so
eyes and integration point you're
talking about testing or or what's the
question exactly
I guess maybe in terms of functional
testing I mean read
have you guys done in at like anything
all the way through like so many amor
like any other approaches that you
recommend
here we have got to that stage yet but I
you know I think slams
a decent way to go there on you know you
can automate all in that kinda stuff
on and 8 you know
I think as long as you can unit test all
the things you doing
on the angular side a unit test all the
things you doing on the Python side
actually give you mostly a good idea
that everything's working and then
you know I'll always a few kind of light
integration testers is a good idea on
to what one more question
I think you and do you have any tips for
Buckeyes station
I'm sorry for what phone lookup
physician french-english
whatever language I E apologize I don't
I'm American
thank you