will welcome to the beginning of the end
who yeah I see that that that
they River our booth by we're all tired
I'm not saying you look tired I'm just
saying that I can tell because I know
you
so well and were almost near the end and
you hung in there
the stalk some lightning talks and we
will all
be done and Brandon Rhodes and I'm here
to announce that the day
at the EXT is upon us ald Monae mint
doctor vaughn I'm he threw us a real
curveball it used to be you knew your
computer we do you when you switched it
on
because before powering it up you %uh
disconnected and reconnected a bunch of
wires
not to set up what computation the
computer would do when you
turned on and it was on women that
catapulted us into the computing age by
suggesting that instead of having to
set the computer a perspex a specific
calculation
you could chanced I have a
general-purpose
machine he called it that read
instructions
rate out and memory just like computers
had already been reading
data this swept the world so that by the
time I grew up
and learned machine language on the
little arm
up color computers to that my dad behind
a hex 86 sitting in memory what is it
what does it mean what is that by going
to do
it depended it depended on whether you
told The
processor that it should run that as an
instruction that it is a command it
should obey
or whether you simply treated treated it
as
data but it looked exactly the same
either way
cell if I saw 8686 sitting in memory
it could mean the instruction low
devalue in to register a
and here's the number 134 x86 that you
were to load instruction
and data scattered together in memory
and you can't
tell difference I you can't
tell just by looking at it you can guess
but you don't know what's supposed to be
code not supposed to be data
someone called doctor by nine Men's idea
ambiguous
some people said that his ideas were
dangerous but
I prefer to look at it a bit differently
when I walk into the coffee shop in
amassed what programming language I'm
using and I'm like oh it's
it's really cool it's really really
harmful iconic
even I can't tell my dad after my code
sometimes
it's really bare metal
it's out really really low level
which is course is a complete lie did
you know that Intel
like a decade ago Intel got six
is sick x86 I machine language
and then refused to implement it anymore
they have engineers that right a
translator to translate it
into what they call micro ops which is a
cleaner machine language that they're
actually willing to implement on their
own processors
I tell them that if machine language is
just going to be a jetty interpreted
layer
they need to do better marketing and
just call it x86 dot che ask and I think
that it would sell
better some more chips and that everyone
would end leave it was really bare metal
given von no women's idea
that code and data would all be numbers
the idea
this interesting for cursive idea I was
invented a compiler
a piece of code that works hopefully and
that rapes
new pieces of code for you that
parole is it information over the fence
from being data to be in code now this
architecture poses a problem for a
language like
pipeline that initially one person was
writing by themselves
targeting processors with machine code
is a complex undertaking it's slow it's
difficult you need a lot of specialized
knowledge
papon just wants to run on every single
processor
without having added needing an intimate
knowledge in each of them
and sell without having to know
everything about every single processor
how can we solve this problem how did
kedo solve this problem
what turns out there's this guy named
David wheeler
he once said that all problems in
computer science
can be solved by another level of
indirection
and so like many languages before
incense the Sea pipeline an interpreter
the download from the website
uses bytecode Python compiles in by
to a pretend machine language its
bytecode
that runs inside a little pretend
processor that
implements so see people and does not
by my earlier definition do actual
compiling in
turns some data into some other data but
it never actually
throws it over the fence to being
something that the processor can be
exposed to
brawl and know what to do with it your P
wifi on is readiness text
see pipeline I purses compiles it
into bytecode which is another
data structure another piece of
information over there on the data side
of the house
it also saves it out in a dot people I
see file
if found in your dot profile you set
pipeline don't right bytecode
equals 1 it bought right to PIC file
I share that with you just in case
you've never had a problem
because PIC file was sitting around
cell the it that compiles the text if
your program to a code object which it
optionally squirrels away an appeal I
see file
when it's time for your code to run when
you call your function
see pipeline reads that data structure
to understand what your function is
suppose to accomplish but no point
does your Python script ever leave the
data structure side of the house
to actually become machine code here's a
simple little sum of squares
routine %uh byte code is very much like
an old RPN HP calculator
also like be on-board computer language
fourth
both use which is
the basis for both up a script in PDF
and
that little sum of squares comes out
like this if you import the disassembly
module
and asked by don t disassemble its byte
code for you
see their Hastings talk last year if you
want all of the details about the whole
stack based language in
see what's possible what Python does
this is it's the C code
is it has what it would do it we would
call a while true loop in pipeline you
say forcing me compensate me Colin
see I itself infinite loop that just
reads new opcodes
and then as a switch statement a big
else that
when it figures out which opcode the new
one matches
up runs in in the case have a multiply
that we just saw
it run something called plate number
multiply
remember multiply does not actually know
how to multiply anything
it goes asks the typeof initially the
left argument
do you know how it do you understand
this staying
multiply and if it's afloat as it was in
my example
dandy flow type says Yesi do have an
implementation and undermine all sitting
in my
at type structure it looks like this and
I'll bet you for gotten by this point
what we're trying to actually accomplish
but look week actually Malta plight
who numbers together at thanks to all a
back in direction
so let's go back through that again you
know just cuz it was so much fun
this time thinking of coding data and I
fitted into a single slide
that the infinite loop has two look at
the data stored in memory
in order to Paul the next byte code out
that helps it make a decision about what
operation needs to be done next
but it actually doesn't know what
something like multiply means integers
and floats and complex numbers
each implement that themselves so it has
to do a second
lookup in memory to ask the type
do you have a multiply and an ad a
divide operation
all of which brings up the question
python is slower than see
see by tonic the stairs is Python slow
because it's interpreted
or is pipe Onslow because it is
dynamic in terms of our diagram is it
the fact that Pike /url
papon is a loop running over by TKO that
slows us down the most
or is it the fact that papon doesn't
know how to multiply that's really
standing in the way of
ultimate efficiency well
what if we skip the interpretation step
produced no bytecode
and simply called multiply multiply and
add on our own
I tried that it turns out get a bag at
best about a 40 percent speed-up
which might sound impressive it means
that site to see pipeline incurs at
worst about
maybe thirty percent overhead from our
for your
the fact that it's %ah deferring to this
list
%uh byte codes to know what your
function does
but if we then take it all the way to
the
bare metal and skip allocating integer
ISO floating point objects that have
leaders to their type so that we know
what multiply means if we just %ah
do the multipliers and adds if in other
words we take
the second dereference there at the
bottom away
574 percent speed-up on my laptop
I earlier this week or last week that
means the pipeline can spend
after the reference effective in
treating the bytecode is done
and additionally 5 percent if it's time
simply dispatching
simply figuring out for the tight it's
looking at what multiplication means
the moral is that if you really want
Python to be fast
you've got to fix dynamic fixing
interpreted is just not bad
big away and are
how can you fix dynamic there are ways
that you can do it directly in C++
Python
X some of these approaches are explicit
when you you can ask for something to be
faster
and some of them are magic eyesight pipe
I as the
a great example were you don't get to
like a tell it which parts to accelerate
it just does it when it wants to and so
your code is often
much faster I number looks like this
you basket to just in time compile a
function that you've defined in you
Kelly
what you expect the types of the
arguments can be because only by
promising it floats in this case
do I exempted from having to go look up
information about the type of checks
see also if you're playing with little
microcontrollers and
playing with the microplate on project
it's not a full implementation a python
semantics
but it has the same idea encased in a
pair decorators
I he if you don't want to have to
decorate the functions that you want
fast and instead you want
magic to happen there were several all
projects have varying degrees of success
the current raining solution
very very powerful in this area is pipe
I and just last week
Dropbox announced that they want their
own pie pie
and so piston is now a going concern you
can find on the internet
so given the wonders at this ecosystem
we can compile things we need to in run
fast otherwise we run interpreted
why would you need an EXE file
a big reason this distribution I
especially if you're distributing to
customer computers
this is what it looks like native Lee if
you just want
a I Python application you have to have
the ER interpreter the Python files the
dll's or shared objects and then some
start
script to run when I double click the
icon that will start pipeline
pointed correctly at the application
pipeline
though the can also import pie and pea y
si files
automatically from a zip archive if one
happens to be on the Python path
and will execute named up high if it's
given a zip file to run on the command
line
so we can eliminate all of the key why
files from that example
on by setting them up into source top
zip
I meaning your little startup routine
arm
Dunder main top high and then your start
got back just
points Python at bat now there are other
tracks I have seen
I don't recommend them but on UNIX you
can roll the source Sep
together with a startup script by
ship banging does that file
can you do that can you combine text in
binary and the same fire
file thanks to people like finally many
you can you can because it's just biked
and so here it you get to skip I
having your startup file separate from
your source and
everywhere even on Windows you can
instead
puts or stop Sep credit hide it away by
appending
a pending yet to I the Python dot EXE
file
because by dad design zip files
have their signature in info it be into
the file
thus making them are parking all to
basically all other file formats the
count from the front
the I Windows or Unix want even notice
that their zip file hanging off the end
because it determines its a binary
execute a ble by looking at the first
few bites
and so that eliminates another few files
another trick
is that you can %uh throw into the mix a
module that pipe on auto imports during
startup
why have a startup script just start the
Python interpreter
next to a site customized up high that
subverts
papon's desire to start up a look at its
command line
by having it just load and start your
application instead I've seen this done
I might even have done it before I
what's a
but having looked at several tricks for
combining coding execute a ball
if your gonna go to all this trouble why
not just compile
a new copy of the Python interpreter
that
will Autostar your app is a built-in
feature and there's a whole stack up
projects over the years
the give you this tied up in a box I
most recently pie installer but I
recently saw updates to see experience
it still looks to be under development
these rig a special Python interpreter
that just wants to auto execute a nap
without being given any command-line
arguments
day worker sadly with varying degrees of
success
try to find all of your dependencies and
get them loaded up as well
and can even do a build step to put as
much as can be fit together into a
single
EXE file slash months one of those tools
is gone to work
typically a stand-alone binary
it really has your appeal I see files
set up inside
and then your binary dependencies your
shared objects in the dll's
at some people are annoyed these have to
be hanging out on the file system in
your install directory
some people just leave them there next
to your pipe and I
EXE some people bundle them
in and have the execute a ball when it
runs secretly unpack them to a temp
directory
load them from there and then moved in
before the user notices
or if you are plight techniques you can
use this wine
we read track
the pie techniques person author went
and learned how pipeline loads dll's
from files
and emulated windows standard portable
execute a ball loader against the dll's
the
the runs loads into RAM so it doesn't
even touch the filesystem no one's ever
done this for Unix
I be because meeting everything in a
single files kind against the culture
there
by it it's been done before and when it
works
it doesn't always but when it works only
pie techniques provides a truly general
single-file bundle on the Windows
platform thanks
spun here track on
the one or two road bumps you will run
across with these products are
in line files when text templates are
images
are sitting inside the directory tree at
the package
if a package uses a plain old opened to
try to get the file sitting with its
source code
you're either going to have to monkey
patch open so that it knows to look in
your zip file
or just keep the plane file sitting
outside at the EXE
which might expose a little about your
apt you're uncomfortable with but you
can do it
on well-behaved marshals when you run
across on this doesn't seem to be
well-known
will always instead of opening a file
sitting next to the doc he wife I'll
will use get data and let pipeline which
he knows whether you're running from
inside the zip file or not
make the decision you make the call
about where that date where that data
comes from
so that's the ecosystem as it existed a
year or two ago
have great interpreters we have just in
time compilation
and weak even have dislike one we're
track for bundling
everything up as a single piece of code
who would need
anything more
you might have heard at this guy before
name
Gandalf in about the year
30 18 in the Third Age
he visited our Frodo Baggins and then
telling him a story about a ring that
Friday would come into possession have
he said
I am myself dared
to pass the doors up the Necromancer
in dole cool door and secretly explored
his way
us well you might not know what about me
but I once worked in the enterprise
the enterprise sometimes demands
he axes specifically and is very
offended
any of your code persists as data
rather than becoming real machine code
core language developers on the other
hand because Python
it doesn't come out of that world Python
comes out I love the UNIX
Academy text by all on
environment Corel English developer: see
no point
in nearly eliminating interpretation
they're targeting dispatch
what's the point of eliminating if you
buy code lookup secure still
asking floats how to multiply in fact
core language developers might publicly
expressed dismay
that your even trying to nearly
eliminate that
first step have interpretation that in
other words
getting rid of a bytecode and simply
having pre
written out the sea calls that need to
be made but in the enterprise
that does not necessarily have 0 value
because %uh very conservative culture
a look-alike phenomena warning a your
about not wanting to admit Python to the
club unless it can produce the same kind
of artifacts as other tools
and sometimes a bit of a culture up
secrecy around
their source code any fear that P Y C
finals
dangling in a zip archive of the end of
an execute a ball might be the targeted
d compilation
which is its own little shadow world the
Python community
a series of projects that startup
that work with one version of python
ever and then disappear off into
commercial projects
the very first one that was open source
then disappeared behind
a close source web site where you had to
pay around it
is anyone here ever paid to decompile
appear I see file I got bit curious
who per state
so and I was curious I want to ask you
specifically
but I went online and looked at the
reviews at this product
thinking it because I if okay I was
doing espionage
if I want to know how Dropbox works deep
inside and I think that
reading their source code is a good way
to learn their secrets for my own
project
I wouldn't go pee sitting there P Y C
files up on someone else's commercial
website
who uses this so I went in ninety you
the speaking to some reviews
do I have to take back what I said about
P Y C files a few minutes ago
maybe all those P Y C files are useful
after all
okay public service announcement is now
necessary
do not set papon don't right bytecode
equal whiny if they are the only backup
you have
I love your car
and and I'm just kidding I'm not gonna
let you I see files off the hook because
they cause the problem
and our why the people running remove
all the time in their pipeline project
I the real PSA here is you some kinda
version control
even if it's a throwaway Weibo that
you'll delete at the end of the day
have something sitting there or your
editor open that you can go hit Save
then again
never have just one copy of your source
code use Dropbox
it's written in Python self
what if because if your environment are
your situation you just a really really
need an EXE
not because you're shy about dispatched
to the
multiply operation not because you need
incredible speed
but because your environmental demands
the delivery
I've compiled code where on
where the artifact is not bytecode over
on the heap
but real execute a ball machine covered
I'm here to announce
it is now possible you can now
accomplishment accomplish it
the day up EXE is upon us
and their are to competing
solutions let me outline them quickly
Nootka
by high heightened I he's given a series
I believe to talks at subsequent Europe
I pans about it
I tried a number of different programs
about it and for the most part
it was compiling 2.6 2.7 3.2 and 3.3
and like pie to eat it comes with a
built
in bundler that after its done compiling
your Python code
to real C code will bundle it all
together into as much of a single
EXE files that can manage without using
the shady one weird trick
I tried print hello world
and it worked I got an execute a ball
with out any
evident by TKO that I could find inside
it cell
identified alright that one time that I
had to make that
at EXE per client and it didn't work
that was because %uh the script ha
Griffey libraries
so I first tried the one we did
eventually get working with IDEX E
Pike crypto handed
worked alright I then went to the one
that we had had to throw away and only
right
because it didn't I could never get it
to bundle
into crypto compiled
and worked this is amazing
this means that in a wide variety of
situations
you can now with a little bit of work
get your project to producing
EXE where no compilation are bytecode
interpretation
happens runtime: you can bundle
dependency
work just put it elsewhere on the pipe
on path it's your call you're trying to
protect
you're not too shy about the customer
seeing that into crypto
is sitting next to you on the desk you
have either option I
but you can also has a competitor saipan
which I had been led to believe was a
domain-specific language to make it easy
to let Python talk to you see I assumed
it was some little sub set up the Python
language that barely got you up and
running
so that you could then make calls in to
see without having to use
are at this so that the translation
between the two
environment happened transparently and
it was last year talking to one of those
arm Python science people that there
that that that that they're like yeah
it's like Python
plus you can make Skype calls and Isaac
but you mean it's
it's Paul Python and they're like ap
you can make see call us and as likely
many
you guys have secretly come up with a
way to compile
pie time generators actions classes
to see code yet to see code
and you haven't told anyone like
like people asked this on Stack Overflow
every day in you've been keeping it a
secret
and they're like out but with with
Saipan
you can't make calls to see
max because then we'll have two previous
space
and so need ca insight on and I
Nootka and seitan are the two solutions
and
with them you can bundle your project
together
as a single EXE thank you very much
I don't see anyone by the Mikes
for one question in which case oh well I
invite you to talk to the speaker in the
open spaces or anywhere
thank you again see me at the sprints if
you wanna play with some examples I've
been experimenting with