good afternoon everyone earning a story
with an accession
I'd like to lose one gomez is a mobile
engineering event break is we talked to
us about push notifications afternoon
thanks there was a
Rd good okay good luck on to
thanks for coming obvious -1 Thomas
amount model engineer November right and
I'm gonna be talking
a little bit about push notifications
and specially
why job our current model op
not physically rest but I i current web
mall model
is just not enough for for mobile
applications
ob so first I'm not talk about
wide the talk it's going to be about to
let you know
what you're in for out to basically
gonna give you a brief introduction to
push notifications and not tell you what
they are
and then tell you why you wanna be using
them I am going to give you a brief
rundown
a very high level rundown are or how
over how to implement push notifications
and bike on
and how to leverage %ah couple servicers
that make it a little easier in how to
use some projects that
that would take a little bit of the pain
away out what I'm not going to be
covering
I'm not gonna be covering the mall sad
side somehow gonna be speaking specifics
about
angry and I'll as there's there's a lot
of stuff that specific to Google and
Apple
that I'm going to be covering covering
but from the server side
not from the mall site I'm also not
going to be showing a lot a code I'm
sorry to disappoint everybody
are but this is label as a novice talk
to Matt try to keep it as high-level
us arm as possible but when my objective
is that when you leave here you know
where to go how to start
and where to find what you need to be
successful and implement
push notification so although there's
not a lot of code you going to know what
to do once decisions done
and into my detailed updates so wanna
start with up
a question I love us of have probably
wasted
hours offer live saying at this screen
for those of you not familiar with it
is tracking page at UPS %ah so when we
have a package
especially a package that we're excited
about we just stare out the webpage
incessantly hitting f5
and and then out waiting for finally
seeing their
their glorious the Leary out page up but
sometimes when this happens I wonder if
there's a better way
%ah up doing things out why do I have to
go into a web page and like I have to be
up hitting at five every time if UBS
knows when the package is delivered the
person that delivers the packet has to
scan it and put it on my door
so daigneault that my package has been
delivered why do I have to be checking
on
on a web page and and this is partly the
model dubbed we had
out for a long time on on the web its
we always I we always use a browser in a
browser
goes to the server and then obtains are
information
mostly because limitations around how
TCPIP work
up that's the model that we've been used
for years I just think that it's
not very efficient it reminds me of some
road trips %ah
that that I took a child where asking my
dad job
if we we were there yet didn't make the
trip go any faster
hot sell I think it's time to rything
I am things a little bit and specially
in like the
up developments on the mobile side
as most viewed no of moles are
unfortunately not
not growing %ah that their smartphone
using the
world is now growing a lot is exploding
its
it's huge now ended there was the
journal put some numbers
about two weeks ago that really blew me
away
because and in granted social networks
are a little bit ahead of the curve
up but this are numbers on on the usage
on social networks both on mobile and on
the desktop
and as you can see on most social
networks than
that the mobile usage is way higher %ah
then than the best abused Sep for some
social networks
so as he said something that was are
ahead of the curb raping
all a fast if you're not going to
numbers you probably should go back and
try to do this
all of us are seen how our users
are increasingly using our services on
our website more and more
on their mobile device so I thing we
need to do more to give them
a good experience on their devices
because that
though all wet model they've been the
words so used to
it's really not very efficient for
mobile devices
mostly because moles are really
restricted obviously
on memory on processing and and
on battery life as well hot so the
the that model love having to be
following the server
every couple seconds or minutes if you
want to see
there's new data and most of the time
does not new data
%ah it's really efficient and ended it
gets
it gets really evident on mobile where
years really
depleting those precious resources like
battery
and network and servers are smart
just like UPS servers no when they eat
out is there so
if there's something that the server
needs to give me observer knows
one when that that a man has happened
and a mobile
that the mall phone pauling the server
every five seconds every 10 seconds
is not going to make that happen any
faster
so there has to be a better way there
has to be a way that servers
can tell the phone when they have data
for them
and that will make things more efficient
and turn will Merrick make our serb is a
lot more engaging
and a lot more pleasant to use out for
users
so so how do we solve this problem and
and the answer of course is
is push notifications and that's what
I'm gonna be %ah
speaking about to push notifications are
just out
tiny little text messages to show up on
your phone screen
our sometimes they have to be or a
vibration
to call your attention up but mostly are
small chunks of information
the hopefully will be delivered on I
relevant I'm
so for instance a viewer I am and and I
was
I'll with some friends not too long ago
and we were wondering we all have
weather apps on our phones
but you weather app tells you if you if
you checked the weather
it tells you what the weather's going to
be like during the day but it never
warns you for example that it's going to
rain
cell our phones art smart enough to be
able to tell us hate
it's going to start raining you should
prolly head inside
if you're outside or something of that
nature so
push notifications make services more
engaging and more delightful to use
and third tiny messages that get
delivered
are at the right time the
Arctic is really simple %ah basically
there's the the provider which is your
service
are there's a middleman in this case the
two
biggest smart and providers our Apple
and Google
and then there's the actual devices on
Apple's case they're extending
the Push Notification modeled to the
dust up to
i jus affari was not restricted to the
mall anymore and you can push
information into the desktop using
Safari on
on the Apple platform so the the general
high-level architecture is really simple
and then that the the orange I'll
the orange circle our hearings being
it's yours it supposed to be your
service
hot did the push notification is really
%uh they said as mall piece of text and
even at the low level it's still a small
around his mall upbeat Jason this is a
specific
I Apple push notification so it has
doubt the we're action lock key that
basically
it's telling the phone what to do when
the user unlock the phone
job doesn't you have an iPhone no the
you push notifications
I'm sometimes shown your lock screen so
we have to tell the phone what to do
when you block out so it's a really
simple
are gays in string %ah that's far above
the beauty of push notifications their
base on on the technologies that we
already use
is not being super complicated it's
stuff that we already know
outsider relatively easy implanted the
release to implant an
and by fun outside visitors there's to
I'll the two big providers for for
smartphones are Apple and Google
they have that most robust
implementations and the two that were
gonna be covering today
oz it is a high-level comparison between
the two job services
cell I'll the main difference between
the two is died on the Apple side
you have to you actually open a TCP IP
socket
and then send by any data to Apple out
for that needed to be pushed into the
phone google has a more
out but a web friendly job for a call
where the use
HTTP and they have recently implemented
a new version of the serb is
that uses XMPP which is what a lot about
Noah's
Java which is out just chat pro cool
that use a socket as well
om then there's are out
interesting ob points and the two
services
security wise they're pretty similar
although with
will see that that the security side on
Apple is a little bit more complicated
on Google
and then the payload which is the actual
message it's a lot smaller on the Apple
site mostly because
on the Apple site out once you send the
push to a phone
%uh the the operating system is the one
that controls the bush
on Android push gets passed directly to
the application
and the application decides what to do
so that's kinda why
out the payload it's a little bigger or
are a little bigger on the
on the Google site that on on the Apple
site and finally there's
the how I get errors %ah usually when
I'm pushing to a lot of devices
there's a lot of out the device could be
of the device to be
permanently unregister from the service
others many
up issues decker writes on out during
the execution of your app
outside to get those errors back on the
Apple model you have to
havin a single ounce process stop
calling
the Apple server to a socket to get the
air is back
on the Google model I it's a little bit
more family again
you get those errors directly when you
make your request so you're doing you
using the ATP
API you get it on your FB response if
you using the XMPP
I am implementation you get it on your
exam BB response
so it's it's a little bit easier on on
the Google site
%ah push notifications are great by the
old up downside
the biggest downsides there they're not
ass reliable
of us I would like them to be there's no
guarantee that your message is going to
be delivered
in most cases it gets delivered so in
most cases
you do get that that the message and
you you're able to push the message to
users but there's no guarantee from the
provider that that's going to be the
case
so you have to be prepared for those
cases and you have to plan ahead and I
guess that's a
thats downside the art downside is dad
sometimes have your phone is of a
reviewer outside of your area
connectivity
I it could happen that by the time you
get the message
%ah the data is no longer run so the way
both providers
are dealing with it is the I an
expiration om
expiration time to the messages so when
you send a message
to I did after all Google you have to
put an expiration time on
on the message so that they know that
after out
certain amana seconds the message is not
really a fan of
and and it should not be deliver because
what happens underside
is dad once you send a message did not
try to keep retrying
to deliver the message out to the phone
until they finally
sexy surfers were not talk
I about the specifics of the Apple
implementation
so what you need to get started are I
and II was out that's running on the
phone number and tell you a little bit
about
I mean white that's a an important
component
you can eat out provisioning profile
which is something specific to
are you create your app are you gonna
need a certificate that i'm gonna
describe bob
how do you get it and then you're gonna
need your device tokens
I and the device the way you get device
token it very similar both on the Apple
and Google Sites only gonna described
I year and on on on the Apple site
and you need to have a lot of course
which is up your message
so how do you get the certificate
process is not
%ah very different from getting a normal
now as
felt certificate I it's just that it's
tied 2-yard
to your I'll as application so you
basically generate out certificate
request
you go to the Apple website job where
you have your app register
you upload your certificate request you
tie it to your
you up I D and then you generate your
I your certificates from the Apple
website and then
with those a difficult %ah you put them
on your service and we'll see
now in a little bit when you're
implementing I am
how your service needs to present those
credentials basically
to the Apple service before make it can
start sending
up push notifications
Phil moving into the device token the
device token is basically I'm
you can think of it as an IP address and
sorrow like an address
that Apple assigning a specific ap
on a specific device so it's it's both a
combination
of a specific phone so my iPhone and my
specific app to let say my UPS out
that's gonna want me
when my package finally gets delivered
%ah sadat's the device token
and the device token needs to be
obtained specific to the Vice
in needs to be obtained on the device so
the actual
out bringing your phone I do your
Android app for your I'll asap
it's the one the ones in it against
install and and used for the first time
it has to go and negotiate that device
token
Wed the the Apple platform or the Google
platform
and then get that device token any needs
to send it back to your service
hot so that you can keep track of the
devices and and and be able to send a
message
so that's a I'll a little bit a
complicated part in this diagram covers
I'm how that happens so it's the device
the one to negotiate talking
then independently it has to send that
talking back to you
so that you can address that device
directly
and then I'm up to you have your your
toe can stain you need to
tube speak directly to the actual arm
Apple server
and that's done chewed out the socket
child I describe
using the certificates IJ's previously
generated
out so it's just it's a normal I am
known come trust communication %ah as
you would do anything TCP IP connection
to their certificate on the Apple site
is a certificate on your side and then
you both validate
the out in city of those certificates
before you start
doing your your arm
you start sending messages an apple
stars are
delivering your results of those missed
the best way to do by far I
a push notifications on pipe on 8 Sep
%uh palo back its cold
hi apne and by AP a lot by AP an ass
I and by AP an ass job aid
handles all the socket connection for
you it handles all the
day SSL negotiation for you and makes
writing
that code really was a simple you can go
out and find
let's say you have a Django's harbors
out there's like django packages to try
to do this
i'd don't recommend you do that because
since this is a socket connection
%ah both for simplicity reasons and for
its Kayla Billy reasons and we're gonna
talk a little bit about it
of and a couple slides it's better to
have this as a separate process
and you can ride with pie APNs I a
little bit more efficient by PN as
the sources up and get Hobbes and you
can download you can peep inside
and its it in the cheese shop
so this is the actual code oh how I love
how you send
ahh I you style is your connection with
the Apple server
this again the the Apple site with up by
AP an ass
so as you can see is really simple you
give it %ah
some books parametered that by default
is true and whatnot
%ah what that means is it tells object
that by AP and as
which server to address when you when
you create your
push notification profile on the Apple
website Apple create a proper boast on
their test servers
and on their production servers so you
can a you can use
up both depending on the pure testing or
if you're already in production
so by by making that furnace out use
sandbox
compass to I'm telling by AP and as hey
just right ahead dat test servers so
that we can do some
some testing on on push notifications
and then
I give it that path who might certain
file
and to Mikey so that it can negotiate
the trust with the absurd
and then a after Don Dada I have two
options the first in the simplest option
is just
San a single message and a single
message
you have to use up the token token is
died number
that address that I got from the device
sorted by
obtain dot token and send it to my
server so i'd
I touch it from my data store and I use
a token
to send my actual message and then the
bailout here I'm using a very simple
payload
on is using a hello world %ah that's not
show up on the phone and
Mb but you can use I more complicated
the load and there's
there's ways to doing that I'm just
showing you did
simplest case i cant also and this is
that
a really cool thing on on by AP in as I
can also send multiple push
notifications
%ah out on the same time up taking a ban
internet connection that's already
established
out for dot by PSU something at school a
frame so I have to do is
add items to my frame n each I am it's
going to be %ah
message cell edge item has the exact
same components as in our message
it has a token I it has a up a load and
then
you can specify more advance job
browner's like the expiration that I
spoke about a little bit
that tells the server for how many
seconds to keep that message
and nails so the priority in case you
have multiple message
you can't stop the priority I if there's
messages that are more important than
dollars I just basically once the frame
is constructed
descended and then by PN as in Taunton
enough to reuse the socket connection
that's already stylish
to send all the mess all those messages
once
I'm and this slide its little bit of
I love a high level architecture how I
recommend you try to
ob I am arc de Cure your service
they said ideally you won your pot year
by AP and has to be running on a
separate
are it doesn't have to be a separate
service but separate from like your web
server or your web application
and then ideally what you could do is
Yuki create Hughes
on your data store that every time an
event happens there needs to be
communicated to the user
to a push notification are those workers
does does sorry that doesn't matter just
get put on the Q
and then you can have a group of workers
and that can allow you to scale
to to I'm massive I am massive size
if you need to I you have different
workers
that get work from dot you and then send
the messages
to to the Apple or Google server this
architecture applies
%ah across-the-board outsell
now where you have a I a queuing system
your messages get delivered to the same
socket connection
you are using your resources being able
to send more messages
with the same connection and that's
gonna make you serve as a lot more
efficient
and value %uh they said out to scale a
lot better
then did you try you something like a
general packager or something
on oMG I'm switch gears a little bit and
I'm going to go to the glove side
a lot of the stuff that we just talked
about on the Apple site applies to
Google as well
the its it just has its own lil ob
specifics but the same process applies
for negotiating tokens
and and negotiating trust between the
odd the servers the thing is on the
Google site is a little bit easier
since I am says this is
%ah an HTTP connection or on the XMPP
side since is again sockets
get saluted more complicated again but
an XMPP it's a protocol that is widely
distributed
hot so there's a lot of libraries in a
lot of documentation to make it
up easier to to implement so on an
underside
it seems like you need a lot more but
most have dollars job
ID's are things that you get item from
the Google Website when you register
your service
are or again the device token that you
get from there the eighty there's only
one thing that you need and his did you
mean a Google user ID so
anybody that has an Android phone by
default has a
a google account but you need to capture
that account in order to be able to send
them
%ah notifications easy Emma they said in
the beginning as to implementation
there's a very simple
ACP job implementation that is just a
REST API
and there's the XMPP implementation I'm
not gonna go into details of the HTTP
it's really simple to
to implement I'm gonna talk about to
service in the end
that are similar so there's gonna be
some code that
that would apply to using the the HTTP
side
I'm not talk more about the XMPP version
that's a little bit more interesting
I'll so ago way to do it is using
hours leak XMPP which is again in our
fight library that's in the Chi shode
you can be been solid
are you can job look at the source code
on GitHub
op but it's not the only 1i they said
XMPP have been around for a long time
there's a lot of libraries a lot of
options a lot of implementation
I believe some %uh view my have already
used it so you might have your own
preference of what you want to use I but
that's the a man is in
on the Google side %ah that they use
something that
that were used to entity just pick up
little you already have
I'd recommend this one because it makes
again the code really easy
so this is how you solve the connection
again
you just imported package create decline
XMPP
given the dad your API keys give a day
the Google address %ah you have to use
date uses el
equals to you August who if you don't
know what's gonna reactor connection
and that's it you have your XMPP
connections dollars
and then XMPP the chat pro decal so
messages are gonna be coming back and
forth
the biggest downside job for me and at
least is that XMPP is base on
on XML so all your messages are gonna be
wrapped in XML
odd so that's my major payload bigger
and it's there's
you you don't really i mean you have to
part said there's a lot of external
parts is out there
I just think is a downside since using
jason is so easy
now we have this extra layer of other
XML on top of our messages
but i think is nice the globalized as
days out camp chat for a cool
the biggest advantage by far as stat
the XMPP protocol it's a two-way Prada
khalsa push notifications usually work
from the server to the device
up but up using XMPP you can
send messages from the device to the
server and died
opens up a whole new I'll range up
scenarios
that you don't have princeton's on the
Apple site or at least
not not us straightforward as you do on
the cool side
%ah as you can see it's relatively easy
depending on the
on the livor did you choose but it's a
little bit papal
so fortunately there's two up providers
out there
and I'm just government mentioned it to
them Miller Wed
they have really good solutions dead
dropped a little bit of this complexity
and and make make city make make it
easier to to
implement push especially using pipe oz
in the first one is sparse
of parts got acquired by Facebook about
a year ago
%ah they do a lot more them push push is
not their main business day
they're basically out there said
business basically out free back in for
mobile developers
so they let you store %ah the alleged
store
job objects and a bunch of other stuff
but they do push
on top they have pressed my firm is the
Cayenne
the way they do push notifications is
sure SAPI
so it's really easy you can use I'm
using HTTP Live exam trying to keep it
that their lowest common denominator for
you can use
your live do or any other %ah ACP
michael i read your comfort comfortable
with is just a POST request
that you issue against that that I'm
parser burger
you make a connection you send the
request their request again it's just
Jason data
%ah I'm using dictionaries here but all
that gets married to
to Jason you send the gate and eat over
you can said you had urs your hairs have
to have
out specific tokens said you get from
the service and then you
just send that and then you get back
again Jason data
out from buyers and then fires handles
everything for you and sense the push
notifications to
to the devices there's a few downsides
with pars
I'm not I mean they're great service
at this is just my experience of
and my limited experience cell hot they
have a
they don't have an official pipe as the
Kani thing for me that's downside
we're all fighting developers so they
have a I've bite and as the cato they
recommend but its is not very good
%ah and then there they have some issues
on the mall site and reliability
%ah so thats that something to to be
wary of
but they're working really hard and
they've come a long way so the
there a really really good option if you
want out abstract all the complexity of
the different providers
and no one is Urban Airship %ah there
really great they have an official
python is the case that is great
I think on how great the SDK is it's
that maybe
the only one out that that the one
implies doesn't look as good
up but there is the case great they have
was poppin support
and out its it's again a simple rest
up API to desist how you implemented
again is really simple you can see that
the API's really clean
and this is how you send a message to
all types of devices
%ah and this is a very simple miss you
see that I'll have to do the gate on
on my own like a hat on on on pars so
it's
it's really really so in summary
I I wanted to
out thing to pitch in a little bit of
how mobile is
basically eating the world I if you're
not doing mole you're probably thinking
about doing mall also
when you're planning to go your most
Reidy you have to think about
push notifications as a way to
communicate with users I am
it will make your servers smarty you
will be able to deliver information
at the time that the user needed it'll
be really personalize another bite at
the user carries
and it will make your service up more
more personal to
to the user and finally doing to them by
honeys easy
uses up a standard protocols and
and the implementation details are are
not the heart
and we all have tools are ready for for
a lot of this stuff
cell that's kinda why why wanna talk
about
up hopefully you got just a bit
and and especially you got curious about
it gotta go
home and look at some other stuff
somebody's project and and try to do it
on your own
hopefully we'll see a lot more services
offering push in the future
thank you
so I think we have time for a job couple
questions
so someone wants to come up to them yeah
you can come up to the mic and
yeah this attack our ives
Chiesi it seems like you briefly
mentioned how
there's no guarantees
that push notifications being delivered
now I was wondering what pic cases are
where they're not delivered in
half Rican that is in what people should
be aware of
our unfortunately is more frequent than
I would like
it's getting better at at both have
their services %ah
get more mature %ah but there's
there's a little models by I mean by
their own nature are not as reliable as
as any desktop so from tel could be of
could be out of service coverage our
data connectivity could not be good
I love us know that app crashes on
your asking price in your phone at any
time for many different reasons
you have memory issues so dozers some
are that's in a reason which you could
lose up wid
but it's getting better and the fact
that we have expirations they it
spiritually time now and and a couple
into a working really hard to make this
problem go away but it's something to be
wary about
is not not out completely
a complete show stopper by something to
be to be I'll
is sorry to follow up really quick but
is there
am throttling word
abuse checks richer which might lead to
are there is a both sides a non-apple
you you can send more than a hundred
Methodism
one push like one connection
I but that's about it I mean you can san
andreas close it's an art 100
its not so much restrictions I
restriction again
abuse I think the abuse far goes more on
the
Apple policing since they have to
approve your app before they posted they
police how you do
push notifications on Android is a lot
more
there's a lot more freedom up but I I
have really seen people abusing it done
I'm thanks okay
I want greater talk I this question
might be out of scope for what you just
discussed but
you discussed a few libraries for
don't push notifications for pipe on for
mobile development
arm I'm curious if you know of the top
your head good live
good Python libraries for like
non-mobile development on
for put for push notifications no those
are well those two sir for bush
up do you mean for selling pushed to the
desktop
yes well I think there's a fight wish
for Apple
works exactly the same as as as firm
also
the seeing live reply at the end as well
will give you a job
so if I presented and eventually we're
at a time so
thank you very much again for coming and
and I'm gonna stay here and
around the conference if you have any
questions thanks again