are for lack of a better name DNS
explained
please welcome lynn
kenya oo hey you can hear me
I just have to like take a picture /a
br/ and tweet about it because
it's amazing to see this many people
just as confused about DNS as I am
and am
so yeah I am when great and
see myself organized here an
so yeah I am lender oh there's no slides
a.m.
just just kidding I'm I work for us
Spotify has a a partner
engineer with Mom to leap right good
morning
I and I'm also an
and founder pilot is in San Francisco
and I I do love organization for an
make workshops and speaker series and
stuff like that
am and if you want to start your own
local pile ET's
and it should be an you should be able
just pip install pie ladies and get your
own
I'm handbook am yeah and I am also on
board member
the papon suffer foundation am awesome
a.m. so yeah cool let's get this started
I'm so as it nerdy
person who likes to jet away to Lake
I don't know a hotel like an hour away
do you still like hacking over a long
weekend trying to like
deploy a sun-like cool app a always seem
to like
messed it up great like a simple like
get pushed to her okay like
doesn't work on who's ever had that
issue
China like to play something simple get
pushed
yeah from can see it yeah okay I see a
lot of hands um
and I'm sure you recognize this on it's
always like a DNS issue when you're
trying to
on China deploy your app on and I'm sure
not a few here have had like clean at
DNS setup the first time around
otherwise
you would not be here who has had a very
clean set up a DSLR like first time
around
now okay up one person
I don't know why you hear the music at
the time I'm
so I'm yes they follow the instructions
and
probably set the DNS records in the %uh
something doesn't work
and we've all been there and so without
a solid understanding at DNS
in sometimes a folks just like I'll just
try this now disliked week this record
or some like that
waiting for DNS to propagate to see an
if your guess was correct
so hopefully this presentation will give
you a better understanding
am curiosity got the best in me when I
was
get pushed China Plain and it didn't
work i want to sale
dive deeper into a DNS is I'm not so I'm
a new their DNS was like answer the
phone book
and the back onto the internet but on I
also knew that the cloud
spilled on DNS and duct tape and DNS
itself is
pretty much duct tape together so well
it is confusing and
has Lake and a text books or definition
but
it doesn't always work the way we think
it does I'm so what exactly be going
over is
am what DNS is and why you should care
about DNS and what's to do with it what
to do
with the NS as well as like are some
things I learned along the way
so first I wanna explain like why DNS is
put it important
and it allows you to visit very
productive web sites like Reddit
it allows you to like to see very time
critical emails like Groupon
her guilt and deploy or whatever kind to
do up on her okay room
and I'm that allows you to them
for your corporate mean generator to not
be accessible by non-employees
I'm still we know that
the DNS is essentially the phone but it
stands for a domain name system
and translates from human readable names
to computer family
addresses but the actual like textbook
definition
set DNS is it distributed storage system
for resource records
on each your DNS resolver or
authoritative server: stores these
records and its cash or
opal's owned by on the record music
contains a label a class type in some
data
so that might be a text but but
that still like you're a parade I kind
of like
sorry kinda behind i cud still doesn't
make sense on
you get up but you don't actually get so
let's actually see it CDNs
in action so commoner to understand the
NS
I was playing with and Python for sale
used
landscape be to sniff some DNS traffic
and to browse like
the interwebz so I'm using ski be
dismissed like scabies the function
and to pick up my local traffic as you
can see I've
filtered my traffic via UTPA and
import 53 just to hone in on DNS traffic
on and i've only limited to like 10
packets
cell as I let this sniff function run
and I want to type in my browser
Rogaland outcome which is my website
locally see it I'm so was pretty cool
is an as an at that I found they can
kinda see here is
I was typing robe lynda.com into the
CMake chrome
address bar and a DNS query would take
place for every
autocomplete guess that chrome to so
first
it pings a they will not calm because
the address
is also search function right
and then as a tape are a complete to
read it
because I can't go there very often and
nominee can actually see the DNS query
on
on the second line for for bed and then
as I type are
0 and prom dresses are broken dust by
I'm which is and my super awesome how to
style a python presentation that you
should check out
on and then and we can see and it's its
related query that it
points Tim on the election define
and then on it finds Aeroplan dot com
want I type
Roog and press Enter with the crumbs and
our position
like I guess it's more purple thing
about from the Nespresso things pretty
calm
on but one thing that you might notice
here and in
not sure if you can really see it an but
all these DS prairies have
a dot at the end and I'm sure but many
have you
know it's like just how DNS does things
but and is anyone know like why it's
there raisins
get like 3 okay get your own right place
am so the difference between a dot in a
no dot
an is this is same difference between
absolute file path and relative file
path
so on like bill to file cuz it can be an
them like this dot dot such data can be
mangled are mapped incorrectly
cell and depending upon how your local
DNS
is set up if you have search and
example dotnet in years all dot com and
you navigate to
example dot com a DNS surgery will take
the year old not to be fully qualified
I'm
and therefor will look up example dot
com dot example dotnet
dot or whatever on and
so and you can see that I am if I
actually
search for example dot com dot Hill go
to double dot com not that
example that con got example dotnet I'm
so if there's a dot at the
and minutes and unambiguous fully
qualified domain name
and it's not prone to the search path
spoofing
um no I didn't put a dot well navigating
to
pro-clinton am but putting a dot is not
exactly
user friendly when you're trying to like
type in something so chrome kinda have
inherently
am assumes a dot
so I'm handling all this DNS stuff
father's death carrying stuff kinda got
me curious
you know as one is IOM and I want to
figure out what route leading as curry
takes to file I get an answer
for where Roque lyn is hosted in as not
actually that
easy to figure out once again as pre
hits the router
to better the black box an and that the
query is forwarded to you
if it's not locally cached I know that
my computers DNS
is set up to one are 192 die 168 at 11
in which is my router and my router's
DNS is set up to study but that's only
5.7 5.7 5
um in I found this out by actually doing
a logging into the admin page at my
router
so I do a host query for my for the
routers DNS I can see that there is a
pointer to
Comcast dotnet subdomain
now if I do and who is clearly on that
ipsa a Comcast my ISP and provider
actually owns
and the IP address but beyond that I do
not know if Comcast DNS Hasbro glenda
Comcast
and if not I don't know where it goes to
an
to get that information but DNS as some
you might know is
I'm hierarchical on an and getting
familiar with a dick man can let us
that can help us understand that serve
hierarchy in how queries are resolved
on dig it man actually has this nice
trace
flag that makes enters queries to
resolve the name being looked up
am it follows referrals from the root
servers
I'm showing the answer from each server
that is used that was used to look at
to do a reverse lookup Sophie try that
out with them
Python .org and you can see I use the
day communal apologize if it's
too small and aid to the day command
against Python .org with the
trace flag and I'm the kinda see it like
a buyer for the information but let's
let's look at it
them in a very prettier representation
so the query actually starts from
Maya local DNS 192 dot 168 that 1.1
where if not cached is passed onto
the fruit server which is just dot
and the curry from my local DNS for
Python org
first ass for the root server on the dot
who knows and that one of these hosts
should have that on the information
below those host there
and so the name server responds with Mia
go ahead try one is
which corresponds to a dot word name
server:
the dot org name server: receive the
query and then
says something like try one of these
hosts which corresponds to the Python
decor name server: and a paper and out
or get them
name services yep I haven't a record for
Python org which is one
42 11 1069
I'm sowwy sorry successively resolved
Python .org but you can see we have like
other like subdomains am if you want to
know more about say like
HG to Python .org am
began to take a man and we actually see
that it's a CNAME record
map to an an app to record that sound by
am
organ State University's open source lab
am which
is a different am which is a different
record also I'm
so now I'm sure that Python door cuz
on more records than just an ass and a
records
so if you're curious we can run the day
command with them the Dashti
any and many am unfortunately only see
it a records in NS records
but if we look at on pilot is dot com as
all the more interesting you can see
am SOA records pointing to name dot com
you can see
our mail records RMX records plane to
Google
an arm a records pointing to you our web
host
hmmm what you don't get is with any is
the full
on zone feiler the DNS setup like all
the sea names that are possible on an
obscenely
go into that all been few minutes
moving on am so we were easily to
we can easily see how a DNS like that
path takes for resolving
and by Thunderbird however it's not the
most efficient way and for DNS to
respond to queries
and the route and the top will name
servers like dot and I ordered
would be inundated with requests a free
for DNS resolvers always go to that
the start and so that's where I'm DNS
caching comes into play
so when a DNS resolver 30 did name
server receives
aquarium it searches its cash for an
achingly will
if there's no matching label in the cash
to serve remains said retrieved from its
cash
and a referral response containing
resource record set have
annus records for a label that might be
closer to the domain
which is the subject at the cream sunset
did
um to receiving her for a response a DNS
resolver can also be configured
to you and initiate an to initiate
them on
nursing curry for an authoritative a DNS
server room
responsible for the domain name an which
is
the sobriquet aquarium and the thirtieth
name so we can respond with an answer if
roller field response
and the thirtieth a.m. names a response
is accepted by
DNS resolver and then is subsequently
stored into
cash if it only needs a certain
conditions which is specific to the
resolvers implementation
so if my local DNS servers cash was
completely empty
am I could send it as carrie Ann for
Python that order to root server room
and then get pointed to go to the name
Syria handled or domain
but it's more likely that I have
something like dot already am sites
already cash so I can go straight to the
like the dot work sites
um and then it just kinda trickles down
from there
am SCO and DNS caching is all
you know great hunky-dory Intel you get
to propagation
her occasion is how long someone has to
wait for DNS changes to show a fact
am adidas record will hold an item
called TTL
on time to live number am which and
at which point it deleted if that time
the light is
up and so after its deleted I have
someone makes a new request that furs
refers to that record in on the DNS
server will go through that process
again a
trying to find that information
having and a tu hi time to live
that number an will it take longer for
for cash into flushing for your friend
said be able to go to your glory a
studio apt that's on her a VM
am having a tool 0 TTL am the set then a
server will be it
inundated with them a high-low damn
might not have the ability to deal with
her curry lamb
another pain have propagation
in NT TL is that some and Internet
service providers completely ignore
details and have their own comics expect
like expiry for records
I'm cashing actually opens up the
ability to
to poison a DNS cache is cash am
by for this is not my area of expertise
but as I understand it
DNS cache poisoning works like Sam am
if the server doesn't validate a DNS
response
like for instance via and in a sec am
someone could exploit that but I am
essentially spoofing and IP address that
he or she
owns forgiven hostname forcing users
that certain hostname to be directed
elsewhere
to be able to spook a DNS entry am an
attacker
would have to create a faster response
and then that a legitimate a 38-7
now you can and effectively and de dos
a DNS server are cashing survey with
probable
non-cash entries providing many attempts
to send fake responses
and those random demands that are now
cast aren't to use phone
but what an attacker can do is include a
name server in his or her response
for the desired remained to compromise
so on those are the band potential
issues with cashing in a lot of people
actually do face issues with publication
am when trying to like deploy on her ok
im
I'm bird on my kinda want to go into
like
that kinda cool dirty things they did
learn while exploring DNS
and maybe you will enjoy them as much as
I'd in
I'm so first up I'll start off with them
interesting ways to interact with TNS
am so previously and when doing a dig
any queries like an dick pie ladies
Dashti any
and the we know so we can I get any
CNAME records
and back like Debbie to be carried out
public is to come
and you can certainly run big angry
against Derby Derby Derby oppose dot com
but how many subdomains are there you
don't really down
and being able to look up a full DNS
zone file
I'm is barely allowed on but there's
this
am loses to all called DNS map that
literally brute force is
a sub domain lookup so I'm
China Deanna I'm trying to do in a snap
up I ladies
unfortunately I returns for results even
though I know that there's over 20 min
and so donuts like if your users don't
expect them
the results to be comprehensive or fast
since is clearly
searching base on adults and are
provided wordless
I'm so yeah this tool is limited by
worthless but you can supply on your own
like it much longer wordless
b1 am
am so when another thing they learned
dominos play around by Dennis
I want to figure out what was cashed
locally my own
and local DNS so am for
maximally say I'm not share for an when
its systems or a window systems
you in order to find out what is cached
locally
and you either have to kill the DNS
process and Senate to syslog
so after you run on this command of you
flush the cache
and you go into your spam system but log
on
am under system you can see some
familiar looking results I have a leech
and the cert actually looks kinda
descend on the slides but there's a lot
more information
am and interesting enough on all these
entries are were made from when I was
DNS mapping Spotify
so so it's pretty fun and if we and
actually look at
captured packet minnows I'm using scibi
to sniff traffic generated by Dennis
napping Spotify am
done dotnet and you can see an actually
a very top the internet lehrman the act
and then the IP layer in
which you can see it went from my
computer IP address to you my DNS route
I'm
and then it D and the DNS map was trying
to
trying out the Zr doubts but if I dot
net at the bottom
and so you can see that question record
that DNS will send
am so I think I am I think looking for
and through
escapee in sniffing and yes chapters is
pretty interesting
but I'm I'm hearing telepathically from
you guys a an
not enough Python so am
so here comes twisted I'm so you can
actually ran a
very simple a DNS server with Preston am
Paul does again if you if it's not that
read a bomb so this is a very
get very simple DNS server am is based
off for
ECT resolve dot com of but you can
supply on and DNS servers to take him
and so we can run this season as well as
fire apps KPN run
the day command against the server room
and many consider question
and down their nose digging for Python
.org on
has the crew name type in class and
again it goes from my eye
from my IP address my computer to my
router
and so here it is a response am with the
DNS
resource record in the data associated
with it
so if ur said that question and now this
is the actual response
it am went from my router to my computer
am
and you can see the resource record name
in the bottom with Python or the type
class TTL them and did assist you with
that
am alright so we'd Owen over interesting
ways to interact with the an ass now
some interesting ways to actually use
DNS
and some the am its me folks may know
the types of IP network addressing
methodology including
unique ass small dick ass broadcasts
anycast
is a fourth one where datagrams are sent
from
a single-center to a group have
potential return receivers
all identified by the same address
referred to as 12
nearest Association and so Google
actually uses any cast for its public
DNS servers the
8.8 8.8 and 8.8 up 4.4
where someone looking up an 8888
in Australia Australia may am go
somewhere different then if someone
on in the US where to go to and to look
up
8888 but they both received the same
information
to look Google configures alt
applications for anycast
now allows folks in like operations to
be able to take down like one cluster
a time in like reroute traffic to
another
there's no worry and that about folks
not getting
this the same data when looking at 8
a.m. insert it's quite nice for
for general accounting
and Dane am stands for DNS based
authentication have named entries
basically a protocol um for to the gets
to be bound to
DS names using and DNS security
extensions or heard in a sec
it's a basically a proposed way to
remove
and certificate authority for when at:
less client and server
authenticating so on and German many if
you're familiar with that lock icon on
your web browser im
but am are you sure
and that you're connecting all the way
to the website using correct
kill us certificate am it is
am quite possible and quite common for
like a firewall to get in between
and terminate your tillis in connection
with their website and then recreate the
kill us
connection from your device to your
browser am so you think that your secure
and
any havoc Inc a good connection to your
bank but in fact the connection to be
intercepted in the firewall or another
device
is able to see a potentially awkward all
interactions at the website
so if the browser supporting Dane on
the tax that it is not using a specific
are specified certificate Anakin warn
you that I am near
connection is and secure even though you
see that locked icon
and supposedly and the DNS Python
library has support for this already and
it's a development branch
another dinner Dino ghetto awesomeness
that I
and pepper but my deep dive into Python
herbs Pittman
DNS is and as they can be use for
service every
and there are few ways and tools to
implement service discovery but
ultimately boils down to
what servers run this service
as mention one can leverage DNS to help
answer this question
with the use the a ser B records
cell MSRB records are then DNS zones
map cannot claim step will be in the
format underscore
name underscore protocol as you see here
dot sight come to host names so for
instance
at Spotify is service has its own as RB
record in
with one record cannot be named after
the service itself
so and you spin up a Spotify client it
doesn't as Herbie lookup
similar to am that they commanded
and then the service look at continues
on
so Clank it connects to are a dozen SRB
look at it connects to an access point
and then continues resolving to the data
that's needed either to play this is
torture
or whatever
and lustful nugget much I think it might
be the coolest little nugget
on is the ability to store a DHT ring in
a DNS on DHT stands for distributed hash
table 9
adage T gives you a dictionary like
interface
are key value store I'm but the data or
the nodes are distributed
among the network Spotify I'm store some
updates
service configuration data with in
indiana spared %eh tearing
within a DNS TXT records I'm you may
have seen out here
and TXT records elsewhere I know that
Google App Engine
discern and Guinness mapping with TXT
records
so data from attic a particular Spotify
service
is hashed and is locked at some point am
on
ADHD rating and the servers in the ring
are responsible for certain segment
appearing in this case and since be
owns and keys and from a.m.
3 ass up into 14
and then and since eons from C you 12
and ninety its kinda counterclockwise
little bit confusing
but it's actually it's actually quite
cool to am
use DNS home in this list distributed
fashion
so am I A through um a lot love
DNS at you and dennis is by no means
easy to get into understand within like
a thirty minute talk
so I guarantee you you will and appear
do deployment configuration again
because and DNS is hard
but it's not the only way an but it's
not only hard to learn bit of hard to
make
could talk I was thinking like this talk
is gonna be crap it's actually DNS is
crappy
so some hopefully he'll take some
nearly awesomeness away from those
buying technology and I'm
yeah I hope you enjoyed the talk the
sides will be up soon and I'm
thank you
and now how much time we have through
bit
we have like a minute or two minutes if
them someone
well maybe I'll take one question or
maybe if you want a discussion we could
just
go outside the home does anyone have a
quick question maybe
yeah you
I'm I think pretty hard but
I think it but I think I'll be fine I'm
it probably have to investigate both
like how twisted implemented and
DNS Python implemented on I know that
and
that Spotify has a Duncan Allegri's all
over for a lake at the service
to look up so on I mean so long as you
can to thoroughly understand
the the protocol I guess then I'm can't
be too hard but
it should be a fun exercise actually hmm
yeah
and I i think im at a time but if anyone
wants to catch me outside I'm
then I'm the let's do that thank you
again
one place
thank you he's helping stage yes
months