thank you guys let's start first ball
good afternoon
by from there's on my name is really
cause great nique
and I'm I talkin about
2d/3d graphics with bite on my bile
platforms today
and when we he reads 33 graphics
are we usually think about some games
bottle so it may be not only the game
but some other plications which use
their graphics-intensive leave I like
are for educational purposes or write an
all-south for probably three viewer for
example for
engineer which may show some design
staff
or something like that cell and %ah when
we can't either the use and buy them for
development some
our traffic stop for a while reforms
like Android or I was first equation
which may
are rises and our minds is why
so why you really we should use the
Python as there are a lot of
I existent dole's like unity while
warm many other I game engines which
laws you to do the same
I just to develop the game I ended male
it will be called cross-platform you may
do it both for Android and
chaos well I even have the answers for
this question
and for us to just for fun yes so
we r LAF will off by found many of us
are
albeit or just make the games for I
for Holtby and it's very cool really
when you develop something all the
Python and you my ronit
on your I am favorite my bile
fall on or your iPod iPad and whatever
and you major do are for example right
now
there there are some on games the clone
of the games like
Aug a clone of their flight departs
which is read on the Python and you may
find eat on them
are on their goal on Google Play store
and the first second saris and is the
educational purposes cause
as we all know all the fighting is very
good language for
on educational purposes it's very easy
to learn especially for keys
and are also there open jail which is
quiet well maybe it's just me but I
think that it's quite non-trivial staff
and out with up by them for example its
easier till ornate the because you are
constrained in on the learn in their
open Joe concepts not on their are
buildin
and the bargain this C-plus class called
and stay at
cell really it may be used for are
learning by kids for example
their I use and the pope in jail in
creating the graphic applications which
are maybe a launched on their Obama by
platforms
and second question how which may rise
an hour passes how how can we do it so
of fortunately a
we have their key project which was
measured by greed or hunger also
today and I well it's the framework or
other its them
project are which includes a lot of
frameworks and tools which helps you to
grade the cross-platform application
with bite on four different different
platforms
I didn't lords %ah such such stores like
buy.com for
and Droitwich loss year to year Oct read
the a pic a package
for Android or Kia I'll switch I Los you
to create their
whatever it's called the package for on
for iPad and so
%ah what what's the key via are just
provides for us we may use for our goals
it first of all
it provide a for a white sauce there are
ported
by from core which is the by them either
but there are I was just bored
for are any platform like now I ramp
specific for Android or a also we give
me just
or on aid and Ron any pipeline I
by them called and also it provides them
are robbers around open jail functions
well
are other their OpenGL yes functions cuz
you know
OpenGL ES yes now it's there sup Seattle
they OpenGL for are embedded systems
which are them up I'll platforms as well
sir we have the
by phone interpret their art would have
them our Roberts
of open job functions so in general
art that's all what you what you need to
hear
I'm a graphical applications of your
profession are with
open jail and well I'm a just finished
my talk here
I pop I I'll continue
for their and are I'll explain are which
another obstructions make you provide to
you now
make your life be easier if you want to
do some
by game with Kenya so first of all yes
just
window are which is the class which
represent them
our screen of the divide Dave device for
the mile device
the whole screen and this all screen is
also the canvas
I which way which you may to use for
drawing
our anything you want on this canvas
and also as many other ago where I
libraries have provides the conceptual
we jet and each widget I am may its on
canvas
you may also draw or something on the
scandalous in its maybe
art nah stared it may has are its own
side's position so you may locate it
anywhere you want on this credo
screen of them I'll device and drawl
anything you want
cellco okay sorry I we have right now
they wagered the canvas
and all other are things you may need
are located here
in their graphics module all the key
which is written
are on the site and so it may works
quiet
quite fast are for drawing all the
graphics and
out there main likened sapped all
that draw in are something with the
chibi is
instruction art which may be it well
that two main kinds of its auction exist
are
includes the vertex instruction and
can't get in can
back sorry instructions and I'll let me
explain
difference are between where them
hot-button
barracks instructions it's something
very I am
very easy it's just there graphical
primitives you may use for
drawing some our ICT and goals gusts
Oracle questline
and I we from this primitive sure your
way
create some more complex image on your
plication
are and at the same time comtex
instructions is something non
not feasible really body it's may impact
of hollow
are their other graphical primitives may
be drawn so it's the collar so you may
just said the caller
all their are graphical primitives which
maybe is drawn
are for their just rotate scale
translate been texture whatever you want
to do that with this
are and let's Lacalle it works are in
the Kiwi
and are in the kiryas sale already
mentioned we will we are working with
the canvas
and we just need to specify Billy stop
the instructions for
each canvas which will be executed while
back and was will be redrawn
so are with their with statement weekend
easiest pieces
specified them now number of structures
like cholera
family call or again the lips whatever
you want
are and it will be drawn in this om
in in this canvas and also alternatively
you may just
added via the at function to the canvas
arm and yeah there are some
I some properties of this instructions
like position side for its the perfect
angle
which you may on change done that
dynamically
in Europe occasion at it will be redrawn
cuz each time you change in their
property of Solace auctions
it's triggered bed redrawing all their
canvas
so you may I just change it the size of
their a
dangle somewhere in in their application
and it will be redrawn
immediately are so you're sure you may
just or two
the instruction to somewhere below and
then use it for the new york occasion
and canvas are is justly so
as I already say the you may specify the
number of destructions
and they will be in the executed in that
sequence you
you just said so are dynamically just
may change
something and you know just IOC change
what they were you want in the canvas
during the execution of the program
which
well by well may be used so om
okay let's let's just I'll show a small
them all are for the primitives
com it doesn't work where fosston
fortunately we have the USB but here's
their
simple application I Ron just on the
Android and here's their
on just so recall are rectangle
and triangle which a on drawl
drawn with using of key via and shore
om it maybe not very interesting if you
dont use the textures
and X I use and the pictures with TV
also extremely easy cuz you know
you just need do law the image with
their image class
and I get the picture from me and Seth
for
of 4th for example dangling structure
for any vertex asashoryu mad
May said the texture and you'll get
something like
am once second its
lounge location again or K
you may see something like this are
sayre in this way you may really IOC
creates any duty application
om like game
I am and like in this small game
I just bombed all their all the
graphical style after their
arts I mourn which is the port on the
cheap Mon physical
engine and you may I'm sorry probably
works it not because the queue to slow
its because the used
slow am okay so yes something like this
you may create also we have
their are with the Kia I'll
bot let's returned to my presentation
so yeah here's the question where's
their open jail
are down if I just show your love
graphical primitives
and I am as ellis et
are you may use all the functions of
OpenGL
but its no so here I it may be used with
the special instructions which called
callback and each time when you our
plays the call back
inside of your canvas function well it's
just
call it back it's time the cannisters
redrawn
so you may our place any I
GL function like for example I hear
place that they gona Bowl
are jailed up fast function in my call
back
and then I it will be called each time
when the canvas actually
drawn so in this way if you are
proficient with a rope in jail you may
create
anything you want are inside of called
back but
also as a here out as a mention here
adjuster said
can text I it close to true are it's
very important to do cause you may for
example
break all other stops which should be a
redrawn
after your canvas so are set contains
just
are you know opera set actually can text
to the initial state
before your all your OpenGL instructions
was made
and well be well are very useful if you
don't want to crash something the Europe
occasion
arm so yes really I
just I mentioned about then a blend
their jail that fast
by the fault in the queue it's not on
the table of if you wanna
do something like this I you're really
need to use enable on DAP
render offer before to on be able
do something like 3d staff and let's
meet let me show
very quickly how it may be Don with I
use in the FCIAC
so cute provides your they render
context class which is there
a special canvas which may store all the
variables
I'll which is actually maybe the uniform
variables for your shade or I hope that
someone here
know what is shari's on and
here's how it may be you so first phone
just need to create and
override the camera so that we jet at
dish detailed at
I really you want to use their render
can text instead of
are usual can was down we need to
specify their path
arthur the shade share their file or
either at their
a text all their shape vertex a fragment
shaders itself
on and as on the third section I show
how you may easily said the uniform
wearables just to set the collar
which is are Rep here
and up some other I
variables like model you matrics and
sure
out there applications Symbian
simplified
you weigh looks like bass so you I just
enabling first their jheel they have
then well you
cuite your canvas you should disable its
sure
and inside afraid well it's may be a
good idea to push the metrics cause
if you I you know change their
global matrics you may I again break
something and you're
in Europe the cation II and in the
on some vertex instructions place here
you may just
waste some your Red Sox instructions
like mash
for example our way myspace fiber to sis
in dis iz like it's like OpenGL are
concep
and also you should hospice if I there
now for MoP FMT I'll defer motto
their I attribute I very bills which
will be used in the shade her and
I'll show you here's if SE if you see I
am
spitz find a V posts being normal and V
PC 0
I and then I use well not that we see
heavy this is the Euro our bottom the
first two as their trip with
I variables in my shade or so in this
way you may just
you know greed any mash you wont and
droll any shade there you want to change
are
well yeah do generally whatever arm
okay and then in there and way
are get something like this well
actually it's just the Lord at model
from there
arm option file and let me show how it
looks like
on outlooks on their are
my violin rice so here we are
and okay lift-off so
I am I may just updated as already
implemented their tation found Sherm
on a and well yeah sure and set up this
at you may
face whatever you want and also
are yeah it looks good but not very well
as it
doesn't are in it's not up sorry doesn't
have some textures with pictures
sure it should looks are be better
so here is I they have been in the
textures which
also easy are as with previous example
will just plain
2d instruction so we just are law the
text sure
and arm just said it
are while would create in the mash and
we may get
are sound being like and no
at me see
down well yeah here's
screen some yep something like this are
still again
hi trance on my device quite fast not
started his unfortunately and in Greece
where you mail order any
3d on 3de
model launched bounce some engine
our physical engine and make some
maybe not very on complex but still
are 30-game if you want arm
and are probably its all
their obstructions and helpers their
keep plane keeper lights for you
are barred also I just for fun I just
began to you now
are doing something like port on the 3GS
if you know this library there
Joe strip library are to the key and I
called its q3 and here
that all they are I up provide some more
apps sections like cameras
seen the renders Sol all their arm
sold the staff usually need for are
high-level creation of that 3d
three-year applications well and also as
a
are my families in generally know about
their
are graphic obligation which may be used
with Python
I should also mention about some other
products projects like for example
ni forgot or I hold that they pronounce
there Hyundai Motors framework in the
right way
%ah so it's also the engine for creating
the game it's written on the Python
inside them as well as the key v
bod its it's based on their is delete
and it doesn't provide you with them
are all OpenGL Rupp robbers or just
functions you may use dutifully
and well it has all the advantages and
disadvantages for 3d for example program
in as there's the L
hair has as is based on need and also
here's the
band the 3d very well-known engine are
and
yes the early claimed that on
it may be peeled for Android and now or
send their I
made just create some publication we use
in the this frame or
but first of all I tried it as quiet
non-trivial you know
and the the second second point is
that are its you know quite heavy
after completion may take about one
hundred
megabytes so I of for some simple
3 application it may be quite hairy for
Troy application obviously well
and that's all a half today thank you
very much for attention
and
%ah here's their I
purpose or you may follow-on other
for demoss I shown you today and
if someone have a question your just
welcome to you
austat you have any questions there's a
micro here in front a
thanks for coming into iraqi there's a
great introduction
I was curious if you knew about pile
NGL and whether its I I think I read it
it supports more platforms now and I
wonder if you could use it
with Kitty yet the most complete
possible
up in jail linings hot they do say I did
you say
by by OpenGL right yet sharks lock
of for desktop it's true so you may
place all that by open GL I far chance
inside
call back right I mentioned in my
presentation
and it will work but the problem is hear
that
it will not work for Android and hi
oscars
their are well by a French elsa bro I
just robbers
around open job function/ obviously and
it's quite complicated because I think
that it it's based on this
see types to for date for Android in
there as well
if it will be Don wants you may view
also use the pie of
jail for it but right now known give you
give you functions
official fight works just fine thank you
you're welcome
unico from
Ando question about the compatibility
everything to the
codes to if I were and answer is you
covered this already but
if I E route could to be used with T
intending to deploy it on injury with
certain
compatibility what I have if I also
wanted to deploy to
I O S disc if the serbs track
the code away from when it's running on
so I could compile
to you ATK and deploy that well
hos sorry IOC let me
with me just ask again to end said the
rights of if you are right there by the
courts right
our top like made be I'll
Ron with all the problems of both
Android and Isles problemo
platforms is right yeah yes shore
if you use only the cutest of I yes it's
not the problem the same by from court
maybe you're on the ball
Android and they also problems or
problem sorry
plant for without any problem
as I dot bikini on itself kearse about
it and it provides you
you know their our cross-platform
implementation of this function use
body fuel will you something more
specific
like your own library which is read an
onside
phone with use in some more
platform-specific called
well are it may not work it so we should
nation yeah
be careful about it but you can
generally just use the Python court your
pipe in court
with use in the queue libraries or some
other
libraries which is supported by the Q
project it's not the problem
are France well on both platforms
thank you yeah I think you do and
when I i've seen
code that I Britain I and I want to run
on Android
him but I don't want to do anything
related graphics supposedly present for
Android allows you to do such things
but I did not see any way to connect up
Java code
to to do that typical Angeles out by
four
do you know anything about that is that
something you from there with aus
sorry I'll the problem is that
running running that the Python code
from
from Java control code via icon for
Android is that
something you know about at all on
so running their Java quote from Python
or isomers
now without QB Montreal with south korea
are well it's possible but it's more
complicated
here's arm you need probably
really yeah botch their Java
runner on the Android cause eats
its I am it use more accused of well in
general
I am it just runs your
main dot by all file which may
not call some QB application and may
work like that process
with by from pot are anyway you need to
interact
somehow we their I with the display
yes so of for none graphical application
may be okay by the way still you need
access
there Android API for network and so on
and so on
and yes but I'll
for graphics on its creates their
as DL hot surface for you
and all other things is wrong here its
like like it's implemented for enjoy
something like this
yeah
okay nice see that no more information
great well yeah