okay everyone it's at ten past 12 time
for the
next talk the third and final talk over
this session
before lunch and pick to introduce you
do Christine's bang
gonna tell us about FF I in why you
should use FF I rather than some
processed
hi everybody I'm Christine
huh huh hi
%uh first things first I want to thank
you all for being here in this room
I've been a part of the pipe on
community for a number of years but this
is my first time on stage
and I'm really really excited to give
back to the community
a community that I really really love so
before I jump into my material here
today adds a tiny little bit about me
I i got my start in the Python community
I
in Boston after I graduated from MIT and
boss and I was a cofounder of the possum
pie pan workshop
and others involved in the pipe and use
a group there and also use papon in my
work
at it can be called his place and now I
yeah I moved to San Francisco answered
the company called inbox
at you I learn more about Max you can
talk to me later and but that's not what
the stock is about
at in bucks and a
in my personal hacking I we love Python
a reason price uk buy time for
everything
an height and a really great language
for
a figuring out what you want to write
and rainy quickly
so this talk is about
the times when your writing Python but
you have some other care that you want
to run that's not paid on
sometimes is now a library available to
do what you want are sometimes it's not
fast enough
sometimes you just want to be able to
quickly sell it to some code that
already exists
so we're gonna talk about these to do
different
Anna past you running external code via
Python
the first one is at running an external
binary from papon
and the second one will be wrapping a C
library from papon
and so this kind of stuff the systems
level stuff
is very platform dependent so I wanna
get it out there
from the get-go that I'm talking a/c
pipe on I'm talking about Python 2.7
and also talking about 1x so there be a
few details that are specific to these
particular platforms and but the general
principles definitely our cross-platform
you just need a like figure out the
exact details I have to do with your
platform
r8
the first part a the doc why you
shouldn't shell out
and sometimes why you should so
CIA I and to at work
I me and we have to a building email
platform
and email you consider taxed and
and it turns out the text is rain in
every single language at their
and especially email there a lot two
different ways to represent that text to
computer
and these are called character encodings
and
it turns out the Python only sit a
supports
a subset of all the character encodings
out there at the box
I suspect this is for portability
reasons it has its own implementations a
character in Qatar's
and but it doesn't support
everything and if you want to build a
some software that
is able to handle email from everywhere
in the world also it's a crazy spam
stuff like that
you need to support all them and so I
ran into this problem
where and I wanted to build the Kodak
surprise and in support
so a the first idea I we had here was
and to use this this program called I
calmed which is pretty the standard way
the standard library for and dealing
with that text conversions
on Alex platforms and there's a there's
like manly program called I calm that
you can use on the command line and use
it to convert text from one encoding to
another
so if you want to use this program we
can
and rate a little script and Python say
will call it convert utf8
Anna might look like this: so
you see here super simple and there's
really will only one not lying here
that's actually doing anything
interesting
so we just don't work or pursing some
command line arguments
and then there's one line read the
bottom here says some process that check
call
and then we we see our I calmed command
line program
and all the all the arguments that you
would center down the command line
so this is an example of shelling out
and by shelling out I don't mean using a
shell actually
is not necessarily at like a command
line shell involved here
though there are some arguments to use a
process model dick that can make you
pass your command three shell first
I'm just talking about running this
external program it from
at from tight on and this would
obviously usually be part a
a bigger system but I just cut down the
sample here to make it really simple
alright so what's actually happening
here this is one line of code but it
turns out there's a lot that's happening
behind the scenes
and we want to find out what's going on
so
the first thing I might do when trying
to figure out what's happening in a
particular line up a tankard
and is use the documentation so pet
owners is gray introspection
capabilities so I could just call help
on the function
and shown right here an have at what
exactly is the help string4
check all and we can take a look at it
and
we see it says Iran commended are you
entry for committee completes
every so it doesn't really tell us
what's going on it does tell us how to
use it
which is great that's all you really
need to know but I wanna know more
an and in the case that I wanna know
more I want to know exactly what's
happening with the peace pipe anchored
when I'm gonna do is I'm gonna read the
source
so since I don't open source II can just
take a look at the source code for it so
I let's do that right now so
at yeah I Han hear your just pointing
out one thing
if you want to find the source cared for
any particular Python module
and there's a a python stimuli remodel
called inspects
that will help you with this as you
might have used like but Dunder file
a attribute other model a easier way is
to use the inspect model because
Dunder file it it it doesn't necessarily
always had the right thing in it that
you want
and also will show you that that the
compiled Python file and not the
the source file so you can import this
this function get source file
and then you can call their on your
model and
it'll tell you where the source code is
so we can hold the source can like this
Sarah II pipeline here I'm gonna pull up
this
and this file harry and I mean at it
is a little bit too big he ran specials
more
8 so answer starting out if I know
what's happening here so the first thing
I do is
I am so the the cali wonders call check
call
an so
you can search for that r8 and we just
kinda follow the cold chain downed
until we find out where the actual work
is happening at so you can see this
calls a
another faction called call and it does
some stuff with the return cared to wrap
it properly
so actually calls are here and this is
classic and is wrapping this
this this P open class so we go again
an effort turned out if you like Paul
this call chain down
at far enough and you get to a place
where
a he calls this this line of code
West up for work and if you look at the
documentation for our stuff work
this is a wrapper for and these the fork
system call on your system
right so what's actually happening there
what's a system call sewer system call
is the interface between a user space
application
such as this little script confer utf8
and
the operating system a the machine that
you're running on such as Linux
so let's talk a little bit about the
fork system call and what it does
so if you wanna learn more about a
system call weekend use and
man page to you read about it so
everyone exist and I
should come with able said a man pages
for
at the system calls 9 night that the
next program's annual
and so if we take a look at the fork
system call
man page it gives a lot of information
about what what's happening here
so tells us that fork works by
duplicating
at the process that's calling for work
so when we
do this suppresses call we're actually
duplicating or Python process
how that's interesting right so let's
look a little bit about at at a visual
representation
have what is actually happening we call
for here
at is a few other system calls involved
when we're doing this suppresses call
so what happens is that the Python
interpreter calls for work
at splits into two processes one is
apparent and one is the child
at the parent ends up sitting around
waiting for the child so there's a
system called
call we pitted an and
the the child actually runs as other
system call called exec
and that loads this other program icon
into memory
and then runs it
great so few more details about fork
sOooo I said that the Python interpreter
copies itself
are the operating system copy is a
Python interpreter when
you call for work an this would be
really really expensive if they weren't
a specific way that this happened
and that made it so it wasn't so it
didn't take so long
so when you copy a process you have to
decree
an entire copy at the memory stack but
if week really copy every single
pc memory they belong to that process it
would take a long time and it also use a
lot of memory
so it turns out that at the lips curl
implements this fork
forecast system call by by making the
new process
Use the Memory at low prices into it way
called copy on write
so that means that Italy copies the
pages if the new process
ends up rating to those pages are
changing them
so that way it's it's a lot faster but
it still it still has all this
overhead love abusing operating system
whenever we
and ask for something from the operating
system it has two
the the computer has to do the single
the context which and switches into like
the kernel-mode
and does stuff for the the program and
then it switches back
and in the case have a doing a fork
within a two processes that the
the next girl that has a schedule
between
so to illustrate a little bit more about
this copy on right thing
and have shown to a little excerpt a a
top command running
and a Python program that I F I look at
a lot of stuff into memory and then I
fort
an and the night I captured on top and
you can see here that
and demand a memory being used by
those who prostheses is more than is
actually available on this particular
machine
and it's not using add you heard of us
what cease
there's no spot is being used on this
machine right now so it's not swap
that's
that's taking up that slack it just so
happens that this this tool top
doesn't really know lab oka pran I just
it just thinks that and that memories
being used
an so in order to be able to do this
pork thing
and the Linux kernel has to have a a
certain way it's like looking at memory
allocation
on so those hoping which has two to
assume that process could possibly
on share all of its pages after does a
fork
so it has this this sermon feature that
I wanna talk about a little bit that
allows it to kinda like assume that it's
going to be okay
entered industry how that works a when I
compare this to
to how on surveillance colonel its
memory allocator it
it reads memory allocation a bit Lake
how
airports and our airlines treats an
at selling tickets for flights so
the goal love an airline is to maximize
their profit by
a having other fights be as full as
possible
and so they do this by actually selling
more tickets
then their seats on the flight
because it turns out that most the time
some
at some passengers don't show up but you
still wants to you have a full flight
see sell a few too many tickets and then
some people to show up and then you hope
that it works out
just so that and the man feel they don't
show up are bad as many tickets as the
oversold
and of course you can do models to to
make sure you like it approximately the
right amount
and usually work said okay and supply
skurdal basically does the same thing
with memory
and it has a speaker called over commit
in which
it it actually it turns out that most at
user space processes
also asked for more memory than and
abusing and so it
it will allow people to request an
more memory than they actually end up
didn't than actually is available
and this is what allows the Linux kernel
to be like okay
you can fork its cabin rain an
but you my own share everything but it's
okay
so just a little more Mac over commit
you get a tweak these
settings on the kernel an you can I
change that how it how it actually
allocates
a response to requests if you disable
overcommitted
at fork if it will take up more memory
if if copying the entire process would
take up more memory than
on is available the machine or dispel
and its can get a bit more complicated
if you aster involving virtualization
and containers
and sometimes a
your run into situations where and
the police Colonel actually does exhibit
too much memory and
DM equivalent to the airline and giving
people doubters
for and taking a different flight is
actually the single button killer
in which it uses algorithm to just pick
in random processes to kill
and that's not really a good situation
but the point that I am trying to get
across your is mostly that
there's a lot of things going on under
the hood when you call it's a process
you can run into weird failure modes
depending on what your setup is
and also there's a lot of overhead in in
in that it has to ask for a lot of
things from
the underlying operating system at Cedar
under problems there
but and they're also like a lot of
reasons to use a process
and turns out that most the time I I do
use a like shelling out a lot
an it's really simple if there's just
command line program that you have that
you
and did you want to run from a Python
script I would just chill out
it's super easy and it was that it works
and is pretty flexible on at plus-one of
in most cases
you can like read the standard air and a
standard air and communicate via pipes
and spy drones rappers will will for
Python exceptions you have to deal
return codes really
but there's these dangers attacker the
overhead
it also it is the case that its limited
API if you disconnect mickey over the
command line
and also if you have to transfer a lot
of data to an
to this program you're into battery
issues
if you're after a you you'll have
overhead from I O if you're writing out
temporary files because you can just
transfer data in memory at two to the
process
and if you're using an about original
pipe
I if you like sending information to to
the process and get information back you
can run into deadlocking issues
soaking in a little complicated and I
would say that
if you're trying to do something more
than a simple just like run and look at
the center towers center dare
you probably don't actually want to be
shelling out
rate to do it anyway usually I i do it
all the time
and but never gonna talk about
an a different case so there are a lot
of times when
shelling out to process is not good
enough and
those those cases are are usually when
you care a lot about performance like
you're gonna be invoking that program a
lot of times
an or decide you need a more flexible
interface
and it mainly program just doesn't work
have enough
and it doesn't want you to just to
invoke a single function
so how do we do that how do we call as
he cared for by Don
so this is all something called a
foreign function interface and foreign
function interface is just a way that
at ruling which translates between the
Konkan mentions 0 one language and the
other
and reps like the data structures and
makes them available
so there but two different options for
calling seek aid from papon
I hope to shine a little bit late on the
landscape here
so the first to go option is to racy
extension
so python is just RC pipeline at least
is just a C++ program
and you can make at more code
available for Python I just rating more
at the same period as a rate moore's C
Python
and then you have more papon available
you to bring a lot of see that way
newspaper ANSI API
teen you see types which is
per the Python standard library I wrap
sis other library called live better 5
you don't you C compiler and you can
just load the
the model rain to memory and it's a bit
tedious
its kinda computer has a few a few
drawbacks
and isn't is this thing called site on
which eyes have like hybrid language
between president seen
and employees at more for leaking
optimizing speed than just like
accessing
external libraries are just like ined I
have this
this one little function and that's and
kinda slow
somewhere really great insight on and
use that and the option to talk about a
bit more is called see if I'm
this was written by the pipe I authors
on
to address and c-type shortcomings and
you can use it at the EPIA be available
so you can
and rated against like this see and the
API that the CIA provides or you can
do to EVA eyes like that the compiled
version which is less flexible and like
a bit more brittle but you don't use a
compiler
which is kinda nice art so wanna talk a
little bit more about these different
options in the context a problem that I
had at work
which we talked about before so in order
to get around this like oh I have to
excel at every time I wanna
and it converts in tax from these weird
in coatings an
we looked at and wrapping
at this this library that a icon
provides cool if I come
and turns out that the M the command
line program icon just
a is just a a command-line rapper to
this library
so it turns out there's eighty
electrical live by comp that's available
on
I P I that eg implement sissy extension
module
for Python and looks a bit like this and
again she a bit more
about it
go to Mexico
a here it is so you can see it's like
about 250 landed see
now looks like seeing me and this
this ray here's kinda the media there's
there's like three API functions in that
live by conference at
provides it's super simple at a called
icon open
icons and I comes close
an so the main one is called icon which
does the actual conversion
and you can see this rapper here a
string seeker can be a a bit tedious
cell
you know is that there's like and I've
shinyuka pager code here and it's
actually just still pursing the AM
the the that the arguments to this
function
an so definitely a lot less concise than
Python
and not really doing anything here that
involves
actually interfacing with the library
yet
sale know this is really interesting
until we get to hear where we actually
ran
performing the conversion and actually
read a lot of this code when
and I was thinking a very rating it and
and it is like a few
questionable things I has a few bugs
that I want to fix
but I can't decide that that whole
approach that they were taking was not
very good after all in that
at Lake converts things to a cutie
F-sixteen and then
dumps that directly into pythons
internal on
internal unico representation our view
the
like that papon's see API and like
that's actually at dependent on like the
platform you're on
answer I was a presidentially works but
I prime means that I'm
just running on the same platform as the
person who wrote it
so there are a couple reasons that I
want to improve this bed
can I have decided that I didn't
actually want to use it after all
great so I decided to you ready
different implementation using see if I
which
I'd heard was pretty much the best
option for
on shelling out to an external library
from Petrino
and we show you a bit about I the
implementation I wrote so this is an
excerpt which is actually the
and the interesting part but i wanna put
up in a terminal so you can look at some
more
and gosh this is too big any
set the whole thing you pry can't read a
lot of it by alt a little bit
that something's in so this whole
filings are being
and 150 lines and I have like actually a
lot of documentation in here
so I'll tail around house you for
fireworks
so it's pretty simple to setup and
and you have like a little boy %oh point
here we have to i get a hand on it a
fight class
and then you gotta tell see for 5k
an a little bit about the seeker that
you're wrapping just so it knows how do
I setup the
the mapping from sea to papon and so
here I am just like
at giving some declarations but I can
actually an
I can leave a few different a few things
out here so I i tell it that there's
some constants I want to use
but are the Telit white the constant
with the value of the conference are
and because it turns out the super
Viking figure that out on its own
and I see there's like this some see
struck said I want to use but I don't
have a tell it
and the size of the struct or what the
individual members are because
see if I can also figure that iron which
is pretty pretty sweet
an and then you run this verifying call
which is what and in development
see for viola actually transparently
invoke your compiler behind the scenes
which is really sweet
an you end up not having to go through
that
the typical see workflow and found you
and your code
and invoke make aren't like manually
compile and then
your check and see if it works are
running it as you see provide for
development just does that behind the
scenes for you
which is really magical experience
hearse Inc
a yes it is verify Sep is just what
wants you provide us for like figure and
what's what what are the sizes are these
things in setting up
and the mapping to fight on as a lot of
the rest to this file
actually ends up being papon and when
the
amazing things about using gallery likes
you for FY is
that you end up being able to you see
code but also use Python
Python mechanisms for abstraction to
rate here I'm actually I'm reading a
class
calling i com and giving it my fans
and I also implement
it as a context manager so I can use a
the with statement with it and you have
it automatically know call I come close
when it's done
so it's really nice to to building used
the better abstraction mechanisms that
the pipe and provides and to not have to
a great
all my curry in a typical as see fashion
rate so it's a little bit about the
interesting part here
so inching heard this code is this one
an this one method I com and
a lot of the I love the work years
actually an
is actually just allocating a buncha
at cd2 structures from Python is really
cool
am taken call a fight at new here in the
passage character pointer hand
live like I'll keep his memory and I
have a Hamilton papon
and thence then see for FY handles a
bunch of things behind the scenes
and have magically in that you can use a
Python string and assign it to a
character array
a/c character and it will do the right
thing
an and it has a bunch a different
other different features I love this is
just
an is just setting up the proper
pointers and and strings and batteries
and then to have this one call here
where I a call the icon
CE function from from
fight on and then I actually cast it to
an integer
and that's that's the interesting for
here it's like a belt 40 lines at code
that actually interfaces with C
which is definitely a far cry from the
250 lines that
that we saw in that Python extension
so you see that if you go from
this is not like it completes at like a
totally production-ready virginian
I have to a fix a few bags and also
package it properly
and its system single development file
right now
an but in the general case
you in a break it a ton last see if
using something like see if I
9 stuttering issue extension
and that's really great because it means
we
she is really awesome and it allows you
to eat to be really close to the machine
and
if you like a wizard and do a lot of
things that you can t from had none
but it doesn't mean that we want to be
writing see all the time
I don't want to be spending pages have
could pursing
at like argument sir I dealing with a
lot of different string things
and so if I can
make them manage see that I rate just
the amount that I need to interface with
this library and do kinda interesting
see things that
that the library provides an my life is
in me a lot
easier I mean it's been a lot less time
in team things
it can be faster to rate in also an
easier to debug
so the conclusion a this'll section is
to
rate lissy and for all those reasons
that I just mentioned
little serene the pregnancy extension
that we looked at dinner 59 to see me
see fire ever 120 lines of Python and
C++
rare forty those actually interface with
C
r8 so let's
take a look at everything that we talked
about here what do we learn
first we talked about calling external
process scenes from some process
and this is the really simple simple way
to do things
and but it has a few caveats one is that
its release pensions
a King do crazy things that memory and I
can take a lot of computation time
because at the context switches between
userspace
and curl space and insulin flexible
so if Ed if that's not gonna be
sufficient for your needs
you might want to look at rapping C
library an
and we showed you that one night example
from and this from the tires having
and wish a reduce the amount I see that
her
or rather I do some options
an and heredity extension even you see
types
axle Kanchi are you can you see if I and
and using seaver file as you to minimize
the amount of see that your rating
and there's obviously cases where you
not gonna did were some other option is
going to be better there's tons a
different rappers out there
like if you're using sepals plus you may
want to use a boost Python or something
like that
but if you for the civil case where
you're wrapping issue library
and supervisor leary option
and so we talked a bit about alive like
system sobel things that to think about
when you're writing code
an and i really wanna highlight here
that
even though most the time we spend
writing a high-level languages like
Python
a high-level language means that that
there's a lot of levels
underneath your level and all those
different pieces
affect what you're doing so you need to
understand them
sometimes most the time you can you
cannot think about them because things
just work but when things go wrong
you still need to understand the pieces
that are underneath and paid on
so it pays to to learn those those
pieces
lanting's about your operating system in
interface between pat on your operating
system
it'll really payoff when you have to be
optimizing things for speed
we have to be debunking weird errors now
in Ft running systems in production
and that's all I have for you today
thanks so much for coming
I say hi to me and you follow me on
twitter all the code that I a show you
today is on get herbs again how dot com
slash spanning
if you have any questions about an Icee
are several see their systems or
inbox and ask
ask away I'll be here I guess lunch is
up next cerro
and I can hang around for a few minutes
after its a problem
but plenty of time for questions if
anybody wants to use the microphone
man I'll and the other side I'll so when
you were writing the CFI code
huh how did you debug sec faults I
um there's always you can you can still
print things Fran
using see if if I as well he just kinda
do print our friend from Python
that there are a few things but I had to
deal with in that and
doing all that text processing from
Taipan an
is often so those are you like you know
cast something to the wrong type and
Mike
I get my some crazy 0.0 reich I it was
giving it
a pointer to the wrong data structure
and we just crash
and but it's pretty much the same as
seeing separates nicer because you
provide us to compile set for you
which is which is present thanks
I do you have any suggestions on
resources for
learning more about the layers between
Python and everything under Python yes
sure
um for Linux there's a great book called
The the Luminex
programming interface TLD PKI ads really
good book you should check it out
and ever have anything else I can think
about the top my head but I can think
about it a bit and migrate something out
cool is using us he tapes
as like is the a lot more complicated
and see if that I
'em I haven't done it personally because
an
everything I read said that see if I
would be easier and I use and it worked
cerro and I've heard ever heard that its
kinda clicking after Mr cared and
there's some problems are then
and as a civic Sam
yet prevent I it seems like to see if I
might be a decent sort of
the a bridge step to some to someone who
with experience ring Python
wanting to learn more about reading see
up but I can also see %uh that might not
be the case in much as wonder what your
penis
our much I think if you're like a very
beginner you probably you want to start
is writing see
actually aka an just there's fewer
moving parts so
your things together on at if you just
near ratings he found compiling in
and you want to know about that stuff
anyway because if something goes wrong
with Steve Irvine then you don't know
what's going on
coolant we get the other ranked like
actually
thanks for the turkey does great
location
and then i'm new slavery supports J
them some Java libraries calls um
I I don't think it does it supports pipe
I
but and it's obviously dependent on the
the back end okay thinkin
a are you have you tried so big
or is there is is there any reason you
didn't use a week because it would look
like a
how to the books kinda easy solution for
C especially I
I didn't you swing on my mission this
week in the desert like code generation
and like the Kanata automatic stuff
issue fighters was really an
appealing to me but there's like a lot
of options so
the reason that I haven't real them is
mostly that there's a lot of options
okay thanks you know
us
looks like that's it for question so
thank you Christine I hereby declare at
lunch time