Devlin please welcome her Friday
a burger Japan Catherine Devin govern
you I see docs run run docs ran
I hope that came out right that's all
the French I got but time
thank you I'm all these slides are
already online at tiny URL
slash run docs run and I will give that
URL again at the end
and it has links to make it have repo
and everything else you gonna need to go
that's the only part that you need to
write down you don't even need to write
it down yet
so the stock is on execute about
documentation which is a term that I
just made up
to better define it i'm talking about.
documents that poet in real living code
and execute that code
and the results so that execution either
validate or get incorporated
into the document when you generate that
document or refresh that document
or even when the reader is reading the
document as for what a document is and
what you think
really brought me here so I can get away
with being in the education track
I yeah i'm talking about. I wrote this
package here's how you use it
but I'm also talking about educational
documents like here's how you learn to
program
here's how you do this science problem
here so you do this math problem
or organizational documentation here's
how you request a new laptop here's how
we do our builds
here's how you request funding to come
to Pike on these are all kinds of
documents that can actually
benefit from having code embedded in
them wire we bothering our docs perfect
well docks and perfect on Bundchen
problems with them
this doesn't address although many
dresses summer them one of the big
problems
is inaccuracy that results from
forgetfulness you think okay now I'm
gonna write the docs to do it works like
this it works like this
and you've already forgotten summer the
details about the program works in you
right
inaccuracies in or it was accurate to
begin with
but then time passes the code changes
the organization changes
and you forget to update the documents
also
there's boredom most first love to Cody
it really engages our brain we get
focused on the problem and we
with do a fairly good job writing code
and documentation is more like a chore
we can resent it and that boorda me
shows through
and the boredom spreads to the reader
and just not that engaging or relevant
are fun to read
so what we end up writing is historical
fiction
it wasn't even true to begin with is
progressively less true
and nobody's interested in reading it
now
I've never read this book but it sure
looks like it sucks
so
coating your documents can help fix this
problem both in that
the document can become self verifying
the document lets you know when it's
false
or the document cannot be false because
it's pulled straight
out have live working code also because
it's Cody your brain will re in gage
it wakes up it gets back into the
problem its write something that purse
relevant and that you care about and
then the reader will end up caring about
it and the quality of your documentation
will improve
sir to illustrate all this
I'm going t I made up a fake little
package called argument clinic and we're
going to just
run through how we might document up
some users samples and checking on the
software requirements
we're going to do that with four
different technologies
and because that's a lot to cover gonna
be going fast the examples are going to
be really simple
but I want to cover some the basic
boilerplate abusing each of these
and then you can decide what might sue
your project to the oldest one is doc
tests this goes back to a previous
millennium
lost wisdom of the ages the idea docked
s
is simply that your arm your your doc
strings can and should include usage
samples
though should show the user how to use a
piece of code in what the result
should be that they can expect now in
this case here's a piece of code
where clearly the code is not complete
it's not going to succeed at both these
it will answer this first one correctly
but is not going to respond the way our
doctor suggests it should
her doc string suggests should and Doc
tests job is to go through pluck out
those examples in doc strings and let
you know when they fail
so this is just a verification technique
for your doc strings
doc strings gets kinda bad rap from
testing snobs because they feel like
it's not a
good complete rigorous unit testing
solution and
fine gonna concede that this is
orthogonal to your unit testing solution
not competing with knows our product
tester anything else
instead I'm renaming these to execute a
boat dock strings now the word test
isn't even in their
and the whole point is simply to make
your doc strings
relevant and accurate and more
interesting and enjoyable to read
Sep those been around forever next
technology up sphinx is more recent
and this is actually part of why the
documentation in the Python world has
improved a ton
because sinks takes a buncha restructure
text documents
and generates a complex but not overly
complex
I I tree documents they can refer to
each other
they include search ability in index
ability really a pleasure to read in a
pleasure to use
stinks in itself isn't exactly what I'm
calling execute with documentation
but there's some really worthwhile
plugins for six extensions rather
for instance the doc test extension does
exactly what the regular doc test module
does
but it does it against your six document
it comes with think so all you have to
do is say that you want it as you
setting up
each speaks project and popping into the
directory where
alright here's a restructured text
document that uses it
that big truck in the middle layer is
just it looks exactly like
a doc test you might use in a regular
piece of code but its
included in this doc test directive and
one side done that
when I build my spank stock and include
the magic word doc test
the extension is going to run through
their grab their stock guests and run
them
just the same way the doc test module
itself would
and give me a complaint and thus verify
that the user samples I put in my spinks
document
are in fact still up to date
6 also has an auto dock extension which
will go through the doc strings in your
code
pull them into your specs document and
the Sphinx doc test extension
understands what the eye doc extension
is doing
will see those doc tests that have been
brought in that way we recognize the man
execute them so
there'll be another chance to execute
their stock tests and verified it is
working
another possibility this one is not
included with thinks it's called
auto run CF to go through a few steps
first to install it and then to enable
it with each
within each thinks project but the idea
is that once you've done so you can
create these
run block directives and then have a
literal block that with this looks a lot
like a doc test
but what is missing is the response
instead of predicting what the response
should be and complaining if it's
Ron this leaves the response blank and
let that get filled in at the time that
we build the doc
so here we have were using the package
but were you saying nothing about
the response when we make this document
what we get
now the response is that the program
provided are mixed in there into the
document
there's one option another extension
very very similar
oh I'm sorry it was we have a little
more to show not a run the other
interesting thing
here I just whipped up a package that
can probe this system find out what the
requirements i txt for
are whether the system meets those
requirements
and then I can invoke that from within
my document
so here's a camera live requirements
document I can also go all the way
outside of pipe on all the way out to
the console with this
run block console command and execute a
command line
like I'm going to ask what progress
Russian I'm running
same echo presenter Chamique am
so the result of that
here we have we checked on our what
documentation we've got
an on what push Chris version running
are right another very similar extension
is called program output
again you need to you install this
enable it
and the basic working is really really
similar I'm
but in this case you have a couple
choices you can either use program
output Corp command output I
you can't go directly into Python if you
want to call Python from here you have
to do is if your attic man mein
using the Python man
but let's take it a look at the result
that gives pretty similar the difference
is with the program output
you don't actually see the command it
was used to generate it
whereas with command output the command
that we issued gets echoed back
discover options
tons and advantages to spanks I'm it
generates this lovely structure it's
really become the Python standard
you can host speaks documents well
they're actually playing a shemale so
the really easy to host
but you can also host them at read the
docs for free
and then this weeks eco-system is huge
very rich
all search bags all sorts of extensions
and options and yet it's not too hard to
get started with
just right off the bat give shout outs a
couple projects that I don't really have
time to cover in their little bit
off the beaten track but one is called
literate resting
is really pretty similar to what I was
showing with the Sphinx extensions
in that it takes to restructure tech
stock and let you go out n
insert external code I'm against one
researcher tech stock at a time it
doesn't look straight into sphinx
that's not a Python program but aides
Brown did it so it deserves and
honorable mention anywhere
and then spinks country auto program is
very limited but nice program that just
goes out
if you use Arg purse it looks at your
programs our purse
and pulls that documentation in this pic
so that kinda counts is a version NIV
execute all documentation
next big technology is there anybody
here who isn't yet
gathering with excitement over the iPad
a notebook anybody
good good are as well you should be I am
I am NOT going to try to compete with
the fantastic keynote by Fernando
yesterday if you haven't seen it
definitely watch the video
I am just going to remind you there
every I Python notebook
is in fact a beautiful example %uh
execute herbal documentation as i've
been talking about
because every single cell in that
notebook can either be a markdown cell
which will be interpreted into a good
looking piece a document
or a code cell which you can execute
and get the results right there and of
course because it's I Python
you're not limited to Python you can use
the
exclamation point and go outside the
system so this is doing
what this week six engines were doing
doing it really fast and easy when it
comes to ease
integrating the documentation part with
the code part you
you really can't beat this every single
cell I'm
are you do you say oh okay this one
occurred sell this one to market and
sell
and that's all there is to it
you our image change that's right mine
I price I know but you have a bunch I
have options for serving them you can
certainly certainly yourselves
NB viewer is supplied by the iPad time
project
basically if your notebook is save out
there on the web
anywhere and has a URL then you pump
that URL
over to NB viewer and Nazif
and then is hosted on line this is a
free service now in this case
its a static copy of the document to the
user can actually use it live
but they can always download and then
run it on their own machine if they like
and then I'm continue analytics will let
you host a notebook live
at work carried out I L again for free
at least for certain
Nasher at the cutoff is or how they're
running works but on
so you have all these options for
hosting in the iPod iPhone nobody's
going to the most executed documentation
because not
only do you get to execute it when you
generate the document
the user can execute it well they're
reading it and see what actually to run
their system
in fact they can jump in an experiment
with these code tells
try things out so that they you can be
introducing a concept to them
in the documentation part and their work
area to try it out an experiment and
learn things
is right there in the very same window
their brain doesn't have to switch gears
as the move back and forth between other
windows
amazing amazing 20
now the notebook that i've shown really
basic
really dull but the iPad from project
has some
amazing tools out there look at the main
in the viewer site
which hosts some great-looking notebooks
the there's a galleria interesting I
Python notebooks likewise
really expand your brain with some other
possibilities I'm just gonna quickly
show you
one notebook that was used to generate a
text book abusive educational material
so if you want to know if a miss crusher
the sizable if the notebook can
do the sort rich output that you need
for what you're looking for
on the answers almost certainly s
so not only does it have all this the
user can go and mess with things
I'm yeah really easy integration between
the code in the document
he's a guest to experiment and all these
hosting options definitely want
check out the iPad and MacBook
last technology I think i'm brushing
from their nervousness is
forgive me I'm Dec see here's the only
one you probably haven't heard on at a
guess
this is a framework for applying various
transformations to documents that
sounds kinda meaningless but will get it
installed
and then we'll try their several steps
to using it
first you need to run setup to build can
be
infrastructure that you need in the
directory
then you right up your source text files
these can be there restructure text or
markdown
then you need to write a recipe and
that's just a text file that tells Dec
see
what transformations you want to apply
finally year ended exit command itself
to
generate the document from all this
source
cell here's an example of a source file
that's going to run through Dec see
it looks pretty similar to that what
we've seen before but now
who I wish hang on can I crank that
France as a now it's
rather resists having the size cranked
up sorry about that
I'm
what we had here this looks like a
ginger to tag in fact
is agenda to tag and it says we want to
go out to taxi
and have it grab a document and include
that in here
and then pipe that through its own
intent filter index EE to the
transformation to refer to as filters
so basically we want the right exit this
script and then we watch it again but
this time
we're grabbing the Texas the script and
they were popping it through the
pipeline filter in other words
run it through Python and get the
results include that right here
and then we're going to do something
similar on the software requirements
finally we're going to go out n use a
bash script
and pump there is also that bash her
sorry pump this bash script
through bash itself to executed and
we're going to insert
those results right here in the
paragraph and Dec see is the only tool
that makes it easy to
insert your results wherever you want
them in the document they don't need to
be in
separate blocks they can be right there
in the flood the text if that's what you
want
so let's see the result I'm sorry I
forgot
the recipe file the next thing you have
to do is say to Texas alright
for although the restructured text file
defined in this directory
please apply ginger so that the tags be
work
and then there's a couple on filters
that basically set up some sane defaults
for an HTML page
and then these intended items does
represent requirements
there required for the IRS e-file namely
you're going to need to pump
I the Python files through the pipe and
filter and bash house had through the
bash filter
so finally once we've done at my
goodness
her Hatton not a problem I have thought
I had that going let
an ass which winners this
haha
I know ok that's right a big burn
remember would have to you thank ru
doing great here
they're bigger alright here's our result
so we have the techs %uh the Python
program and then we have
the result and Python program here we
didn't ask for the tax if it we just ask
for the result
and here we have requires Bob apply you
have
PostgreSQL and this is the result that
bash script
inserted directly into my paragraph
money back up a place
art
advantages and exceed you get a huge
variety of transformations in fact
I meant to put this in stride but let's
arm I mention that
each of these transformations is called
a filter index E
so Dec see has a
lot I love available filters
how can as I get your as almost too many
I'm and XE others written in Python
the code your executing doesn't have to
be in Python so if you're doing a ruby
or copy scripter who knows what
you can type it through any of those as
the filter and document up
whatever language you're working in and
you have really
the most complete control of the output
see if you have really exacting demands
and what the output is gonna look like
you very well may need to have end up
using taxi
but I gotta admit this is the hardest
one to work with
on I was up kinda late last night caused
XE was doing some last-minute betrayal
on me
I'm to you can put more work into this
if that's the way you need to go
I'm there's a dixie reset commit command
that you will probably need to fall back
on sometimes because
Dixie caches and either there's a bug or
I'm bad at using it and it keeps on
thinking that issue reuse cashed
material that I have refreshed also
here's the irony: the documentation for
Dixie is incomplete
white okay wherever I'm nonetheless an
extremely powerful 20
so I'm shown you mechanics
mechanics a really basic hello world
style wrapping Cody into documentation
honestly that was not the most important
part in the talk
this is the most important part the talk
which is where you use your imagination
to apply these techniques to you all
sorts of problems also to documents that
you write
almost anything that you write this on
the computer could benefit
if you think about imaginatively for
example
don't just assert white on Python
versions your code runs with
run talks include the results ever talks
run
right there in the document how about
living lecture notes where the student
can experiment
as the read without even breaking away
from your text that would be an iPad for
notebook
technique in intact I've used that to
teach it does work very well
how about tutorials actually
assist with configuration obviously they
would need to install
your document first but then the
tutorial could
look at the system see what they have in
help talkin to what else they need
or a troubleshooting document that
doesn't just say what the problem might
be
but the examines the system tries to
figure out what the problem might be
don't just say this needs to gigs memory
say
this needs to gigs memory and I see that
you only have one gig
maybe that's the problem how about
dashboards
that don't just give you statistics and
facts about the system
but included text explaining the
relevance and those statistics and those
facts
how about organizational documentation
that response to changes in the
organization
so it no longer says see joe for a new
laptop
once joe's user account disappears from
the system how about
compliance documentation for those if
you have to do PCI compliance
documentation or government compliance
documentation
the actually can verify itself don't
just
assert that the data is hashed in the
database for example
you can query the database in the
document and verify that
tons of possibilities I hope that your
imagination will get fired up
that you will start to include these
techniques in document to rate in the
future
and I hope that your imagination will
work on some questions
I'm they get have ripple is right here
and all the slides are rate here plus of
course you will be able to find them
on the Python web site I finished way
early so if you don't have some
questions are gonna have a long break
thank you
hi I grow talk
I was wondering so I'm running a saucer
where we have going to the conditions
tutorial
I love how to install the software and
the steps the
also create for the congressional Sloan
Anza
on maybe I'm missing something I was
wondering if we could run
this story all the games like like a
test it was a solution for that for
creating files
and changing those two lines and so on
on
yes I do think that you should be able
to do that if you can
the trouble is of course that the user
is first going to need to get
enough installed so that one of these
techniques will work
on so that they will need to have a
little bit
have I though even need to have been
notebook or whatever the technology is
but at that point you could definitely
have on a document that
then oh no I was wondering there was a
way to make sure that the strip but this
tutorial is still valid
like we don't have to David Stewart like
if every time we do a comment on our
software
rear-ended the that with this tutorial
against the softer
I C yes well if it for instance if it's
thinks then every time you run make HTML
I it's going to execute those the if
you're using like the iran or program
output
that will in fact execute every time you
run make HTML see if you can run a make
a bit
wherever that fits into your workflow
generating the document it will
confirm that live distinct exactly and
when I was wondering if
if there was a tool for because here
like they are great tools for doctors
stand for Python testing but what about
unabashed testing modify missile I think
this file
and I'm good so for example there is a
the choice asking trade this followed
this
exact path yes is there such school arm
if you're let me think you can
right up to say if you wrote up a bash
script that would look at the system to
see if they'd
followed this tutorial steps arm then
you could include the result from that
in a document and many I'm a close to
what you're getting at I'm not sure
I am not really a I think we can chat
about
yet to 800 I'm sorry I'm mad at me I'm
missing the point okay that's right 36
will have a catch you after
I'm say I guess I actually have a very
similar question so
we shouldn't write documentation that is
Taz but it for putting code in our
documentation
ih0 can any of these tools
test the expected result I mean if we
put a doc test but if we say
you know I don't want my documentation
is a not implemented or value error:
something
in that case arm the doc test
extension 26 would be a good one in that
it doesn't
throw ugly things into the document it
just verifies that what you have
is what you expected on so that might be
the way you want to go in a case
this probably way too I'm sure you could
hack up the other techniques like
the notebook to do that to you but yet
the doctor succession would be
the easiest way to approach that just
quick answer also this
if anybody knows about seaborn plotting
library
on top of met put leap for a partner
boobs
so that gay road little script which
tested notebook produces the same
output as before writes a few great
document tonight but nobody just
rerun it and it would with verify the
doubt but is the same so it's simple
solution for that
big and isn't that in 0 cash there's a
repository over I Python notebook
add-ons is that do you know if that's
where that is
I just saw it in seaborne itself so if
you go to Kop
on just search for a seaborne and its
beautiful plotting library gay so
based on panda so if you want really
quick overview
Andries tutorials on that and how he
analyzed
Titanic data using seaborn just really
going step by step
ok but that's all we had a virgin so
sent pete has the tool seaborn for
verifying that an iPad and notebook is
not giving you weird unexpected results
okay thank you for that I'm the question
use
doxie as a preprocessor spanks basically
keep the output has restructured test
and unprofor that means for example you
can in fact do that
arm and that would be one way to still
use stinks
and grab some additional options for how
to incorporate live data for your system
via the Dexia excellent example yeah yet
because you re
your output format from Dec see doesn't
have to be
anything a couldn't you can just put it
right back into restructure text
and the process that from there thank
you for a great example
I'm so like you said we've all seen eye
Python notebook do you like insanely
mind-blowingly awesome things
om has anyone tried to integrate that
into staying so that you can get all
those cool like
a spinny charts in like sliders that
make we graphed things are
I mean so that probably wouldn't be
possible in stock it static environment
but like
has anyone tried to get to like I guess
get to know that I Python magic into
sphinx yes
I'm usually the answer to you has anyone
tried is yes
okay I am but I don't know okay I'm
gonna throw this one out I don't know
such example does anyone know hun
does anyone is a much safer sprints I
I'm that would be a really interesting
project and I can't tell you
but get thank you thank you
okay I'm one other
interesting tool to look at here is and
another things plugin called Manuel
Maj lets you and instead o
displaying your your talk tests as
doc tests allows you to show them as
code snippets which the
more complex examples can be I'm
really helpful and well as in
the waiter from and
both towers I mene you
empl yes whom
I had to put high PI in there as well to
get
fundamentally okay well thank you for
the recommendation to the center is
somewhere out there is thinks Manuel
extension
that well I'm give you other options for
running the doc tests
an OK celibacy my contacts or give me
trouble under the glare I think that's
all the questions we have a right
okay alright thank you
enjoyed a recipe I got